<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Protocols Annexed To The Treaty Establishing A Constitution For Europe on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Protocols Annexed To The Treaty Establishing A Constitution For Europe on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Protocol On The Application Of The Principles Of Subsidiarity And Proportionality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-02/</guid>
      <description>Article 1
Each institution shall ensure constant respect for the principles of subsidiarity and proportionality, as laid down in Article I-11 of the Constitution.
Article 2
Before proposing European legislative acts, the Commission shall consult widely. Such consultations shall, where appropriate, take into account the regional and local dimension of the action envisaged. In cases of exceptional urgency, the Commission shall not conduct such consultations. It shall give reasons for its decision in its proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol On The Location Of The Seats Of The Institutions And Of Certain Bodies, Offices, Agencies And Departments Of The Eu</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-06/</guid>
      <description>Sole article
 The European Parliament shall have its seat in Strasbourg, where the 12 periods of monthly plenary sessions, including the budget session, shall be held. The periods of additional plenary sessions shall be held in Brussels. The committees of the European Parliament shall meet in Brussels. The General Secretariat of the European Parliament and its departments shall remain in Luxembourg. The Council shall have its seat in Brussels. During the months of April, June and October, the Council shall hold its meetings in Luxembourg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol On The Statute Of The European Investment Bank</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-05/</guid>
      <description>Article 1
The European Investment Bank referred to in Article III‑393 of the Constitution (hereinafter called the ‘Bank’) is hereby constituted; it shall perform its functions and carry on its activities in accordance with the provisions of the Constitution and of this Statute.
Article 2
The task of the Bank shall be that defined in Article III‑394 of the Constitution.
Article 3
In accordance with Article III‑393 of the Constitution, the Bank&amp;rsquo;s members shall be the Member States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-1/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE STATUTE OF THE COURT OF JUSTICE OF THE EUROPEAN UNION
Article 1 The Court of Justice of the European Union shall be constituted and shall function in accordance with the Constitution, with the Treaty establishing the European Atomic Energy Community (EAEC Treaty) and with this Statute.
TITLE 1: JUDGES AND ADVOCATES-GENERAL
Article 2 Before taking up his duties each Judge shall, before the Court of Justice sitting in open court, take an oath to perform his duties impartially and conscientiously and to preserve the secrecy of the deliberations of the Court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-2/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 2: ORGANISATION OF THE COURT OF JUSTICE
Article 9 When, every three years, the Judges are partially replaced, thirteen and twelve Judges shall be replaced alternately. When, every three years, the Advocates-General are partially replaced, four Advocates-General shall be replaced on each occasion. Article 10 The Registrar shall take an oath before the Court of Justice to perform his duties impartially and conscientiously and to preserve the secrecy of the deliberations of the Court of Justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-3/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 3: PROCEDURE BEFORE THE COURT OF JUSTICE Article 19 The Member States and the institutions of the Union shall be represented before the Court of Justice by an agent appointed for each case. The agent may be assisted by an adviser or by a lawyer. The States, other than the Member States, which are parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area and also the European Free Trade Association (EFTA) Surveillance Authority referred to in that Agreement shall be represented in same manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-4/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 4: THE GENERAL COURT
Article 47
The first paragraph of Article 9, Articles 14 and 15, the first, second, fourth and fifth paragraphs of Article 17 and Article 18 shall apply to the General Court and its members. Articles 10, 11 and 14 shall apply to the Registrar of the General Court mutatis mutandis.
Article 48
The General Court shall consist of twenty-five Judges.
Article 49
The members of the General Court may be called upon to perform the task of an Advocate-General.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-03/title-5/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 5: FINAL PROVISIONS
Article 63
The Rules of Procedure of the Court of Justice and of the General Court shall contain any provisions necessary for applying and, where required, supplementing this Statute.
Article 64
The rules governing the language arrangements applicable at the Court of Justice of the European Union shall be laid down by a European regulation of the Council acting unanimously. This regulation shall be adopted either at the request of the Court of Justice and after consultation of the Commission and the European Parliament, or on a proposal from the Commission and after consultation of the Court of Justice and of the European Parliament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE STATUTE OF THE EUROPEAN SYSTEM OF CENTRAL BANKS AND OF THE EUROPEAN CENTRAL BANK  CHAPTER 1: THE EUROPEAN SYSTEM OF CENTRAL BANKS
Article 1 The European System of Central Banks
 In accordance with Article I-30(1) of the Constitution, the European Central Bank and the national central banks shall constitute the European System of Central Banks. The European Central Bank and the national central banks of those Member States whose currency is the euro shall constitute the Eurosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1b/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 3: ORGANISATION OF THE EUROPEAN SYSTEM OF CENTRAL BANKS
Article 7 Independence
In accordance with Article III-188 of the Constitution, when exercising the powers and carrying out the tasks and duties conferred upon them by the Constitution and this Statute, neither the European Central Bank, nor a national central bank, nor any member of their decision‑making bodies shall seek or take instructions from Union institutions, bodies, offices or agencies, from any government of a Member State or from any other body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1c/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 4: MONETARY FUNCTIONS AND OPERATIONS OF THE EUROPEAN SYSTEM OF CENTRAL BANKS
Article 17
Accounts with the European Central Bank and the national central banks In order to conduct their operations, the European Central Bank and the national central banks may open accounts for credit institutions, public entities and other market participants, and accept assets, including book entry securities, as collateral.
Article 18
Open market and credit operations
 In order to achieve the objectives of the European System of Central Banks and to carry out its tasks, the European Central Bank and the national central banks may: (a) operate in the financial markets by buying and selling outright (spot and forward) or under repurchase agreement and by lending or borrowing claims and marketable instruments, whether in euro or other currencies, as well as precious metals; (b) conduct credit operations with credit institutions and other market participants, with lending being based on adequate collateral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1d/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 5: PRUDENTIAL SUPERVISION
Article 25 Prudential supervision
 The European Central Bank may offer advice to and be consulted by the Council, the Commission and the competent authorities of the Member States on the scope and implementation of legally binding acts of the Union relating to the prudential supervision of credit institutions and to the stability of the financial system. In accordance with any European law adopted under Article III-185(6) of the Constitution, the European Central Bank may perform specific tasks concerning policies relating to the prudential supervision of credit institutions and other financial institutions with the exception of insurance undertakings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1e/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 7: GENERAL PROVISIONS
Article 34
Legal acts
 In accordance with Article III‑190 of the Constitution, the European Central Bank shall adopt: (a) European regulations to the extent necessary to implement the tasks defined in Article 3(1)(a), Article 19(1), Article 22 or Article 25(2) of this Statute and in cases which shall be laid down in the European regulations and decisions referred to in Article 41; (b) the European decisions necessary for carrying out the tasks entrusted to the European System of Central Banks under the Constitution and this Statute; (c) recommendations and opinions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-04/title-1f/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 8: AMENDMENT OF THE STATUTE AND COMPLEMENTARY RULES
Article 40 Simplified amendment procedures
 In accordance with Article III-187(3) of the Constitution, Articles 5(1), (2) and (3), 17, 18, 19(1), 22, 23, 24, 26, 32(2), (3), (4) and (6), 33(1)(a) and 36 of this Statute may be amended by European laws: (a) on a proposal from the Commission and after consulting the European Central Bank, or (b) on a recommendation from the European Central Bank and after consulting the Commission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE PRIVILEGES AND IMMUNITIES OF THE EUROPEAN UNION  CHAPTER 1: PROPERTY, FUNDS, ASSETS AND OPERATIONS OF THE UNION
Article 1
The premises and buildings of the Union shall be inviolable. They shall be exempt from search, requisition, confiscation or expropriation. The property and assets of the Union shall not be the subject of any administrative or legal measure of constraint without the authorisation of the Court of Justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 4: REPRESENTATIVES OF MEMBER STATES TAKING PART IN THE WORK OF THE INSTITUTIONS OF THE UNION
Article 10 Representatives of Member States taking part in the work of the institutions of the Union, their advisers and technical experts shall, in the performance of their duties and during their travel to and from the place of meeting, enjoy the customary privileges, immunities and facilities. This Article shall also apply to members of the advisory bodies of the Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 7: GENERAL PROVISIONS
Article 17
Privileges, immunities and facilities shall be accorded to officials and other servants of the Union solely in the interests of the Union. Each institution of the Union shall be required to waive the immunity accorded to an official or other servant wherever that institution considers that the waiver of such immunity is not contrary to the interests of the Union.
Article 18
The institutions of the Union shall, for the purpose of applying this Protocol, cooperate with the responsible authorities of the Member States concerned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-07/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-1/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE TREATIES AND ACTS OF ACCESSION OF DENMARK, IRELAND AND THE UNITED KINGDOM OF GREAT BRITAIN AND NORTHERN IRELAND, OF THE HELLENIC REPUBLIC, OF THE KINGDOM OF SPAIN AND THE PORTUGUESE REPUBLIC, AND OF THE REPUBLIC OF AUSTRIA, THE REPUBLIC OF FINLAND AND THE KINGDOM OF SWEDEN  TITLE 1: COMMON PROVISIONS
Article 1
The rights and obligations resulting from the Accession Treaties referred to in Article IV‑437(2)(a) to (d) of the Constitution took effect, under the conditions laid down in those Treaties, on the following dates: (a) 1 January 1973, for the Treaty concerning the accession of the Kingdom of Denmark, Ireland and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland; (b) 1 January 1981, for the Treaty concerning the accession of the Hellenic Republic; (c) 1 January 1986, for the Treaty concerning the accession of the Kingdom of Spain and the Portuguese Republic (d) 1 January 1995, for the Treaty concerning the accession of the Republic of Austria, the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-2/</guid>
      <description>TITLE II PROVISIONS TAKEN FROM THE ACT CONCERNING THE CONDITIONS OF ACCESSION OF THE KINGDOM OF DENMARK, IRELAND AND THE UNITED KINGDOM OF GREAT BRITAIN AND NORTHERN IRELAND SECTION 1
Provisions on Gibraltar
Article 6
 Acts of the institutions relating to the products in Annex I to the Constitution and the products subject, on importation into the Union, to specific rules as a result of the implementation of the common agricultural policy, as well as the acts on the harmonisation of legislation of Member States concerning turnover taxes, shall not apply to Gibraltar unless the Council adopts a European decision which provides otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-3/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 3: PROVISIONS TAKEN FROM THE ACT CONCERNING THE CONDITIONS OF ACCESSION OF THE HELLENIC REPUBLIC
SECTION 1
Provisions on the granting by Greece of exemption from customs duties on the import of certain goods
Article 21
Article III‑151 of the Constitution shall not prevent the Hellenic Republic from maintaining measures of exemption granted before 1 January 1979 pursuant to: (a) Law No 4171/61 (General measures to aid development of the country&amp;rsquo;s economy), (b) Decree Law No 2687/53 (Investment and protection of foreign capital), (c) Law No 289/76 (Incentives with a view to promoting the development of frontier regions and governing all pertinent questions), until the expiry of the agreements concluded by the Hellenic Government with those persons benefiting from these measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-4/</guid>
      <description>TITLE IV PROVISIONS TAKEN FROM THE ACT CONCERNING THE CONDITIONS OF ACCESSION OF THE KINGDOM OF SPAIN AND THE PORTUGUESE REPUBLIC SECTION 1 Financial provisions Article 27 The own resources accruing from value added tax shall be calculated and checked as if the Canary Islands and Ceuta and Melilla were included in the territorial field of application of Sixth Council Directive 77/388/EEC of 17 May 1977 on the harmonisation of the laws of the Member States relating to turnover taxes — Common system of value added tax: uniform basis of assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-08/title-5/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 5: PROVISIONS TAKEN FROM THE ACT CONCERNING THE CONDITIONS OF ACCESSION OF THE REPUBLIC OF AUSTRIA, THE REPUBLIC OF FINLAND AND THE KINGDOM OF SWEDEN SECTION 1 Financial provisions Article 46 Own resources accruing from value added tax shall be calculated and checked as though the Åland Islands were included in the territorial scope of Sixth Council Directive 77/388/EEC of 17 May 1977 on the harmonisation of the laws of the Member States relating to turnover taxes — Common system of value added tax: uniform basis of assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-10/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE EXCESSIVE DEFICIT PROCEDURE  Article 1
The reference values referred to in Article III-184(2) of the Constitution are: (a) 3 % for the ratio of the planned or actual government deficit to gross domestic product at market prices; (b) 60 % for the ratio of government debt to gross domestic product at market prices.
Article 2
For the purposes of Article III-184 of the Constitution and of this Protocol: (a) ‘government’ means general government, that is central government, regional or local government and social security funds, to the exclusion of commercial operations, as defined in the European System of Integrated Economic Accounts; (b) ‘deficit’ means net borrowing as defined in the European System of Integrated Economic Accounts; (c) ‘investment’ means gross fixed capital formation as defined in the European System of Integrated Economic Accounts; (d) ‘debt’ means total gross debt at nominal value outstanding at the end of the year and consolidated between and within the sectors of general government as defined in point (a).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-13/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON CERTAIN PROVISIONS RELATING TO THE UNITED KINGDOM OF GREAT BRITAIN AND NORTHERN IRELAND AS REGARDS ECONOMIC AND MONETARY UNION  Article 1
Unless the United Kingdom notifies the Council that it intends to adopt the euro, it shall be under no obligation to do so. Article 2 In view of the notice given to the Council by the United Kingdom government on 16 October 1996 and 30 October 1997, Articles 3 to 8 and 10 shall apply to the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-14/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON CERTAIN PROVISIONS RELATING TO DENMARK AS REGARDS ECONOMIC AND MONETARY UNION  Article 1
In view of the notice given to the Council by the Danish Government on 3 November 1993, Denmark shall have an exemption. The effect of the exemption shall be that all provisions of the Constitution and the Statute of the European System of Central Banks and the European Central Bank referring to a derogation shall be applicable to Denmark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-16/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE PACIFIC FINANCIAL COMMUNITY FRANC SYSTEM THE HIGH CONTRACTING PARTIES, DESIRING to take into account a particular point relating to France, HAVE AGREED upon the following provisions, which shall be annexed to the Treaty establishing a Constitution for Europe: Sole article France may keep the privilege of monetary emission in New Caledonia, French Polynesia and Wallis and Futuna under the terms established by its national laws and shall be solely entitled to determine the parity of the Pacific Financial Community franc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-18/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE APPLICATION OF CERTAIN ASPECTS OF ARTICLE III-130 OF THE CONSTITUTION TO THE UNITED KINGDOM AND TO IRELAND  Article 1
The United Kingdom shall be entitled, notwithstanding Articles III-130 and III-265 of the Constitution, any other provision of the Constitution, any measure adopted under the Constitution, or any international agreement concluded by the Union or by the Union and its Member States with one or more third States, to exercise at its frontiers with other Member States such controls on persons seeking to enter the United Kingdom as it may consider necessary for the purpose: (a) of verifying the right to enter the United Kingdom of citizens of Member States and of their dependants exercising rights conferred by Union law, as well as citizens of other States on whom such rights have been conferred by an agreement by which the United Kingdom is bound; and (b) of determining whether or not to grant other persons permission to enter the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-20/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE POSITION OF DENMARK  PART I
Article 1
Denmark shall not take part in the adoption by the Council of proposed measures pursuant to Chapter IV of Title III of Part III of the Constitution. The unanimity of the members of the Council, with the exception of the representative of the government of Denmark, shall be necessary for the acts of the Council which must be adopted unanimously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-21/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON EXTERNAL RELATIONS OF THE MEMBER STATES WITH REGARD TO THE CROSSING OF EXTERNAL BORDERS  Sole article
The provisions on the measures on the crossing of external borders included in Article III‑265(2)(b) of the Constitution shall be without prejudice to the competence of Member States to negotiate or conclude agreements with third countries as long as they respect Union law and other relevant international agreements.
PROTOCOL ON ASYLUM FOR NATIONALS OF MEMBER STATES  Sole article</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-23/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON PERMANENT STRUCTURED COOPERATION ESTABLISHED BY ARTICLE I-41(6) AND ARTICLE III-312 OF THE CONSTITUTION  Article 1
The permanent structured cooperation referred to in Article I‑41(6) of the Constitution shall be open to any Member State which undertakes, from the date of entry into force of the Treaty establishing a Constitution for Europe, to: (a) proceed more intensively to develop its defence capacities through the development of its national contributions and participation, where appropriate, in multinational forces, in the main European equipment programmes, and in the activity of the Agency in the field of defence capabilities development, research, acquisition and armaments (European Defence Agency), and (b) have the capacity to supply by 2007 at the latest, either at national level or as a component of multinational force groups, targeted combat units for the missions planned, structured at a tactical level as a battle group, with support elements including transport and logistics, capable of carrying out the tasks referred to in Article III‑309, within a period of 5 to 30 days, in particular in response to requests from the United Nations Organisation, and which can be sustained for an initial period of 30 days and be extended up to at least 120 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-25/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL CONCERNING IMPORTS INTO THE EUROPEAN UNION OF PETROLEUM PRODUCTS REFINED IN THE NETHERLANDS ANTILLES  Article 1 This Protocol is applicable to petroleum products coming under the Combined Nomenclature headings 2710, 2711, 2712 (paraffin wax and petroleum wax), ex 2713 (paraffin residues) and 2714 (shale wax), imported for use in the Member States.
Article 2 Member States shall undertake to grant to petroleum products refined in the Netherlands Antilles the tariff preferences resulting from the Association of the latter with the Union, under the conditions provided for by this Protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-26/</guid>
      <description>26.PROTOCOL ON THE ACQUISITION OF PROPERTY IN DENMARK
THE HIGH CONTRACTING PARTIES, DESIRING to settle certain particular problems relating to Denmark, HAVE AGREED upon the following provision, which shall be annexed to the Treaty establishing a Constitution for Europe:
Sole article
Notwithstanding the provisions of the Constitution, Denmark may maintain the existing legislation on the acquisition of second homes.
PROTOCOL ON THE SYSTEM OF PUBLIC BROADCASTING IN THE MEMBER STATES  Sole article</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-34/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE TRANSITIONAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO THE INSTITUTIONS AND BODIES OF THE UNION  TITLE I
PROVISIONS CONCERNING THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT
Article 1
 In accordance with the second subparagraph of Article I‑20(2) of the Constitution, the European Council shall adopt a European decision determining the composition of the European Parliament sufficiently in advance of the 2009 European Parliament elections. During the 2004‑2009 parliamentary term, the composition and the number of representatives elected to the European Parliament in each Member State shall remain the same as on the date of the entry into force of the Treaty establishing a Constitution for Europe, the number of representatives being as follows: Belgium 24 Czech Republic 24 Denmark 14 Germany 99 Estonia 6 Greece 24 Spain 54 France 78 Ireland 13 Italy 78 Cyprus 6 Latvia 9 Lithuania 13 Luxembourg 6 Hungary 24 Malta 5 Netherlands 27 Austria 18 Poland 54 Portugal 24 Slovenia 7 Slovakia 14 Finland 14 Sweden 19 United Kingdom 78  TITLE 2: PROVISIONS CONCERNING THE EUROPEAN COUNCIL AND THE COUNCIL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-35/</guid>
      <description>PROTOCOL ON THE FINANCIAL CONSEQUENCES OF THE EXPIRY OF THE TREATY ESTABLISHING THE EUROPEAN COAL AND STEEL COMMUNITY AND ON THE RESEARCH FUND FOR COAL AND STEEL  Article 1
 The net worth of the assets and liabilities of the European Coal and Steel Community, as they appear in the balance sheet of the European Coal and Steel Community of 23 July 2002, subject to any increase or decrease which may occur as a result of the liquidation operations, shall be considered as Union assets intended for research in sectors related to the coal and steel industry, referred to as the ‘European Coal and Steel Community in liquidation’.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
