<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Order on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Order on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Culture</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-03b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-03b/</guid>
      <description>Section 2: Culture
Article 215. The state shall ensure to all the full exercise of the cultural rights and access to the sources of national culture and shall support and foster the appreciation and diffusion of cultural expressions. (CA No. 48, 2005)
Paragraph 1. The State shall protect the expressions of popular, Indian and Afro-Brazilian cultures, as well as those of other groups participating in the national civilization process.
Paragraph 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education, Culture and Sports</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: Education
Article 205. Education, which is the right of all and duty of the State and of the family, shall be promoted and fostered with the cooperation of society, with a view to the full development of the person, his preparation for the exercise of citizenship and his qualification for work.
Article 206. Education shall be provided on the basis of the following principles:
 equal conditions of access and permanence in school; freedom to learn, teach, research and express thought, art and knowledge; pluralism of pedagogic ideas and conceptions and coexistence of public and private teaching institutions; free public education in official schools; appreciation of the value of school education professionals, guaranteeing, in accordance with the law, career schemes for public school teachers, with admittance exclusively by means of public entrance examinations consisting of tests and presentation of academic and professional credentials; democratic administration of public education, in the manner prescribed by law guarantee of standards of quality a nationwide professional minimum salary for public school teachers, under the terms of a federal law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>Article 225. All have the right to an ecologically balanced environment, which is an asset of common use and essential to a healthy quality of life, and both the Government and the community shall have the duty to defend and preserve it for present and future generations.
Paragraph 1. The Government will:
 preserve and restore the essential ecological processes and provide for the ecological treatment of species and ecosystems preserve the diversity and integrity of the genetic patrimony of the country and to control entities engaged in research and manipulation of genetic material define, in all units of the Federation, territorial spaces and their components which are to receive special protection, any alterations and suppressions being allowed only by means of law, and any use which may harm the integrity of the attributes which justify their protection being forbidden demand, in the manner prescribed by law, for the installation of works and activities which may potentially cause significant degradation of the environment, a prior environmental impact study, which shall be made public control the production, sale and use of techniques, methods or substances which represent a risk to life, the quality of life and the environment promote environment education in all school levels and public awareness of the need to preserve the environment protect the fauna and the flora, with prohibition, in the manner prescribed by law, of all practices which represent a risk to their ecological function, cause the extinction of species or subject animals to cruelty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family, Children, Adolescents and the Elderly</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>Article 226. The family, which is the foundation of society, shall enjoy special protection from the State.
Paragraph 1. Marriage is civil and the marriage ceremony is free of charge.
Paragraph 2. Religious marriage has civil effects, in accordance with the law.
Paragraph 3. For purposes of protection by the State, the stable union between a man and a woman is recognized as a family entity, and the law shall facilitate the conversion of such entity into marriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Provision</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-01c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-01c/</guid>
      <description>Section 3: Social Security
Article 201. The social security system shall be organized as a general scheme, of a contributory basis and mandatory participation, with due regard for criteria that preserve financial and actuarial balance, and shall provide for, in accordance with the law: (CA No. 20, 1998; CA No. 41, 2003; CA No. 47, 2005)
 coverage for the events of illness, disability, death, and old age; protection to maternity, especially to pregnant women; protection to workers in a situation of involuntary unemployment; family allowance and confinement allowance for the dependents of the low-income insured; pension for death of the insured, man or woman, to the spouse or companion, and dependents, complying with the provision of paragraph 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-01b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-01b/</guid>
      <description>Article 196. Health is a right of all and a duty of the State and shall be guaranteed by means of social and economic policies aimed at reducing the risk of illness and other hazards and at the universal and equal access to actions and services for its promotion, protection and recovery.
Article 197. Health actions and services are of public importance, and it is incumbent upon the Government to provide, in accordance with the law, for their regulation, supervision and control, and they shall be carried out directly or by third parties and also by individuals or private legal entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>Article 231. Indians shall have their social organization, customs, languages, creeds and traditions recognized, as well as their original rights to the lands they traditionally occupy, it being incumbent upon the Union to demarcate them, protect and ensure respect for all of their property.
Paragraph 1. Lands traditionally occupied by Indians are those on which they live on a permanent basis, those used for their productive activities, those indispensable to the preservation of the environmental resources necessary for their well-being and for their physical and cultural reproduction, according to their uses, customs and traditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Communication</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Article 220. The manifestation of thought, the creation, the expression and the information, in any form, process or medium shall not be subject to any restriction, with due regard to the provisions of this Constitution.
Paragraph 1. No law shall contain any provision which may represent a hindrance to full freedom of press in any medium of social communication, with due regard to the provisions of article 5, IV, V, X, XIII and XIV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Welfare</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-01a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-08/chapter-01a/</guid>
      <description>Article 193. The social order is based on the primacy of work and aimed at social well-being and justice.
CHAPTER 2: Social Welfare Section 1: General Provisions
Article 194. Social welfare comprises an integrated whole of actions initiated by the Government and by society, with the purpose of ensuring the rights to health, social security and assistance.
The Government shall organize social welfare, based on the following objectives:
 universality of coverage and service uniformity and equivalence of benefits and services for urban and rural populations selectivity and distributiveness in the provision of benefits and services; irreducibility of the value of the benefits; equitable participation in funding diversity of the financing basis democratic and decentralized character of administration, by means of a quadripartite management, with the participation of workers, employers, retirees, and the Government in the collegiate bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
