<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inequalities in employment or industry on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inequalities in employment or industry on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agreeableness or cost of job</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1a/</guid>
      <description>1  The advantages and disadvantages of the different employments of labour and stock must be perfectly equal or continually tending to equality in the same neighbourhood.
If there was advantageous employment, so many people would crowd into it in the one case, and so many would desert it in the other, that its advantages would soon be at level with other employments. This would happen where=
 there was perfect liberty things were left to follow their natural course everyone was free to choose and change their occupation as they saw fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality from Constancy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1b/</guid>
      <description>14  Wages vary with the constancy or inconstancy of employment.
 15  &amp;ldquo;Employment is much more constant in some trades than in others.&amp;rdquo;
In most manufactures, a journeyman can get a job almost everyday. But a mason or bricklayer, on the contrary, cannot work in bad weather.
 His employment depends on the calls of his customers. He frequently has no work. His earnings must:  maintain him while he is idle and compensate his anxiety and despondence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Equality in Wages and Profits</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1e/</guid>
      <description>42  Those five circumstances create inequalities in wages and profits.
But they create equality when the advantages and disadvantages in employments are both taken into account. They balance out gains and losses.
 43  To create this balance or equality, three things are needed on top of the most perfect freedom=
Equality Through Length of Time in Operations    44  The employments must be well known and long established in the neighbourhood   45 Where all other circumstances are equal, wages are higher in new than in old trades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequalities in Wholesale and Retail Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1d/</guid>
      <description>Groceries and Retail  39  In a small sea-port town, a little grocer will make 40-50% from a stock of £100.
A wholesale merchant in the same place will make 8-10% on a stock of £10,000. The trade of the grocer may be necessary for the conveniency of the inhabitants. The narrowness of the market may not admit a larger capital. Man, must not only live by his trade, but live by it suitably to the qualifications it requires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality by Increasing Competition Through Wage subsidies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>B. The Economic Policy unnaturally increases the competition in some employments, leading to an opposite inequality Scholarships  88-89  Many pensions, scholarships, exhibitions, bursaries, etc. were founded for the education of young people.
 These draw many more people into those trades than natural.  In all Christian countries, the education of most churchmen is paid this way. Very few of them are educated at their own expence.
Those who pay for their own long, tedious, and expensive education will not always get the suitable employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality from Restrictions on Immigration and Employment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2c1/</guid>
      <description>Economic Policy that Restricts the Free Movement of Labor and Stock leads to Inequality  97  This creates a very inconvenient inequality in the different employments.
 98  The statute of apprenticeship obstructs the free circulation of labour from one employment to another, even in the same place. The exclusive privileges of corporations obstruct it from one place to another, even in the same employment.
 99  Often, one manufacture gives high wages while another gives only bare subsistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality from Wage Controls</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2c2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2c2/</guid>
      <description>Wage Controls  119  The ancient practice of setting wages by laws have now gone entirely into disuse.
 120  Doctor Burns says=
After over 400 years, the attempt to strictly limit everyone to equal wages should by now be ended to allow industry and ingenuity.   121  Particular acts of parliament, however, still attempt to regulate wages.
The 8th of George the 3rd prohibits all master tailors in London and five miles round it, from giving more than 31.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Profit and Wage Inequality from Economic Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2a1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2a1/</guid>
      <description>56  The policy of Europe prevents perfect liberty and creates other more important inequalities.
 57  Inequality is done in three ways=
 By restraining the competition to fewer than natural. By increasing the competition beyond the natural. By obstructing the free circulation of labour and stock from employment to employment and from place to place.  A. The Economic Policy that Reduces Competition leading to Inequality  58  The policy of Europe creates a very important inequality in the employments of labour and stock by reducing competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profit and Wage Inequality from Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-2a2/</guid>
      <description>Reducing Competition through Exclusive Corporations  72  All corporations and most of corporation laws have been established to prevent this reduction of price by restraining that free competition which would most certainly occasion it.
This price reduction would lower wages and profit. Only the town corporate&amp;rsquo;s authority was needed to establish a corporation in ancient times. In England, a charter from the king was necessary. But this prerogative of the crown was to extort money from the subject, than for defending against oppressive monopolies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-10/part-1c/</guid>
      <description>Trust  20  Wages vary according to the trust reposed in the workers.
 21  The wages of goldsmiths and jewellers are superior to other workmen because they are entrusted with precious materials.
 22  We trust our health to the physician and we trust our fortune, life, and reputation to the lawyer.
Such confidence could not safely be entrusted to mean or low people.
 Their reward must give them that rank which so important a trust requires.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
