<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What is Being? on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What is Being? on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accidental Being</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/part-3/</guid>
      <description>There are principles and causes which are generable and destructible without ever being in course of being generated or destroyed.
For otherwise all things will be of necessity, since that which is being generated or destroyed must have a cause which is not accidentally its cause. Will A exist or not? It will if B happens; and if not, not. And B will exist if C happens.
And thus if time is constantly subtracted from a limited extent of time, one will obviously come to the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causes of Being</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/part-1/</guid>
      <description>What are the principles and causes of the things that are of being?
There is a cause of health and of good condition. The objects of mathematics have first principles and elements and causes, and in general every science which is ratiocinative or at all involves reasoning deals with causes and principles, more or less precise, all these sciences mark off some particular being-some genus, and inquire into this, but not into being simply nor qua being, nor do they offer any discussion of the essence of the things of which they treat;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pure Being</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-6/part-2/</guid>
      <description>The unqualified term &amp;lsquo;being&amp;rsquo; has many meanings such as:
 figures of predication (e.g. the &amp;lsquo;what&amp;rsquo;, quality, quantity, place, time, and any similar meanings which &amp;lsquo;being&amp;rsquo; may have), and again besides all these there is that which &amp;lsquo;is&amp;rsquo; potentially or actually:- the true (&amp;rsquo;non-being&amp;rsquo; being the false) the accidental= there can be no scientific treatment of it. No science troubles itself about it  For on the one hand he who produces a house does not produce all the attributes that come into being along with the house; for these are innumerable; the house that has been made may quite well be pleasant for some people, hurtful for some, and useful to others, and different-to put it shortly from all things that are; and the science of building does not aim at producing any of these attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
