<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crop Rotation on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crop Rotation on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crop Rotation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/rotation/</guid>
      <description>CROP ROTATION In crop rotation, the soil is under cultivation for most of the year.
In the Purulia district of West Bengal, many farmers grow only one crop of paddy a year. Through crop rotation, 4 crops can be harvested in a year.
In the rainy season, no mixed crop can be grown with paddy, only small fish.
Autumn paddy can be combined with big onions, summer paddy with radish, and spring paddy with small onions grown from seeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop Rotation for Rice and Banana</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/rotation-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/rotation-rice/</guid>
      <description>Rice (Paddy) The rái and yellow but not the red varieties of mustard, khesári, the small black variety of peas, Bengal gram and lentils (the small variety) can all be sown as “pigeon crops” with paddy.
The rice is planted in Shrávańa, and then in the last week of Áshvina [[the “pigeon crop” is tossed into the field without tilling the soil or applying fertilizers.]] After the rice has been harvested, the “pigeon crop” remains in the field until maturity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop Rotation for Vegetables</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/rotation-veg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/rotation-veg/</guid>
      <description>Some examples of crop rotation include the following:
Oil Seeds Oil seeds can be planted in the following way:
1 | Vaeshákha | mid-April to mid-May 2 | Jyaeśt́ha | mid-May to mid-June 3 | Aśádha | mid-June to mid-July 4 | Shrávańa | mid-July to mid-August 5 | Bhádra | mid-August to mid-September 6 | Áshvina | mid-September to mid-October 7 | Kárttika | mid October to mid November 8 | Agrahayańa | mid November to mid December 9 | Pauśa | mid December to mid January 10 | Mágha | mid January to mid February 11 | Phálguna | mid February to mid March 12 | Caetra | mid March to mid April</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed and Supplementary Cropping</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/mixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/mixed/</guid>
      <description>Our system of integrated farming is designed to utilize every inch of land. The surface, the sub- surface and the space above the surface is to be used 100%.
This is done through 3 main systems of cropping:
 mixed cropping supplementary cropping crop rotation.  Cultivation should be done on the cooperative basis. Only cooperatives can support the expanding economic requirements of agriculture, like creating ponds, purchasing machinery, uniting local people to pressurise the government for irrigation facilities, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Cropping for Boundary Plants</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/boundary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-2/boundary/</guid>
      <description>To ensure the maximum utilization of every inch of land, there is also a system of planting in the boundary areas of all schools, farms, orchards, homes, etc., as well as beside all roads.
For example, trees with spreading branches, like most fruit trees and even some timber trees, should be planted all around the perimeter of such places at fixed distances.
Palm trees, which grow straight up, should be planted in between the fruit trees, as they do not block the sun light from the fruit trees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
