<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sidereal Messenger on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sidereal Messenger on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/introduction/</guid>
      <description>In 1609, Galileo, then Professor of Mathematics at Padua, in the service of the Venetian Republic, heard from a correspondent at Paris of the invention of a telescope, and set to work to consider how such an instrument could be made. The result was his invention of the telescope known by his name, and identical in principle with the modern opera-glass.
In a maritime and warlike State, the advantages to be expected from such an invention were immediately recognised, and Galileo was rewarded with a confirmation of his Professorship for life, and a handsome stipend, in recognition of his invention and construction of the first telescope seen at Venice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Galileo Galilei A Gentleman Of Florence, Professor Of Mathematics In The University Of Padua, With The Aid Of A Telescope
THERE is certainly something very noble and large-minded in the intention of those who have endeavoured to protect from envy the noble achievements of distinguished men, and to rescue their names, worthy of immortality, from oblivion and decay. This desire has given us the lineaments of famous men, sculptured in marble, or fashioned in bronze, as a memorial of them to future ages; to the same feeling we owe the erection of statues, both ordinary and equestrian;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE COSMIAN STARS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/kepler/sidereal-messenger/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>THE ASTRONOMICAL MESSENGER
Containing and setting forth Observations lately made with the aid of a newly invented Telescope respecting the Moon’s Surface, the Milky Way, Nebulous Stars, an innumerable multitude of Fixed Stars, and also respecting Four Planets never before seen, which have been named.
IN the present small treatise I set forth some matters of great interest for all observers of natural phenomena to look at and consider. They are of great Introduction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
