<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organization of the Powers on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organization of the Powers on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accounting, Financial and Budgetary Control</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01e/</guid>
      <description>Article 70. Control of accounts, finances, budget, operations and property of the Union and of the agencies of the direct and indirect administration, as to lawfulness, legitimacy, economic efficiency, application of subsidies and waiver of revenues, shall be exercised by the National Congress, by means of external control and of the internal control system of each Power.
Accounts shall be rendered by any individual or corporation, public or private, which uses, collects, keeps, manages, or administers public monies, assets or values, or those for which the Union is responsible or which, on behalf of the Union, assumes obligations of a pecuniary nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electoral and Military Courts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03e/</guid>
      <description>Section 6: Electoral Courts and Judges
Article 118. The following are the bodies of Electoral Justice:
 the Superior Electoral Court; the Regional Electoral Courts; the Electoral Judges; the Electoral Boards.  Article 119. The Superior Electoral Court shall be composed of a minimum of 7 members chosen:
 through election, by secret vote: a) three judges from among the Justices of the Supreme Federal Court; b) two judges from among the Justices of the Superior Court of Justice; through appointment by the President of the Republic, two judges from among six lawyers of notable juridical learning and good moral repute, nominated by the Supreme Federal Court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labour Courts and Judges</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03d/</guid>
      <description>Article 111. The following are the bodies of Labour Justice:
 the Superior Labour Court; the Regional Labour Courts; Labour Judges.  Article 111-A. The Superior Labour Court shall be composed of 27 Justices, chosen from among Brazilians over thirty-five and under 65 years of age, appointed by the President of the Republic after approval by the absolute majority of the Federal Senate, as follows:
 1/5 from among lawyers effectively practicing their professional activity for more than ten years and from among members of the Labour Public Prosecution with over 10 years of effective exercise, with due regard for the provisions of article 94 the others, from among career judges of the Regional Labour Courts, nominated by the Superior Labour Court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legislative Process</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01d/</guid>
      <description>Subsection 1: General Provision
Article 59. The legislative process comprises the preparation of:
 amendments to the Constitution; supplementary laws; ordinary laws; delegated laws; provisional measures; legislative decrees; resolutions.  A supplementary law shall provide for the preparation, drafting, amendment and consolidation of laws.
SUBSection 2: Amendments to the Constitution
Article 60. The Constitution may be amended on the proposal of:
 at least one-third of the members of the Chamber of Deputies or of the Federal Senate; the President of the Republic; more than one half of the Legislative Assemblies of the units of the Federation, each of them expressing itself by the relative majority of its members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liability of the President; Ministers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-02b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-02b/</guid>
      <description>Article 85. Those acts of the President of the Republic which attempt on the Federal Constitution and especially on the following, are crimes of malversation:
 the existence of the Union; the free exercise of the Legislative Power, the Judicial Power, the Public Prosecution and the constitutional Powers of the units of the Federation; the exercise of political, individual and social rights; the internal security of the country; probity in the administration; the budgetary law; compliance with the laws and with court decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Council of the Republic and the National Defense Council</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-02c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-02c/</guid>
      <description>SUBSection I: The Council of the Republic
Article 89. The Council of the Republic is a higher body for consultation by the President of the Republic.
Its members are:
 Vice-President of the Republic; President of the Chamber of Deputies; President of the Federal Senate; majority and the minority leaders in the Chamber of Deputies; the majority and the minority leaders in the Federal Senate; the Minister of Justice; six born Brazilian citizens, with over thirty-five years of age, two of which appointed by the President of the Republic, two elected by the Federal Senate and two elected by the Chamber of Deputies, all with a term of office of three years, the re-appointment being prohibited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Executive Power: The President and Vice-President</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-02a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-02a/</guid>
      <description>Article 76. The Executive Power is exercised by the President of the Republic, assisted by the Ministers of State
Article 77. The election of the President and Vice-President of the Republic shall take place simultaneously, on the first Sunday of October, in the first round, and on the last Sunday of October, in the second round, as the case may be, of the year preceding the one in which the current presidential term of office ends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Federal Regional Courts and the Federal Judges</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03c/</guid>
      <description>Article 106. The following are the bodies of Federal Justice:
 the Federal Regional Courts the Federal Judges  Article 107. The Federal Regional Courts are composed of a minimum of 7 judges, selected, whenever possible, in the respective region and nominated by the President of the Republic from among Brazilians over 30 and under 65 years of age, as follows:
  1/5 shall be chosen from among lawyers effectively practicing their professional activity for more than ten years and from among members of the Federal Public Prosecution, with over ten years of service</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Federal Senate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01b/</guid>
      <description>Article 52. The Federal Senate shall:
 effect the legal proceeding and trial of the President and Vice-President of the Republic for crime of malversation, and the Ministers of State and the Commanders of the Navy, the Army, and the Air Force for crimes of the same nature relating to those effect the legal proceeding and trial of the Justices of the Supreme Federal Court, the members of the National Council of Justice and of the National Council of the Public Prosecution, the Attorney-General of the Republic, and the Advocate-General of the Union for crimes of malversation give prior consent, by secret voting, after public hearing, on the selection of: a) judges, in the cases established in this Constitution; b) Justices of the Federal Audit Court appointed by the President of the Republic c) Governor of a territory; d) president and directors of the Central Bank; e) Attorney-General of the Republic; f) holders of other offices, as the law may determine; give prior approval, by secret voting, after closed hearing, on the selection of heads of permanent diplomatic missions; authorize foreign transactions of a financial nature, of the interest of the Union, the states, the Federal District, the territories and the municipalities; establish, as proposed by the President of the Republic, total limits for the entire amount of the consolidated debt of the Union, the states, the Federal District and the municipalities to provide for the total limits and conditions for foreign and domestic credit transactions of the Union, the states, the Federal District and the municipalities, of their autonomous Government entities and other entities controlled by the Federal Government; to provide for limits and conditions for the concession of a guarantee by the Union in foreign and domestic credit transactions to establish total limits and conditions for the entire amount of the debt of the states, the Federal District and the municipalities to stop the application, in full or in part, of a law declared unconstitutional by final decision of the Supreme Federal Court to approve, by absolute majority and by secret voting, the removal from office of the Attorney-General of the Republic before the end of his term of office to draw up its internal regulations to provide for its organization, functioning, police, creation, change or abolishment of offices, positions and functions of its services, and the introduction of a law for the establishment of their respective remuneration, taking into account the guidelines set forth in the law of budgetary directives; to elect the members of the Council of the Republic, as established in article 89, VII.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Functions Essential to Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-04a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-04a/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: The Public Prosecution Article 127. The Public Prosecution is a permanent institution, essential to the jurisdictional function of the State, and it is its duty to defend the juridical order, the democratic regime and the inalienable social and individual interests.
Paragraph 1. Unity, indivisibility and functional independence are institutional principles of the Public Prosecution.
Paragraph 2. The Public Prosecution is ensured of functional and administrative autonomy, and it may, observing the provisions of article 169, propose to the Legislative Power the creation and abolishment of its offices and auxiliary services, filling them through a civil service entrance examination of tests or of tests and presentation of academic and professional credentials, the remuneration policies, and the career plans; the law shall provide for its organization and operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Judicial Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03a/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: General Provisions Article 92.
The following are the bodies of the Judicial Power:
 the Supreme Federal Court; a. the National Council of Justice; the Superior Court of Justice; the Federal Regional Courts and the Federal Judges; the Labour Courts and Judges; the Electoral Courts and Judges; the Military Courts and Judges; the Courts and Judges of the states, of the Federal District and of the territories  Paragraph 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legislative Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01a/</guid>
      <description>Section I The National Congress Article 44. The Legislative Power is exercised by the National Congress, composed of:
 the Chamber of Deputies the Federal Senate.  The legislative term is 4 years.
Article 45. The Chamber of Deputies is composed of representatives of the people, elected, by the proportional system, in each state, territory and in the Federal District.
Paragraph 1. The total number of Deputies, as well as the representation of the states and of the Federal District shall be established by a supplementary law, in proportion to the population, and the necessary adjustments shall be made in the year preceding the elections, so that none of those units of the Federation has less than eight or more than 70 Deputies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Public Advocacy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-04b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-04b/</guid>
      <description>Article 131. The Advocacy-General of the Union is the institution which, either directly or through a subordinated agency, represents the Union judicially or extrajudicially, and it is responsible, under the terms of the supplementary law which provides for its organization and operation, for the activities of judicial consultation and assistance to the Executive Power.
Paragraph 1. The Advocacy-General of the Union is headed by the Advocate-General of the Union, freely appointed by the President of the Republic from among citizens over thirty-five years of age, of notable juridical learning and spotless reputation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sessions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-01c/</guid>
      <description>Article 57. The National Congress shall meet each year in the Federal Capital, from February 2 to July 17 and from August 1 to December 22.
Paragraph 1. If sessions scheduled for these dates fall on a Saturday, a Sunday or a holiday, they shall be transferred to the subsequent workday.
Paragraph 2. The legislative session shall not be interrupted before the approval of the bill of budgetary directives.
Paragraph 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Supreme Federal Court</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-04/chapter-03b/</guid>
      <description>Article 101. The Supreme Federal Court is composed of eleven Justices, chosen from among citizens over 35 and under sixty-five years of age, of notable juridical learning and spotless reputation.
The Justices of the Supreme Federal Court shall be appointed by the President of the Republic, after their nomination has been approved by the absolute majority of the Federal Senate.
Article 102. The Supreme Federal Court is responsible, essentially, for safeguarding the Constitution, and it is within its competence:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
