<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 2 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 2 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-07/prop-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-07/prop-35/</guid>
      <description>PROPOSITION XXXV. PROBLEM If a rare medium nitudes, medium from A than any other circular solid whatsoever, VII. consist of very small quiescent particles of equal mag at equal distances from one another = to and freely disposed this jind the resistance of a globe moving uniformly forward in medium. CASE 1. Let a be cylinder described with the same diameter and altitude conceived to go forward with the same velocity in the direction of its axis through the same medium and let us suppose that the particles of the ; medium, on which the globe or cylinder falls, fly back with as great a force of reflexion as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-07/prop-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-07/prop-36/</guid>
      <description>PROPOSITION XXXVI. PROBLEM
To define the VIII. motion of water running out of a cylindrical vessel through a hole made at the bottom. Let AC D B be a cylindrical CD vessel, AB the mouth p Q= EF a G the the horizon, of it, the bottom p the of middle circular hole in the bottom, irallel to GH the axis of the cylin- of the hole, and And suppose a horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-07/prop-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-07/prop-37/</guid>
      <description>PROPOSITION XXXVII. THEOREM XXIX. If a cylinder move uninformly forward in a compressed, infinite, arid non-elastic finid, in the direction of its length, the resistance arising from its the magnitude of its transverse whole motion moves four times may section is to the force by be destroyed or generated, in the its length, as the density of the which time that medium sity of the cylinder, nearly. For let the vessel touch the surface of stagnant water with bottom CD, and let the water run out of this vessel into the stagnant ABDC ter let EFTS it den to the its wa and through the cylindric canal perpendicular co the horizon the little circle PQ, be placed parallel to the horizon any where in the ;OF NATURAL PHILOSOPHY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example 1</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-02/prop-10ex1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-02/prop-10ex1/</guid>
      <description>EXAMPLE 1 Let the line PFHQ, be a semi-circle described upon the PQ, to find the density of the medium that shall make a projec diameter move tile in that line. PQ Bisect the diameter CD, o ; then DI 2 in A and ; AD AQ, 2 or AQ, n ; AC, call = nn 2 aa a 2ao ; CH, oo, or e ; ec. and 2ao and the root being extracted by our method, will give DI e aaoo ao 3 a 3 o 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section 2= The motions of bodies that are  resisted in the duplicate ratio of the velocities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-02/prop-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-2/sec-02/prop-05/</guid>
      <description>Proposition 5 Theorem 3 If a body is resisted in the duplicate ratio of its velocity, and moves by innate force only through a similar medium; and the times be taken in a geometrical progression, proceeding from less to greater terms = that the velocities at the beginning of each of the times are in the same geometrical progression inversely ; and that the spaces are equal, which are described in each of the times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
