<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sciences on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Sciences on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A person whose first language was not Arabic has a harder time acquiring the sciences</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-43/</guid>
      <description>This is because all scientific research deals with ideas of the mind and the imagination.
This applies to the religious sciences in which research is mostly concerned with words and the substance of which is the laws derived from the Qur&amp;rsquo;an, the Sunnah, and the language used in (both the Qur&amp;rsquo;an and the Sunnah) that leads to (the formulation of) these (laws). These are all matters of the imagination.
The same fact also applies to the intellectual sciences, which are matters of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Intellect</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-01/</guid>
      <description>Man&amp;rsquo;s ability to think  God distinguished man from all the other animals by an ability to think. Perception - that is, consciousness, on the part of the person who perceives, in his essence of things that are outside his essence - is something peculiar to living beings to the exclusion of all other being 6 and existent things.
Living beings may obtain consciousness of things that are outside their essence through the external senses God has given them, that is, the senses of hearing, vision, smell, taste, and touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific instruction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-06/</guid>
      <description>6. Man is essentially ignorant, and becomes learned through acquiring (knowledge). We have already explained at the beginning of these sections 31 that man belongs to the genus of animals and that God distinguished him from them by the ability to think, which He gave man and through which man is able to . This is
There are various kinds of intellect=
 The discerning intellect  This lets us arrange our actions in an orderly manner</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hadith: sciences concerned with Prophetic traditions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-11/</guid>
      <description>There are many and varied hadith. One of them concerns abrogating and abrogated traditions. The permission to abrogate previous statements and the occurrence of abrogation have been established in our religious law.
It is a favor shown by God to His servants and a kind of relief granted them to help them along in matters affecting their well-being (masalih) for which He is responsible to them. God said= &amp;ldquo;Whenever We abrogate a verse or consign it to oblivion, We bring one that is better, or as good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islamic Jurisprudence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-12/</guid>
      <description>12. Jurisprudence and its subdivision, inheritance laws. Jurisprudence is the knowledge of the classification of the laws of God, which concern the actions of all responsible Muslims, as obligatory, forbidden, recommendable, disliked, or permissible.
These laws are derived from:
 the Qur&amp;rsquo;an the Sunnah (traditions) the evidence Muhammad has established for knowledge of the laws  The laws evolved from the whole of this evidence are called &amp;ldquo;jurisprudence&amp;rdquo; (fiqh).
The early Muslims evolved the laws from that evidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science, Principles, Dialectics of Jurisprudence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-13/</guid>
      <description>The science of the principles of jurisprudence is one of the greatest, most important, and most useful disciplines of the religious law.
It is concerned with the evidence of the religious law from which the laws and legal obligations of the Muslims are derived.
The basic sources of legal evidence are:
 the Qur&amp;rsquo;an the Sunnah, which clarifies the Qur&amp;rsquo;an  At the time of the Prophet, the laws were received directly from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of speculative theology</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-14/</guid>
      <description>This is a science that involves arguing with logical proofs in defense of the articles of faith and refuting innovators who deviate in their dogmas from the early Muslims and Muslim orthodoxy.
The real core of the articles of faith is the oneness of God.
Therefore, we shall present here, first, a znice specimen of logical argumentation that will show us the oneness of God in the most direct method and manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ambiguity in the Qur&#39;an and the Sunnah and the resulting dogmatic schools</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-15/</guid>
      <description>The Prophet Muhammad told us in the Quran about the obligations that would lead us to salvation and bliss.
This process included and necessitated references to:
 God&amp;rsquo;s names and attributes to make us acquainted with His essence the spirit attaching itself to us the revelation and the angels in-between God and His messengers.  The Quran includes:
 the Day of Resurrection and its warning signs, except the exact time for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Levels of Reality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-15b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-15b/</guid>
      <description>Even though human reality is a uniform element, it has different levels which lead to different realities.
  Level 1 is made up of our external sense perception, our worldly thoughts such as that for making a living  Level 2 is made up of sleep as perception by the imagination.
  Man lets the perceptions of his imagination rove in his inward (being). With his external senses, he perceives some of them as unencumbered by time, place, or any other condition of the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sufism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-16/</guid>
      <description>16. The science of Sufism Sufism is based on the assumption that the method of the Sufis was always the path of truth and right guidance by:
 the important early Muslims, the men around Muhammad, the men of the second generation, and those who came after them  The Sufi approach is based on:
 constant application to divine worship complete devotion to God aversion to the false splendor of the world abstinence from the pleasure, property, and position to which the great mass aspires, and retirement from the world into solitude for divine worship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of dream interpretation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-17/</guid>
      <description>This belongs to the sciences of the religious law. It originated in Islam when the sciences became crafts 553 and scholars wrote books on them.
Dream visions and dream interpretation existed among the ancients, as among later generations. It existed among former (pre-Islamic) religious groups and nations. However, their dream interpretation did not reach us, 554 because we have been satisfied with the discussions of Muslim dream interpreters.
In any case, all human beings can have dream visions, and these visions must be interpreted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The history of the intellectual sciences</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-18/</guid>
      <description>These sciences naturally arise from us being thinking beings. They are not restricted to any particular religious group.
They are studied by the people of all religious groups who are all equally qualified to learn them and to do research in them. They have existed (and been known) to the human species since civilization had its beginning in the world.
They are called the sciences of philosophy and wisdom and have four categories:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arithmetic: The sciences concerned with numbers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-19/</guid>
      <description>This is the knowledge of the properties of numbers combined in arithmetic or geometric progressions.
 arithmetic progression is where:  each number is always higher by one than the preceding number the sum of the first and last numbers of the progression is equal to the sum of any two numbers in the progression that are equally far removed from the first and the last number, respectively, of the progression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The geometrical sciences</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-20/</guid>
      <description>This studies quantities (measurements) 653 Quantities (measurements) may be continuous, like lines, planes, and (geometrical) solids, or discontinuous, like numbers.
It also studies the essential properties of the quantities (measurements), as, for instance=
The angles of any triangle are equal to two right angles.
Parallel lines do not intersect anywhere, even when they extend to infinity.
The opposite angles formed when two lines intersect are equal to each other. The result of multiplying the first and the third of four quantities in a proportion is equal to that of multiplying the second and the fourth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-21/</guid>
      <description>Astronomy studies the motions of the fixed stars and the planets.
From the manner in which these motions take place, astronomy deduces by geometrical methods the existence of certain shapes and positions of the spheres requiring the occurrence of those motions which can be perceived by the senses. Astronomy thus proves, for instance, by the existence of the precession of the equinoxes, that the center of the earth is not identical with the center of the sphere of the sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of logic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-22/</guid>
      <description>Logic concerns the norms enabling a person to distinguish between right and wrong, both in definitions that give information about the essence of things, and in arguments that assure apperception.
This 687 comes about as follows: The basis of perception is the sensibilia that are perceived by the five senses. All living beings, those which are rational as well as the others, participate in this kind of perception. Man is distinguished from the animals by his ability to perceive universals, which are things abstracted from the sensibilia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Physics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-23/</guid>
      <description>This investigates bodies from the point of view of the motion and stationariness which attach to them. It studies the heavenly and the elementary bodies (substances), as well as the human beings, the animals, the plants, and the minerals created from them. It also studies the springs and earthquakes that come into being in the earth, as well as the clouds, vapors, thunder, lightning, and storms that are in the atmosphere, and other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of metaphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-26/</guid>
      <description>This studies existence.
First, it studies general matters affecting corporeal and spiritual things, such as the quiddities, oneness, plurality, necessity, possibility, and so on.
Then, it studies the beginnings of existing things and (finds) that they are spiritual things. It goes on to study the way existing things issue from (spiritual things), and also (studies) their order. Then, (it studies) the conditions of the soul after its separation from the body and its return to (its) beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sciences of sorcery and talismans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-27/</guid>
      <description>These are sciences showing how human souls may become prepared to exercise an influence upon the world of the elements, either without any aid or with the aid of celestial matters.
The first kind is sorcery. The second kind is talismans.
These sciences are forbidden by the (various) religious laws, because they are harmful and require (their practitioners) to direct themselves to (beings) other than God, such as stars and other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of the secrets of letters</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-28/</guid>
      <description>This science is now called simiya&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;letter magic.&amp;rdquo; 805
The word was transferred from talismans to this science and used in this conventional meaning in the technical terminology of Sufi practitioners of magic. Thus, a general (magical) term came to be used for some particular aspect (of magic).
This science originated in Islam after some time 806 of (its existence) had passed. When the extremist Sufis appeared, they turned to the removal of the veil of sense perception, produced wonders, and were active in the world of the elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does the stone that makes alchemy work?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-29b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-29b/</guid>
      <description>Some philosophers have thought such a stone is found in animals, plants, minerals, or in everything.
The (alchemical) operation might potentially, be performed with anything, because the elements exist in every thing.
We want to know what produces the (alchemical) operation (both) potentially and actually. Therefore, we turn to the statement of al-Harrani 985 that 986all dyeing consists of two kinds.
One may use a substance such as saffron, which is used to dye a white garment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of alchemy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-29/</guid>
      <description>This studies the substance through which the generation of gold and silver may be artificially accomplished, and comments on the operation leading to it. The alchemists acquire knowledge of the tempers and powers of all created things and investigate them critically.
They hope to come upon the substance that is prepared to produce gold and silver. They even investigate the waste matter of animals, such as bones, feathers, hair, 955 eggs, and excrements, not to mention minerals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The corruption of philosophy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-30/</guid>
      <description>The sciences occur in civilization. They are much cultivated in the cities. They can greatly harm religion. The intelligent representatives of the human species think:
 that the essences and conditions of existence, both the perceivable and those beyond sensual perception, as well as their causes, can be perceived by mental speculation and intellectual reasoning. that the articles of faith are established as correct through (intellectual) speculation and not through tradition, because they belong among the intellectual perceptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrology is wrong, has weak achievements, harmful goal</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-31/</guid>
      <description>Astrologers think that astrology, with the knowledge it gives of astral powers, individually or in combination, and of astral influences upon elemental creations, enables them to know the things that are going to be in the world of the elements, before they are created. The positions of the spheres and the stars (are) thus (taken to) indicate every single kind of future event, both universal and individual.
The ancient (astrologers) were of the opinion that the knowledge of astral powers and influence is acquired through experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The impossibility of alchemy and the harm it causes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-32/</guid>
      <description>Many unemployed peopleare led by greed to cultivate alchemy. They think that:
 it is a proper way of making a living the alchemists find it easier and simpler to acquire property  In fact, however, they have to pay for (their efforts) in the form of trouble, hardship, and difficulties, and in the form of persecution by the authorities and loss of property through expenditures. In addition, he 1073 loses standing and, eventually, when his secret 1074 is discovered, faces ruin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Alchemy is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-32b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-32b/</guid>
      <description>The (alchemical) process follows these lines= The (alchemists) take a substance possessing primary preparedness. They use it as the basis. In treating and processing it, they imitate the way nature processes substances in mines and, eventually, transforms them into gold or silver. They (try) hard to increase the active and passive powers (in the process), so that it will be completed in a shorter time (than required by nature). It has been explained in the proper place that an increase in the power of the agent shortens the time needed for his activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The valid purposes which must be remembered when writing a literary composition</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-33/</guid>
      <description>The storehouse of human science is the soul of man. In it, God has implanted perception (idrak) enabling it to think and, thus, to acquire (scientific knowledge). (The process) starts with perception (tasawwur) of the realities and is then continued by affirmation or negation of the essential attributes of the (realities), either directly or through an intermediary.
Man&amp;rsquo;s ability to think thus eventually produces a problematic situation which it tries to solve affirmatively or negatively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The great number of scholarly works is an obstacle to attaining scholarship</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-34/</guid>
      <description>Among the things that are harmful to the human quest for knowledge and to the attainment of a thorough scholarship are the great number of works (available), the large variety in technical terminology (needed for purposes) of instruction, and the numerous (different) methods (used in those works). 1133
The student is required to have a ready knowledge of (all) that. Only then is he considered an accomplished scholar.
Thus, the student must know all the works, or most of them, and observe the methods used in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The study of the auxiliary sciences should not be prolonged</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-37/</guid>
      <description>There are two kinds of sciences=
 The religious sciences  This includes Qur&amp;rsquo;an interpretation, Prophetic traditions, jurisprudence, and speculative theology
The physical and metaphysical sciences of philosophy  There are also auxiliary to these. Examples are=
 Arabic philology and arithmetic, etc  These are auxiliary to the religious sciences   Logic  This is auxiliary to philosophy and often also to speculative theology and the science of the principles of jurisprudence (when treated) according to the method of recent scholars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severity to students does them harm</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-39/</guid>
      <description>Severe punishment during teaching harms the student, especially little children, because it belongs among the things that make for a bad habit. Students, 1191 slaves, and servants who are brought up with injustice and (tyrannical) force are overcome by it. It makes them feel oppressed and causes them to lose their energy. It makes them lazy and induces them to lie and be insincere.
That is, their outward behavior differs from what they are thinking, because they are afraid that they will have to suffer tyrannical treatment (if they tell the truth).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most of the scholars in Islam have been Persians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-42/</guid>
      <description>Most Muslim scholars both in the religious and in the intellectual sciences have been non-Arabs. When a scholar is of Arab origin, he is non-Arab in language and upbringing and has non-Arab teachers. This is so in spite of the fact that Islam is an Arabic religion, and its founder was an Arab.
This is because at the beginning Islam had no sciences or crafts because of the simple desert attitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of lexicography</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-44b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-44b/</guid>
      <description>This science is concerned with explaining the (conventional) meanings of the words of the language. This comes about as follows. The habit of the Arabic language, as far as the vowels called i&amp;rsquo;rab by the grammarians are concerned, became corrupted. 1254 Rules for protecting the (vowel endings) were developed, as we have stated. However, the (process of) corruption continued on account of the close contact (of the Muslims) with non-Arabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sciences concerned with the Arabic language</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-44/</guid>
      <description>There are four pillars of the Arabic language=
 lexicography grammar syntax and style (bayan) literature  Knowledge of them all is necessary for religious scholars, since the source of all religious laws is the Qur&amp;rsquo;an and the Sunnah, which are in Arabic. Their transmitters, the men around Muhammad and the men of the second generation, were Arabs. Their difficulties are to be explained from the language they used. Thus, those who want to be religious scholars must know the sciences connected with the Arabic language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language is a technical habit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-45/</guid>
      <description>All languages are habits similar to crafts techniques. They are habits (located) in the tongue and serve the purpose of expressing ideas.
The good or inadequate (character of such expression) depends on the perfection or deficiency of the habit. This does not apply to individual words but to word combinations. A speaker who possesses a perfect (linguistic) habit and is thus able to combine individual words so as to express the ideas he wants to express, and who is able to observe the form of composition that makes his speech conform to the requirements of the situation, is as well qualified as is (humanly) possible to convey to the listener what he wants to convey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The science of syntax and style and literary criticism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-44c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-44c/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;lsquo;science which originated in Islam after Arabic philology and lexicography. It belongs among the philological sciences, because it is concerned with words and the ideas they convey and are intended to indicate.
This is as follows:
 The thing that the speaker intends to convey to the listener through speech may be a perception (tasawwur) regarding individual words which are dependent and on which (something else) depends 1282 and of which one leads to the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The current language of sedentary is different from the Mudar</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-47/</guid>
      <description>The usual form of address used among the urban and sedentary population is not the old Mudar language nor the language of the (present-day) Arab Bedouins.
It is another independent language, remote from the language of the Mudar and from the language of presentday Arab Bedouins. It is more remote from the former (than from the latter).
It is an independent language by itself. The fact is attested by the changes it shows, which grammatical scholarship 1353 considers solecisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the real meaning of the word &#39;taste&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-50/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;ldquo;taste&amp;rdquo; is in current use among those who are concerned with the various branches of literary criticism (bayan). It means the tongue&amp;rsquo;s possession of the habit of eloquence. What eloquence is 1380 was explained above.
It is the conformity of speech to the meaning (intended), in every aspect, (and this is achieved) by means of certain qualities that give this (conformity) to the word combinations. An eloquent speaker of the Arabic language chooses the form (of expression) that affords such (conformity) according to the methods and ways of Arab address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The urban population is generally deficient in linguistics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-51/</guid>
      <description>The more remote urban people are from the Arabic language, the more difficult 1392 it is for them to obtain it.
This is because the student has previously obtained a habit incompatible with the desired Arabic linguistic habit, since he has grown up speaking the sedentary language which was influenced by non-Arab speech to such a degree that, eventually, the original habit of the Arabic language was replaced by another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The division of speech into poetry and prose</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-52/</guid>
      <description>The Arabic language and Arab speech are divided into two branches. (One of them) is rhymed poetry. It is speech with meter and rhyme, which means that every line of it ends upon a definite letter, which is called the &amp;ldquo;rhyme.&amp;rdquo; The other branch is prose, that is, non-metrical speech.
Each of the two branches comprises various sub-branches and ways of speech. Poetry comprises laudatory and heroic 1417 poems and elegies (upon the dead).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Poetry?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-54b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-54b/</guid>
      <description>The prosodists define poetry as a metrical rhymed speech. This is a wrong defintion. Prosody considers poetry only 1466 under the aspect of the agreement of the verses (of a poem), with respect to the number of successive syllables with and without vowels, 1467 as well as with respect to the similarity of the last foot of thefirst hemistich of the verses of a poem to the last foot of the second hemistich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry and prose work with words, and not with ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-55/</guid>
      <description>Both poetry and prose work with words, and not with ideas.
The ideas are secondary to the (words). The (words) are basic. The craftsman who tries to acquire the habit of poetry and prose uses words for that purpose. He memorizes appropriate words from Arab speech, so as to be able to employ it frequently and have it on his tongue. Eventually, the habit of the Mudar language becomes firmly established in him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ability to write both good poetry and prose is rarely found in one person</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-53/</guid>
      <description>This is because a habit is (located) in the tongue. If another habit previously occupied the place of (that habit), the subsequent habit has iii, s26 not enough room to develop, because the acceptance and obtainment of habits is simpler and easier for natures in their original state.
If there are other previous habits, they resist the (new habit) in the substance that is to receive the (new habit). They prevent it from being quickly accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural and contrived speech</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-57/</guid>
      <description>The secret and spirit of speech that is, expression and address - lie in conveying ideas.
If no effort is made to (convey ideas), (speech) is like &amp;ldquo;dead land&amp;rdquo; (mawat) 1568 which does not count.
The perfect way of conveying (ideas) is eloquence as shown by the literary critics.
Definition of eloquence They say that eloquence is conformity of speech to the requirements of the situation. 1570 Knowledge of the conditions and laws governing the conformity of word combinations to the requirements of the situation is the discipline of eloquence (rhetoric).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People of rank are above cultivating poetry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-58/</guid>
      <description>Poetry was the archive of the Arabs, containing their sciences, their history, and their wisdom. 1604
Leading Arabs competed in it. They used to stop at the fair of &amp;lsquo;Ukaz 1605 to recite poetry. Each would submit his product for criticism 1606 to outstanding and intelligent personalities. Eventually, (Arab poets) came to vie in having their poems hung up at the corners of the Holy Sanctuary to which they made pilgrimage, the house of their ancestor Ibrahim (the Ka&amp;rsquo;bah).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quranic sciences</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-10/</guid>
      <description>The Quran is the word of God that was revealed to His Prophet.
It was written down between the two covers of copies of the Qur&amp;rsquo;an (mushaf). Its transmission has been continuous in Islam.
However, the men around Muhammad transmitted it on his authority in different ways. Eventually, seven ways of reading the Qur&amp;rsquo;an became established. Transmission (of the Qur&amp;rsquo;an readings), with their particular pronunciation, also was continuous. They came to be ascribed to certain men from among a large number of persons who had become famous as their transmitters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sciences are numerous only in large, sedentary civilizations with a culture highly developed</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-6/part-08/</guid>
      <description>This is because scientific instruction is one of the crafts, and crafts are numerous only in cities.
The quality and the number of the crafts depend on the greater or lesser extent of civilization in the cities and on the sedentary culture and luxury they enjoy, because (highly developed crafts) are something additional to just making a living.
When civilized people have more labor available than they need for mere subsistence, such (surplus) labor is used for activities over and above making a living.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
