<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Treatise on Political Economy on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Treatise on Political Economy on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Treatise on Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00a/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For a long time the science of politicswas confounded with political economy. But wealth is essentially independent of political organization.
Under every form of government, a state, whose affairs are well administered, may prosper. Nations have risen to opulence under absolute monarchs, and have been ruined by popular councils. If political liberty is more favourable to he development of wealth, it is indirectly, in the same manner that it is more favourable to general education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Treatise on Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c17/</guid>
      <description>Digression on the Balance of Trade The exclusive system proceeds upon these maxims:
 The commerce of a nation is advantageous, in proportion as its exports exceed its imports, and as there is a larger cash balance receivable in specie, or in the precious metals= watch-cases, spoons, forks, dishes, coffee-pots; or rolled out into leaves for the embellishment of picture frames, bookbinding, and the like; in which case, they form part of that portion of the capital of the community, which yields no interest, but is devoted to the production of utility or pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Treatise on Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c06/</guid>
      <description>What Branches of Production Yield the most Liberal Recompense to Productive Agency.
The aggregate value of a product, in the way just described, refunds to its different concurring producers the amount of their advances, with the addition in most cases, of a profit, that constitutes their revenue. But the profits of productive agency are not of equal amount in all its branches; some yielding but a very scanty revenue for the land, capital, or indus- try, embarked in them; while others give an exorbitant return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Treatise on Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07b/</guid>
      <description>Section 2: The Profits of the Man of Science I am speaking only of the revenue a man of science derives from his calling. There is nothing to prevent his being at the same time a landed proprietor, capitalist or adventurer and possessed of other revenue in these different capacities.
The philosopher, the man who makes it his study to direct the laws of nature to the greatest possible benefit of mankind, receives a very small proportion of the products of that industry, which derives such prodigious advantage from the knowledge, whereof he is at the same time the depository and the promoter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Treatise on Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07c/</guid>
      <description>Section 4= The Profits of the Operative Labourer. 47 Simple, or rude labour may be executed by any man possessed of life and health; wherefore, bare existence is all that is requisite to insure a supply of this description of industry.
Consequently, its wages seldom rise in any country much above what is absolutely necessary to subsistence; and the quantum of supply always remains on a level with the demand; nay, often goes beyond it; for the difficulty lies not in acquiring existence, but in supporting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Treatise on Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c22/</guid>
      <description>Signs or Representatives of Money People imagine that all debts to foreigners can be paid by bills of exchange; and measures have been frequently suggested, and sometimes adopted, for the encouragement of this fictitious mode of payment.
But this is a mere delusion.
A bill of exchange has no intrinsic value; it can only be drawn upon any place for a sum actually due at that place; and no sum can be there actually due, unless an</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00d/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith was educated in that school in Scotland which has produced so many scholars, historians, and philosophers, of the highest celebrity. He published his Wealth of Nations in 1776.
He demonstrated that:
 wealth was the exchangeable value of things its extent was proportional to the number of things in our possession having value wealth could be created and engrafted on things previously destitute of value just as value could be given or added to matter wealth could be preserved, accumulated, or destroyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix A</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/appendix-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/appendix-a/</guid>
      <description>A Table, Showing the Result of Value Lent to the State.
A bankruptcy would probably obviate the necessity of fresh loans; but would not release an atom of the former taxation, where the interest of the debt is habitually paid, not with the proceeds of taxation, but with new loans. Thus, the burthens of the people would not be alleviated, 114 nor the charges of production reduced= consequently there would be no sensible reduction in the price of commodities; nor would British products find a readier market either at home or abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix A: Temporary and Permanent Emigration, Considered as National Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c20/</guid>
      <description>When a traveller arrives in France, and there spends 2000 dollars, it must not be supposed that the whole sum is clear profit to France. The traveller expends it in exchange for the values he consumes= the effect is just the same, as if he had remained abroad and sent to France for what he wanted, instead of coming and consuming it here; and is precisely simi- lar to that of international commerce, in which the profit made is not the whole or principal value, received, but a larger or smaller percentage upon that principal according to the circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 Production</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c01/</guid>
      <description>Civilized nations are still unenlightened and ignorant!
If we take the pains to inquire what that is, which mankind in a social state of existence denominate wealth, we shall find the term employed to designate an indefinite quantity of objects bearing inherent value, as of land, of metal, of coin, of grain, of stuffs, of commodities of every description.
When they further extend its signification to landed securities, bills, notes of hand, and the like, it is evidently because they contain obligations to deliver things possessed of inherent value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10: the Transformations Undergone by Capital in The Progress of Production</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c10/</guid>
      <description>So much it was necessary to specify, in enumerating the various means of production. We now come to consider and exam- ine, what becomes of capital in the progress of production, and how it is perpetuated and increased. To avoid fatiguing the reader with abstract speculation, I shall begin with giving examples, which I shall take from every day’s experience and observation. The general principles will follow of themselves, and the reader will immediately see their applicability to all other cases, which he may have oc- casion to pronounce a judgment upon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11 The Formation and Multiplication of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c11/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10 showed how productive capital, though kept, during the progress of production, in a continual state of employment, and subject to perpetual change and wear, is yet ultimately reproduced in full value, when the business of production is at an end.
Since, then, wealth con
But let us trace the disposal of this surplus of 1000 dollars to every imaginable destination. Suppose, for instance, that in-
resown or planted, without having undergone any transmutation; perhaps the wood, that might have been used as firing to warm superfluous apartments, may have been converted into palings or other carpenter’s work; and what was cut down in the first instance as an item of revenue, be so employed, as to become an item of capital.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12 Unproductive Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c12/</guid>
      <description>Values once produced may be devoted, either to the satisfaction of the wants of those who have acquired them, or to a further act of production. They may also be withdrawn both from unproductive consumption and from reproductive employment, and remain buried or concealed.
The owner of values, in so disposing of them, not only deprives himself of the self-gratification he might have derived from their consumption, but also of the advantage he might draw from the productive agency of the value hoarded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 14 The Right to Property</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c14/</guid>
      <description>A whole country may grow rich even upon its ornamental possessions. Were trees planted wherever they could thrive without injury to other products, 118 besides the accession of beauty and salubrity, and the additional moisture attracted by the multiplication of timber-trees, the value of the timber alone would, in a country of much extent, amount to something considerable.
It is the province of speculative philosophy to trace the origin of the right of property; of legislation to regulate its transfer; and of political science to devise the surest means of protecting that right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1s06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1s06/</guid>
      <description>Book I= On Production
Section 6= Why is Money neither a Sign nor a Measure.
adulterated coin, that he again may pay over at the same rate as he receives it, than to curtail his claim by ¼, ½, or in any other proportion. Let us see how the two methods differ. Money would be a mere sign or representative, had it no in- trinsic value of its own; but, on the contrary, whenever it is employed in sale or purchase, its intrinsic value alone is con- sidered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 Operations Alike Common to All Branches of Industry.</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c06/</guid>
      <description>take the example of a product of external commerce; such as indigo.
The science of the geographer, the traveller, the astronomer, brings us acquainted with the spot where it is to be met with, and the means of crossing the seas to get at it. The merchant equips his vessels, and sends them in quest of the commodity; and the mariner and land-carrier perform the mechanical part of this production. If we examine closely the workings of human industry, it will be found, that, to whatever object it be applied, it consists of three distinct operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7: The Labour of Mankind, of Nature, and of Machinery Respectively</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c07/</guid>
      <description>It is in this light that all machinery must be regarded, from the simplest to the most complicated instrument, from a common file to the most expensive and complex apparatus. Tools are but simple machines, and machines but complicated tools, whereby we enlarge the limited powers of our hands and fingers; and both are, in many respects, mere means of obtaining the co-operation of natural agents. 72 Their obvious effect is to make less labour requisite for the raising the same quan- tity of produce, or, what comes exactly to the same thing, to obtain a larger produce from the same quantity of human labour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8: The Advantages and Disadvantages Resulting from Division of Labour, and of the Extent to Which it May Be Carried.</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c08/</guid>
      <description>The close pursuit of this inquiry through all the arts of industry would show, that the advantage of machinery is not limited to the bare substitution of it for human labour, but that, in fact, it gives a positive new product, inasmuch as it gives a degree of perfection before unknown. The flatting-mill and the die execute products, that the utmost skill and attention of the human hand could never accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9: The Different Methods of Employing Commercial Industry, and the Mode in Which They Concur in Production.</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c09/</guid>
      <description>In Book 2, we shall see how the actual demand for a product originating in its utility, is limited by the amount of the cost of production, and upon what principle its relative value is determined in each particular place. At present it is sufficient for the clear conception of commercial production, to con- sider the value of a product as a given quantity or datum. Thus, without examining the reason why oil of olives is worth at Marseilles thirty, and at Paris forty sous per lb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter V. The Mode in Which Industry, Capital, and Natural Agents Unite in Production.</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c05/</guid>
      <description>Industry and capital are likewise competent to produce by themselves, when that industry is employed upon products of foreign growth, procurable by capital only; as in the Euro- pean manufacture of cotton and many other articles. So that every class of manufacture is competent to raise products, provided there be industry and capital exerted. The presence of land is not absolutely necessary, unless perhaps the area whereon the work is done, and which is commonly rented, may be thought to come under this description, as in extreme strictness it certainly must.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonies and Their Products</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c19/</guid>
      <description>Colonies are settlements formed in distant countries by an elder nation, called the mother-country. When the latter wishes to enlarge its intercourse with a country, already populous and civilized, whose territory it has, therefore, no hopes of getting into its own possession, it commonly contents itself with the establishment of a factory or mercantile residence, where its factors may trade, in conformity with the local regulations, as the Europeans have done in China and Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Revenue is Distributed In Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c05/</guid>
      <description>A portion of the demand for the precious metals is occasioned by their gradual destruction by use; for, although less subject to decay than most products, they are still perishable in a certain degree; and doubtless the wear, though slow, must be considerable upon the immense quantity of gold and silver in constant use, as well in the character of money, as in the various objects of spoons, forks, goblets, dishes, and jewellery of all sorts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Consumption — Its Motives and its Effects</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c05/</guid>
      <description>Great inequality of private fortune is hostile to those kinds of consumption, that must be regarded as most judicious. In proportion as that inequality is more marked, the artificial wants of the population are more numerous, the real ones more scantily supplied, and the rapid consumption more common and destructive. The patrician spendthrifts and imperial gluttons of ancient Rome thought they never could squander enough. Besides, immoral kinds of consumption are infinitely more general, where the extremes of wealth and poverty are found blended together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Debt</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c09/</guid>
      <description>To this fixation of the tax, many writers attribute the high state of the cultivation of the land in England= and doubtless it may have done much to promote improvement. But, what would be thought of a government that should say to a tradesman in a small way of business, “You are trading in a small way upon a small capital, and consequently pay very little in direct taxes.
Borrow, and enlarge your capital, extend your dealings, and increase your profits as much as you can, and we will not charge you with any increase of taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Agents That Assist in the Production of Wealth, Specially of Land</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c04/</guid>
      <description>Independently of the aid that industry receives from capital, that is to say, from products of her own previous creation, towards the creation of still further products, she avails herself of the agency and powers of a variety of agents not of her own creation, but offered spontaneously by nature= and from the co-operation of these natural agents derives a portion of the utility she communicates to things.
What is true of one, two, three, or four individuals, is true of society in the aggregate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nominal Variation of Price, and of the Peculiar Value of Bullion and of Coin</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c04/</guid>
      <description>In treating of the elevation and depression of the price of commodities, although value has been expressed in money, no notice has been taken of the value of money itself; which, to say the truth, plays no part in real, or even in relative variation of the price of other commodities.
One product is always ultimately bought with another, even when paid for in the first instance in money.
When the price of wool is doubled, it is purchased with twice the quantity of every other commodity, whether the exchange be made directly, or through the intermediate agency of money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3-notes/</guid>
      <description>My brother, Louis Say of Nantes, has attacked this position in a short tract &amp;ldquo;Principales Causes de la Richesse et de la Misère des Peuples et des Particuliers&amp;rdquo;, 8vo. Paris. Deiterville.  He lays down the maxim, that objects are items of wealth,, solely in respect of their actual utility, and not of their admitted or recognised utility.
In the eye of reason, his position is certainly correct; but in this science relative value is the only guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Consumption</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c06/</guid>
      <description>Section 1= The Nature and general Effect of Public Consumption.
Besides the wants of individuals and of families which it is the object of private consumption to satisfy, the collection of many individuals into a community gives rise to a new class of wants, the wants of the society in its aggregate capacity, the satisfaction of which is the object of public consumption.
The public buys and consumes the personal service of the minister, that directs its affairs, the soldier, that protects it from external violence, the civil or criminal judge, that protects the rights and interests of each member against the aggression of the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Credit, its Basis, and the Circumstances that endanger its Solidity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c09b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c09b/</guid>
      <description>The sentiments of lenders and of mankind are more powerfully operated upon by the impressions of the moment, than by any other motive; experience of the past must be very recent, and the prospect of the future very near, to have any sensible effect. The monstrous breach of faith on the part of the French government in 1721, in regard to its paper-money and the Mississippi share-holders, did not prevent the ready negotiation of a loan of 200,000,000 liv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real and Relative Variation of Price</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c03/</guid>
      <description>When revenue is added to capital, it thenceforth ceases to be revenue, or, as such, to be capable of satisfying the wants of the proprietor. It can only yield an increased revenue, being an item of productive capital, consumable in the manner of capital, that is to say, in such way as to yield a product in exchange and return for the value consumed.
The price of an article is the quantity of money it may be worth; current price, the quantity it may be sure of obtaining at the particular place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Section V. The Independence accruing to the Moderns from the Advancement of Industry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07z/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07z/</guid>
      <description>The maxims of political economy are immutable; ere yet observed or discovered, they were operating in the way above described;
the same cause regularly producing the same effect; the wealth of Tyre and of Amsterdam originated in a common source. It is society that has been subject to change, in the progressive advancement of industry.
The ancients were not nearly so far behind the moderns in agriculture, as in the mechanical arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c08b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c08b/</guid>
      <description>Section 2: The different Modes of Assessment, and the Classes they press ups respectively.
A 1% tax on the redemption of ground-rents and rent-charges was virtually a penalty upon an act, equally advantageous to the parties and to the community at large; a fine upon the meritorious exertions of prudent land-owners to pay off their incumbrances.
Taxation is a requisition by the government upon its subjects for a portion of their products, or of their value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c08c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c08c/</guid>
      <description>Section 3: Taxation in Kind Taxation in kind is the specific and immediate appropriation of a portion of the gross product to the public service. It has this advantage, of calling on the producer only for what he has actually in hand, in the identical shape which it happens to be under. Belgium, after its conquest by France, found itself at times unable to pay its taxes, in spite of abundant crops; the war, and the prohibition of exportation, obstructed the sale of its produce, which the government enforced by demanding payment in money; whereas, the taxes might have been collected without difficulty, had the government been content to take payment in kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Actual Contributors to Public Consumption</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c07/</guid>
      <description>A portion of the objects of public consumption have, in some very rare instances, been provided by a private individual. We see occasional acts of private munificence, in the erection of a hospital, the laying out of a road, or of public gar- dens upon the land, and at the cost, of an individual. In ancient times, examples of this kind were more frequent, though much less meritorious. The private opulence of the ancients was commonly the fruit of domestic, or provincial, plunder and peculation, or perhaps the spoil of a hostile nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basis of Value and of Supply and Demand</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c01/</guid>
      <description>Book 2: The Distribution of Wealth Chapter 1 The Basis of Value and of Supply and Demand The principal phenomena of production have been investigated in the first book; wherein I have shown how human industry, with the aid of capital and of natural agents and prop- erties, creates every kind of utility, which is the primary source of value; and in what way social institutions and public au- thority operate to the benefit or the prejudice of production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits from the Quick Circulation of Money and Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c16/</guid>
      <description>Jobbing in merchandise necessarily causes a loss, either to the jobber, if the price be not raised by the transaction, or to the consumer, if it be raised. 142
It is common to hear people descant upon the benefits of an active circulation; that is to say, of numerous and rapid sales. It is material to appreciate them correctly.
The activity of circulation is at the utmost pitch to which it can be carried with advantage, when the product passes into the hands of a new productive agent the instant it is fit to receive a new modification, and is ultimately handed over to the consumer, the instant it has received the last finish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Demand or Market for Products</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c15/</guid>
      <description>it not for the purchase of raw materials or stock for your trade, or victuals for your support? 129 Wherefore, it is products that you want, and not money. The silver coin you will have received on the sale of your own products, and given in the purchase of those of other people, will the next moment execute the same office between other contracting parties, and so from one to another to infinity; just as a public vehicle successively transports objects one after another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Different Kinds of Consumption</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c01/</guid>
      <description>Book 3: The Consumption of Wealth Chapter 1: The Different Kinds of Consumption Whatever cannot possibly lose its value is not liable to consumption. A landed estate cannot be consumed; but its annual productive agency may; for when once that agency has been exerted, it cannot be exerted again. The improvements of an estate may be consumed, although their value may possibly exceed that of the estate itself; for these improvements are the effect of human exertion and industry; but the land itself is inconsumable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Different Kinds of Industry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c02/</guid>
      <description>Production is the creation of utility, not matter. It is not to be estimated by the length, the bulk, or the weight of the product, but by the utility it presents.
Some items of human consumption are the spontaneous gifts of nature, and require no exertion of man for their production; as air, water, and light, under certain circumstances.
These are destitute of exchangeable value; because the want of them is never felt, others being equally provided with them as ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Consumption in General</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3ch02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3ch02/</guid>
      <description>The immediate effect of consumption of every kind is, the loss of value, consequently, of wealth, to the owner of the article consumed. This is the invariable and inevitable conse-
fore, in common parlance, to spend and to consume have become nearly synonymous. Yet, by the mere act of buying, the value expended is not lost; for the article purchased has likewise a value, which may be parted with again for what it cost, if it has not been bought over-dear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Productive Consumption</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c03/</guid>
      <description>The value absorbed by productive consumption is called Capital. The trader, manufacturer, and cultivator, purchase the raw material 8 and productive agency, which they consume in the preparation of new products. The immediate effect is precisely the same as that of unproductive consumption, namely, to create a demand for the objects of their consumption, which operates upon their price, and upon their production; and to cause a destruction of value But the ultimate effect is different; there is no satisfaction of a human want, and no resulting gratification, except that accruing to the adventurer from the possession of the fresh product the value which replaces that of the products consumed, and commonly affords him a profit into the bargain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Revenue Derived by One Nation from Another</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c10/</guid>
      <description>One nation cannot take from another the revenues of its industry. A German tailor, establishing himself in France, there makes a profit, in which Germany had no participation. But, if this tailor contrive to amass a little capital, and after the lapse of several years carry it back with him to his native country, he injures France to the same extent as a French capitalist, who should emigrate with the same amount of fortune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Taxation in general</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c08/</guid>
      <description>Taxation is the transfer of a portion of the national products from the hands of individuals to those of the government, for the purpose of meeting the public consumption or expenditure. Whatever be the denomination it bears, whether tax, contribution, duty, excise, custom, aid, subsidy, 66 grant, or free gift, it is virtually a burthen imposed upon individuals, either in a separate or corporate character, by the ruling power for the time being, for the purpose of supplying the consumption it may think proper to make at their expense; in short, an impost, in the literal sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Unproductive Consumption in General</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b3c04/</guid>
      <description>The most judicious kinds of consumption are:
 Such as conduce to the satisfaction of positive wants  by which term I mean those, upon the satisfaction of which depends the existence, the health, and the contentment of the generality of mankind; being the very reverse of such as are generated by re fined sensuality, pride, and caprice. Thus, the national consumption will, on the whole, be judicious, if it absorb the articles rather of convenience than of display the more linen and the less lace; the more plain and wholesome dishes, and the fewer dainties; the more warm clothing, and the less embroidery, the better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect on National Wealth, Resulting from the Productive Efforts of Public Authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c18/</guid>
      <description>The substance of the argument of the prohibitionists may be reduced to this; that it is expedient to encourage domestic agriculture, even at the expense of the consumer, to avoid the risk of starvation by external means; which is seriously to be apprehended on two, occasions in particular; first, when the power or influence of a belligerent is able to intercept or check the import, which might become necessary; secondly, when the corn-growing countries themselves experience a scarcity, and are obliged to retain the whole of their crops for their own subsistence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Mercantilism and the French Revolution</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00b/</guid>
      <description>In every part of Europe, personal freedom became more generally respected due to the influence of public sentiment.
 calling all loans with interest as usury making idleness a quality of nobility  They perceived the decline of such prejudices to be favourable to the advancement of science, or to a more exact knowledge of the immutable laws of nature. This then has been favourable to the progress of industry, and industry to national opulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Mercantilism and the French Revolution</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c00c/</guid>
      <description>Air and water were only accurately analyzed less than 40 years ago.
doctrine is founded, &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; are continually assailed even if they have been repeated a thousand times in different countries. A similar lack of agreement exists in moral and political science.
The same facts are, indeed, observed
Political economy, in the same manner as the exact sciences, is composed of a few fundamental principles, and of a great number of corollaries or conclusions, drawn from these principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mode in Which the Quantity of the Product Affects Population</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c11/</guid>
      <description>Trade and barter adapt the products to the general nature of the demand.
The objects most in demand are food and habitation. The wants of each family or individual, are more or less fully satisfied, in proportion to the ability to purchase these objects. which ability depends upon the productive means and exertion of each respectively; in plain terms, upon the revenue of each respectively.
Thus, in the end, if we sift this matter to the bottom, we shall find, that families, and nations, which are but aggregations of families, subsist wholly on their own products; and that the amount of product in each case necessarily limits the numbers of those who can subsist upon it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature and Uses of Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c21/</guid>
      <description>Section I. General Remarks In a society ever so little advanced in civilization, no single individual produces all that is necessary to satisfy his own wants; and it is rarely that an individual, by his single exertion, creates even any single product; but even if he does, his wants are not limited to that single article; they are numerous and various, and he must, therefore, procure all other objects of his personal consumption, by exchanging the overplus of the single product he himself creates beyond his own wants, for such other products as he stands in need of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b1c03/</guid>
      <description>Stewart was the leading advocate of the mercantile system. Its maxim is= the wealth of one set of men is derived from the impoverishment of another.
He is wrong in asserting, that, “when once a stop is put to external commerce, the stock of internal wealth cannot be aug- mented.” 54 Wealth, it seems, can come only from abroad; but abroad, where does it come from? from abroad also. So that in tracing it from abroad to abroad, we must necessarily, in the end, exhaust every source, till at last we are compelled to look for it beyond the limits of our own planet, which is absurd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Profit of Landed Property</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c09/</guid>
      <description>What is the profit of land independent of that accruing from the industry and capital, devoted to its cultivation; and to consider the profit of land in the abstract, and whence it originates, without any inquiry as to who may be the cultivator, whether the proprietor himself, or a tenant under him.
Land has the faculty of transforming and adapting to the use of mankind an infinity of substances, which, without its inter- vention, would be to them of no service; it yields nutriment and vegetative juices to the grain, the fruits, and vegetables, whereon we subsist; as well as to the forests, whereof we construct our houses, ships, and furniture, and whence we derive fuel to keep us warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Revenue of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c08/</guid>
      <description>The capital used in productiion establishes a demand for capital to be so employed. It enables its owners to charge for that service.
&amp;ldquo;The profit of capital&amp;rdquo; earned by capitalist is distinct from the profit of the industry employing it.
 If he employs his capital himself, it becomes the revenue of his capital, which is added to that of his personal talent and industry, and often confounded with it. If he lends it, the revenue of capital is the interest paid for its use, the proprietor abandoning to the borrower the profit derivable from his personal employment of the capital lent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Revenue of Industry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c07/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: The Profits of Industry in general The general motives, which stimulate the demand of products, have been above investigated. 38 When the demand for any product whatever, is very lively, the productive agency, through whose means alone it is obtainable, is likewise in brisk demand, which necessarily raises its ratio of value= this is true generally, of every kind of productive agency. Industry, capital, and land, all yield, ceteris paribus, the largest profits, when the general demand for products is most active, affluence most expanded, profits most widely diffused, and production most vigorous and prolific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sources of Revenue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/b2c02/</guid>
      <description>Book 1 showed that products are raised by the productive means at the command of mankind, that is to say, by human industry, capital, and natural powers and agents.
The products thus raised, form the revenue of those possessed of these means of production, and enable them to procure such of the necessaries and comforts of existence, as are not furnished gratuitously either by nature, or by their fellow-creatures.
Such as are capable of consumption, as, for instance, the float-ing values, whereon production expends its energies, may be consumed either in such manner as to occasion a re-production, in which case they will still constitute a part of the means of production; or in such manner as to yield no further production, in which case they cease to form any part of those means, and are devoted to pure destruction, more or less rapid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/say/treatise/notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes
 The following extract of a letter from M. Say, to the Ameri- can editor, it may not be improper to subjoin, as it con- tains the author’s opinion of the value he attaches to the preliminary discourse. “Your translation and restoration of the preliminary discourse adds, in my eyes, a new value to your edition. It could only have been from a narrow calculation of the English publisher, that it was omitted in Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
