<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Idea and Ideology on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Idea and Ideology on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolution and the 4 Ages of Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Primitive humans had no society. Their whole set-up was individualistic.
Even the concept of family was absent. Life was brute and non-intellectual.
Nature was the direct abode and physical strength ruled the day. The strong enjoyed at the cost of the weak, who had to surrender before the voracity of the physical giants.
However, the sense of acquisition had not developed in them, and they worked manually, and there was no intellectual exploitation in that age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is Life Created?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01d/</guid>
      <description>How does life get expression within the physical unit structure?
The 5 Layers Physical structures are composed of 5 fundamental layers:
 Ethereal Aerial Luminous Liquid Solid  A unit structure has a body made up of a composite of these 5 layerswith controlling nuclei.
 These layers should remain in requisite proportion.  Vital energy or práńáh is the structure&amp;rsquo;s collective creative unifying energy.
 It depends on the mutual cohesion of these layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideology and Personality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>The Cosmic Consciousness acts as the witnessing entity with the help of His Citishakti.
The wavelength of this Citishakti is infinite. So we say that it flows in a straight line.
When the mind or manah takes the átman – the witnessing entity of the unit mind – as its so-called object (this is to be done by complete surrender – there is no other way because actually the mind is the object of the átman), the mental waves will get straightened gradually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind, Práńendriya and Vrtti</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>The Creation of the Universe The Transcendent Entity is one Infinite. Its immanent principles are the:
 sentient mutative static.  These forces are naturally belligerent. Their direction is haphazard, forming infinite figures with innumerable sides.
Stage 0: Nirguna (Anucchúnyá Prakrti) Prakrti here is anucchúnyá. Brahma here is objectless. This is because there is no subject or object. Therefore, Brahma is called nirguńa, “beyond all the attributes” of Prakrti. Here, there is not even the seed of creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samskara or Reactive Momenta</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-07b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-07b/</guid>
      <description>Every stage results from the previous stages.
 Even the stage after formation of the unit mind is the effect of all the past stages.  &amp;ldquo;Saḿskára&amp;rdquo; is the effect of action in the past stages.
 It gives momentum to the unit mind.  The initial creation of the unit mind is the result of certain forces reacting in crudification.
The ultimate cause of momentum of every force is the Macrocosm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtilification (Pratisaiṋcara)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>The essence of all physical and metaphysical diversities is the Supreme One – the noumenal cause of this phenomenal world.
There are 5 fundamental layers of this phenomenal world:
 kśiti (solid) ap (liquid) tejas (luminous) marut (aerial) vyoma (ethereal)  These are physical for the microcosm, but mental for the Macrocosm.
Crudification (saiṋcara or saḿkrama) is:
 the transformation or metamorphosis of the One into these layers. a process of analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtlification or Pratisaiṋcara</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>Due to internal clash and cohesion, and division and association amongst the 3 immanent principles (sentient, mutative and static), the resultant force bursts out at any one vertex of the triangle formed due to the ever-flowing eternal force. This leads to the crudification which is the inanimate phase of creation.
In the living bodies after the formation of crudest solid layer, the division and association of matter result in the formation of mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/summary/</guid>
      <description>The 3 gunas get imbalance because of probability This creates desire as an identity-wave, powered by static negative energy. This is why yoga and Buddhism advocates ending desire or just desiring the Supreme The wave degrades into 5 physical layers, with its physical energies Many waves lead to some waves being the environment of other waves A combo of the 5 layers has a probability of getting a lot of sentient prakrti (manifest shiva) to be a good environment for life The good combo creates pranah and unit mind In time, from clash and cohesion of the shiva and shakti, the unit mind develops an ego from its inherent atman The unit mind is a reflection of the paramatman which is its goal since it was created from the positive force Pranah, as positive static energy, has 5 internal and 5 external types to help the mind grow and the atman to be more like the paramataman The growth of mind is through its heart chakra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Táraka Brahma Versus Avatara</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-06c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-06c/</guid>
      <description>The Cycle of Existence or Brahma Cakra is tthe collective name of crudification and subtilification.
 It has no uniformity of flow.  the sentient force is faster than the mutative the mutative force is faster than the static.    Thus, in the beginning of crudification speed is attained. Similarly, after elevation, the influence of the sentient force causes the unit mind to reach sámánya deha (a stage beyond the hirańmaya kośa where the unit mind experiences only the sentient force), the speed is faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Created Layers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>The Created Layers (Bhútatattva) Crudification (saiṋcara) is a process of analysis, transforming one into many.
Avidyámáyá is the operative force behind its multicreative characteristics.
 At different phases of this crudification, creation-layers (bhútas) with their peculiar properties come into existence.  Bhúta means “created being”. Generally, it refers to the past.
Through the influence of the sentient force on the Macrocosmic Nucleus, the Identity-Layer comes into being.
 It turns into the Ego-Layer by the activation of the mutative force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Atman or Individual or Unit Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>Saccidánanda has 3 terms, wrongly translated as:
 sat: existence cit: knowledge ánanda: bliss  The correct translation is:
 sat: a Transcendental Entity that undergoes no change chit: consciousness ananda: divine bliss  The Transcendental Entity may appear to undergo a metamorphosis but actually undergoes no qualitative change.
 Hence, Sat can only mean the Transcendental Entity – an absolute entity which undergoes no change. Ananda is divine bliss experienced subjectively and not in an objective manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collective Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-06b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-06b/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Paramátman&amp;rdquo; [active collective consciousness] is the collective name for the Macrocosmic Nucleus..
 It means “conscious of creations”. It is the consciousness in the Nucleus and the consciousness in the Macrocosm and microcosms. It is made up of individual consciousnesses or Átman which is in the unit structure.   Macrocosm (Cosmic Mind) and microcosms (unit mind) themselves are not included in Paramátman.
Saguna Brahma &amp;ldquo;Saguńa Brahma&amp;rdquo; is the collectivity of:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cosmic Brotherhood</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>Spirituality is not a utopian ideal.
 It is a practical philosophy which can be practised and realized in daily life, however mundane it be.  Spirituality stands for evolution and elevation, and not for superstition in action or pessimism.
All fissiparous tendencies and group or clan philosophies which tend to create the shackles of narrow-mindedness are not connected with spirituality and should be discouraged.
Only that which leads to broadness of unison should be accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crudification Cycle (Saiṋcara)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>The Principle of Consciousness and the Principle of Activity Crudification or Saiṋcara is the centrifugal activity of the Nucleus (Puruśottama) of the Macrocosm.
This Nucleus is:
 the center, witness, or subject of the Macrocosm which is Its periphery, experience, or object. The Principle of Consciousness    Hence, the activation of Consciousness without the Principle of Activity is impossible. Action results only when the Principle of Activity gets a chance to express itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Life</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-02b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-02b/</guid>
      <description>Reflection Leads to the Physical, Psychic, and Spiritual Forces The movement of the unit mind accelerates proportionally to the increase in the reflection of Supreme Consciousness on its mental plate.
 As a result of thisdenser reflection, the crude mind is converted into subtler mind.  Its mental scope increases as a psychic dilation.
 This dilation comes from clash, which leads to 3 operative forces:    Physical force, created out of physical clash Psychic force, created as a result of clashes in the psychic sphere Spiritual force emanated from longing for the Great  The resulting dilation is not mere puffing up, but an expansion in volume and mass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Formation of Identity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01b/</guid>
      <description>The Cosmic Identity as Identity-Layer from Sentient Principle of Activity Thus, Activity expresses Herself as the resultant force that starts crudification*.
 This Activity is sentient, though rudimentally static. It creates the Pure “I” feeling in Consciousness.   *Superphysics Note: Crudificationis the start of the feelings
 It is a pure “I” feeling because sentient Activity cannot go any further.
This stage is known as the Identity-Layer (Mahattattva).
 It is nothing but the Cosmic “I” This is the first bondage of Consciousness by His innate sentient Activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Formation of Mind</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01c/</guid>
      <description>Objects as Mind-Stuff As static Activity starts its domination, it forces the Ego-Layer or Active Identity to separate from the Identity-Layer or Cosmic Identity to become the object of the Cosmic Identity.
This allows the Ego-Layer to have full activity through the cruder mind-stuff (citta). Thus, the Cosmic Subjective “I” or Cosmic Identity is partially transformed by the Principle of Activity into:
 the Cosmic Active “I” [Acting Identity or cause] the Cosmic objective “I” from a portion of its Cosmic Subjective “I” [target or effect].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heart Chakra and Práńáyáma</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-04b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-04b/</guid>
      <description>The Heart Chakra The heart cakra (anáhata) is not in the mechanical heart. It is not listed as a sense-organ because:
 its controlling point is not in the brain it is a layer and not a sense-organ  The job of the 10 sense-organs (indriyas) is only to send and receive quantum-perceptions The Heart Chakra is the collective name of the 10 váyus    The sense-organs are the activators and perceivers of the 5 layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kuńd́alinii or Coiled Serpentine</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-08b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-08b/</guid>
      <description>The kulakuńd́alinii, the “coiled serpentine”, is the theoretical negative force of the unit body.
This is why it is different for each individual.
Its fundamental negativity tends towards the final merger into Consciousness for liberation.The sádhaná is for a psycho-physical liberation in the initial stage. Its starting-point must be in the crudest manifestation.
It must reside in that portion of the physical body from which the crudest matter (kśititattva) of the body is controlled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mind and the 10 Energies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Mind Crudification transforms the transcendental Consciousness into Mind, as the Identity-Layer, Ego-Layer, and mindstuff.
The first 2 stages of bondage are theoretical.
 The movement or vibration is unrestricted by the relative factors of time, space and person. These 2 stages are not perceivable.   But the third stage, He as mindstuff, comes within the jurisdiction of autoperception.
In the process of subtilification (pratisaiṋcara), by division and decimation, solids get metamorphosed into subtler factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Minimum Essentials of Life</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-11b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-11b/</guid>
      <description>The availability of the minimum essentialities of life plays a vital part not only in achieving world brotherhood, but also in the development of human personality.
This should be tackled on a world footing, and should be based on certain fundamental presumptions.
Every human being has certain minimum requirements which he or she must be guaranteed. Guaranteed availability of foodstuff, clothing, medical assistance and housing accommodation should be arranged so that human beings may be able to utilize their surplus energy (energy up till now engaged in procuring the essentialities of life) in subtler pursuits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perception Layers and Sense-Layers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-03b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-03b/</guid>
      <description>Waves Brahma Cakra is the Cosmic Circle. It is a Cosmic dance in which every created object, under the magic spell of the Cosmos, is moving in proper harmony and rhythm.
An object or objectivity is nothing but a wave motion within the body of the Cosmos. We thus establish the wave theory of modern science through an independent logical outlook.
Life consists only of an ocean of waves.
Every layer (bhúta) from the aethereal to the solid is in an eternal flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Portions of the Mind</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Consciousness is the supreme subjectivity.
 All other, mundane, subjectivities or objectivities are mere blendings of the absolute subjectivity.  Therefore, the mind is not an absolute entity.
 Instead, it is a transformed state of consciousness. To perform its actions, it depends on the motor or sensory organs as its direct agents. Afferent and efferent nerves, in their turn, act as direct agents of these organs.  The nerves:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Propensities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-04c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-04c/</guid>
      <description>Mind is a state in the process of Brahma Cakra.
 It is the result of changing positions It is essentially a stage in the process of motion.  This implies a momentum which mind has to express.
 To find expression, the mind adopts certain inter- and intra-ectoplasmic occupations. These occupations (love, hatred, fear, etc.) are known as propensities (vrtti).  A propensity is “the way of expression of mind”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vital Energy (Pranah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-01e/</guid>
      <description>In Sanskrit, this vital energy is always plural because it is a collection of 10 important forces (váyus) with 5 working internally, and 5 working externally of the physical structure.
   Internal Vayu Jurisdiction Function     Práńa navel point to the vocal cord inhalation and exhalation   Apána anus to the navel point controls the movement of urine and stool   Samána navel maintains adjustment between práńa and apána   Udána throat controls the vocal cord and the voice   Vyána  regulates blood circulation and the afferent and efferent nerves    Death A physical deficiency or defect in any portion of the body results in the weakening of práńa and apána.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yama and Niyama</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-10b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-10b/</guid>
      <description>Those spiritual revolutionaries who work to achieve such progressive changes for human elevation on a well-thought, pre-planned basis, whether in the physical, metaphysical or spiritual sphere, by adhering to the principles of Yama and Niyama, are sadvipras.
The 5 principles of Yama are:
   Yama Meaning     ahiḿsá not causing suffering to any harmless creature through thought, word or deed   satya action of mind or use of words with the object of helping others in the real sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-07d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/idea/chapter-07d/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
