<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chinese Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chinese Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Rights and Obligations of Citizens</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 33
All persons holding the nationality of the PRC are citizens of the PRC.
All citizens of the PRC are equal before the law.
The state shall respect and protect human rights.
Every citizen shallenjoy the rights prescribed by the Constitution and the law and must fulfill the obligations prescribed by the Constitution and the law.
Article 34
All citizens of the PRC who have reached the age of 18, regardless of ethnicity, race, gender, occupation, family background, religious belief, level of education, property statusor length of residence,shallhave the right to vote and stand for election; persons deprived of political rightsin accordance with lawshallbe an exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Principles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 1
The People’s Republic of China (PRC) is a socialist state governed by a people’s democratic dictatorship led by the working class, based on an alliance of workers and peasants.
It is led by the Communist Party of China. No organization or individual can damage the socialist system.
Article 2
All power in the PRC belongs to the people through the:
 National People’s Congress (NPC) local people’s congresses (LPCs)  Article 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preamble</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/preamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/preamble/</guid>
      <description>Preamble
China is one of the countries with the longest history. After 1840, feudal China gradually became a semi-colonial, semi-feudal country.
The Revolution of 1911, led by Dr. Sun Yat-sen, created the Republic of China to abolish the feudal monarchy. However, imperialism and feudalism still remained. In 1949, the Communist Party of China finally overthrew imperialism, feudalism and bureaucrat-capitalism, and founded the People’s Republic of China. This transitioned from a new democratic society to a socialist society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: The National People’s Congress Article 57
The National People’s Congress (NPC) of the PRC is the highest state organ of power. Its permanent organ is the NPC Standing Committee.
Article 58 The NPC and the NPC Standing Committee exercise the legislative power of the state.
Article 59 The NPC shall be composed of deputies elected from the provinces, autonomous regions, cities directly under central government jurisdiction, special administrativeregions and armed forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Central Military Commission</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2c/</guid>
      <description>Article 93
The Central Military Commission leads the country’s armed forces.
It is composed of:
 a chairperson vice chairpersons members.  It follows a chairperson responsibility system and shall have the same term of office as that of the NPC.
Article 94
The chairperson of the Central Military Commission shall be responsible to the NPC and the NPC Standing Committee.
Section 5
Local People’s Congresses at All levels and Local People’s Governments at All Levels</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The President of the PRC</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>Article 79
The president and the vice president of the PRC shall be elected by the NPC.
Citizens of the PRC who have the right to vote and stand for election and who have reached the age of 45 are eligible for election as president or vice president of the PRC.
The president and the vice president of the PRC shall have the same term of office as that of the NPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/cn/chapter-2d/</guid>
      <description>Section 6 Autonomous Organs of Ethnic Autonomous Areas
Article 112The autonomous organs of ethnic autonomous areas are the people’s congresses and the people’s governments of autonomous regions, autonomous prefectures and autonomous counties.
Article 113In the people’s congresses of autonomous regions, autonomous prefectures and autonomous counties, aside from deputies of the ethnic group that exercises regional autonomy, other ethnic groups resident in that administrative area should also have an appropriate number of deputies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
