<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Buddhist Economics Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/buddhist-economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Buddhist Economics Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/buddhist-economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Consumption</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/buddhist-economics/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/buddhist-economics/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Buddhist Economics focuses on optimal consumption, Economics focuses on optimal production Buddhist economics tries to maximise human satisfactions by the optimal pattern of consumption.
Modern economics tries to maximise consumption through the optimal pattern of production.
A life which aims for the optimal consumption will need less effort than a life which aims for maximum consumption.
 Therefore, it is not surprising that the pressure and strain of living is very much less in Burma than in the US, despite the US having so much more labour-saving machinery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Buddhist Concept of Work</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/buddhist-economics/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/buddhist-economics/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Superphysics note: This is a simplified version of Buddhist Economics      Modern Economics Buddhist Economics     Motive Maximize Consumption in order to maximize Production Minimuze Consumption in order to make Production sustainable   Priority Material Development Human Development   Employment Maximization of Employment for Maximized Production Full Employment (Mothers can leave work to care for their children)   Energy Use High Low   Environmental Policy Exploit Natural Resources Conserve Natural Resources   Spirituality None High    “Right Livelihood” is one of the requirements of the Buddha’s Noble Eightfold Path.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
