<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 4 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 4 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Philosophy of Aristotle -- Matter</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/section-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/section-3/</guid>
      <description>Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Original Substance as a Universal Identity Several moralists have recommended it as an excellent method of=
 becoming acquainted with our own hearts, and knowing our progress in virtue= to recollect our dreams in a morning, and examine them with the same rigour that we would apply on our most serious actions.  They say that our character=
 is the same throughout, and appears best where=  artifice, fear, and policy have no place, and men can neither be hypocrites with themselves nor others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hume&#39;s Physics: Identity and Space for that Identity to Exist</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/section-4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/section-4b/</guid>
      <description>Hume&amp;rsquo;s Primary Qualities of the Material Universe: Space and Identity If we remove the sounds, colours, heat, cold, and other sensible qualities of an external object, then we only are left with &amp;lsquo;primary qualities&amp;rsquo;.
Primary qualities are the only real ones which we have any adequate notion of. These primary qualities are space and identity, with their different mixtures and modifications; shape, motion, gravity, and cohesion.
The following are merely changes of shape and motion=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philosophy of Descartes -- Imagination</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/section-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/treatise/book-1/part-4/section-4/</guid>
      <description>Descartes has an Irregular Imagination I am unjust in blaming the for:
 using the imagination, and allowing themselves to be entirely guided by the imagination in their reasonings.  There are two kinds of imagination:
 the imagination based on permanent, irresistible, and universal principles  Examples are the habitual transition from causes to effects, and from effects to causes. These are the foundation of all our thoughts and actions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
