<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Bhagavad Gita on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Bhagavad Gita on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Bhagavad-Gita</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>(From the Mahabharata)
Being a Discourse Between Arjuna, Prince of India, and the Supreme Being Under the Form of Krishna
Translated from the Sanskrit Text by Sir Edwin Arnold, New York 1900
Dedication
TO INDIA
So have I read this wonderful and spirit-thrilling speech, By Krishna and Prince Arjun held, discoursing each with each; So have I writ its wisdom here,&amp;ndash;its hidden mystery, For England; O our India! as dear to me as She!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bhagavad-Gita</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Sanjaya.
He was filled with such compassion and grief.
Krishna Why did you grow weak? Cast off cowardice! Wake up!  Arjuna How could I shoot with shafts in the battle?
It is better to live on beggar&amp;rsquo;s bread with those we love alive, than survive with them dead.
 Sanjaya: Arjuna became silent.
Krishna You grieve when you should not be grireving!
You lacking wisdom! The wise in heart mourn not for those who live, nor those who die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bhagavad-Gita</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Arjuna.
Thou whom all mortals praise, Janardana!
If meditation be a nobler thing than action, wherefore, then, great Kesava! Dost thou impel me to this dreadful fight? Now am I by thy doubtful speech disturbed! Tell me one thing, and tell me certainly; By what road shall I find the better end?
Krishna.
There are 2 paths, 2 schools of wisdom.
  The Sankhya&amp;rsquo;s, which doth save in way of works Prescribed[FN#4] by reason</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bhagavad-Gita</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Krishna.
This deathless Yoga, this deep union, I taught Vivaswata,[FN#6] the Lord of Light; Vivaswata gave it to Manu who gave it to Ikshwaku.
In time, the truth grew dim and perished.
I have reincarnated many times.
Maya is my magic which I stamp on floating Nature-forms.
I come, and go, and come.
When Righteousness declines, I rise, from age to age, and take Visible shape, and move a man with men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bhagavad-Gita</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Arjuna.
Yet, Krishna! at the one time thou dost laud Surcease of works, and, at another time, Service through work. Of these twain plainly tell Which is the better way? Krishna. To cease from works Is well, and to do works in holiness Is well; and both conduct to bliss supreme; But of these twain the better way is his Who working piously refraineth not. That is the true Renouncer, firm and fixed, Who&amp;ndash;seeking nought, rejecting nought&amp;ndash;dwells proof Against the &amp;ldquo;opposites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Yogi or Sanyasi</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>A Yogi and Sanyasi does rightful work, not seeking gain from it.
And he is neither who lights not the flame Of sacrifice, nor setteth hand to task.
Regard as true Renouncer him that makes
Worship by work, for who renounceth not Works not as Yogin. So is that well said:
&amp;ldquo;By works the votary doth rise to faith, And saintship is the ceasing from all works; Because the perfect Yogin acts&amp;ndash;but acts Unmoved by passions and unbound by deeds, Setting result aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Yogi or Sanyasi</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>Learn now, dear Prince! how, if thy soul be set Ever on Me&amp;ndash;still exercising Yog,
Still making Me thy Refuge&amp;ndash;thou shalt come Most surely unto perfect hold of Me.
I will declare to thee that utmost lore, Whole and particular, which, when thou knowest, Leaveth no more to know here in this world.
Of many thousand mortals, one strives for Truth. Of those few who strive, one only knows me as the very Truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER VIII
Arjuna. Who is that BRAHMA? What that Soul of Souls, The ADHYATMAN? What, Thou Best of All! Thy work, the KARMA? Tell me what it is Thou namest ADHIBHUTA? What again Means ADHIDAIVA? Yea, and how it comes Thou canst be ADHIYAJNA in thy flesh? Slayer of Madhu! Further, make me know How good men find thee in the hour of death? Krishna. I BRAHMA am! the One Eternal GOD, And ADHYATMAN is My Being&amp;rsquo;s name, The Soul of Souls!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER IX
Krishna.
Now will I open unto thee&amp;ndash;whose heart Rejects not&amp;ndash;that last lore, deepest-concealed, That farthest secret of My Heavens and Earths, Which but to know shall set thee free from ills,&amp;ndash; A royal lore! a Kingly mystery! Yea! for the soul such light as purgeth it From every sin; a light of holiness With inmost splendour shining; plain to see; Easy to walk by, inexhaustible! They that receive not this, failing in faith To grasp the greater wisdom, reach not Me, Destroyer of thy foes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER X Krishna.[FN#l6] Hear farther yet, thou Long-Armed Lord! these latest words I say&amp;ndash; Uttered to bring thee bliss and peace, who lovest Me alway&amp;ndash; Not the great company of gods nor kingly Rishis know My Nature, Who have made the gods and Rishis long ago; He only knoweth-only he is free of sin, and wise, Who seeth Me, Lord of the Worlds, with faith-enlightened eyes, Unborn, undying, unbegun. Whatever Natures be To mortal men distributed, those natures spring from Me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 11
Arjuna. This, for my soul&amp;rsquo;s peace, have I heard from Thee, The unfolding of the Mystery Supreme Named Adhyatman; comprehending which, My darkness is dispelled; for now I know&amp;ndash; O Lotus-eyed![FN#21]&amp;ndash;whence is the birth of men, And whence their death, and what the majesties Of Thine immortal rule. Fain would I see, As thou Thyself declar&amp;rsquo;st it, Sovereign Lord! The likeness of that glory of Thy Form Wholly revealed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XII Arjuna. Lord! of the men who serve Thee&amp;ndash;true in heart&amp;ndash; As God revealed; and of the men who serve, Worshipping Thee Unrevealed, Unbodied, Far, Which take the better way of faith and life? Krishna. Whoever serve Me&amp;ndash;as I show Myself&amp;ndash; Constantly true, in full devotion fixed, Those hold I very holy. But who serve&amp;ndash; Worshipping Me The One, The Invisible, The Unrevealed, Unnamed, Unthinkable, Uttermost, All-pervading, Highest, Sure&amp;ndash; Who thus adore Me, mastering their sense, Of one set mind to all, glad in all good, These blessed souls come unto Me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 13
Arjuna. Now would I hear, O gracious Kesava![FN#26] Of Life which seems, and Soul beyond, which sees, And what it is we know-or think to know. Krishna. Yea! Son of Kunti! for this flesh ye see Is Kshetra, is the field where Life disports; And that which views and knows it is the Soul, Kshetrajna. In all &amp;ldquo;fields,&amp;rdquo; thou Indian prince! I am Kshetrajna. I am what surveys! Only that knowledge knows which knows the known By the knower!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XIV Krishna. Yet farther will I open unto thee This wisdom of all wisdoms, uttermost, The which possessing, all My saints have passed To perfectness. On such high verities Reliant, rising into fellowship With Me, they are not born again at birth Of Kalpas, nor at Pralyas suffer change! This Universe the womb is where I plant Seed of all lives! Thence, Prince of India, comes Birth to all beings!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XV
Krishna. Men call the Aswattha,&amp;ndash;the Banyan-tree,&amp;ndash; Which hath its boughs beneath, its roots above,&amp;ndash; The ever-holy tree. Yea! for its leaves Are green and waving hymns which whisper Truth! Who knows the Aswattha, knows Veds, and all. Its branches shoot to heaven and sink to earth,[FN#30] Even as the deeds of men, which take their birth From qualities: its silver sprays and blooms, And all the eager verdure of its girth, Leap to quick life at kiss of sun and air, As men&amp;rsquo;s lives quicken to the temptings fair Of wooing sense: its hanging rootlets seek The soil beneath, helping to hold it there, As actions wrought amid this world of men Bind them by ever-tightening bonds again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 16
Krishna. Fearlessness, singleness of soul, the will Always to strive for wisdom; opened hand And governed appetites; and piety, And love of lonely study; humbleness, Uprightness, heed to injure nought which lives, Truthfulness, slowness unto wrath, a mind That lightly letteth go what others prize; And equanimity, and charity Which spieth no man&amp;rsquo;s faults; and tenderness Towards all that suffer; a contented heart, Fluttered by no desires; a bearing mild, Modest, and grave, with manhood nobly mixed, With patience, fortitude, and purity; An unrevengeful spirit, never given To rate itself too high;&amp;ndash;such be the signs, O Indian Prince!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER XVII
Arjuna.
If men forsake the holy ordinance, Heedless of Shastras, yet keep faith at heart And worship, what shall be the state of those, Great Krishna! Sattwan, Rajas, Tamas? Say! Krishna. Threefold the faith is of mankind and springs From those three qualities,&amp;ndash;becoming &amp;ldquo;true,&amp;rdquo; Or &amp;ldquo;passion-stained,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;dark,&amp;rdquo; as thou shalt hear! The faith of each believer, Indian Prince! Conforms itself to what he truly is. Where thou shalt see a worshipper, that one To what he worships lives assimilate, [Such as the shrine, so is the votary,] The &amp;ldquo;soothfast&amp;rdquo; souls adore true gods; the souls Obeying Rajas worship Rakshasas[FN#34] Or Yakshas; and the men of Darkness pray To Pretas and to Bhutas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/gita/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 18
Arjuna. Fain would I better know, Thou Glorious One! The very truth&amp;ndash;Heart&amp;rsquo;s Lord!&amp;ndash;of Sannyas, Abstention; and enunciation, Lord! Tyaga; and what separates these twain! Krishna. The poets rightly teach that Sannyas Is the foregoing of all acts which spring Out of desire; and their wisest say Tyaga is renouncing fruit of acts. There be among the saints some who have held All action sinful, and to be renounced; And some who answer, &amp;ldquo;Nay!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
