<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dynasties, Royal Authority on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dynasties, Royal Authority on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Royal Authority Comes Only from Group Feeling</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-01/</guid>
      <description>This is because aggressive and defensive strength is obtained only through group feeling which means (mutual) affection and willingness to fight and die for each other.
Royal authority is a noble and enjoyable position. It comprises all the good things of the world, the pleasures of the body, and the joys of the soul.
Therefore, there is, as a rule, great competition for it. It rarely is handed over (voluntarily), but it may be taken away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religious propaganda adds to group feeling</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-05/</guid>
      <description>5. Religious propaganda gives a dynasty at its beginning more power This is because religious coloring does away with mutual jealousy and envy among people who share in a group feeling, and causes concentration upon the truth.
When people (who have a religious coloring) come to have the (right) insight into their affairs, nothing can withstand them, because their outlook is one and their object one of common accord.
They are willing to die for (their objectives).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political power relies on the feelings of supporters</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-08/</guid>
      <description>8. The greatness, territorial size, and length of a dynasty depend on the numbers of its supporters. This is because royal authority exists only through group feeling.
Representatives of group feeling are the militiamen who settle in the territories of the dynasty. The more numerous the tribes and groups of a large dynasty, the stronger and larger are its and lands. Their royal authority, therefore, is wider.
An example of this was the Muslim dynasty when God united the power of the Arabs in Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nature of Royal Authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-10/</guid>
      <description>10. By its very nature, the royal authority claims all glory for itself and goes in for luxury and prefers peace This is because the group feeling that leads to royal authority is a composite of the amalgamation of many groups, one of which is stronger than all the others.
Thus, a group feeling is able to overcome and gain power over all the others. Eventually, it brings them all under its sway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Progress of Royal Authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-11/</guid>
      <description>11. The dynasty becomes senile after it claims all glory for itself and establishes luxury and tranquility This can be explained in several ways.
 The royal authority, by its very nature, must claim all glory for itself.  As long as glory was the common (property) of the group, and all members of the group made an identical effort (to obtain glory), their aspirations to gain the upper hand over others and to defend their own possessions were expressed in exemplary unruliness and lack of restraint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Barbarity to Civilization</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-13/</guid>
      <description>These stages are natural ones for dynasties. The superiority through which royal authority is achieved is the result of group feeling and of the great energy and rapacious habits which go with it. As a rule, these things are possible only in connection with desert life.
The first stage of dynasties, therefore, is that of desert life. When royal authority is obtained, it is accompanied by a life of ease and increased opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monuments to Dynasties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-16/</guid>
      <description>16. The monuments of a given dynasty are proportionate to its original power This is because monuments owe their origin to the power that brought the dynasty into being. The impression the dynasty leaves is proportionate to (that power).
The monuments of a dynasty are its buildings and large (edifices, haykal). They are proportionate to the original power of the dynasty. They can materialize only when there are many workers and united action and cooperation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ruler&#39;s Supporters</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-17/</guid>
      <description>17. The ruler seeks the help of clients and followers against the men of his own people and group feeling. A ruler can achieve power only with the help of his own people. They are his group and his helpers in his enterprise.
He uses them to fight against those who revolt against his dynasty. He fills the administrative offices with them as his wazirs and tax collectors, helping him achieve superiority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Character of Royal Authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-20/</guid>
      <description>20. Those who gain power over the ruler do not share with him in the special title that goes with royal authority This is because the first men to achieve royal and governmental authority at the beginning of the dynasty do so with the help of the group feeling of their people and with the help of their own group feeling which causes their people to follow (them) until they and their people have definitely adopted the coloring of royal authority and superiority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Police</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32e/</guid>
      <description>The police 512 In Ifriqiyah, the chief of police is now called the &amp;ldquo;magistrate&amp;rdquo; (hakim).
In Spain, he is called the &amp;ldquo;town chief&amp;rdquo; (sahib al-madinah).
In the Turkish dynasty in Egypt, he is called the &amp;ldquo;governor&amp;rdquo; (wali).
It subordinate to the person in charge of &amp;ldquo;the sword&amp;rdquo; in the dynasty, who at times uses the chief of police to execute his orders.
This was originally created by the &amp;lsquo;Abbasid dynasty. The person who held it had a twofold duty:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shia</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-25/</guid>
      <description>25. Shi&amp;rsquo;ah tenets on the question of the imamate. Linguistically, Shi&amp;rsquo;ah means &amp;ldquo;companions and followers.&amp;rdquo;
In the customary usage of old and modern jurists and speculative theologians, &amp;lsquo;Shiah&amp;rsquo; is used for the followers and descendants of All. The tenet on which they all agree is that the imamate is not a general (public) interest to be delegated to the Muslim nation for consideration and appointment of a person to fill it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transformation of the caliphate into royal authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-26/</guid>
      <description>Royal authority is the natural goal of group feeling. It results from group feeling, not by choice but through (inherent) necessity and the order of existence, as we have stated before.287 All religious laws and practices and everything that the masses are expected to do requires group feeling.
Only with the help of group feeling can a claim be successfully pressed, as we have stated before. 288
Group feeling is necessary to the Muslim community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of the oath of allegiance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-27/</guid>
      <description>The bay&amp;rsquo;ah (oath of allegiance) is a contract to render obedience.
It is as though the person who renders the oath of allegiance made a contract with his amir, to the effect that he surrenders supervision of his own affairs and those of the Muslims to him and that he will not contest his authority in any of (those affairs) and that he will obey him by (executing) all the duties with which he might be charged, whether agreeable or disagreeable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The succession</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-28a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-28a/</guid>
      <description>The caliph is the guardian and trustee of the Muslims. He looks after them as long as he lives. It follows that he should also look after their (affairs) after his death, and, therefore, should appoint someone to take charge of their affairs as he had done (while alive), whom they can trust to look after them as they had trusted him then.
Such appointment of a successor) is recognized as part of the religious law through the consensus of the (Muslim) nation, (which says) that it is permissible and binding when it occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of the oath of allegiance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-28b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-28b/</guid>
      <description>Differences of the sort in Islam include those:
 between Ali on the one hand, and Mu&amp;rsquo;awiyah, as well as az-Zubayr, Talhah, and &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo;ishah on the other, between al-Husayn and Yazid, and between Ibn az-Zubayr and &amp;lsquo;Abd-al-Malik.  Ali When &amp;lsquo;Uthman was killed, the important Muslims were dispersed over the various cities. They were not present when the oath of allegiance was rendered to &amp;lsquo;Ali.
 Of those who were present, some rendered the oath of allegiance to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ministry of financial operations and taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32c/</guid>
      <description>The ministry (diwan) of (financial) operations and taxation The ministry of taxation is is concerned with tax operations and guards the rights of the dynasty in the matters of income and expenditures. It takes a census of the names of all soldiers, fixes their salaries, and pays out their allowances at the proper times.
In this connection recourse is had to rules set up by the chiefs of (tax) operations and the stewards of the dynasty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The religious functions of the caliphate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-29a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-29a/</guid>
      <description>To be caliph in reality means acting as substitute for Muhammad with regard to the preservation of the religion and the political leadership of the world.
Muhammad was concerned with both things, with religion in his capacity as the person commanded to transmit the duties imposed by the religious laws to the people and to cause them to act in accordance with them, and with worldly political leadership in his capacity as the person in charge of the (public) interests of human civilization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police: The religious functions of the caliphate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-29b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-29b/</guid>
      <description>The police In the &amp;lsquo;Abbasid dynasty and in the dynasties of the Umayyads in Spain and under the &amp;lsquo;Ubaydid(-Fatimids) in Egypt and the Maghrib, the control of crimes and imposition of punishments required by the religious law was also a special (task) and was delegated to the chief of police (sahib ashshurtah). 380
The police is another religious function that under these dynasties belonged to the positions connected with the religious law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The position of official witness (adalah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-29c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-29c/</guid>
      <description>This is a religious position depending on the office of judge and connected with court practice. The men who hold it give testimony-with the judge&amp;rsquo;s permission-for or against people&amp;rsquo;s (claims). They serve as witnesses when testimony is to be taken, testify during a lawsuit, and fill in the registers which record the rights, possessions, and debts of people and other (legal) transactions. This is the significance of the position.
I say &amp;ldquo;the judge&amp;rsquo;s permission&amp;rdquo; because people may have become confused, and (then) only the judge knows who is reliable and who not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Caliph&#39;s title of &#39;Commander of the Faithful&#39;</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-30/</guid>
      <description>This was created in the period of the first four caliphs. This is because the men around Muhammad and all the other early Muslims called Abu Bakr, when he received the oath of allegiance, &amp;ldquo;representative&amp;rdquo; (khalifah, caliph) of the Messenger of God. This form (of address) was used until he died.
Then, the oath of allegiance was rendered to &amp;lsquo;Umar who was appointed by (Abu Bakr), and people called &amp;lsquo;Umar &amp;ldquo;Representative of the Representative of the Messenger of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ministry of official correspondence and writing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32d/</guid>
      <description>The ministry (diwan) of (official) correspondence and writing This office is not required by the nature of royal authority. Many dynasties were able to dispense with it completely, such as the dynasties rooted in the desert.
In the Muslim dynasty, the Arabic language situation and the custom of expressing what one wanted to express in good form intensified the need for the office.
Thus, writing came to convey, as a rule, the essence of a matter in better stylistic form than was possible in oral expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pope and Patriarch</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-31/</guid>
      <description>In the Christian religion and on the word &amp;ldquo;Kohen&amp;rdquo; used by the Jews.
After the removal of its prophet, a religious group must have someone to take care of it. (Such a person) must cause the people to act according to the religious laws. In a way, he stands to them in the place (khalifah, caliph) of their prophet, in as much as (he urges) the obligations which (the prophet) had imposed upon them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ranks and titles of royal and governmental authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32/</guid>
      <description>By himself, the ruler is weak. He carries a heavy load and needs help from others for his necessities and much more to:
 exercise political leadership defend his subjects restrain the people in order to prevent mutual hostility and attacks upon property.  This includes:
 improving the safety of the roads letting the people act in their own best interests supervising such general matters involving their livelihood and mutual dealings as foodstuffs and weights and measures, in order to prevent cheating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wazir</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-32b/</guid>
      <description>Afterwards, royal authority flourished. The (official) councilor and assistant for tribal and group affairs and good relations (with the various tribes and groups) made his appearance. For him, the name of wazir was used.
Bookkeeping remained in the hands of clients, Jews, and Christians. For (official) documents, a special secretary was appointed, as a precaution against possible publication of the ruler&amp;rsquo;s secrets, something that would be disastrous to his role as political leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The different importance of the ranks of the sword and the pen</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33/</guid>
      <description>Both &amp;ldquo;the sword&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;the pen&amp;rdquo; are instruments for the ruler to use in his affairs. However, at the beginning of the dynasty, so long as its people are occupied in establishing power, the need for &amp;ldquo;the sword&amp;rdquo; is greater than that for &amp;ldquo;the pen.&amp;rdquo; In that situation, &amp;ldquo;the pen&amp;rdquo; is merely a servant and agent of the ruler&amp;rsquo;s authority, whereas &amp;ldquo;the sword&amp;rdquo; contributes active assistance.
The same is the case at the end of the dynasty when its group feeling weakens, and its people decrease in number under the influence of senility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The methods of waging war practiced by various nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-35/</guid>
      <description>The origin of war is the desire of certain human beings to take revenge on others. Each (party) is supported by the people sharing in its group feeling.
When they have sufficiently excited each other for the purpose and the two parties confront each other, one seeking revenge and the other trying to defend itself, there is war. It is something natural among human beings.
No nation and no race is free from it because revenge comes from jealousy, hostility, or zeal in behalf of God, or zeal in behalf of royal authority and the effort to found a kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33b/</guid>
      <description>The mint 563 This is concerned with the stamping of the dinars and dirhams used in commercial transactions. This is done with a die of iron, upon which pictures or words are engraved in reverse. The stamp is pressed upon the dinar or the dirham, and the designs (legends) of those engravings appear on the coin clearly and correctly. Before this is done, the standard of purity of the particular coin, the result of repeated refinings, is taken into consideration, and the individual dinars and dirhams are given the proper, fixed weight that has been agreed upon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to the ruler becomes restricted in a dynasty growing senile</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-43/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning, the dynasty is remote from royal aspirations.
It needs group feeling through which its power and domination can materialize, and the desert attitude is characteristic of group feeling.
A dynasty based upon religion is remote from royal aspirations. In one based exclusively upon superior (political) power, the desert attitude, through which superiority is achieved, likewise is remote from royal aspirations and ways. Now, if a dynasty at the beginning of its rule is a Bedouin one, the ruler possesses austerity and the desert attitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial activity on the part of the ruler is harmful to his subjects and ruinous to the tax revenue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-38/</guid>
      <description>A dynasty may find itself in financial trouble because of its luxury and high expenditures and the insufficiency of the tax revenue to pay them.
So it imposes customs duties on the commercial activities of its subjects. Sometimes, it tortures its officials and tax collectors and sucks their bones dry (of a part of their fortune). (This happens) when officials and tax collectors are observed to have appropriated a good deal of tax money, which their accounts do not show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting the future of dynasties and nations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-52/</guid>
      <description>52. Forecasting the future of dynasties and nations This includes a discussion of predictions (malahim) and an exposition of the subject called &amp;ldquo;divination&amp;rdquo; (jafr)
This innate desire to know future is especially great with important events. People want to know, for instance, how long the world or certain dynasties are going to last. Towns have a group of people who strive to make a living out of predicting the future because they know that the people are most eager to know it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a New Dynasty Begins</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-47/</guid>
      <description>47. How a new dynasty originates When the ruling dynasty starts on the road to senility and destruction, the rise of the new dynasty happens in 2 ways:
 The provincial governors in the old dynasty to gain control over remote regions when (the dynasty) loses its influence there.  Each one of them founds a new dynasty for his people and a realm to be perpetuated in his family. His children or clients inherit it from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Once senility has come upon a dynasty, it cannot be made to disappear</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-44/</guid>
      <description>Senility is a chronic disease that cannot be cured or made to disappear because it is something natural, and natural things do not change.
Many a politically conscious person among the people of the dynasty becomes alert to it and notices the symptoms and causes of senility that have affected his dynasty. He considers it possible to make that senility disappear.
Therefore, he takes it upon himself to repair the dynasty and relieve its temper of senility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police: The religious functions of the caliphate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-49/</guid>
      <description>49. There is an abundant civilization (large population) at the end of dynasties, and pestilences and famines frequently occur then. At the beginning, dynasties are inevitably kind in the exercise of their power and just in their administration. The reason is either their religion, when (the dynasty) is based upon religious propaganda, or their noble and benevolent attitude toward others, which is required by the desert attitude that is natural to dynasties (at the beginning).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police: The religious functions of the caliphate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-51/</guid>
      <description>51. The truth about the Fatimid At the end of time a man from the family (of the Prophet) will without fail make his appearance, one who will strengthen the religion and make justice triumph. The Muslims will follow him, and he will gain domination over the Muslim realm.
He will be called the Mahdi. Following him, the Antichrist will appear, together with all the subsequent signs of the Hour (the Day of Judgment), as established in (the sound tradition of) the Sahih.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The differences of opinion on the Caliphate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-24/</guid>
      <description>24. The differences of Muslim opinion concerning the laws and conditions governing the caliphate The institution called &amp;ldquo;the Caliphate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;imamate&amp;rdquo; substitutes for Muhammad in as much as it serves, like him, to preserve the religion and to exercise (political) leadership of the world.
Its leader is &amp;ldquo;the caliph&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;the imam.&amp;rdquo; In later times, he has also been called &amp;ldquo;the sultan,&amp;rdquo; when there were numerous (claimants to the position) or when, in view of the distances (separating the different regions) and in disregard of the conditions governing the institution, people were forced to render the oath of allegiance to anybody who seized power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dynasty&#39;s authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-46/</guid>
      <description>At first, it expands to its limit. Then it is narrowed down in successive stages, until the dynasty dissolves 713
Chapter 3 stated that each dynasty has its specific share of provinces and districts and no more. 715 Its expansion depends 716 on the distribution of the dynasty&amp;rsquo;s group (strength) for the (military) protection of its territory and regions.
Wherever its numbers go, their advance (eventually) comes to a stop at (what is called) the &amp;ldquo;border region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The reason for low and high tax revenues</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-36/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of the dynasty, taxation yields a large revenue from small assessments. At the end of the dynasty, taxation yields a small revenue from large assessments.
This is because when the dynasty follows the ways (sunan) of the religion, it imposes only such taxes as are stipulated by the religious law, such as charity taxes, the land tax, and the poll tax. They mean small assessments, because, as everyone knows, the charity tax on property 649 is low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The reduction of the allowances given by the ruler reduces the tax revenue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-40/</guid>
      <description>Dynasty and government serve as the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest marketplace, 674 providing the substance of civilization.
If the ruler holds on to property and revenue, or if they are lost or not properly used by him, then the property in the possession of the ruler&amp;rsquo;s entourage 675 will be small.
The gifts which they, in their turn, had been used to give to their entourage and people, stop, and all their expenditures are cut down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ruler and his entourage are wealthy only in the dynasty&#39;s middle period</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-39/</guid>
      <description>At the start of the dynasty, the revenues are distributed among the tribe 659 and the people who share in the ruler&amp;rsquo;s group feeling, in accordance with their usefulness and group feeling and because they are needed to establish the dynasty, as we have stated before. 660
Under these circumstances, their leader refrains in their favor from (claiming) the revenues which they would like to have. He feels compensated for (his restraint) by the control over them that he hopes to establish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seal</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33c/</guid>
      <description>The use of the seal is one of the government functions and a royal office.
The sealing of letters and diplomas was known to rulers before and after Islam. It has been established in the two Sahihs that when the Prophet wanted to write to the Byzantine Emperor, he was told that the non-Arabs accepted only sealed letters.
Thus, he took a silver seal (ring) and had the following legend engraved upon it: &amp;ldquo;Muhammad, the Messenger of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tiraz</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-3/part-33d/</guid>
      <description>It is part of royal and governmental pomp and dynastic custom to have the names of rulers or their peculiar marks embroidered on the silk, brocade, or pure silk garments that they wear.
The writing is done by weaving a gold or colored thread different from the fabric&amp;rsquo;s color. It depends on the skill of the weavers.
Royal garments are embroidered with such a tiraz, in order:
 to increase the prestige of the ruler or some other person the ruler distinguishes  The pre-Islamic non-Arab rulers used to make a tiraz of pictures and figures of kings, or (other) figures and pictures specifically (designed) for it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
