<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 7 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 7 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being and Unity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-16/</guid>
      <description>Even of the things that are thought to be substances, most are only potentialities.
Both the parts of animals (for none of them exists separately; and when they are separated, then too they exist, all of them, merely as matter) and earth and fire and air; for none of them is a unity, but as it were a mere heap, till they are worked up and some unity is made out of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Aristotle Misunderstands Forms</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-8/</guid>
      <description>Anything which is produced is produced by something (the starting-point of the production).
I make a brazen sphere from a mold with a sphere shape. The mold is my form and substratum. It is different from the brass. We must then make the mold out of something else. Then we need to make that something else. This leads to infinity.
If follows that the form or shape of the thing is not produced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Comings to Be</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-7/</guid>
      <description>Of things that come to be, some come to be by nature, some by art, some spontaneously. Now everything that comes to be comes to be by the agency of something and from something and comes to be something. And the something which I say it comes to be may be found in any category; it may come to be either a &amp;rsquo;this&amp;rsquo; or of some size or of some quality or somewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 11</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-11/</guid>
      <description>What sort of parts belong to the Form and what sort not to the form, but to the concrete thing?
Yet if this is not plain it is not possible to define any thing; for definition is of the universal and of the form.
If then it is not evident what sort of parts are of the nature of matter and what sort are not, neither will the formula of the thing be evident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 12</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-12/</guid>
      <description>What is the unity of the formula of a definition? The formula for a man is a &amp;rsquo;two-footed animal&#39;.
Why, then, is this one, and not many, viz. &amp;lsquo;animal&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;two-footed&amp;rsquo;?
For in the case of &amp;lsquo;man&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;pale&amp;rsquo; there is a plurality when one term does not belong to the other, but a unity when it does belong and the subject, man, has a certain attribute; for then a unity is produced and we have &amp;rsquo;the pale man&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 13</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-13/</guid>
      <description>The substratum and the essence and the compound of these are called substance, so also is the universal.
About two of these we have spoken; both about the essence and about the substratum, of which we have said that it underlies in two senses, either being a &amp;rsquo;this&amp;rsquo;-which is the way in which an animal underlies its attributes-or as the matter underlies the complete reality.
The universal also is thought by some to be in the fullest sense a cause, and a principle; therefore let us attack the discussion of this point also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 14</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-14/</guid>
      <description>These very facts what consequence confronts those who say the Ideas are substances capable of separate existence, and at the same time make the Form consist of the genus and the differentiae. For if the Forms exist and &amp;lsquo;animal&amp;rsquo; is present in &amp;lsquo;man&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;horse&amp;rsquo;, it is either one and the same in number, or different. (In formula it is clearly one; for he who states the formula will go through the formula in either case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 15</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-15/</guid>
      <description>Substance is of two kinds:
 the concrete thing the formula  (I mean that one kind of substance is the formula taken with the matter, while another kind is the formula in its generality), substances in the former sense are capable of destruction (for they are capable also of generation), but there is no destruction of the formula in the sense that it is ever in course of being destroyed (for there is no generation of it either; the being of house is not generated, but only the being of this house), but without generation and destruction formulae are and are not; for it has been shown that no one begets nor makes these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 6</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Is each thing and its essence are the same or different?
This is of some use for the inquiry concerning substance; for each thing is thought to be not different from its substance, and the essence is said to be the substance of each thing.
In the case of accidental unities the two would be generally thought to be different, e.g. white man would be thought to be different from the essence of white man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 9</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-9/</guid>
      <description>Why are some things are produced spontaneously as well as by art?
e.g. health, while others are not, e.g. a house.
The reason is that in some cases the matter which governs the production in the making and producing of any work of art, and in which a part of the product is present,-some matter is such as to be set in motion by itself and some is not of this nature, and of the former kind some can move itself in the particular way required, while other matter is incapable of this; for many things can be set in motion by themselves but not in some particular way, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The formula for things</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-10/</guid>
      <description>A definition is a formula. Every formula has parts. The formula to the thing is the part of the formula to the part of the thing.
Must the formula of the parts be present in the formula of the whole or not?
For in some cases the formulae of the parts are seen to be present, and in some not. The formula of the circle does not include that of the segments, but that of the syllable includes that of the letters; yet the circle is divided into segments as the syllable is into letters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Be</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-1/</guid>
      <description>THERE are several senses in which a thing may be said to &amp;lsquo;be&amp;rsquo;
In one sense the &amp;lsquo;being&amp;rsquo; meant is &amp;lsquo;what a thing is&amp;rsquo; or a &amp;rsquo;this&amp;rsquo;
In another sense it means a quality or quantity or one of the other things that are predicated as these are.
While &amp;lsquo;being&amp;rsquo; has all these senses, obviously that which &amp;lsquo;is&amp;rsquo; primarily is the &amp;lsquo;what&amp;rsquo;, which indicates the substance of the thing. For when we say of what quality a thing is, we say that it is good or bad, not that it is three cubits long or that it is a man; but when we say what it is, we do not say &amp;lsquo;white&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;hot&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;three cubits long&amp;rsquo;, but &amp;lsquo;a man&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;a &amp;lsquo;god&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Essence?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-4/</guid>
      <description>What is essence?
The essence of each thing is what is to be propter se. For being you is not being musical, since you are not by your very nature musical. What, then, you are by your very nature is your essence.
&amp;ldquo;Nor yet is the whole of this the essence of a thing; not that which is propter se as white is to a surface, because being a surface is not identical with being white.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Substance?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-7/part-3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The word &amp;lsquo;substance&amp;rsquo; is applied in 4 ways:
 the essence the universal the genus, These are thought to be the substance of each thing, the substratum  Now the substratum is that of which everything else is predicated, while it is itself not predicated of anything else.
What is the nature of the substratum?
In some senses, matter is:
 a substratum a shape the compound of these  By the matter I mean, for instance, the bronze, by the shape the pattern of its form, and by the compound of these the statue, the concrete whole.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
