<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Art of War Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Art of War Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attack by Fire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>There are five ways of attacking with fire.
 Burn soldiers in their camp Burn stores Burn baggage trains Burn arsenals and magazines Hurl dropping fire amongst the enemy  The material for raising fire should always be kept ready.
There is a proper season for making attacks with fire, and special days for starting a conflagration.
 The proper season is when the weather is very dry The special days are those when the moon is in the constellations of the Sieve, the Wall, the Wing or the Cross-bar; for these four are all days of rising wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attack by Stratagem</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>In the practical art of war, the best thing of all is to take the enemy&amp;rsquo;s country whole and intact.
 Shattering and destroying it is not so good. It is better to recapture an army, a regiment, a detachment or a company entire than to destroy it.  Supreme excellence is in breaking the enemy&amp;rsquo;s resistance without fighting. It is not in fighting and conquering in all your battles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Controlling a large force is the same as the controlling a few men. It is merely a question of dividing up their numbers.
Fighting with a large army under your command is not different from fighting with a small one. It is merely a question of instituting signs and signals.
Direct and indirect maneuvers ensure=
 that your whole host may withstand the brunt of the enemy&amp;rsquo;s attack and remain unshaken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laying Plans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>The art of war is of vital importance to the State. It is a matter of life and death. It is governed by five constant factors, to be taken into account in one&amp;rsquo;s deliberations, when seeking to determine the conditions obtaining in the field=
 The Moral Law - this causes the people to be in complete accord with their ruler, so that they will follow him regardless of their lives, undismayed by any danger Heaven - this signifies night and day, cold and heat, times and seasons Earth - this comprises distances, great and small; danger and security; open ground and narrow passes; the chances of life and death The Commander - this stands for the virtues of wisdom, sincerely, benevolence, courage and strictness Method and discipline - these are the marshaling of the army in its proper subdivisions, the graduations of rank among the officers, the maintenance of roads by which supplies may reach the army, and the control of military expenditure  These five should be familiar to every general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maneuvering</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>In war, the general receives his commands from the sovereign.
Having collected an army and concentrated his forces, he must blend and harmonize the different elements thereof before pitching his camp.
 After that, comes tactical maneuvering, than which there is nothing more difficult. The difficulty of tactical maneuvering consists in turning the devious into the direct, and misfortune into gain.
  Thus, to take a long and circuitous route, after enticing the enemy out of the way, and though starting after him, to contrive to reach the goal before him, shows knowledge of the artifice of deviation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong and Weak Points</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>Whoever is first in the field and awaits the coming of the enemy, will be fresh for the fight; whoever is second in the field and has to hasten to battle will arrive exhausted.
Therefore, the clever combatant imposes his will on the enemy, but does not allow the enemy&amp;rsquo;s will to be imposed on him.
By holding out advantages to him, he can cause the enemy to approach of his own accord; or, by inflicting damage, he can make it impossible for the enemy to draw near.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tactical Dispositions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>The good fighters of the past first put themselves beyond the possibility of defeat. Then, they waited for an opportunity of defeating the enemy.
It is up to us to avoid defeat, but the opportunity of defeating the enemy is provided by the enemy himself.
Thus the good fighter is able to secure himself against defeat, but cannot make certain of defeating the enemy.
Hence the saying= One may know how to conquer without being able to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terrain</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>There are six kinds of terrain
   Name Description Strategy     Accessible ground can be freely traversed by both sides occupy the raised and sunny spots before the enemy, to fight with advantage. Carefully guard your line of supplies   Entangling ground can be abandoned but is hard to re-occupy if the enemy is unprepared, you may sally forth and defeat him. But if the enemy is prepared and your attack fails, then it will be disaster   Temporizing ground neither side will gain by making the first move You should retreat to lure the enemy out and then attack him   Narrow passes  garrison this strongly and await the enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nine Situations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>The art of war recognizes nine kinds of ground=
   Ground Description Tactic     Dispersive when a chieftain is fighting in his own territory Do not fight   Facile When he has penetrated into hostile territory, but to no great distance Do not stop   Contentious ground Ground the possession of which imports great advantage to either side Do not attack   Open ground Ground on which each side has liberty of movement do not try to block the enemy&amp;rsquo;s way   Ground of intersecting highways Ground which forms the key to three contiguous states, so that he who occupies it first has most of the Empire at his command join hands with your allies   Serious ground When an army has penetrated into the heart of a hostile country, leaving a number of fortified cities in its rear gather in plunder   Difficult ground Mountain forests, rugged steeps, marshes and fens&amp;ndash;all country that is hard to traverse keep steadily on the march   Hemmed-in ground Ground which is reached through narrow gorges, and from which we can only retire by tortuous paths, so that a small number of the enemy would suffice to crush a large body of our men resort to stratagem   Desperate ground Ground on which we can only be saved from destruction by fighting without delay fight    Those who were called skillful leaders of old knew how to drive a wedge between the enemy&amp;rsquo;s front and rear; to prevent co-operation between his large and small divisions; to hinder the good troops from rescuing the bad, the officers from rallying their men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Spies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Raising an army of 100,000 men and marching them great distances entails heavy loss on the people and a drain on the resources of the State.
The daily expenditure will amount to 1,000 ounces of silver. There will be commotion at home and abroad. Men will drop down exhausted on the highways. As many as 700,000 families will be impeded in their labor.
Hostile armies may face each other for years, striving for the victory which is decided in a single day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variation in Tactics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>In war, the general receives his commands from the sovereign, collects his army and concentrates his forces.
When in difficult country, do not encamp.
In country where high roads intersect, join hands with your allies.
Do not linger in dangerously isolated positions.
In hemmed-in situations, you must resort to stratagem.
In desperate position, you must fight.
There are:
 roads which must not be followed armies which must be not attacked towns which must be besieged positions which must not be contested commands of the sovereign which must not be obeyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variation in Tactics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>When encamping the army, the signs of the enemy should be observed.
 Pass quickly over mountains Keep in the neighborhood of valleys.  Camp in high places, facing the sun.
Do not climb heights in order to fight. After crossing a river, you should get far away from it.
When an invading force crosses a river in its onward march, do not advance to meet it in mid-stream. It will be best to let half the army get across, and then deliver your attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waging War</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sun-tzu/art-of-war/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>The cost of raising an army of 100,000 men is 1,000 ounces of silver per day.
This includes=
 1,000 swift chariots 1,000 heavy chariots 100,000 mail-clad soldiers food for traveling 1,000 li entertainment of guests small items such as glue and paint  If the fighting is prolonged without victory, the men&amp;rsquo;s weapons will grow dull and their ardor will be damped. If you lay siege to a town, you will exhaust your strength.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
