<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Particle Problem in the General Theory of Relativity on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Particle Problem in the General Theory of Relativity on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to fit electricity into General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/part-3/</guid>
      <description>If besides the pure gravitational ﬁeld, other ﬁeld variables are also present, the ﬁeld equations of gravitation are=
Rik—%gikR= &amp;#34;Tile; (4) where T“, is the “material” energy tensor, i.e., that part of the mathematical expression of the energy which does not depend exclusively on the g”. In the case of the phenomenological representation of matter—if it is to be considered as “dust-like,” that is, without pressure—one takes
T”= p(dxi/ds)(dxk/ds), where p is the density-scalar, dxi/ds the velocity—vector of the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wormhole Singularity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/part-1/</guid>
      <description>JULY 1,1935
We investigate the possibility of an atomistic theory of matter and electricity which, while excluding singularities of the ﬁeld, uses only gm of General Relativity and Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s theory.
Through a simple example, these modify slightly the gravitational equations. This then allows regular solutions for the static spherically symmetric case.
These solutions involve the mathematical representation of physical space by a space of two identical sheets which has a particle acting as a “bridge” connecting these sheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Sheets of Spacetime</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/particle-problem/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Schwarzschild found the spherically symmetric static solution of the gravitational equations
ds2 = - (1/1-2m/r) dr2 - r2 (d 2 + sin2 d 2) + (1-2m/r)dt2 (5) (r&amp;gt;2m, θ from 0 to 7r, «5 from 0 to r); the variables x1, x2, x3, x4 are here r, Φ, t.
The vanishing of the determinant of the guv for 0= 0 is unimportant, since the corresponding (spatial) direction is not preferred. On the other hand gm for r=2m becomes inﬁnite and hence we have there a singularity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
