<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politicians on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politicians on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rodrigo Duterte: Benevolent Dictator</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/duterte/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/duterte/</guid>
      <description>In Eastern philosophy, there is no such thing as an absolute good and bad. Instead, &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; is anything that matches one&amp;rsquo;s True Nature, while &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo; is anything that goes against it. This True Nature is called Tao by the Chinese and Dharma by the Indians.
Being in line or in-sync with one&amp;rsquo;s True Nature is called being &amp;lsquo;dharmic&amp;rsquo;, while being out of sync with it is called &amp;lsquo;adharmic&amp;rsquo;. Thus, the moral system derived from this prefers to classify things as dharmic or adharmic instead of good or bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gloria Macapagal-Arroyo: Evil Genius</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/gloria-arroyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/gloria-arroyo/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, we pinpointed the guaranteed collapse of the Philippines to the neoliberal policies of the corrupt Diosdado Macapagal in the early 1960&amp;rsquo;s. He devalued the peso on January 22, 1962 for the sake of easy economic growth. This made borrowing attractive since the currency could be devalued to make debt payments easier at the cost of inflation.
This is what Marcos did to perfection.
If the Philippines of the 1970s were a family with Marcos the father, then he was a father who became so dazzled by foreign money that he sold his house and his children as slaves just to get that money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Andres Bonifacio Should Be The National Hero</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/andres-bonifacio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/politicians/andres-bonifacio/</guid>
      <description>Currently, Jose Rizal is the national hero of the Philippines because of his martyrdom. Compared to the other revolutionaries and nationalists, Rizal was rich and highly educated.
 Unlike Marcelo del Pilar, he did not die of poverty from his activities Unlike Andres Bonifacio, he was able to publish his views extensively  However, the main problem with Rizal was that he did not believe that the Philippines should be fully independent from Spain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
