<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 1987 Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 1987 Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Declaration of Principles and State Policies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 1: National Territory The national territory comprises:
 the Philippine archipelago, with all the islands and waters embraced therein all other territories over which the Philippines has sovereignty or jurisdiction, consisting of its terrestrial, fluvial, and aerial domains, including its:  territorial sea the seabed the subsoil the insular shelves other submarine areas.    The waters around, between, and connecting the islands of the archipelago, regardless of their breadth and dimensions, form part of the internal waters of the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education, Science and Technology, Arts, Culture, and Sports</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-14/</guid>
      <description>Education Section 1. The State shall protect and promote the right of all citizens to quality education at all levels and shall take appropriate steps to make such education accessible to all.
Section 2. The State shall:
 Establish, maintain, and support a complete, adequate, and integrated system of education relevant to the needs of the people and society Establish and maintain a system of free public education in the elementary and high school levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-12b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-12b/</guid>
      <description>Section 12
The State shall promote the preferential use of Filipino labor, domestic materials and locally produced goods, and make them competitive.
Section 13
The State shall pursue a trade policy that serves the general welfare and utilizes all forms and arrangements of exchange on the basis of equality and reciprocity.
Section 14
The sustained development of a reservoir of national talents consisting of Filipino scientists, entrepreneurs, professionals, managers, high-level technical manpower and skilled workers and craftsmen in all fields shall be promoted by the State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Economy and Patrimony</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-12/</guid>
      <description>Article 12 Section 1
The national economy shall aim for:
 a more equitable distribution of opportunities, income, and wealth a sustained increase in the amount of goods and services for the people&amp;rsquo;s benefit an expanding productivity   The State shall promote industrialization and full employment based on sound agricultural development and agrarian reform, through industries that make full and efficient use of human and natural resources, and which are competitive in both domestic and foreign markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Justice and Human Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-13/</guid>
      <description>Section 1
The Congress shall give highest priority to the enactment of measures that protect and enhance the right of all the people to human dignity, reduce social, economic, and political inequalities, and remove cultural inequities by equitably diffusing wealth and political power for the common good.
To this end, the State shall regulate the acquisition, ownership, use, and disposition of property and its increments.
Section 2.
The promotion of social justice shall include the commitment to create economic opportunities based on freedom of initiative and self-reliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Family</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-15/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. The State recognizes the Filipino family as the foundation of the nation. Accordingly, it shall strengthen its solidarity and actively promote its total development.
Section 2. Marriage, as an inviolable social institution, is the foundation of the family and shall be protected by the State.
Section 3. The State shall defend:
(1) The right of spouses to found a family in accordance with their religious convictions and the demands of responsible parenthood;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitory Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-18/</guid>
      <description>Section 1
The first elections of Members of the Congress under this Constitution shall be held on the second Monday of May, 1987.
The first local elections shall be held on a date to be determined by the President.
 It may be simultaneous with the election of the Members of the Congress. It shall include the election of all Members of the city or municipal councils in the Metropolitan Manila area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill of Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-03/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. No person shall be deprived of life, liberty, or property without due process of law, nor shall any person be denied the equal protection of the laws.
Section 2. The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects against unreasonable searches and seizures of whatever nature and for any purpose shall be inviolable, and no search warrant or warrant of arrest shall issue except upon probable cause to be determined personally by the judge after examination under oath or affirmation of the complainant and the witnesses he may produce, and particularly describing the place to be searched and the persons or things to be seized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legislative Department</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-05/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. The legislative power shall be vested in the Congress of the Philippines which shall consist of a Senate and a House of Representatives, except to the extent reserved to the people by the provision on initiative and referendum.
Section 2. The Senate shall be composed of twenty-four Senators who shall be elected at large by the qualified voters of the Philippines, as may be provided by law.
Section 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Executive Department</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-07/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. The executive power shall be vested in the President of the Philippines.
Section 2. No person may be elected President unless he is a natural-born citizen of the Philippines, a registered voter, able to read and write, at least forty years of age on the day of the election, and a resident of the Philippines for at least ten years immediately preceding such election.
Section 3. There shall be a Vice-President who shall have the same qualifications and term of office and be elected with and in the same manner as the President.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Judicial Department</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-08/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. The judicial power shall be vested in one Supreme Court and in such lower courts as may be established by law.
Judicial power includes the duty of the courts of justice to settle actual controversies involving rights which are legally demandable and enforceable, and to determine whether or not there has been a grave abuse of discretion amounting to lack or excess of jurisdiction on the part of any branch or instrumentality of the Government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constitutional Commissions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-09/</guid>
      <description>A. Common Provisions Section 1. The independent Constitutional Commissions are:
 Civil Service Commission Commission on Elections Commission on Audit  Section 2
No Member of a Constitutional Commission shall, during his tenure, hold any other office or employment.
Neither shall he engage in the practice of any profession or in the active management or control of any business which in any way be affected by the functions of his office, nor shall he be financially interested, directly or indirectly, in any contract with, or in any franchise or privilege granted by the Government, any of its subdivisions, agencies, or instrumentalities, including government-owned or controlled corporations or their subsidiaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-10/</guid>
      <description>General Provisions Section 1. The territorial and political subdivisions of the Republic of the Philippines are the provinces, cities, municipalities, and barangays. There shall be autonomous regions in Muslim Mindanao and the Cordilleras as hereinafter provided.
Section 2. The territorial and political subdivisions shall enjoy local autonomy.
Section 3. The Congress shall enact a local government code which shall provide for a more responsive and accountable local government structure instituted through a system of decentralization with effective mechanisms of recall, initiative, and referendum, allocate among the different local government units their powers, responsibilities, and resources, and provide for the qualifications, election, appointment and removal, term, salaries, powers and functions and duties of local officials, and all other matters relating to the organization and operation of the local units.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accountability of Public Officers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1987/article-11/</guid>
      <description>Section 1
Public office is a public trust. Public officers and employees must at all times be accountable to the people, serve them with utmost responsibility, integrity, loyalty, and efficiency, act with patriotism and justice, and lead modest lives.
Section 2
The President, the Vice-President, the Members of the Supreme Court, the Members of the Constitutional Commissions, and the Ombudsman may be removed from office, on impeachment for, and conviction of, culpable violation of the Constitution, treason, bribery, graft and corruption, other high crimes, or betrayal of public trust.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
