<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charter Of Fundamental Rights Of The EU on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Charter Of Fundamental Rights Of The EU on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citizens&#39; Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-5/</guid>
      <description>Article 39
Right to vote and to stand as a candidate at elections to the European Parliament
 Every citizen of the Union has the right to vote and to stand as a candidate at elections to the European Parliament in the Member State in which he or she resides, under the same conditions as nationals of that State. Members of the European Parliament shall be elected by direct universal suffrage in a free and secret ballot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dignity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 1
Human dignity is inviolable. It must be respected and protected.
Article 2
Right to life
 Everyone has the right to life. No one shall be condemned to the death penalty, or executed.  Article 3
Right to the integrity of the person
 Everyone has the right to respect for his or her physical and mental integrity. In the fields of medicine and biology, the following must be respected in particular: (a) the free and informed consent of the person concerned, according to the procedures laid down by law; (b) the prohibition of eugenic practices, in particular those aiming at the selection of persons; (c) the prohibition on making the human body and its parts as such a source of financial gain; (d) the prohibition of the reproductive cloning of human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-3/</guid>
      <description>EQUALITY
Article 20
Equality before the law Everyone is equal before the law.
Article 21 Non-discrimination 1. Any discrimination based on any ground such as sex, race, colour, ethnic or social origin, genetic features, language, religion or belief, political or any other opinion, membership of a national minority, property, birth, disability, age or sexual orientation shall be prohibited. 2. Within the scope of application of the Treaties and without prejudice to any of their specific provisions, any discrimination on grounds of nationality shall be prohibited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedoms</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 6
Right to liberty and security
Everyone has the right to liberty and security of person.
Article 7
Respect for private and family life
Everyone has the right to respect for his or her private and family life, home and communications.
Article 8
Protection of personal data
 Everyone has the right to the protection of personal data concerning him or her. Such data must be processed fairly for specified purposes and on the basis of the consent of the person concerned or some other legitimate basis laid down by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Provisions On The Charter&#39;s Interpretation And Application</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-7/</guid>
      <description>Article 51
Field of application
 The provisions of this Charter are addressed to the institutions, bodies, offices and agencies of the Union with due regard for the principle of subsidiarity and to the Member States only when they are implementing Union law. They shall therefore respect the rights, observe the principles and promote the application thereof in accordance with their respective powers and respecting the limits of the powers of the Union as conferred on it in the Treaties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-6/</guid>
      <description>Article 47
Right to an effective remedy and to a fair trial
Everyone whose rights and freedoms guaranteed by the law of the Union are violated has the right to an effective remedy before a tribunal in compliance with the conditions laid down in this Article. Everyone is entitled to a fair and public hearing within a reasonable time by an independent and impartial tribunal previously established by law. Everyone shall have the possibility of being advised, defended and represented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solidarity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-2/title-4/</guid>
      <description>Article 27
Workers&amp;rsquo; right to information and consultation within the undertaking
Workers or their representatives must, at the appropriate levels, be guaranteed information and consultation in good time in the cases and under the conditions provided for by Union law and national laws and practices.
Article 28
Right of collective bargaining and action Workers and employers, or their respective organisations, have, in accordance with Union law and national laws and practices, the right to negotiate and conclude collective agreements at the appro­ priate levels and, in cases of conflicts of interest, to take collective action to defend their interests, including strike action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
