<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Provisions on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Provisions on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Definition And Objectives Of The Union</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-1/</guid>
      <description>TITLE I TRANSITIONAL PROVISIONS ON THE EUROPEAN INVESTMENT BANK
Article 38 The Kingdom of Spain shall pay the amount of EUR 309 686 775 as its share of the capital paid in for the subscribed capital increase. This contribution shall be paid in eight equal instalments falling due on 30 September 2004, 30 September 2005, 30 September 2006, 31 March 2007, 30 September 2007, 31 March 2008, 30 September 2008 and 31 March 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisions On Cyprus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-10/</guid>
      <description>Article 68
 The application of the Community and Union acquis shall be suspended in those areas of the Republic of Cyprus in which the Government of the Republic of Cyprus does not exercise effective control. The Council, on the basis of a proposal from the Commission, shall decide on the withdrawal of the suspension referred to in paragraph 1. It shall act unanimously.  Article 69
 The Council, on the basis of a proposal from the Commission, shall define the terms under which the provisions of Union law shall apply to the line between those areas referred to in Article 68 and the areas in which the Government of the Republic of Cyprus exercises effective control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisions On The Annexes To The Act Of Accession Of 16 April 2003</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-annexes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-annexes/</guid>
      <description>Article 73
Annex I and Annexes III to XVII to the Act of Accession of 16 April 2003, their appendices, and the Annexes to Protocols 2, 3 and 8 to the Act of Accession of 16 April 2003 ( 1 ) form an integral part of this Protocol.
Article 74
 The references made to the ‘Treaty of Accession’ in the Annexes referred to in Article 73 of this Protocol shall be construed as being made to the Treaty referred to in Article IV‑437(2)(e) of the Constitution, those made to the date or time of signing of that Treaty shall be construed as being made to 16 April 2003 and those made to the date of accession shall be construed as being made to 1 May 2004.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisions On Unit 1 And Unit 2 Of The Bohunice V1 Nuclear Power Plant In Slovakia</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-9/</guid>
      <description>Article 64
Slovakia has undertaken to close Unit 1 of the Bohunice V1 nuclear power plant by 31 December 2006 at the latest and Unit 2 of this plant by 31 December 2008 at the latest and subsequently decommission these units.
Article 65
 During the period 2004‑2006, the Union shall provide Slovakia with financial assistance in support of its efforts to decommission, and to address the consequences of the closure and decommissioning of, Unit 1 and Unit 2 of the Bohunice V1 nuclear power plant (hereinafter referred to as ‘the Assistance’).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-3/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 3: PROVISIONS ON THE SOVEREIGN BASE AREAS OF THE UNITED KINGDOM OF GREAT BRITAIN AND NORTHERN IRELAND IN CYPRUS
Article 43
 The Sovereign Base Areas shall be included within the customs territory of the Union and, for this purpose, the customs and common commercial policy acts of the Union listed in Part One of the Annex to Protocol 3 to the Act of Accession of 16 April 2003 shall apply to the Sovereign Base Areas with the amendments set out in that Annex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-4/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 4: PROVISIONS ON THE IGNALINA NUCLEAR POWER PLANT IN LITHUANIA
Article 52 Acknowledging the readiness of the Union to provide adequate additional assistance to the efforts by Lithuania to decommission the Ignalina nuclear power plant and highlighting this expression of solidarity, Lithuania has undertaken to close Unit 1 of the Ignalina nuclear power plant before 2005 and Unit 2 of this plant by 31 December 2009 at the latest and subsequently decommission these units.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-5/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 5: PROVISIONS ON THE TRANSIT OF PERSONS BY LAND BETWEEN THE REGION OF KALININGRAD AND OTHER PARTS OF THE RUSSIAN FEDERATION
Article 57 The Union rules and arrangements on transit of persons by land between the region of Kaliningrad and other parts of the Russian Federation, and in particular the Council Regulation (EC) No 693/ 2003 of 14 April 2003 establishing a specific Facilitated Transit Document (FTD), a Facilitated Rail954393_TRAITE_EN_301_350 12-01-2005 15:56 Pagina 333 Treaty establishing a Constitution for Europe 333 Transit Document (FRTD) and amending the Common Consular Instructions and the Common Manual ( 1 ), shall not in themselves delay or prevent the full participation of Lithuania in the Schengen acquis, including the removal of internal border controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-09/provisions/title-8/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 8: PROVISIONS ON THE RESTRUCTURING OF THE POLISH STEEL INDUSTRY Article 63
 Notwithstanding Articles III‑167 and III‑168 of the Constitution, State aid granted by Poland for restructuring purposes to specified parts of the Polish steel industry shall be deemed to be compatible with the internal market provided that: (a) the period provided for in Article 8(4) of Protocol 2 on ECSC products to the Europe Agreement establishing an association between the European Communities and their Member States, of the one part, and Poland, of the other part ( 1 ), has been extended until 1 May 2004, (b) the terms set out in the restructuring plan, on the basis of which the abovementioned Protocol was extended are adhered to throughout the period 2002—2006, (c) the conditions set out in this Title are met, and ( 1 ) OJ L 348, 31.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
