<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 11 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 11 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should science focus on the elemental or the universal?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom is a science of first principles is evident from the introductory chapters, in which we have raised objections to the statements of others about the first principles; but one might ask the question whether Wisdom is to be conceived as one science or as several.
If as one, it may be objected that one science always deals with contraries, but the first principles are not contrary. If it is not one, what sort of sciences are those with which it is to be identified?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is movement?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Some things are only actually, some potentially, some potentially and actually, what they are, viz. in one case a particular reality, in another, characterized by a particular quantity, or the like. There is no movement apart from things; for change is always according to the categories of being, and there is nothing common to these and in no one category.
But each of the categories belongs to all its subjects in either of two ways (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Nature of Number?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Must we suppose something apart from individual things, or is it these that the science we are seeking treats of?
But these are infinite in number. Yet the things that are apart from the individuals are genera or species; but the science we now seek treats of neither of these. The reason why this is impossible has been stated.
It is in general hard to say whether one must assume that there is a separable substance besides the sensible substances (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the attributes of being?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy treats of being qua being universally and not in respect of a part of it, and &amp;lsquo;being&amp;rsquo; has many senses and is not used in one only, it follows that if the word is used equivocally and in virtue of nothing common to its various uses, being does not fall under one science (for the meanings of an equivocal term do not form one genus); but if the word is used in virtue of something common, being will fall under one science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Even the mathematician uses the common axioms only in a special application.
This is why first philosophy should also examine the principles of mathematics.
That when equals are taken from equals the remainders are equal, is common to all quantities, but mathematics studies a part of its proper matter which it has detached, e.g. lines or angles or numbers or some other kind of quantity-not, however, qua being but in so far as each of them is continuous in one or two or three dimensions;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being and Not Being</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Protagoras said that man is the measure of all things. It means:
 that which seems to each man is also is. that the same thing both is and is not, and is bad and good that the contents of all other opposite statements are true, because often a particular thing appears beautiful to some and the contrary of beautiful to others, and that which appears to each man is the measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Science</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-7/</guid>
      <description>Every science seeks certain principles and causes for each of its objects-e.g. medicine and gymnastics and each of the other sciences, whether productive or mathematical.
Each of these marks off a certain class of things for itself and busies itself about this as about something existing and real,-not however qua real; the science that does this is another distinct from these. Of the sciences mentioned each gets somehow the &amp;lsquo;what&amp;rsquo; in some class of things and tries to prove the other truths, with more or less precision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Luck?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Being&amp;rsquo; has several senses. One is &amp;lsquo;being by accident&amp;rsquo;. For neither does architecture consider what will happen to those who are to use the house (e.g. whether they have a painful life in it or not), nor does weaving, or shoemaking, or the confectioner&amp;rsquo;s art, do the like; but each of these sciences considers only what is peculiar to it, i.e. its proper end. And as for the argument that &amp;lsquo;when he who is musical becomes lettered he&amp;rsquo;ll be both at once, not having been both before;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Infinite</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-10/</guid>
      <description>The infinite is either that which is incapable of being traversed because it is not its nature to be traversed (this corresponds to the sense in which the voice is &amp;lsquo;invisible&amp;rsquo;), or that which admits only of incomplete traverse or scarcely admits of traverse, or that which, though it naturally admits of traverse, is not traversed or limited; further, a thing may be infinite in respect of addition or of subtraction, or both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinds of Movement</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-11/part-12/</guid>
      <description>If the categories are classified as substance, quality, place, acting or being acted on, relation, quantity, there must be three kinds of movement-of quality, of quantity, of place.
There is no movement in respect of substance (because there is nothing contrary to substance), nor of relation (for it is possible that if one of two things in relation changes, the relative term which was true of the other thing ceases to be true, though this other does not change at all,-so that their movement is accidental), nor of agent and patient, or mover and moved, because there is no movement of movement nor generation of generation, nor, in general, change of change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
