<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Charter of the United Nations Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Charter of the United Nations Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/introduction/</guid>
      <description>SAN FRANCISCO • 1945
WE THE PEOPLES OF THE UNITED NATIONS DETERMINED to=
 save succeeding generations from war reaffirm faith in fundamental human rights, in the dignity and worth of the human person, in the equal rights of men and women and of nations large and small, and establish justice and respect for the obligations arising from treaties and other sources of international law can be maintained, and promote social progress and better standards of life in larger freedom,  AND FOR THESE ENDS=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purposes And Principles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 1 The Purposes of the United Nations are=
 To maintain international peace and security.  To that end, to take effective collective measures to prevent and remove threats to peace and to bring about the settlement of international disputes in conformity with the principles of justice and international law
To develop friendly relations among nations based on respect for the principle of=   equal rights self-determination of peoples  To strengthen universal peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Membership</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Article 3 The original UN Members are the states which=
 participated in the UN Conference on International Organization at San Francisco, or having previously signed the Declaration by United Nations of January 1,1942, sign the present Charter and ratify it in accordance with Article 110.  Article 4   Membership is open to all other peace-loving states which accept the obligations in the present Charter and are able and willing to carry them out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organs</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Article 7  The principal organs of the UN are=   a General Assembly [GA] a Security Council [SC] an Economic and Social Council a Trusteeship Council an International Court of Justice a Secretariat  Such subsidiary organs as may be found necessary may be established in accordance with the present Charter.  Article 8 The United Nations shall place no restrictions on the eligibility of men and women to participate in any capacity and under conditions of equality in-its principal and subsidiary organs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The General Assembly</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Article 9: Composition  The GA is made up of all the UN Members Each Member shall have not more than 5 representatives in the GA.  Article 10: Functions and Powers The GA may discuss any questions or any matters within the scope of the present Charter or relating to the powers and functions of any organs provided for in the present Charter, and, except as provided in Article 12, may make recommendations to the Members of the United Nations or to the Security Council or to both on any such questions or matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pacific Settlement Of Disputes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>Article 33  The parties to any dispute, the continuance of which is likely to endanger the maintenance of international peace and security, shall, first of all, seek a solution by negotiation, enquiry, mediation, conciliation, arbitration, judicial settlement, resort to regional agencies or arrangements, or other peaceful means of their own choice. The Security Council shall, when it deems necessary, call upon the parties to settle their dispute by such means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action on Threats To The Peace, Breaches Of The Peace, And Acts Of Aggression</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>Article 39 The SC shall determine the existence of any threat to the peace, breach of the peace, or act of aggression. It shall recommen or decide what measures shall be taken in accordance with Articles 41 and 42, to maintain or restore international peace and security.
Article 40 In order to prevent an aggravation of the situation, the Security Council may, before making the recommendations or deciding upon the measures provided for in Article 39, call upon the parties concerned to comply with such provisional measures as it deems necessary or desirable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional Arrangements</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>Article 52  Nothing in the present Charter precludes the existence of regional arrangements or agencies for dealing with such matters relating to the maintenance of international peace and security as are appropriate for regional action, provided that such arrangements or agencies and their activities are consistent with the Purposes and Principles of the United Nations. The Members of the United Nations entering into such arrangements or constituting such agencies shall make every effort to achieve pacific settlement of local disputes through such regional arrangements or by such regional agencies before referring them to the Security Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Economic And Social Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>Article 55 With a view to the creation of conditions of stability and well-being which are necessary for peaceful and friendly relations among nations based on respect for the principle of equal rights and self-determination of peoples, the UN shall promote=
 a. higher standards of living, full employment, and conditions of economic and social progress and development b. solutions of international economic, social, health, and related problems; and international cultural and educational cooperation; c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economic And Social Council</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Article 61: Composition  The Economic and Social Council shall consist of 18 UN Members elected by the GA. Subject to the provisions of paragraph 3, 6 members of the Economic and Social Council shall be elected each year for 3 years. A retiring member shall be eligible for immediate re-election. At the first election, eighteen members of the Economic and Social Council shall be chosen. The term of office of six members so chosen shall expire at the end of one year, and of six other members at the end of two years, in accordance with arrangements made by the General Assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Declaration On Non-self-governing Territories</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>Article 73 The UN Members which assume the responsibilities of administering territories whose peoples have not yet attained self-government recognize the principle that thhose peoples&amp;rsquo; interests are paramount.
They accept as a sacred trust the obligation to promote to the utmost, within the system of international peace and security established by the present Charter, the well-being of the inhabitants of these territories, and, to this end=
 a. to ensure, with due respect for the culture of the peoples concerned, their political, economic, social, and educational advancement, their just treatment, and their protection against abuses; b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Trusteeship System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Article 75 The UN shall establish under its authority an international trusteeship system for the administration and supervision of &amp;ldquo;trust territories&amp;rdquo; as may be placed thereunder by subsequent individual agreements.
Article 76 The basic objectives of the trusteeship system,in accordance with the Purposes of the United Nations laid down in Article 1 of the present Char- ter, shall be=
 a. to further international peace and security; b. to promote the political, economic, social, and educational advancement of the inhabitants of the trust territories, and their progressive development towards self-government or inde- pendence as may be appropriate to the particular circumstances of each territory and its peoples and the freely expressed wishes of the peoples concerned, and as may be provided by the terms of each trusteeship agreement; c.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trusteeship Council</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Article 86= Composition  The Trusteeship Council shall consist of the following UN Members= a. those Members administering trust territories; b. such of those Members mentioned by name in Article 23 as are not administering trust territories; and c. as many other Members elected for three-year terms by the General Assembly as may be necessary to ensure that the total number of members of the Trusteeship Council is equally divided between those Members of the United Nations which administer trust territories and those which do not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Court Of Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>Article 92 The International Court of Justice shall be the UN&amp;rsquo;s principal judicial organ. It shall function according to the Statute of The International Court Of Justice, which is an integral part of the present Charter.
Article 93  All Members of the United Nations are ipso facto parties to the Statute of the International Court of Justice. A state which is not a Member of the United Nations may become a party to the Statute of the International Court of Justice on conditions to be determined in each case by the General Assembly upon the recommendation of the Security Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secretariat</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>Article 97 The Secretariat is made up of a Secretary-General and his staff. He shall be appointed by the GA upon the SC&amp;rsquo;s recommendation.
He shall be the chief administrative officer of the UN.
Article 98 He shall act in that capacity in all meetings of the GA, of the SC, of the Economic and Social Council, and of the Trusteeship Council. He shall perform such other functions as are entrusted to him by these organs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>Article 102   Every treaty and every international agreement entered into by any Member of the United Nations after the present Charter comes into force shall as soon as possible be registered with the Secretariat and published by it.
  No party to any such treaty or international agreement which has not been registered in accordance with the provisions of paragraph 1 ofthis Article may invoke that treaty or agreement before any organ of the United Nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitional Security Arrangements</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>Article 106 The special agreements referred to in Article 43 may take time to come into force.
In the meantime=
 the SC can exercise its responsibilities under Article 42 pending such agreements. France and the parties to the Four-Nation Declaration, signed at Moscow, October 30,1943 shall, in accordance with paragraph 5 of that Declaration, consult with one another and with other UN Members to maintain peace  Article 107 Nothing in the present Charter shall invalidate or preclude action, in relation to any state which during the Second World War has been an enemy of any signatory to the present Charter, taken or authorized as a result of that war by the Governments having responsibility for such action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Security Council</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/un/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Article 23: Composition  The Security Council shall consist of 11 Members of the UN. The permanent members are=   China France USSR UK USA  The GA shall elect 6 other Members to be non-permanent members of the Security Council, due regard being specially paid, in the first instance to the contribution of Members of theUnited Nations to the maintenance of international peace and security and to the other purposes of the Organization, and also to equitable geographical distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
