<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metaphysics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metaphysics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Metaphysics of the Marcos-Aquino Rivalry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/marcos-aquino-rivalry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/marcos-aquino-rivalry/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the Philippine media was alarmed at the candidacy of Bongbong Marcos for President for 2022.
Bongbong is the son of dictator Ferdinand Marcos who plunged the country to debt and crisis from 1983 to 1986. Ferdinand was ousted by Cory Aquino, a housewife who had no knowledge of governance. This resulted in coups, disorders, and natural disasters which were only stabilized in 1992 after the election of Fidel Ramos, a military general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Democracy is Bad for the Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/democracy-is-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/democracy-is-bad/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who views all of human history will see that democracy is a recent and tiny political phenomenon originating from the American and French Revolutions.
Western democracy originally came from the Greeks. There were other democratic societies in Asia and tribal regions, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t survive because of the inherent problems inherent in democracy, mainly the weakness and instability that it creates.
 Greece was quickly overrun by the Persians who did not have democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is the Philippines Poor?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/poor-philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/poor-philippines/</guid>
      <description>According to Adam Smith, there are three basic factors needed to be a major economic power:
 The people must have a good moral system The people must not be stupid The country must have access to the ocean  Natural resources are not so important as long as the basics are available (i.e. the country is not barren like the Sahara or Antartica)
Economic power is in the value that a society creates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maharlika Social Cycles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/maharlika-social-cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/metaphysics/maharlika-social-cycles/</guid>
      <description>According to Socrates, all societies have alternating seasons that begin with democracy that switches to tyranny, then aristocracy, then oligarchy, and finally back to democracy.
 A democracy is dominated by freedom-loving people. Its positive aspect is social justice, while its negative is chaos and mob rule. This chaos leads people to want order, paving the way for tyranny A tyranny is dominated by warriors and generals. Its positive aspect is peace and order, while its negative is abuse and corruption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
