<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Postulates of Classical Economics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Most theories of value and production focus on the distribution of a given volume of employed resources between different uses. These uses determine their relative rewards and the relative values of their products.
Those theories describe the volume of the available resources relative to:
 the employable population size the extent of natural wealth the accumulated capital equipment  But the pure theory of what determines the actual employment of the available resources has seldom been examined in detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Wages versus Real Wages</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-02b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-02b/</guid>
      <description>What is the actual statistical relationship between:
 changes in money-wages and changes in real wages?  In a particular industry, one would expect the change in real wages to be in the same direction as the change in money-wages.
But in the case of general wages, the change in real wages associated with a change in money-wages, is so far from being in the same direction. It is almost always in the opposite direction:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Involuntary Employment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-02c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-02c/</guid>
      <description>The struggle over money-wages is often believed to determine the general level of real wages.
Workers have an imperfect mobility. Wages do not tend to an exact equality of net advantage in different occupations. Anyone accepts lower money-wages relative to others, will get lower real wages. This makes workers resist it.
On the other hand, it would be impracticable to resist every reduction of real wages, due to inflation. Workers do not resist this unless the inflation is extreme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Effective Demand</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Based on resources and costs, the employment of a given volume of labour by an entrepreneur involves him in two kinds of expense:
  His payments for the factors of production (exclusive of other entrepreneurs) for their current services, which we shall call the factor cost of the employment in question
  His payments to other entrepreneurs for purchases
  The &amp;ldquo;user cost&amp;rdquo; is the cost of using his own equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Choice of Units</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Chapters 4 to 7 are a digression on three perplexities:
  The choice of the units of quantity for an economic system as a whole
  The part played by expectation in economic analysis
  The definition of income
  The units of Economics are unsatisfactory. This is proven by the National Dividend which is the stock of real capital and the general price-level:
  The National Dividend   This was defined by Marshall and Professor Pigou.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectation Determines Output and Employment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>The goal of aLL production is to satisfy a consumer. Time elapses after the producer incurs costs and before the ultimate consumer purchases the output.
Meanwhile, the entrepreneur (including both the producer and the investor) has to form the best expectations[1] as to what the consumers will pay when he is ready to supply them after the long time from investment to production.
Business decisions depend on these expectations as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Definition of Income, Saving and Investment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>Let:
 A be an entrepreneur&amp;rsquo;s income from a sale of a product A1 is his expense in buying that product from his supplier G is his expense for capital equipment  This includes his unfinished goods (working capital) and finished goods    Some part, however, of A + G - A1 will be attributableto the capital equipment which he had at the start.
The income of the current period is obtained by deducting from A + G - A1 a certain sum, to represent that part of its value which has been contributed by the equipment inherited from the previous period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Saving and Investment Further Considered</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>1. Additional Defintion of Saving and Investment Chapter 6 defined Saving and Investment to be equal in amount, as different aspects of the same thing to the society as a whole.
I and several contemporary writers have, however, given special definitions of these terms which are not equal. Others have written on the assumption that they may be unequal without prefacing their discussion with any definitions at all.
I classify some of the various uses of them which appear to be current.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix on User Cost</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-07appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-07appendix/</guid>
      <description>1. Classical User Cost The Classical theory of value has an important concept called the USER cost, which has been overlooked.
U = A1 + (G&#39; - B&#39;) - G
 U= An entrepreneur’s user cost A1 is the amount of our entrepreneur’s purchases from other entrepreneurs G the actual value of his capital equipment at the end of the period G&amp;rsquo; the value it might have had at the end of the period if he had refrained from using it and had spent the optimum sum B&amp;rsquo; on its maintenance and improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Propensity to Consume</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>1 The Objective Factors The volume of employment is determined by intersection of the aggregate supply function with the aggregate demand function.
The aggregate supply function depends on the physical conditions of supply, involves few considerations which are not already familiar.
The form may be unfamiliar but the underlying factors are not new.
Chapter 20 will elaborate on the aggregate supply function and its inverse, &amp;ldquo;the employment function&amp;rdquo;.
But it is the part played mainly by the aggregate demand function which has been overlooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Propensity to Consume</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>The Subjective Factors The subjective and social incentives are the second category of factors which affect the amount of consumption from a given income.
These determine how much is spent, given the aggregate of income in terms of hourly wage given the relevant objective factors already discussed.
The analysis of these subjective factors is not new. We can classify eight main subjective motives which lead individuals to refrain from spending their incomes=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Propensity to Consume and the Multiplier</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Book 3 The Propensity to Consume Chapter 8 established that employment can only increase pari passu with investment. The Multiplier in our theory of employment is a definite ratio between:
 income and investment total employment and primary employment (employment directly employed on investment).  This establishes a precise relationship, given the propensity to consume, between aggregate employment and income and the rate of investment.
This was originally from Mr. R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marginal Efficiency of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>When a man makes an investment, he buys the right to prospective returns.
I call this &amp;ldquo;the prospective yield of the investment&amp;rdquo;.
This prospective yield has a supply price which is the cost to create that investment.
This supply price is not the market price at which it is bought.
The relation between the prospective yield and its supply price gives us its marginal efficiency of capital.
 It is equal to that rate of discount which would make the present value of the series of annuities given by the returns expected from the capital-asset during its life just equal to its supply price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Long-Term Expectation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11 explained that the scale of investment depends on the relation between:
 the interest rate and the schedule of the marginal efficiency of capital corresponding to different scales of current investment  The marginal efficiency of capital depends on the relation between:
 the supply price of a capital-asset its prospective yield.  What are the factors which determine the prospective yield of an asset?
These may be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The General Theory of the Rate of Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>*Superphysics Note= Here, we dissect Keynes&amp;rsquo; reasoning on why his system is totally different from Classical &amp;ndash; because he enshrines the love for cash!
 Chapter 11 shows that there are forces causing the rate of investment to rise or fall so as to keep the rate of return on investments equal to the rate of interest.
Yet the rate of return on investments is, in itself, a different thing from the rate of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Liquidity Preference</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-13b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-13b/</guid>
      <description>The three divisions of the love for future cash depend on:
 the transactions-motive, i.e. the need of cash the precautionary-motive as the desire for security as to the future cash equivalent the speculative-motive, i.e. the object of securing profit from knowing better than the market what will the future be  A debt-market allows wide fluctuations in the love for cash due to speculation.
But without such a market, the love for cash for the security of cash would be greatly increased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Classical Rate of Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>1 Investment is the use of assets (circulating or fixed) to earn profits.
 Interest is the revenue from lending those circulating assets to someone else for them to earn a profit from. Interest rate is the rate of revenue in lending. Savings are the assets that are taken out of one&amp;rsquo;s own circulation to be circulated by someone else.  According to the Classical Theory:
 Investment is the demand for investable resources Savings represents the supply for investable resources The rate of interest is the “price” of investable resources at which the two are equated A commodity&amp;rsquo;s price is fixed where its demand is equal to the supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interest Rates According to Different Economists</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-14appendix/</guid>
      <description>THERE is not much discussion of the rate of interest in the works of Marshall, Edgeworth or Professor Pigou.
Alfred Marshall= Interest is the price of capital Principles of Economics **Interest is the price paid for the use of capital in any market.** It tends towards an equilibrium level such that the aggregate demand for capital in that market, at that rate of interest, is equal to the aggregate stock forthcoming there at that rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychological and Business Incentives To Liquidity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>What are the motives for liquidity-preference?
It is also closely connected with the &amp;ldquo;income-velocity of money&amp;rdquo;.
The income-velocity of money merely measures what proportion of their incomes the public chooses to hold in cash, so that an increased income-velocity of money may be a symptom of a decreased liquidity-preference.
It is not the same thing since it is in respect of his stock of accumulated savings, rather than of his income, that the individual can exercise his choice between liquidity and illiquidity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sundry Observations on the Nature of Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>AN act of individual saving is a decision not to have dinner today. But it does lead to a spending of that saving to buy dinner at a later date.
Thus, it depresses the food service business or other consumption businesses. It is a net reduction of such demand. The expectation of future consumption is based on present consumption. A reduction in present consumption will likely depress future consumption. This will result in the act of saving:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essential Properties of Interest and Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>The interest rate of money sets a standard to which the marginal efficiency of a capital-asset must attain if it is to be newly produced. This makes it play a part in limiting the level of employment.
At first sight, this is most perplexing. It is natural to enquire wherein the peculiarity of money lies as distinct from other assets, whether it is only money which has a rate of interest, and what would happen in a non-monetary economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Summary of the General Theory</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-18a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-18a/</guid>
      <description>My proposed system has the following as a given:
 the existing skill and quantity of available labour the existing quality and quantity of available equipment the existing technique the degree of competition the tastes and habits of the consumer the disutility of different intensifies of labour and of the activities of supervision and organisation, as well as the social structure including the forces, other than our variables set forth below, which determine the distribution of the national income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Saving and Investment Further Considered</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-18b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-18b/</guid>
      <description>The actual economic system are also coloured by certain special characteristics of the propensity to consume, the schedule of the marginal efficiency of capital and the rate of interest, about which we can safely generalise from experience, but which are not logically necessary.
In particular, it is an outstanding characteristic of the economic system in which we live that, whilst it is subject to severe fluctuations in respect of output and employment, it is not violently unstable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in Money-Wages</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>Book V Money-Wages and Prices What are the effects of a change in money-wages?
The consequences of a change in money-wages are complicated.
The Classical Theory assumed that:
 the economic system was self-adjusting on an assumed fluidity of money-wages rigidity is to be blamed on maladjustment  A reduction in money-wages can in certain circumstances stimulate output, as the classical theory supposes. But I analyze it differently.
Classical economics says that a reduction in money-wages will cet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pigou’s Theory of Unemployment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-19appendix/</guid>
      <description>Pigou makes the volume of employment to depend on two factors:
  The real rates of wages for which workpeople stipulate
  The shape of the Real Demand Function for Labour
  His work determines the shape of the latter function.
The fact that workpeople in fact stipulate, not for a real rate of wages, but for a money-rate, is not ignored; but, in effect, it is assumed that the actual money-rate of wages divided by the price of wage-goods can be taken to measure the real rate demanded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Employment Function</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3 defined the aggregate supply function Z = φ(N).
This relates the employment N with the aggregate supply price of the corresponding output.
The employment function:
 only differs from the aggregate supply function in that it is, in effect, its inverse function and is defined in terms of hourly pay. aims to relate the amount of the effective demand, measured inhourly pay, directed to a given firm or industry or to industry as a whole with the amount of employment, the supply price of the output of which will compare to that amount of effective demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>The Theory of Value has traditionally been based on supply and demand, particularly in changes in marginal cost and the elasticity of short-period supply.
But when they pass to the Theory of Money and Prices, value becomes governed by
 the quantity of money,  its income-velocity,   the velocity of circulation relative to the volume of transactions  hoarding, forced saving, inflation and deflation et hoc genus omne.    Little attempt is made to relate these vaguer phrases to our former notions of the elasticities of supply and demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-21b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-21b/</guid>
      <description>Section 5 True inflation happens when a further increase in effective demand produces no increase in output. Instead the demand raises the cost-unit proportional to the increase in effective demand.
Up to this point, the effect of monetary expansion is entirely a question of degree, and there is no previous point at which we can draw a definite line and declare that conditions of inflation have set in.
Every previous increase in the quantity of money is likely, in so far as it increases effective demand, to spend itself partly in increasing the cost-unit and partly in increasing output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on the Trade Cycle</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Book 6: Short Notes Suggested by the General Theory The preceding chapters showed what determines the volume of employment at any time.
It follows that our theory can explain the Trade Cycle.
The Trade Cycle is highly complex. Every element in our analysis will be required for its complete explanation.
We shall find that fluctuations in the propensity to consume, in the state of liquidity-preference, and in the marginal efficiency of capital have all played a part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercantilism, Usury Laws, Stamped Money, Under-Consumption Theories</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>Book 6 Short Notes Suggested by the General Theory Section 1 FOR 200 years, people saw a national advantage in a favourable balance of trade, and grave danger in an unfavourable balance, particularly if it results in an efflux of the precious metals.
But this changed in the past 100 years.
Most statesmen, practical men in most countries, and nearly half of them even in Great Britain, the home of the opposite view, have remained faithful to the ancient doctrine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silvio Gesell</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-23b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-23b/</guid>
      <description>Silvio Gesell (1862-1930) is an unduly neglected prophet. His work has flashes of deep insight. He only just failed to reach down to the essence of the matter.
In the post-war years, his devotees bombarded me with copies of his works. As is often the case with imperfectly analysed intuitions, their significance only became apparent after I had reached my own conclusions in my own way.
Meanwhile, like other academic economists, I treated his profoundly original strivings as being no better than those of a crank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Philosophy towards which the General Theory might Lead</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/keynes/general-theory/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>THE outstanding faults of the economy are:
 its failure to provide for full employment its arbitrary and inequitable distribution of wealth and incomes.  My theory will obviously affect employment. But it is also relevant to inequality in 2 respects.
Since the end of the 19th century, direct taxation has significantly removed very great disparities of wealth and income especially in Great Britain. This manifests as:
 income tax surtax death duties  Many people want this carried much further.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
