<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Material Superphysics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/categories/material-superphysics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Material Superphysics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/categories/material-superphysics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Einstein&#39;s General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/fallacies/general-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/fallacies/general-relativity/</guid>
      <description>While collating the works of Socrates in order to unify them with those of David Hume to harmonize Superphysics, I came upon his maxims on astrophysics: The spangled heavens should be used as a pattern and with a view to that higher knowledge. Any geometrician who saw them would never think that there is a true equal, true double, or true proportion in the spangled heavens. Likewise, a true astronomer..will never imagine that the proportions of night and day, the stars to one another are eternal and subject to no deviation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrons are Positive, Protons are Negative</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoe/</guid>
      <description>Have you wondered why negative ions make us feel positive, and positive ions make us feel negative?
That&amp;rsquo;s because electrons are really positively charged! Benjamin Franklin made a mistake when he called electrons as negative. Rather than confuse everyone by calling the negative as positive, we&amp;rsquo;d rather call the negative as &amp;lsquo;feminine charge&amp;rsquo;, the positive as a &amp;lsquo;masculine charge&amp;rsquo;, and neutral as a &amp;lsquo;bisexual charge&amp;rsquo;.
We shall use the word &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Layers of Superphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/five-layers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/five-layers/</guid>
      <description>Our Five Layers are derived from the Five Elements of the Greeks, Hindus, and Chinese. Such a concept is absent in science because science came from the Western civilization which is really just the Roman Empire.
The Western Limitation Physics came from Isaac Newton* who came up with classical mechanics to explain why 17th-century things move. For example, a falling apple immediately includes three of the four forces:
 Strong force to keep the apple&amp;rsquo;s identity Gravitational force to make the apple fall Electromagnetism for the apple to repel the Earth and not fall through the soil   *Newton&amp;rsquo;s Principia is written in Latin, the language of the Roman Empire</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational Signatures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/gravsigs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/gravsigs/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we fixed relativity* by adhering to the rules** which Socrates*** mentioned earlier:
 Photons must not be used to build the solution There must be no constant The solution and cause of movement must be inherent to the object, as opposed to being external The solution must be universal, that is, applicable to all five layers of the Greek or Asian model of Earth, Water, Fire, Air, and Ether   *We fix Newton in this post   **This adherence of logic to timeless metaphysical truths is the key aspect of the dialectical method that makes it different from the scientific method which is based on evidence supplied by the limited physical senses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light-based Computing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/solutions/light-based-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/solutions/light-based-computing/</guid>
      <description>Light, as analog waves, carry more data as &amp;ldquo;R-O-Y-G-B-I-V&amp;rdquo; than electrons that can only carry digital binary data as &amp;ldquo;ON-OFF&amp;rdquo; at a time. This analog light data can then be absorbed by glass or semiconductor crystals to be processed by normal computer logic.
This principle was recently proven to be realizable in Germany . In their experiment, intense light pulses of waves ranging from near-infrared to visible orange were used to generate oscillating currents in a chip made with gallium arsenide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Quantum of Aether or Qoa?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoa/</guid>
      <description>We all know that physical reality exists inside space and time, and that space and time are the properties of the universe. But how were space and time and the universe created?
According to Physics, it was created through a &amp;ldquo;Big Bang&amp;rdquo; of a material Singularity. This led to matter and energy, just as we see sharpnel and light, and feel the energy from exploding fireworks. What is the nature of this Material Singularity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Quantum of Spacetime or Qost?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qost/</guid>
      <description>The Five Layers of Superphysics In a previous post , we explained that a universe begins as a &amp;ldquo;Big Bootup&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Wakeup&amp;rdquo; when ideas flow from the metaphysical plane onto the physical plane. These ideas flow down onto the five layers or elements of the Greeks, Hindus, and Chinese in five phases:
   Phase Layer Physics Name Sequence     0 Metaphysical Pseudo-science The pre-existing ideas as potentialities are deployed onto reality   1 Aethereal Higgs The aether compiles the compound ideas as potential universes in the multiverse   2 Spatial Gravitation The compiled ideas are sent through qosts as galaxies and then as stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spin is the Reflective Ability of Particles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/spin/</guid>
      <description>Physics is based on a materialistic interpretation of reality, which is opposite of the metaphysical interpretation by Superphysics.
For example, physics prefers to view things as particles. This is consistent with the atomic model of Democritus and opposite of the musical model of Pythagoras.
 The atomic model was embraced by Newton and Einstein The musical model was embraced by Socrates and Kepler  We continue this musical paradigm by using waves instead of particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Universal Relativity?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/universal-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/universal-relativity/</guid>
      <description>In Superphysics, physical existence is made when the aether arbitrarily creates quanta of spacetime or qost *, which are 1-dimensional points, within itself. Each point is a discrete and unique identity filled with an arbitrary amount of qualities as potentiality.
 *pronounced as &amp;lsquo;kost&amp;rsquo;. This is supposed to be the graviton which will never be found, because it can only be felt since it lies in the spatial layer which is above the visible eletromagnetic layer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
