<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Plan Of Creation on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Plan Of Creation on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Human Engine and the Life Current</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Mankind are earthen jugs with spirits in them.&#34; Hawthorne  THE human body is the earthly tenement of the mind or soul. In its construction and operation is very like a mechanical engine.
Every mechanical engine is built upon the plan that will best enable it to do the kind of work it is intended to perform ; some are so small that their mission is to become the interior works of a watch; some are built to propel a locomotive at high speed, and others to furnish power to some gigantic manufacturing establishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mount Of Apollo</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-21-apollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-21-apollo/</guid>
      <description>THE third Mount type is the Apollonian, and the parts of the hand which identify him are the Mount and finger of Apollo.
This is a pleasant type to handle because it is a good type.
The Apollonian sometimes becomes mercenary and shoddy but he does not often become bad or criminal.
Saturn and Mercury, the bilious types, become bad and vicious.
While the others are sometimes coarse, they do not often descend to criminality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mount Of Jupiter</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-19-jupiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-19-jupiter/</guid>
      <description>As single signs, or in combination with each other, the star, triangle, circle, square, single vertical line, or trident strengthen a Mount.
As single signs, or in combination with each other, the grille, cross-bars, cross, island, or dot indicate defects of the Mount either of health or of character, the main lines, chance lines, color, etc., will determine which.
There are a few variations of this rule as applied to some of the Mounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mount Of Luna</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-24-luna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-24-luna/</guid>
      <description>THE sixth Mount type is the Lunarian represented by the Mount of Luna or the Mount of the Moon.
This mount is strengthened by the=
 star triangle circle single vertical line square, or trident  Defects are shown by=
 grills crosses cross-bars islands dots, or badly formed stars either of health or character  Color, nails, and other matters detailed in the course of this chapter will determine which (119).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mount Of Mars</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-23-mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-23-mars/</guid>
      <description>THE fifth Mount type is the Martian. He is identified by=
 the two Mounts of Mars the Upper Mount on the percussion and above the Line of Head the Lower Mount under the Line of Life and above the Mount of Venus  The Plain of Mars is located in the centre of the palm, which bears some relation to the Martian type.
In the map, the lower boundary of Lower Mars is the word &amp;ldquo;aggression,&amp;rdquo; and all under that word belongs to the Mount of Venus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mount Of Mercury</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-22-mercury/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-22-mercury/</guid>
      <description>THE fourth Mount type is the Mercurian, who is identified by the Mount and Finger of Mercury.
He is always pronounced in his characteristics, and has great power as an orator, a scientist, a physician, or a lawyer, and is also very successful in business. The first aim, with every subject of this type, should be to discover which of his several phases is strongest, and whether the good or bad side is dominant, for of all the types, none gives way to dishonesty with more ease than the Mercurian.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mount Of Saturn</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-20-saturn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-20-saturn/</guid>
      <description>The Saturnian is the second type to be considered, and the parts of the hand by which he is identified are the Mount and finger of Saturn.
The higher the Mount of Saturn is developed, the larger and longer the finger, and the squarer the tip of this finger, the more pronounced is the type of the subject.
A highly developed Mount of Saturn is a rarity, and in the greatest number of hands there is instead a depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mount Of Venus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-25-venus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-25-venus/</guid>
      <description>The seventh type is the Venusian located by the Mount of Venus at the base of the thumb.
This is strengthened by the=
 triangle circle square, or single vertical lines  The cross, grille, island or dot show defects of the Mount (127).
This Mount rises into the palm, has the largest prominence shown by any of the Mounts, and by its size and markings you must estimate the amount and kind of Venusian qualities possessed by the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seven Mount Types</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-1/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Wisdom hath builded her house. She hath hewn out her seven pillars.&#34; Proverbs ix., I  THE science of Palmistry is founded on the shape of the hand.
The 7 mounts lie at the base of the fingers and along the sides of the hand. The proper estimation of the combination of these mounts can let us accurately delineate the character of person.
There are other separated elements which enter into and add to a proper understanding of the science, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
