<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Questions of Metaphysics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Questions of Metaphysics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 3</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Is it the genera that should be taken as elements and principles, or rather the primary constituents of a thing?   e.g. it is the primary parts of which articulate sounds consist that are thought to be elements and principles of articulate sound, not the common genus-articulate sound; and we give the name of &amp;rsquo;elements&amp;rsquo; to those geometrical propositions, the proofs of which are implied in the proofs of the others, either of all or of most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 6</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Besides perceptible things and the intermediates, we have to look for another class of things &amp;ndash; the Forms which we posit.
If it is for this reason, because the objects of mathematics, while they differ from the things in this world in some other respect, differ not at all in that there are many of the same kind, so that their first principles cannot be limited in number (just as the elements of all the language in this sensible world are not limited in number, but in kind, unless one takes the elements of this individual syllable or of this individual articulate sound-whose elements will be limited even in number;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question 11= Are being and unity the substances of things?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-4b/</guid>
      <description>The hardest and most necessary inquiry for knowledge of the truth is whether being and unity are the substances of things.   Is each of them, without being anything else, is being or unity respectively?
What is the nature of being and unity?
Some people think they are of being. Others think they are of unity. Plato and the Pythagoreans thought being and unity were nothing else, but this was their nature, their essence being just unity and being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions 1 to 3</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Should the sciences investigate all the kinds of causes?   How could it belong to one science to recognize the principles if these are not contrary?
There are many things to which not all the principles pertain. How can a principle of change or the nature of the good exist for unchangeable things, since everything that in itself and by its own nature is good is an end, and a cause in the sense that for its sake the other things both come to be and are, and since an end or purpose is the end of some action, and all actions imply change?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions 4 to 5</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>Does our investigation deal with substances alone or also with their attributes?   If the solid is a substance and so are lines and planes, is it the business of the same science to know these and to know the attributes of each of these classes (the attributes about which the mathematical sciences offer proofs), or of a different science? If of the same, the science of substance also must be a demonstrative science, but it is thought that there is no demonstration of the essence of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Questions of Metaphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Our problems are:
  Does the investigation of the causes belongs to one or to more sciences?
  whether such a science should survey only the first principles of substance, or also the principles on which all men base their proofs, e.g. whether it is possible at the same time to assert and deny one and the same thing or not, and all other such questions; and
  If the science in question deals with substance, whether one science deals with all substances, or more than one, and if more, whether all are akin, or some of them must be called forms of Wisdom and the others something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-4/</guid>
      <description>If there is nothing apart from individual things, and the individuals are infinitely many, how can we know the infinite individuals?   All things that we come to know, we come to know in so far as they have some unity and identity, and in so far as some attribute belongs to them universally.
&amp;ldquo;But if this is necessary, and there must be something apart from the individuals, it will be necessary that the genera exist apart from the individuals, either the lowest or the highest genera; but we found by discussion just now that this is impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 5</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-3/part-5/</guid>
      <description>Are numbers, bodies, planes, and points substances?  If they are not, then what is being and what are the substances of things?
Modifications, movements, relations, dispositions, and ratios do not indicate the substance of anything. All are predicated of a subject, and none is a &amp;rsquo;this&#39;.
And as to the things which might seem most of all to indicate substance, water and earth and fire and air, of which composite bodies consist, heat and cold and the like are modifications of these, not substances, and the body which is thus modified alone persists as something real and as a substance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
