<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Timaeus on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Timaeus on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Republic Reviewed</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>PERSONS OF THE DIALOGUE= Socrates, Critias, Timaeus, Hermocrates.
Socrates Socrates= The chief theme of my yesterday’s discourse was the State—how constituted and of what citizens composed it would seem likely to be most perfect. We began by separating the husbandmen and the artisans from the class of defenders of the State.  We gave each one that single employment and art which was suited to his nature.
We said who we wanted to be our warriors who were to be guardians of the city against attacks from inside and out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Egypt and Atlantis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Critias I will tell an old-world story which I heard from an aged man; for Critias, at the time of telling it, was, as he said, nearly 90 years old and I was about ten.
Now the day was that day of the Apaturia which is called the Registration of Youth wherein our parents gave prizes for recitations, and the poems of several poets were recited by us boys. Many of us sang the poems of Solon, which at that time had not gone out of fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timaeus&#39; Lecture</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Timaeus is the most of an astronomer amongst us. He has made the nature of the universe his special study.  TIMAEUS:
All men who have any degree of right feeling, at the beginning of every enterprise always call on God.
We also invoke the aid of Gods and Goddesses as we talk about the nature and creation of the universe. What is that which always is and has no becoming?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colors and Causes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05e/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05e/</guid>
      <description>Colors Color is the fourth class of sensible things, having many intricate varieties. It:
 is a flame which emanates from every body has particles corresponding to the sense of sight.  Of the particles coming from other bodies which fall upon the sight, some are smaller and some are larger, and some are equal to the parts of the sight itself.
Those which are equal are imperceptible, and we call them transparent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Created Beings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-04b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-04b/</guid>
      <description>Until the birth of time, the created universe was made in the likeness of the original. But since all animals were not yet created, it was still Unlike.
What remained, the Creator then proceeded to fashion after the nature of the pattern. The mind perceives the idea of an animal a certain nature and number. And so He thought that this created animal should have a like nature and number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heart, Lungs, and Liver</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>When all things were in disorder, God created all the measures and harmonies possible:
 in each thing in relation to itself, and in all things in relation to each other  Back then, nothing had any proportion except by accident. Nothing even was named.All these the creator first set in order, and out of them he constructed the universe, which was a single animal comprehending in itself all other animals, mortal and immortal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Motion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05c/</guid>
      <description>It is impossible:
 for anything to be moved without a mover. for a mover to exist without something which can be moved  Motion cannot exist where either of these are lacking. It is for impossible for these to be uniform. Therefore we must assign rest to uniformity and motion to the lack of uniformity.
Inequality is the cause of the nature which is lacking in uniformity. Why things when divided do not cease to pass through one another and to change their place?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senses</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05d/</guid>
      <description>What do we mean that &amp;ldquo;fire is hot?&amp;rdquo;
Fire has a dividing or cutting power on our bodies. We all feel that fire is sharp. We may further consider:
 the fineness of the sides of fire the sharpness of the angles of fire the smallness of the particles of fire, and the swiftness of the motion of fire  All this makes the action of fire violent and sharp, so that it cuts whatever it meets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Because of all these affections, the soul, when encased in a mortal body is at first without intelligence.
It becomes a rational being after:
 the flood of growth and nutriment abates the courses of the soul calm down and go their own way and become steadier as time goes on the several circles return to their natural form  their revolutions are corrected, and they call the same and the other by their right names    If he has true nurture or education, he attains the fulness and health of the perfect man, and escapes the worst disease of all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>The Creator rejoiced when He saw the creature which he had made moving and living, the created image of the eternal gods. He decided to make the copy still more like the original; and as this was eternal, he sought to make the universe eternal, so far as might be.
The nature of the Idea-being was everlasting.
But it is impossible to make the creature everlasting. So He resolved to have a moving image of eternity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-07b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-07b/</guid>
      <description>There are 3 kinds of soul within us, having each of them motions
 one part, if remaining inactive and ceasing from its natural motion, must necessarily become very weak, but that which is trained and exercised, very strong.  Wherefore we should take care that the movements of the different parts of the soul should be in due proportion.
God gave the sovereign part of the human soul to be the divinity of each one, being that part which, as we say, dwells at the top of the body, and inasmuch as we are a plant not of an earthly but of a heavenly growth, raises us from earth to our kindred who are in heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Diseases</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>The disorders of the soul depend on the body and originate as follows.
The disease of the mind is caused by a lack of intelligence. It has two kinds:
 madness ignorance  These are mental diseases. Excessive pains and pleasures are the greatest diseases of the soul.
For a man who is in great joy or in great pain, in his unreasonable eagerness to attain the one and to avoid the other, is not able to see or to hear anything rightly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Soul</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-03b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-03b/</guid>
      <description>The Creator conceived that a being which was self-sufficient would be far more excellent than one which lacked anything.
He did not think it necessary to give to such a being:
 hands, since it did not need to take anything or defend itself. feet, since the chakras would provide movement.  It was made to move in the same way and on the same spot, within his own limits revolving in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Elements</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-05b/</guid>
      <description>Creation is mixed, being made up of necessity and mind.
Mind is the ruling power. It persuaded necessity to bring the greater part of created things to perfection. This created the universe when the influence of reason got the better of necessity.
But if a person will truly tell of the way in which the work was accomplished, he must include the other influence of the variable cause as well. Wherefore, we must return again and find another suitable beginning, as about the former matters, so also about these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kundalini</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06b/</guid>
      <description>Kundalini The bones and flesh are made in the following phases.
 The generation of the marrow  The bonds of life which unite the soul with the body are made fast in the marrow. They are the root and foundation of the human race.
The marrow itself is created out of other materials.
God took such of the primary triangles that were:
 straight and smooth adapted by their perfection to produce fire and water, and air and earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants and Trees</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06c/</guid>
      <description>The life of mortal animal necessarily consisted of fire and breath. This allowed it to waste away by dissolution and depletion.
The gods contrived a remedy for this by creating another kind of animal.
These are the trees and plants which have been improved by cultivation.
Anciently, they were wild. They are a third kind of soul, which is seated between the midriff [heart chakra] and the navel [chakra].
It has no reason or mind, but only in feelings of pleasure and pain and the desires which accompany them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cause of Diseases: Pitta, Vata, Kapha</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/timaeus/chapter-06d/</guid>
      <description>Diseases arise from the unnatural excess or defect of the four natures out of which the body is compacted:
 earth fire water air  Disorders and diseases are produced when there is a wrong change in any of them:
 from its own natural place into another, or from any similar irregularity  Fire Diseases (Pitta in Ayurveda) When any of them is produced or changed in a manner contrary to nature, all sorts of changes occur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
