<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Principles of Supersociology on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Principles of Supersociology on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Social Topographic Behavior?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/social-topographic-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/social-topographic-behavior/</guid>
      <description>The Influence of Nature David Hume explained, in &amp;ldquo;National Characters&amp;rdquo;, that the natural environment of a society plays are role in its behavior. If a person were shaped by nature and nurture, then a society&amp;rsquo;s character is likewise shaped by its natural environment and the social cycles that nurture it.
Lord Bacon observed that the inhabitants of the warm south are generally more ingenious than those of the cold north. But where the native of a cold climate has genius, he rises to a higher pitch than can be reached by the southern wits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Society Organism and Social Networkism?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/social-networkism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/social-networkism/</guid>
      <description>Update: July 1, 2021  Overhauled on to harmonize Socrates with Hume and Smith   Our proposed science of pantrynomics is based on a new paradigm that sees individual entities as naturally part of a larger group of entities called a society.
Unlike normal definitions of society*, our definition describes a society* as a kind of metaphysical organism or mind that is made up of individual minds that agree to be part of that society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law of Social Cycles by Socrates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/law-social-cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/law-social-cycles/</guid>
      <description>According to Socrates, all societies have alternating cycles that begin with democracy that switches to tyranny, then aristocracy, then oligarchy, and finally back to democracy.
 A democracy is dominated by working-class people. Its positive aspect is social justice, while its negative is chaos and mob rule. This chaos leads people to want order, paving the way for tyranny A tyranny is dominated by warriors, leaders, and generals. Its positive aspect is peace and order, while its negative is abuse and corruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Common Interest?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/common-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/common-interest/</guid>
      <description>A soul manifests in the physical dimension through a physical body which can be thought of as its vehicle. To maintain itself, the soul develops two things:
 an ego which is needed to drive action in physical existence a sense called a conscience to regulate that ego to keep it within its dharma . This sense leads to personal morals or personal do&amp;rsquo;s and dont&amp;rsquo;s while the soul is in the duality of physical existence  Souls can then bind themselves into a new entity called a society which gets its own soul from the individual souls that make it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fourth Branch of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/fourth-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/fourth-branch/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the French Revolution, there have been three branches of government:
 Legislative - this branch is the most important branch as it creates the laws Executive - this branch executes laws and is the most visible one Judicial - this branch settles legal conflicts  If we view society as a family and the government as the parents, then the legislative and executive are the father, while the judicial is the mother.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Collective Wave of Human Desire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/collective-wave-of-desire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/principles/collective-wave-of-desire/</guid>
      <description>Buying and selling are rooted in waves of desires, which manifest objectively as prices-particles, just as a subjective beauty contest is decided by objective beauty-points from judges.
The ideas of GDP, Inflation, and Wealth then all extend from prices. Pantrynomics is the branch of Social Superphysics that deals with the changing waves of demand in order to match supply to it as quickly as possible by using social contracts and pool clearing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
