<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solutions from Economic Superphysics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solutions from Economic Superphysics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Swap Donations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/swap-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/swap-donations/</guid>
      <description>The pandemic has forced many people out of jobs and livelihoods. This has then led governments to turn to give dole-outs, pandemic loans, and stimilus checks.
Those measures try to ease the present burdens by transferring it to the future, from the reasoning and hope that the pandemic will be gone by then. That would then allow economies to go back to normal and the debts to be repaid.
However, our model * from 2015 shows that things will not get better anytime soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Reduce the 2020 Inflation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/2020-inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/2020-inflation/</guid>
      <description>Inflation surged in the second half of 2021 as the effect from the Covid which began in Q1 of 2020.
Covid forced the world to go on lockdown. Without a normal economy going, people started buying cryptocurrencies and NFTs with their savings (retail money). This caused a surge in the crypto prices. The money that was supposed to go to circulate the real economy was funneled into a virtual casino that inflated crypto prices without producing any real utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Modern Economic Table</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/modern-economic-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/modern-economic-table/</guid>
      <description>The Modern Economic Table is a flowchart invented by Francois Quesnay of the Physiocrats in the 18th century.
They say that it serves as data-driven proof of how real wealth is generated from agriculture and mining instead of from manufacturing and services which merely add value.
Of course, this is not totally true. It is true that raw materials and agriculture create value from scratch, as coming from Mother Nature. But the value added by manufacturing and services might just be as valuable, or even more valuable than the initial value created from Nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Restore the Gold Standard through Clearing Funds</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/gold-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/gold-standard/</guid>
      <description>Our proposed Multilateral Clearing system , derived from EF Schumacher and Adam Smith, can prevent currency attack and commodity speculation since:
 forward contracts will not be transferrable private currency trading will not be allowed  The job of providing liquidity and transferring working capital to the producers and exporters will be done instead by clearing funds.
But how will the system work for overseas investments?
Bank Gold If a Japanese investor wants to invest his JPY 1b in Vietnam using the current financial system, he will convert it to USD which the Vietnamese banks will convert into VND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alternative to GDP</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/gdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/gdp/</guid>
      <description>Pantrynomics will use Purchasing Power as its alternative to GDP, as explained in The Digression on the Value of Silver of the Wealth of Nations.
In that Digression, Adam Smith proved that money supply, as the prices of gold and silver, are not correlated with a society&amp;rsquo;s wealth or poverty. Instead, he wanted to prove that it is the money price of some rude produce relative to the main food grain (such as wheat), which is the clearest indicator of a society&amp;rsquo;s wealth or poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Investment Points?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/investment-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/investment-points/</guid>
      <description>We have moved this to Pantrypoints </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Points Banking?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/points-banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/points-banking/</guid>
      <description>In previous posts, we explained two alternative subsystems for a financial or monetary crisis:
 Basic Universal Revenue (BUR) for creating basic value as food Resource Credits (RC) for keeping companies afloat and avoiding bankruptcy  Both BUR and RC have a common denominator which is their values are pegged to rice so that BUR is in ultimately in grams of rice just as RC is in kilos of rice or wheat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Universal Revenue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/bur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/bur/</guid>
      <description>Universal Basic Income (UBI) became popular in 2016 after it was adopted by a few Western countries.
In UBI, money is given to poor people without any strings attached. This makes it a bit different from Conditional Cash Transfers (CCT) which imposes conditions that the poor must meet.
What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong with Universal Basic Income? In general, studies have found two flaws in UBI:
 It contributes little to alleviate poverty as a whole It is expensive to administer  Adam Smith, the founder of Economics, would be against UBI because:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pointtax as a Solution to Tax Evasion and Budget Deficits</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/pointtax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/pointtax/</guid>
      <description>We have moved this to Pantrypoints </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Tips on How to be Rich according to Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-be-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-be-rich/</guid>
      <description>In The Wealth of Nations, Adam Smith gave tips on wealth-generation:
1. Build capital, not expense Capital is anything that produces value. It can be a physical thing like a machine that produces a valuable product or a metaphysical thing like skill, knowledge, relationships, trust, and integrity. Expense is spending that does not return any value. An example is consumption.
Capitals are increased by parsimony and decreased by prodigality and misconduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prevent Economic Stagnation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-prevent-stagnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-prevent-stagnation/</guid>
      <description>Stagnation was a common phenomenon for large and developed countries. It usually happened when everyone achieved their natural state of wealth and is called a &amp;lsquo;stationary&amp;rsquo; state by Adam Smith:
In a country fully peopled.. the competition for employment would necessarily be so great as to reduce wages to the minimum needed to keep up the number of labourers. The population would not increase since the country is already populous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Solve Inequality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-solve-inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-solve-inequality/</guid>
      <description>According to Socrates, inequality takes root most commonly when a society transitions from intellectual rule to an oligarchy:
An Oligarchic State is not one, but two States, the one of poor, the other of rich men. They are living on the same spot and always conspiring against one another. Their fondness for money makes them unwilling to pay taxes. Under such a constitution, the same persons have too many callings. They are husbandmen, tradesmen, warriors, all in one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be a Wealthy Country</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-be-a-wealthy-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/solutions/how-to-be-a-wealthy-country/</guid>
      <description>3 Requirements for a Wealthy Country According to Adam Smith, there are three basic factors needed to be a major economic power:
 The people must have a good moral system The people must not be stupid The country must have access to the ocean  A fourth optional factor would be having natural resources.
Economic power is in the value that a society creates. This produced value is transmitted through exchange which is facilitated by morals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
