<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 2 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 2 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bondage to Sorrow</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/chapter-01b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/chapter-01b/</guid>
      <description>The burden of bondage to sorrow has its root in these hindrances.  It will be felt in this life, or in a life not yet manifested.
The burden of bondage to sorrow has its root in the darkness of:
 unwisdom selfishness lust hate attachment to sensation.  All these are, in the last analysis, absorption in the psychical self. This means sorrow, because it means the sense of separateness, and this means jarring discord and inevitable death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eight Means of Yoga</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>The 8 means of Yoga are:
  the Commandments
  the Rules
  right Poise
  right Control of the life-force
  Withdrawal
  Attention
  Meditation 8/ Contemplation.
  These eight means are to be followed in their order, in the sense which will immediately be made clear.
We can get a ready understanding of the first two by comparing them with the Commandments which must be obeyed by all good citizens, and the Rules which are laid on the members of religious orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yogic Practices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-2/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>1  The practices which make for union with the Soul are:
 fervent aspiration spiritual reading complete obedience to the Master.  “Fervent aspiration” means “fire”. In the Eastern teaching, it means the fire which gives life and light, and at the same time the fire which purifies.
We have, therefore, as our first practice, as the first of the means of spiritual growth, that fiery quality of the will which enkindles and illumines, and, at the same time, the steady practice of purification, the burning away of all known impurities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
