<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 1 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 1 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Human society is necessary. The philosophers expressed this by saying= &amp;ldquo;Man is `political&amp;rsquo; by nature.&amp;rdquo;
He cannot do without the social organization for which the philosophers use the technical term &amp;ldquo;town&amp;rdquo; (polis).
This is what civilization means.
The necessary character of human social organization or civilization is explained by the fact that God created and fashioned man in a form that can live and subsist only with the help of food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Earth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2a/</guid>
      <description>Philosophers speculated about the condition of the world in the books. They say that the earth is a sphere enveloped by water, like a grape floating on water.
The water withdrew from certain parts of (the earth), because God wanted to create living beings upon it and settle it with the human species that rules as (God&amp;rsquo;s) representative over all other beings. 14
The natural &amp;ldquo;below&amp;rdquo; of the earth is the core and middle of its sphere, the center to which everything is attracted by its gravity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Earth&#39;s northern quarter has more civilization than the southern</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>The first and the second of the cultivated zones have less civilization than the other zones.
The latter is interspersed with empty waste areas and sandy deserts and has the Indian Ocean to the east. The nations and populations of the first and second zones are few.
The third, fourth, and subsequent zones are just the opposite.
Waste areas there are few. Sandy deserts also are few or non-existent. The nations and populations are tremendous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seven Zones</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2c/</guid>
      <description>The ancient philosophers divided the cultivated part of the earth in the north into seven zones by means of imaginary lines running from west to east. They maintain that these zones have different latitudinal extensions. This will be discussed in detail.
The first zone runs along the equator, north of it. South of it, there is only the civilization to which reference was made by Ptolemy. Beyond that are waste regions and sandy deserts, up to the circle of water which is called the Surrounding Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 1 Egypt, Yemen, Sri Lanka, Korea</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2d/</guid>
      <description>The Canaries from which Ptolemy began the determination of geographical longitude, are in the west. They are not part of the land mass of the first zone.
They lie in the Surrounding Sea. A number of islands constitute them. The largest and best known are three in number. They are said to be cultivated.
European Christian ships reached them in the middle of this century, fought with the inhabitants, plundered them, captured some of them, and sold some of the captives along the Moroccan coast where they came into the service of the ruler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 2 Ghana, Kashmir, China</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2e/</guid>
      <description>Zone 2 This is contiguous with the northern boundary of the first zone.
Opposite its western limit in the Surrounding Sea are two of Canary Islands. At the southernmost part of the first and second sections of the second zone, there is the land of Qamnuriyah.95
Then, to the east, there are the southernmost parts of the land of Ghanah. Then, there are the desert plains of the Zaghay Negroes. In the northernmost part, there is the desert of Nisar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 3</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2f/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2f/</guid>
      <description>Zone 3 This is contiguous with the northern boundary of Zone 2.
Section 1 This is about 1/3 of the way from the southernmost part of the zone, contains the Atlas Mountain 1 07 which runs from the western part of the first section at the Surrounding Sea to the eastern end of the section.
This mountain is inhabited by innumerable Berber nations, as will be mentioned.108 In the region between this mountain and the second zone, at the Surrounding Sea, there is the Ribat (Monastery) Missah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 4</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2g/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2g/</guid>
      <description>This is contiguous with the northern part of Zone 3.
Its first section, in the west, contains a portion of the Surrounding Sea which, oblong in shape, extends from the southern to the northern boundary of the section. The city of Tangier is situated on it in the south. North of Tangier, the Mediterranean branches off from this portion of the Surrounding Sea in a narrow straits that is only twelve miles wide, Tarifa and Algeciras (lying) to the north of it and Qasr al-Majaz 143 and Ceuta to the south of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 5</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2h/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2h/</guid>
      <description>Most of the first section of the fifth zone is covered by water, except a small portion of the south and of the east. In this western region, the Surrounding Sea enters into the fifth, sixth, and seventh zones from the circle it describes around the zones.
Section 1 The portion to the south that is free from water has a triangular shape. It there touches Spain and comprises the remainder of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 6</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2i/</guid>
      <description>Section 1 Half of this section is mostly covered by the sea, which stretches eastward in a curving line along the northern part, then runs southward along the eastern part, and ends near the southern part of the section.
A portion of land in this part is not covered by the sea. It is similar in shape to a peninsula, formed by two arms of the Surrounding Sea. It is long and wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zone 7</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2j/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-2j/</guid>
      <description>The Surrounding Sea covers most of the seventh zone in the north (from the beginning) to the middle of the fifth section, where it touches the Qufaya Mountains that surround Gog and Magog.
Sections 1 and 2 These are covered by water, except where England is located, most of which lies in the second section.
In the first section, there is a corner of England which extends towards the north.The remainder, with a portion of the sea that encircles it, lies in the second section of the sixth zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The temperate and the intemperate zones</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-3/</guid>
      <description>The inuence of the air upon the color of human beings and upon many (other) aspects of their condition.
The cultivated region of that part of the earth which is not covered by water has its center toward the north, because of the excessive heat in the south and the excessive cold in the north. The north and the south represent opposite extremes of cold and heat.
It necessarily follows that there must be a gradual decrease from the extremes toward the center, which, thus, is moderate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of climate on human character</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Negroes generally:
 have levity, excitability, and great emotionalism. are eager to dance whenever they hear a melody are everywhere described as stupid  This is because:
 joy and gladness are due to expansion and diffusion of the animal spirit. sadness is due to the opposite contraction and concentration of the animal spirit.  Heat expands and rarefies air and vapors and increases their quantity. A drunken person experiences inexpressible joy and gladness, because the vapor of the spirit in his heart is pervaded by natural heat, which the power of the wine generates in his spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in food supply in the inhabited regions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-5/</guid>
      <description>Not all the temperate zones:
 are abundant with food, nor have inhabitants with a comfortable life  In some parts, the inhabitants enjoy an abundance of grain, seasonings, wheat, and fruits, because the soil is well balanced and good for plants and there is an abundant civilization.
In other parts, the land is strewn with rocks, and no seeds or herbs grow at all. There, the inhabitants have a very hard time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The types of human beings who have supernatural perception</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6a/</guid>
      <description>God has chosen certain individuals so that they might know Him. He made them connecting links between Himself and His servants.
They are to acquaint their fellow men with what is good for them and to urge them to let themselves be guided aright. They are to make it their task to keep (their fellow men) out of the fire of Hell and to show them the path to salvation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prophecy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6b/</guid>
      <description>Prophecy This world with all the created things in it has a certain order and solid construction. It shows nexuses between causes and things caused, combinations of some parts of creation with others, and transformations of some existent things into others, in a pattern that is both remarkable and endless.
Beginning with the world of the body and sensual perception, and therein first with the world of the visible elements, (one notices) how these elements are arranged gradually and continually in an ascending order, from earth to water, (from water) to air, and (from air) to fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dream visions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6c/</guid>
      <description>Real dream vision is an awareness on the part of the rational soul in its spiritual essence, of glimpse(s) of the forms of events. While the soul is spiritual, the forms of events have actual existence in it, as is the case with all spiritual essences.
The soul becomes spiritual through freeing itself from bodily matters and corporeal perceptions. This happens to the soul (in the form of) glimpse(s) through the agency of sleep, as we shall mention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soothsaying</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6d/</guid>
      <description>Soothsaying Soothsayers are persons who:
 gaze into transparent bodies, such as mirrors, bowls, or water, and examine the hearts, livers, and bones of animals, as well as those who cast pebbles and (date) pits  The real soothsayer does not need to make much of an effort in order to lift the veil of sensual perception. They, however, expend much effort to concentrate all sensual perception in one particular sense, the noblest one, which is vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerology (hisab an-nim)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-1/part-6e/</guid>
      <description>These are thus groups that lay down rules for the discovery of the supernatural:
 those that base their rules on the spiritual perceptions of the soul, as Muslims do those that base their rules on speculations on astral influences, as assumed by Ptolemy and the diviners those that base their rules on the guesswork and conjecturing of the diviners  These are nothing but mistakes which they throw out like snares for weakminded people This is called hisab an-nim 359 is mentioned at the end of the Politics of Aristotle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
