<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Important Vegetables on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Important Vegetables on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cereals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/grains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/grains/</guid>
      <description>CEREALS Cereals are the staple food of human beings. Cereals vary in their type, nutritional value and use.
In many languages the words for food are synonymous with the words for rice or wheat, which signifies the importance of these crops to the people.
Rice is an older crop than wheat. Cereals can be divide into two sections – cereals and grasses.
Some important cereals include:
 rice (paddy). The varieties include: áus – early, áshu áman – haemantik, autumn, pre-winter boro – summer wheat barley maize (corn) oats rye millet (bájrá) Some grass seeds include:  chiná káun kheri nárkát́ia shyámá kada máruya There are other edible grass seeds grown in India, but they have little food value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fertilizers and Research</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/fertilizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/fertilizers/</guid>
      <description>In the distant past, large animals used to go to predetermined places to die. Wild elephants still have this habit.
At such places, with the passage of time the bones of the animals became deposits of calcium sulphate and calcium carbonate. Wherever cretaceous animals lived in groups, limestone will be found.
In Assam, for example, limestone and petroleum can be found.
The fat of these huge animals became petroleum and the bones became limestone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiber Crops</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/fiber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/fiber/</guid>
      <description>Many different kinds of plants are grown as fibre crops. The fibres themselves vary in their consistency. Some fibres may be rough and are used for making mats, baskets, string, rope, etc., while others may be fine and are used for making clothing, etc.
Some of the more common fibre crops are:
 linseed (tisi, mosne, chikaná) jute (pát). The varieties include: miit́há pát́ tiitá pát́ (Mestá pát́ is not actually jute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowers and Trees</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/flowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/flowers/</guid>
      <description>FLOWERS Flowers are grown for their beauty, fragrance, essential oil, medicinal value and floral nectar, and some flower seeds can be eaten, used in cooking or processed to produce oil. For example, flowering plants like night jasmine (shephali or Nyctanthes arbortristis) and ghandharaj can be grown for their fragrant flowers, while sunflower has edible seeds and can be grown as an oil crop or roadside plant.
Flowering trees such as bakphul (Sesbania grandifloria) can also be grown along roadsides or in beauty spots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fruits, Nuts, Coffee, Tea</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/fruits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/fruits/</guid>
      <description>FRUITS Fruits are a vital part of the human diet and the easiest food for humans to digest.
Many fruits have a purifying and cleansing effect on the body, and most fruits are high in vitamins and very nutritious.
Some fruits have medicinal value as well.
In an emergency planting programme, cereals may be omitted from the human diet, but fruits should not be neglected. This shows their importance.
The following system can be used for planting big, medium and small categories of fruit trees:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Farming</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/agriculture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/agriculture/</guid>
      <description>Self-reliance is the main objective of our farming projects, hence they should be oriented towards production.
They should not be dependent on outside resources.
An integrated approach to farming should include:
 agriculture horticulture floriculture sericulture lac culture apiculture dairy farming animal husbandry irrigation pisciculture pest control fertilizers cottage industries energy production research centres water conservation.  This approach will help make farming projects self-reliant.
Agriculture Agriculture is the science of cultivating the soil and rearing animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicinal Plants</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/medicinal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/medicinal/</guid>
      <description>Numerous plants have known medicinal value, but other plants have less. More research should be done on all kinds of plants to discover whether or not they have medicinal value.
Some common medicinal plants include:
 bhrngaráj sushsni shák Asiatic pennywort (brahmi shák, thankuni, centella asiatica, L.) bahed́a (Terminalia chebula) Chinese chaste tree (nishinda, Vitex negundo, L.) ámŕa kálmegh gándál mint (pudiná, rocanii) scholar’s leaves (chátim) cinkona (Cinchona calisaya) giima shák ashwagandha bottle gourd (láu) aloe (ghrta kumárii) neem eucalyptus lemon nágdona asparagus (shatamulii) Bringaraj Bringaraj yields an oil (tel) which is useful as hair oil and as a treatment for the mentally ill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oilseed Plants</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/oilseeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/oilseeds/</guid>
      <description>Many plants have seeds which can be used to produce oil.
The oil extracted from the seeds of some of these plants is used to produce thickened oil, margarine and other products for human consumption.
The oil can also be burnt as a fuel; used to make cosmetics, shoe polish, furniture wax, medicines, hair oil, etc.; or refined for industrial purposes and used as machine oil, etc. The skin of some oil seeds, like groundnut, can also be removed to make flour to produce bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pest Control, Sericulture, Dairy, Fish</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/insects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/insects/</guid>
      <description>Pest Control In the rainy season in the last week of Shrávańa there is water in the paddy fields of Bengal.
In these fields we should cultivate fish, but fishermen should not be allowed to catch these fish while the paddy is still growing. Harmful insecticides or pesticides should not be used in these fields because they will kill the fish and pollute the water system.
Alternative pesticides like neem paste pesticide should be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulses</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/pulses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/pulses/</guid>
      <description>Pulses are a valuable source of protein, and indispensable in the vegetarian diet.
Most pulses are high in protein but have varying degrees of fat. They are easier to digest than casein, but less substantial.
They are more important as a food than cereals, and in emergency conditions, pulses are more essential for health. Some pulses are also used for oil production.
For farming, pulses are important as nitrogen fixers. The roots of all pulses should be left in the soil for some time after the harvest so that they can perform this function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Centres Research centres should be developed on all large farming projects and master units. The order of preference is:
 Agricultural research Biology a. first preference is zoology b. second preference is botany Chemistry  The following should be the research subjects:
 some nuts and fruits such as walnut, chestnut, almond, persimmon, cherry, apricot, grape, fig, pistachio and Paraguay coconut fibre plants such as jute, agave, hemp, okra, permanent and winter cotton, linseed, remi and pineapple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spices And Common Cooking Additives</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/spices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/spices/</guid>
      <description>Some common spices include:
 garlic (rasun) onion (piaz) ginger (ada) chilli (lanka) turmeric (halud) radish (mula) cardamon (eláchi) cinnamon (darucini) cumin (mongrela, kala jiira) basil (tulsi) nutmeg (jáyaphal, Myristika fragrans) anise (saonp, mauri) cloves (lavanga) Garlic (Rasun)  All the parts of the garlic are static. The Saḿskrta name for garlic is “rasona”. It has five out of the six tastes (rasas).
The 6 tastes are:
 tikta – neem (bitter) katu – chilli (hot and spicy) kaśava – plantain (alkaline) lavańa (salty) amala (acidic) madhu (sweet).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugar Crops</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/sugar-crops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/sugar-crops/</guid>
      <description>Sugar is an important part of the human diet. For many farmers, sugar crops are an essential source of income.
Sugar is also used in the production of alcohol, which has many medicinal and industrial uses.
Fermented sugar juice is used to prepare vinegar, and the residual materials from vinegar production are used to make yeast. Sugar foods come in many forms according to the type of sugar crop and the degree to which it is refined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Vegetables</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/seasonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/seasonal/</guid>
      <description>WINTER VEGETABLES Winter vegetables include:
 cauliflower cabbage sugar beet big onion tomato brinjal (eggplant, begun). There are two types:  thorny non-thorny.    The varieties include:
 makdo begun, snake brinjal (coolee begun), winter brinjal (Benarasi begun) lettuce broccoli carrot greens (shák)  Research should be done on winter vegetable such as cauliflower, cabbage, sugar beet and carrot to see if they can be grown all year round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tubers Winter Vegetables</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/creeping-tubers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/creeping-tubers/</guid>
      <description>Creeping Tuber Vegetables Vegetables which require direct sunlight should not be planted with creeping tubers because the creepers will cover the other plants.
For example, cauliflower needs direct sunlight, so it should not be planted with creepers.
Creeping tuber vegetables include:
 sweet juice potato (sháṋkálu) sweet potato (misht́i álu, rángálu, shakkarkand) elephantum potato (khámálu) Sweet juice potato and sweet potato are also sugar crops and are discussed in that section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable Crops</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/vegetables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-1/vegetables/</guid>
      <description>Vegetables are rich in vitamins and minerals.
People can be healthy without eating rice or bread, but they cannot remain healthy if they go without vegetables.
In the emergency food programme the 4 items are:
 Vegetables Potatoes Pulses Animal fodder for milk producing animals.  Potatoes contain carbohydrate, and in an emergency can be eaten as a substitute for cereals.
Vegetables have a variety of uses. They can be eaten raw, cooked, dried, pickled, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
