<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taxation and Budget on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taxation and Budget on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Federal Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01c/</guid>
      <description>Article 153. The Union shall have the power to institute taxes on.
 importation of foreign products; exportation to other countries of national or nationalized products; income and earnings of any nature; industrialized products; credit, foreign exchange and insurance transactions, or transactions relating to bonds or securities; rural property; large fortunes, under the terms of a supplementary law. Paragraph 1. The Executive Power may, observing the conditions and the limits established in law, alter the rates of the taxes enumerated in items I, II, IV and V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitations on the Power to Tax</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01b/</guid>
      <description>Article 150. Without prejudice to any other guarantees ensured to the taxpayers, the Union, the states, the Federal District and the municipalities are forbidden to:
 impose or increase a tribute without a law to establish it institute unequal treatment for taxpayers who are in an equivalent situation, it being forbidden to establish any distinction by reason of professional occupation or function performed by them, independently of the juridical designation of their incomes, titles or rights; collect tributes: a) for taxable events that occurred before the law which instituted or increased such tributes came into force; b) in the same fiscal year in which the law which instituted or increased such tributes was published; c) within the period of ninety days as from the date of publication of the law which instituted or raised such tributes, with due regard for the provision of letter b; use a tribute for the purpose of confiscation; establish limitations on the circulation of persons or goods, by means of interstate or intermunicipal tributes, except for the collection of toll fees for the use of highways maintained by the Government; institute taxes on: a) the property, income or services of one another; b) temples of any denomination; c) the property, income or services of political parties, including their foundations, of worker unions, of non-profit education and social assistance institutions, observing the requirements of the law d) books, newspapers, periodicals and the paper intended for the printing thereof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Revenue Sharing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01d/</guid>
      <description>Article 157. The following shall be assigned to the states and to the Federal District:
 the proceeds from the collection of the federal tax on income and earnings of any nature, levied at source on income paid on any account by them, by their autonomous government entities and by the foundations they institute and maintain; twenty per cent of the proceeds from the collection of the tax that the Union may institute in the exercise of the powers conferred on it by article 154, I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Tax System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-06/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: General Principles Article 145. The Union, the states, the Federal District and the municipalities may institute the following tributes:
 taxes; fees, by virtue of the exercise of police power or for the effective or potential use of specific and divisible public services, rendered to the taxpayer or made available to him; benefit charges, resulting from public works.  Paragraph 1. Whenever possible, taxes shall have an individual character and shall be graded according to the economic capacity of the taxpayer, and the tax administration may, especially to confer effectiveness upon such objectives, with due respect to individual rights and under the terms of the law, identify the property, the incomes and the economic activities of the taxpayer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
