<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Different Accounts which have been given of the Nature of Virtue on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Different Accounts which have been given of the Nature of Virtue on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Different Accounts On the Nature of Virtue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>1 Virtue is the temper of mind in the excellent and praise-worthy character. The nature of virtue may be reduced to three classes=
 The proper direction of all our feelings. These feelings may be virtuous or vicious according to=   their objects and how much they pursue them.  Virtue therefore consists in propriety.
2
Virtue is in the judicious pursuit of our own private interest and happiness through our selfish feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Concept of Suicide in Moral Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1c/</guid>
      <description>Suicide is rooted on pride  35  Suicide was never very common among the Greeks. I cannot remember any illustrious Greek hero who died by his own hand, other than Cleomenes.
Aristomenes&amp;rsquo; death is as much beyond the period of true history as that of Ajax. The common story of Themistocles&amp;rsquo; death was within that period.
However, it bears all the marks of a most romantic fable.
Of all the Greek heroes written by Plutarch, Cleomenes is the only one who died by suicide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Stoicism and other Propriety-based Moral Philosophies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1d/</guid>
      <description>46  The Stoics believed that those who had not attained perfect virtue might have some proficiency in virtue. They organized those proficiencies into different classes, according to their level of advancement. They called the imperfect virtues not as rectitudes, but as proprieties, fitnesses, decent and becoming actions.
 Cicero called these officia. Seneca more exactly called them convenientia  Cicero&amp;rsquo;s Offices wrote about the doctrine of those imperfect, but attainable virtues as &amp;rsquo;the practical morality of the Stoics&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems which make Virtue consist in Prudence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>55 Epicurus&amp;rsquo; system is the most ancient one that renders virtue as prudence. His enemies allege him to have borrowed his philosophy&amp;rsquo;s leading principles from his predecessors, particularly from Aristippus. Despite this, it is very probable that at least his way of applying those principles was original.
56 According to him, bodily pleasure and pain were the sole ultimate objects of natural desire and aversion. These required no proof. Pleasure might sometimes be avoided because it might cause us to=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems which make Virtue consist in Benevolence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>72  The system which makes virtue consist in benevolence is very ancient, but not as ancient as those of the Greeks.
It was the doctrine of most of the Eclectics, after the age of Augustus. They pretended to follow the opinions of Plato and Pythagoras. Thus, they are commonly known as Platonists.
 73  According to them in the divine nature, benevolence or love was the sole principle of action which directed all the other attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Licentious Systems</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>93 All these systems suppose that there is an essential distinction between vice and virtue. There is a real and essential difference between=
 the propriety and impropriety of any feeling, benevolence and any other principle of action, and real prudence and shortsighted folly or precipitate rashness.  All of them mainly contribute to=
 encourage the praise-worthy disposition, and discourage the blamable disposition.  94 It might be true that some of them=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philosophy of Stoicism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-2/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>19  Zeno was the founder of the Stoicism. According to him, every animal was by nature=
 recommended to its own care, and endowed with self-love  Nature causes every animal to preserve its existence as best as it can.
 20  The self-love of man embraced his entire mind and body and desired their preservation. Whatever supported this state was naturally chosen. Whatever destroyed it, was rejected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
