<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditations on First Philosophy on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditations on First Philosophy on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bodies Dispel the Dream</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>Bodies are much more clearly known to me than this puzzling ‘I’ that cannot be pictured in the imagination.
But I see that the trouble is that my mind likes to wander freely. It refuses to respect the boundaries that truth lays down. So I shall let it run free for a while, so that when I rein it in, it won’t be so resistant to being pulled back.
What are physical bodies?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cause and Effect</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-3b/</guid>
      <description>The natural light shows that the total cause of something must contain at least as much reality as does the effect.
Two things follow from this:
 Something cannot arise from nothing The more perfect is something that in itself has more reality. This cannot come from the less perfect.  This is plainly true for:
 ‘actual’ or ‘intrinsic’ reality, and the representative reality of ideas  This representative reality is the reality that an idea represents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material things and the real distinction between mind and body</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Do material things exist?
I perceive them clearly and distinctly as the subject matter of pure mathematics. ; so I at least know that they could exist, because anything that I perceive in that way could be created by God.
(The only reason I have ever accepted for thinking that something could not be made by him is that there would be a contradiction in my perceiving it distinctly.) My faculty of imagination, which I am aware of using when I turn my mind to material things, also suggests that they really exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-3c/</guid>
      <description>I think of:
 myself as a thing that thinks and is not extended the stone as a thing that is extended and does not think so that the two conceptions differ enormously  But they seem to have the classification ‘substance’ in common.
External objects come from external ideas, of which the only remaining idea is the the idea of God. ‘God’ means a substance that is infinite, eternal, unchangeable, independent, supremely intelligent, supremely powerful, which created myself and anything else that may exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between Our Sensations and the Things That Produce Them</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Rene Descartes 1639
FIRST MEDITATION: What can be called into doubt Some years ago, I was struck by:
 how many false things I had believed how doubtful was the structure of beliefs that I had based on them.  I realized that if I wanted to establish anything permanent in the sciences, I needed – just once in my life – to:
 demolish everything completely start again from the foundations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Essence Of Material Things</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-5/</guid>
      <description>What are God’s attributes?
What is the nature of my mind?
Such ideas have their own true and immutable natures, which are not under my control.
Even if there are not and never were any triangles outside my thought, still, when I imagine a triangle I am constrained in how I do this, because there is a determinate nature or essence or form of triangle that is eternal, unchanging, and independent of my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The existence of God</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-3/</guid>
      <description>I will now:
 shut my eyes block my ears cut off all my senses regard all my mental images of bodily things as empty, false and worthless  clear them out of my mind.   talk to myself examine myself more deeply know myself more intimately.  I am a thing that thinks:
 doubts, affirms, denies, understands some things, is ignorant of many others, wills, refuses.  This thing also imagines and has sensory perceptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth and falsehood</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I have realized that it is impossible that God would deceive me. God also has given me a faculty of judgment since God does not want to deceive me. Does this mean that I can never go wrong in my beliefs?
I make a lot of mistakes, which cannot have come from God. I realize that I am somewhere in between God and nothingness, or between supreme being and non-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The nature of the human mind, and how it is better known than the body</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/meditations/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday’s meditation raised serious doubts which I am unable to resolve.
I feel like I suddenly dropped into a deep whirlpool that tumbles me around that I canot stand on the bottom nor swim to the top.
However, I force my way up and try once more to carry out the project that I started yesterday.
I will set aside anything that is doubtful, and treating it as false. I will do this until I:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
