<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yogic Treatments on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yogic Treatments on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Acidity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/acidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/acidity/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Physical weakness Acidic or watery belching Dizziness Burning stomach Heartburn  Cause Oxygen inhaled in breathing enters the body and eventually turns into carbon dioxide. This carbon dioxide activates the digestive fluid-secreting glands.
It becomes impossible for the digestive fluid to digest the food properly when:
 food is taken irregularly and excessively day after day food is forced down with little or no appetite eating rich food becomes a steady habit  The undigested food turns into poisonous gas and the secreted digestive fluid gradually turns into harmful acid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Appendicitis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/appendicitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/appendicitis/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Swelling of the appendix and simultaneous unbearable pain in the abdominal region Fear of eating in spite of appetite  Causes  Aversion to physical labour Spending much time indoors Not taking part in sports and exercises Constipation Overeating  Treatment and Remedies Ásanas, mudrás, diet and dos and don’ts are the same as for dyspepsia patients.
Fibrous foods, all types of non-vegetarian foods, atapa rice (a fine-quality, very white type of rice) and all foods that cause constipation are strictly forbidden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/basics/</guid>
      <description>Proper health needs proper water drinking, sexual restraint, use of mud packs, sunbathing, fresh air, fasting, and mental purity
Water Drinking “Ápashcavishvabheśajii” – that is, “water is medicine for all diseases.” Truly, all types of disease can be relieved if one knows how to use water properly. To maintain the internal functions of the body without hindrance and to maintain the internal liquid balance, everyone should drink a sufficient quantity of water every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causes of Deafness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/deafness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/deafness/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms At the initial stage the patient hears a buzzing sound in the ears, and gradually all other sounds become indistinct to him.
Causes Deafness is not a disease by itself, unless it is congenital. It is an after-effect or reaction to some other ailment. Therefore one may find innumerable reasons behind deafness.
 Excessive use of quinine or similar poisonous medicines for a long time reduces the power of hearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diet for Goiter and Chronic Gland Swelling</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/goiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/goiter/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Inflammation of different glands and their surrounding areas, with simultaneous throbbing pain (this does not mean that pain will accompany the swelling in every case
In chronic cases it is natural for there to be no pain); occasional fever, and aggravation of the swelling during the fever, are the symptoms of this disease.
Causes  The liver and the spleen become weak due to chronic fever, and as a result, the immune defenses of the blood and lymph become diminished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gall Stones</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/gall-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/gall-stones/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms During stone formation:
 Pain on the right side of the navel region while eating Nausea after eating, and getting some relief after vomiting.  During chronic cases:
 loss of appetite physical debility  Causes The liver:
 secretes bile transforms chyle into blood purifies the the blood  The bile secreted from the liver is first stored in the gall-bladder and then is sent to the stomach and to the upper intestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing Diet for Cancer</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/cancer/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Tearing pain in the diseased region, a very intolerant temperament, hyper-sensitivity to touch, weakness and nausea, etc., are the main symptoms of this disease. In the preliminary stage of the disease the patient does not suffer from much pain, so in the beginning the disease is generally overlooked.
Causes Cancer is a disease of the whole body as well as a Tridośaja disease (i.e. involving disturbances of váyu, pitta and kapha).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing Diet for Hernia</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/hernia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/hernia/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms When undigested food builds up offensive internal gas puts a severe strain on the intestine which gets dislodged from its normal position. It opens a hold in the abdominal wall, and protrudes through it.
“Inguinal hernia” is the dislodged intestine coming out through an opening left in the canal to the scrotum.
“Femoral hernia” happens if it pushes out through the hole in the canal of nerve fibres and the muscular network controlling the legs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Diet for Gastric and Duodenal Ulcer</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/ulcer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/ulcer/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Indigestion and constipation Aversion to food Nausea after meals Pain in the stomach immediately or 1-2 hours after eating  Causes Partially-digested food or its juice passes from the stomach into the duodenum or upper intestine for further assimilation. There the digestive fluids with the help of bile from the liver and digestive juices from the pancreas accomplish the task of digestion.
But if, owing to defective working of these organs, the food is not completely digested here either, then it becomes spoiled and vitiated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Diet for Obesity Patients</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/obesity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/obesity/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Fat is important to the human body. Without fat, the natural activity of the bones and muscles could not be sustained for a single moment.
But when this very fat abnormally accumulates beyond the ordinary requirement of the body, it causes all the organs of the body to become incapacitated. This state is called obesity.
Causes  Lack of physical labour while eating lots of curd (yogurt), milk, butter and other high-calorie foods Eating large quantities of sweets and large quantities of mucus-producing foods (fish, tamarind, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Diet for Paralysis Patients</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/paralysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/paralysis/</guid>
      <description>The brain is the apparent controller of the body and its organs. With the help of afferent and efferent nerves, the brain receives impulses from and transmits them to all parts of the body.
The brain is divided into the right and left, with the right side of the brain controlling the left portion of the body and the left side of the brain controlling the right.
If due to high blood pressure or some other cause any portion of the brain’s nervous system becomes damaged, the part of the body controlled by that portion of the nervous system also becomes inoperative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies and Diet for Heart Disease</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/heart-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/heart-disease/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Strong beating sound in the chest Chest pain Breathing troubles Trembling of arms and legs, etc.  Causes There can be many reasons behind heart disease.
 Persons who keep their stomachs full and heavy need more blood for their stomachs. Their hearts have to overwork to provide this extra supply, making their hearts weak. Persons above 35 or 40 years old who consume a lot of non-vegetarian food out of greed may also suffer from heart disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies and Diet for High Blood Pressure</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/high-blood-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/high-blood-pressure/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Palpitation or pain in chest Lack of sound sleep Getting up a number of times at night to urinate Headache, dizziness, etc.  Causes  Usually those who do little physical labour but at the same time have a lot of fatty foods such as oil, ghee, etc., in their diets become victims of high blood pressure.  In the absence of any physical activity, fat is not broken down to be converted into heat or energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Abnormal Menstruation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/menstruation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/menstruation/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Normally, menstruation occurs once in a lunar month either every:
 28 days 29 days 30 days 26 days 27 days  These are according to the woman’s physical condition.
Usually menstruation lasts for 3-5 days. If the menstruation does not follow the above pattern according to the lunar month or if it lasts for a week or two; or if it sometimes occurs and sometimes does not; or if sometimes there is excessive bleeding and sometimes very little; then it may be termed “irregular menstruation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Asthma</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/asthma/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Difficulty in breathing caused partly by kapha and partly by váyu, usually felt towards the end of the night  Causes= Primarily Weakness of the Heart Chakra The Weakness of the Heart Chakra causes certain glands to weaken. These leads to the weakening of the fine bronchial tubes in the lungs be full of phlegm or mucus. This then obstructs the air.
Due to contraction of the weak bronchial tubes, the carbon dioxide of the body cannot come out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Diabetes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/diabetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/diabetes/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Incessant desire for urination burning sensation in the urinary tract Continuous thirst and sweet taste in the mouth Attraction of flies and ants towards the urine Headache, dizziness, pale and dry skin Becoming old in appearance at a young age Discomfort all over the body, etc Cataracts  Causes It is not always the case that sugar is present in the urine of diabetes patients. Diabetes with sugar in the urine is called “somaroga” or “madhumeha”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Dysentery</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/dysentery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/dysentery/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Repeated need to defecate but small movement Urge to strain while defecating Pain in the navel region, etc.  Causes Undigested half-cooked or uncooked meat or pulses or such things, when mixed with contaminated air in the stomach, cause an abnormal reaction in the intestine, and when the pitta, in spite of its best efforts, fails to digest these things, they come out in the form of loose movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Dysmenorrhoea (Cramps)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/dysmenorrhoea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/dysmenorrhoea/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Unbearable pain in the abdominal region, which begins before the commencement of the menstrual discharge and subsides as soon as the menstruation is over; irregular menstruation – too little or too much discharge  Causes Women who are adverse to physical labour, and who generally are from rich or upper middle-class families, are found suffering from this disease.
Due to lack of physical labour, or due to physical debility for any reason, the uterus and the ovaries become weak and cannot stand the pressure of blood during the menstrual period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Eczema</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/eczema/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/eczema/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  The secretion of fluids from sores itching, burning and throbbing regular yearly reappearance of the disease weakness of the body intermittent fever the eating away of the body down to the bones in extreme cases  Causes When the chyle, blood, flesh and fat, these four elements, all become disturbed, eczema appears. That is why this disease is worse and more harmful than leucoderma, or white leprosy.
When, due to weakness of the blood (this weakness is causes in most if not all cases by an attack of dysentery, particularly when this disease has been suppressed by application of some astringent medicine), the skin, flesh and fat become weak and their immune systems lose their strength, the germs of eczema are enabled to settle in a person’s body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Elephantiasis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/elephantiasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/elephantiasis/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Swelling of the legs, sometimes it attacks the arms too. The legs will grow to resemble those of elephants gradual thickening and wrinkling of the skin intermittent fever throbbing pain  Causes By the side of the arteries there is another system of vessels called shukrabahá náŕii which carry shukra, the most essential element of the body, to various body parts.
This shukra maintains the vitality of the nervous system, cells and glands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Gonorrhoea</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/gonorrhoea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/gonorrhoea/</guid>
      <description>This disease has no name in ancient Sanskrit. Because of its many similarities with urethritis (meha), this disease has been called “prameha” in Bengali.
Symptoms  Burning sensation while urinating The head of the penis swelling and becoming blood-red Passing of urine drop by drop or with a white or yellowish coloration seminal discharge of a white colour at first and yellowish in the later stage of the disease Sores around the head of the penis or inside the urinary passage; the penis swelling and becoming hard, etc  Causes According to medical practitioners, this disease is spread by a bacteria called “gonococcus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Hemorrhoids (Piles)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/haemorrhoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/haemorrhoids/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms “Developed piles” happens when contaminated gas and blood cannot get out of the body. This causes pressure on the veins and capillaries around the anus which becomes swollen. “External piles” are those outside the anus. &amp;ldquo;Internal piles&amp;rdquo; are those inside the anus.
“Bleeding piles” happen when blood oozes out of the developed piles under pressure of the Apána Váyu (vital energy controlling the lower abdominal organs).
“Dry piles” are piles which do not bleed but are instead painful, aching, burning or itching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Hydrocele</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/hydrocele/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/hydrocele/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Swelling of the scrotum Swelling and stiffening of the supporting ligaments and the blood vessels of the testicles Throbbing pain in the abdomen and in the scrotum Swelling of the scrotum due to accumulation of water, etc.  Causes This disease has internal and external causes:
 Shukra is stored in different glands. In these glands the life-carrying spermatozoa are produced from the shukra. A male’s testicles are such shukra-producing glands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Impotency and Infertility</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/infertility-male/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/infertility-male/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Quick discharge of semen Absence of any pleasurable nervous sensation Loss of reproductive capacity Fathering stillborn or short-lived children, etc.  Causes In most cases, if not all, impotency is a disease of the intemperate. There are various causes of this disease –
 When the seminal receptacle is already full, a passionate thought will bring a seminal discharge in no time. This is called mental impotency. Excessive accumulation of poisonous acid or pitta in the body can also effect a quick seminal discharge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Kidney Stones</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/kidney-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/kidney-stones/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Difficulty in urinating, passing of urine drop by drop instead of in a flow, stoppage of urine, blood in urine, etc., are symptoms of kidney-stones.
Causes The kidneys are located one on each side of the body, just below the liver and the spleen. When the liver, busy in its manifold duties, is not entirely capable of doing its job of purifying the blood, the remaining work is taken up by the kidneys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Leprosy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/leprosy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/leprosy/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Leprosy comes about when seven elements of the body are defective:
 chyle blood flesh fat bone marrow shukra  Leprosy has three stages.
Stage 1 The patient starts getting a feeling of discomfort all over the body, suffers from pain in the joints, and feels feverish at odd times.
Often he or she suffers from headaches, and sometimes sweats profusely, sometimes not at all. He or she also suffers from general debility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Leucoderma (White Leprosy)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/leucoderma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/leucoderma/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Leucoderma, though identified as a disease of the leprosy group, is not as fatal as leprosy, nor are secretions of fluid present.
That is why leucoderma is not a contagious disease. Leprosy attacks due to the disturbance of all seven elements of the body, and severely affects the entire body and mind within a very short time; but with leucoderma, usually only three elements – blood, flesh and fat – become disturbed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Leucorrhoea</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/leucorrhoea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/leucorrhoea/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms If one suffers from a discharge without any reason or provocation, it is called “leuccorrheoa.”
If the discharge is yellowish, reddish, blackish or foamy; or if it resembles the water in which meat has just been washed, it is called “bloody leucorrhoea.” And if the discharge is whitish, it is called “white leucorrhoea.” White leucorrhoea is very common.
Causes  Abortion or miscarriage; Constipation; Too many medicines or injections; Excessive sexual intercourse; and Anaemia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Premature Ejaculation (Seminal Weakness)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/premature-ejaculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/premature-ejaculation/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Discharge of semen before or after urination Discharge due to slight excitement or lustful thinking Decrease in memory power Headache Weakness of the legs (particularly of the knees)  Causes  Lack of proper sexual knowledge in adolescence or early youth Loss of semen through unnatural means Lack of restraint in married life Eating non-vegetarian food Using intoxicants from an early age Too little physical work and too much mental work Failing to follow the rules for fasting, bathing, taking water and sun-bathing  Treatment Treatment, diet, and dos and don’ts are the same as for impotence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Rheumatism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/rheumatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/rheumatism/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Swelling and contractures of the muscles or of different joints Acute pain or deformity of the swollen parts, etc.  Causes The causes of this disease are just like those of acidity. It occurs when the váyu bodily air is disturbed due to excess of poisonous acids in the body.
Treatment= Same as for acidity Rheumatism patients should drink a sufficient quantity of water (say four to five seers a day, but not much at a time), and should also observe the bathing and sun-bathing procedures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Syphilis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/syphilis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/syphilis/</guid>
      <description>This disease entered India a few centuries ago it from Europe. Many think that it first originated in dogs, and through contact with them the human body got infected.
Symptoms In the first stage, the disease will appear on the genitals as chancres, making the area around them quite hard.
Generally there is no secretion of pus or fluid from them. Then, the chancroid usually appears in the groin.
In most cases, these dry up or heal within a short time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Tuberculosis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/tuberculosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/tuberculosis/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Rattle of the throat in the morning and evening, hoarse voice, dry cough; or sputum with flecks of blood, or bloody vomiting; feeling slightly feverish from evening on; pain in the chest and back; general debility; and sweating at night – especially sweating of the head – are the main symptoms of tuberculosis.
Causes Tuberculosis germs are present in almost all human bodies. As long as the strength of the blood and vitality of the human body remain normal, tuberculosis germs cannot do any harm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Remedies for Wet Dreams</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/wet-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/wet-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms Occurrence of nocturnal emission more than four times a month; weakness on awakening, especially weakness of the knees; voice becoming rasping for one’s age, or cracking; swelling of cheeks and neck; frequent colds; etc., are symptoms of this disease.
Generally a portion of the semen produced in the body is surplus. In single men, this surplus semen is expelled with the urine or during three or four nocturnal emissions per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Treatment for Emaciation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/emaciation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/emaciation/</guid>
      <description>Causes  Babies produced from weak or sickly spermatozoa or ova will naturally be weak and emaciated. If the baby does not get sufficient mother’s milk it generally remains emaciated. When due to poverty parents are unable to provide enough milk for their children and consequently they are fed rice and pulse or plain barley from their early childhood, their digestive organs and livers in particular become very weak, and such children normally turn out emaciated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Treatment for Female Sterility And Infertility</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/infertility-female/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/infertility-female/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  A woman between the 16 and 35 being unable to conceive in spite of having sex  But often it is caused by the sterility of the male partner.
Causes  The ova, produced in the ovaries, pass through the Fallopian tubes to reach the uterus.  When the Fallopian tubes are weak, diseased, or blocked by contaminated matter, the ova either fail to reach the uterus or die on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symptoms of Displaced Uterus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/displaced-uterus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/displaced-uterus/</guid>
      <description>Symptoms  Heavy feeling in the abdomen Difficulty in defecating and urinating Anemia White leucorrhoea Pain in the back and waist Pain like the pain of cramps, etc.  Causes The uterus lies in a suspended position supported by a few ligaments behind the navel region. So it is not at all unusual for the uterus to get displaced or to change sides. Since the uterus is situated in between the urinary bladder and the rectum, any displacement of it may hinder defecation or urination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yama and Niyama</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/yama-niyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/yogic-treatments/yama-niyama/</guid>
      <description>Yama Yama is divided into five:
 Ahiḿsá – Not to inflict pain or hurt on any living thing in the world by thought, word or action Satya – The benevolent use of mind and words Asteya – To renounce the desire to acquire or retain the wealth of others. It means “non-stealing” Brahmacarya – To keep the mind always absorbed in Brahma (the Supreme Entity) Aparigraha – To renounce everything excepting the necessities for the maintenance of the body  Niyama Niyama is also divided into five:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
