<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indonesian Constitution Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indonesian Constitution Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citizens and Residents</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Chapter X. Citizens and Residents
Article 26
  Citizens shall consist of indigenous Indonesian peoples and persons of foreign origin who have been legalised as citizens in accordance with law.
  Residents shall consist of Indonesian citizens and foreign nationals living in Indonesia.
  Matters concerning citizens and residents shall be regulated by law. Requirements for naturalization
  Article 27
  All citizens shall be equal before the law and the government and shall be required to respect the law and the government, with no exceptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Article 31
 Every citizen has the right to receive education. Every citizen has the obligation to undertake basic education, and the government has the obligation to fund this. The government shall manage and organise one system of national education, which shall increase the level of spiritual belief, devoutness and moral character in the context of developing the life of the nation and shall be regulated by law. The state shall prioritise the budget for education to a minimum of 20% of the State Budget and of the Regional Budgets to fulfil the needs of implementation of national education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finances</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>Article 23
 The State Budget as the basis of the management of state funds shall be determined annually by law and shall be implemented in an open and accountable manner in order to best attain the prosperity of the people. The Bill on the State Budget shall be submitted by the President for joint consideration with the DPR, which consideration shall take into account the opinions of the DPD. In the event that the DPR fails to approve the proposed Bill on the State Budget submitted by the President, the Government shall implement the State Budget of the preceding year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Form of the State</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 1
  The State of Indonesia shall be a unitary state in the form of a republic.
  Sovereignty is in the hands of the people and is implemented according to this Constitution.
  The State of Indonesia shall be a state based on the rule of law. Type of government envisioned
  Chapter II. The People&amp;rsquo;s Consultative Assembly (Majelis Permusyawaratan Rakyat or MPR)
Article 2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministers of State</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5. Ministers of State Article 17
The President shall be assisted by Ministers of State which he will appointed and dismiss.
 Each Minister of State shall be responsible for a particular area of Government activity. The formation, change, and dissolution of ministries of state shall be regulated by law.  Chapter 6. Regional Authorities Article 18
 The Unitary State of the Republic is divided into provinces.   Those provinces shall be divided into regencies (kabupaten) and municipalities (kota) Each of which shall have regional authorities regulated by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Defence and Security</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Article 30
  Every citizen shall have the right and duty to participate in the defence and security of the State.
  The defence and security of the State shall be conducted through the total people&amp;rsquo;s defence and security system, with the Indonesian National Military (TNI) and the Indonesian National Police (POLRI) as the main force, and the people as the supporting force.
  TNI, consisting of the Army, Navy and Air Force, as an instrument of the State has the duty to defend, protect, and maintain the integrity and sovereignty of the State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People&#39;s Representative</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/id/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 7 The People&amp;rsquo;s Representative Article 19
 Members of the DPR shall be elected through a general election. The structure of the DPR shall be regulated by law. The DPR shall convene in a session at least once a year. Initiation of general legislation Article 20 The DPR shall hold the authority to establish laws. Each bill shall be discussed by the DPR and the President to reach joint approval.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
