<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kybalion on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kybalion on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Kybalion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/intro/</guid>
      <description>So little written on the Hermetic Teachings.
This work does not aim to explain any special doctrine, but to give a statement of the Truth that will reconcile the bits of occult knowledge that they may have acquired. Such bits are:
 apparently opposed to each other discourage and disgust the beginner.  Our intent is not to erect a new Temple of Knowledge, but to give a Master-Key to for him to open the many inner doors in the Temple of Mystery through the main portals he has already entered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hermetic Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The lips of wisdom are closed, except to the ears of Understanding&#34;—The Kybalion.  Ancient Egypt From old Egypt have come the fundamental esoteric and occult teachings which have so strongly influenced the philosophies of all peoples for several thousand years.
Egypt, the home of the Pyramids and the Sphinx, was the birthplace of the Hidden Wisdom and Mystic Teachings.
All nations have borrowed from her Secret Doctrine.
The following ancient countries liberally ate at the feast of knowledge which the Hierophants and Masters of Egypt so freely provided:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 Hermetic Principles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The Principles of Truth are Seven. The knower of these has the Magic Key before whose touch all the Doors of the Temple fly open.&#34;—The Kybalion  The 7 Hermetic Principles which is the basis or the entire Hermetic Philosophy are:
1. The Principle of Mentalism &#34;THE ALL IS MIND; The Universe is Mental.&#34;—The Kybalion.  THE ALL is the Substantial Reality underlying all the outward manifestations of:
 the Material Universe Life Matter Energy all that is apparent to our material senses  The All is SPIRIT which in itself is UNKNOWABLE and UNDEFINABLE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Transmutation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Mind, metals, and elements may be transmuted from state to state, degree to degree, condition to condition, pole to pole, vibration to vibration. True Hermetic Transmutation is a Mental Art.&#34;—The Kybalion.  The Hermetists were the original alchemists, astrologers, and psychologists, with Hermes asthe founder of these schools.
 from astrology has grown modern astronomy from alchemy has grown modern chemistry from the mystic psychology has grown the modern psychology  The ancients were not ignorant of what is known by the modern schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The All</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Under, and back of, the Universe of Time, Space and Change, is ever to be found The Substantial Reality—the Fundamental Truth.&#34;—The Kybalion.  &amp;ldquo;Substance&amp;rdquo; means: &amp;ldquo;that which underlies all outward manifestations; the essence; the essential reality; the thing in itself,&amp;rdquo; etc. &amp;ldquo;Substantial&amp;rdquo; means: &amp;ldquo;actually existing; being the essential element; being real,&amp;rdquo; etc. &amp;ldquo;Reality&amp;rdquo; means: &amp;ldquo;the state of being real; true, enduring; valid; fixed; permanent; actual,&amp;rdquo; etc.
Under and behind all outward appearances or manifestations, there must always be a Substantial Reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mental Universe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The Universe is Mental—held in the Mind of THE ALL.&#34;—The Kybalion.  THE ALL is SPIRIT! But what is Spirit?
THE ALL cannot be explained or defined. Spirit is simply a name that men give to the highest conception of Infinite Living Mind. It means:
 &amp;ldquo;the Real Essence&amp;rdquo; Living Mind, much superior to Life and Mind as we know them, just as the latter are superior to mechanical Energy and Matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divine Paradox</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The half-wise see the comparative unreality of the Universe and imagine that they can defy its Laws. They are vain and presumptuous fools. They are broken against the rocks and torn asunder by the elements by reason of their folly. The truly wise know the nature of the Universe. They use Law against laws. The higher against the lower. By the Art of Alchemy they transmute that which is undesirable into that which is worthy and thus triumph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The All In All</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&#34;While All is in THE ALL, it is equally true that THE ALL is in ALL. One who truly understands this has great knowledge.&#34;—The Kybalion.  The quote above leads to the Law of Paradox.
THE ALL is Inherent in its Universe, as embodied in the Principle of Correspondence.
The student is told to form a Mental Image of something, a person, an idea, something having a mental form. The image has its existence and being solely within his own mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planes Of Correspondence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&#34;As above, so below; as below, so above.&#34;—The Kybalion.  The Second Hermetic Principle says that there is a harmony, agreement, and correspondence between the several planes of Manifestation, Life and Being. The Universe may be divided into 3 great classes of phenomena, as the Three Great Planes with artificial and arbitrary divisions:
 The Great Physical Plane. The Great Mental Plane. The Great Spiritual Plane.  These are but ascending degrees of the great scale of Life, the lowest point of which is undifferentiated Matter, and the highest point that of Spirit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Vibration [Yin-Yang]</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Nothing rests; everything moves; everything vibrates.&#34;—The Kybalion.  The Principle of Vibration says that:
 Nothing is at rest Everything moves, vibrates, and circles.  This Principle was adopted by some of the early Greek philosophers in their systems. But, then, for centuries it forgotten.
But in the 19th Century science re-discovered this. In the 20th Century, scientific discoveries have added additional proof this truth.
Everything is in constant movement and vibration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Polarity [Yin-Yang]</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Everything is dual, has poles, has its pair of opposites. Like and unlike are the same. Opposites are identical in nature but different in degree. Extremes meet. All truths are but half-truths. All paradoxes may be reconciled.&#34;—The Kybalion.  This says that all manifested things have:
 two sides two aspects two poles pair of opposites with manifold degrees between the two extremes.  The human version of this is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Rhythm [Karma]</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>Everything flows out and in, has its tides, rising and falling. The pendulum-swing manifests in everything. The measure of the swing to the right, is the measure of the swing to the left; rhythm compensates&#34;—The Kybalion.  This says that in everything there is manifested:
 a measured motion a to-and-from movement a flow and inflow a swing forward and backward a pendulum-like movement a tide-like ebb and flow a high-tide and a low- tide between the two-poles manifest on the physical, mental or spiritual planes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Every Cause has its Effect; every Effect has its Cause; everything happens according to Law; Chance is but a name for Law not recognized; there are many planes of causation, but nothing escapes the Law.&#34;—The Kybalion.  The Sixth Hermetic Principle is the Principle of Cause and Effect. It says:
 nothing happens by Chance Chance is merely a term indicating cause existing but not recognized or perceived phenomena is continuous, without break or exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Gender is in everything; everything has its Masculine and Feminine Principles; Gender manifests on all planes.&#34;—The Kybalion.  The Principle of Gender says that there is Gender in everything. Masculine and Feminine principles are ever present and active in all phases of phenomena, on each and every plane of life.
The Hermetic sense of Gender is different from ordinary Sex.
&amp;ldquo;Gender&amp;rdquo; is Latin for &amp;ldquo;to beget, procreate, generate, create, produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Gender</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>In the past 10-15 years, the dual-mind idea has manifested itself so strongly. Psychology students have been struck by its persistence which has led to many plausible theories on the nature of these &amp;ldquo;two minds.&amp;rdquo;
Thomson J. Hudson grew popular in 1893 through his theory of the &amp;ldquo;objective and subjective minds&amp;rdquo; which he held existed in every individual.
Other writers have theories on:
 the &amp;ldquo;conscious and subconscious minds&amp;rdquo; the &amp;ldquo;voluntary and involuntary minds&amp;rdquo; the &amp;ldquo;the active and passive minds,&amp;rdquo; etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermetic Axioms</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hermes/kybalion/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The possession of Knowledge, unless accompanied by a manifestation and expression in Action, is like the hoarding of precious metals-a vain and foolish thing. Knowledge, like wealth, is intended for Use. The Law of Use is Universal, and he who violates it suffers by reason of his conflict with natural forces.&#34;—The Kybalion.  The Hermetic Teachings where always kept securely locked in the minds of its believers. But they were never intended to be stored away and kept secret.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
