<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The World - Treatise On Light on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The World - Treatise On Light on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cartesian Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Bodies that revolve always tend to move away from the centers they revolve from. But what direction do the stars and heavens tend towards?
A body that tends towards some direction does not mean that there is a thought or desire inside the body that carries it there. Instead, it is disposed to move there and that there is something . preventing it. &amp;ldquo;Tend&amp;rdquo; here means that the body is doing an effort to counteract such a resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardness and Liquidity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>There is an infinity of diverse motions that endure perpetually in the world. The greatest of these bring about the days, months, and years.
 The vapors of the earth never cease to rise to the clouds and descend from them. The air is forever agitated by the winds The sea is never at rest Springs and rivers flow ceaselessly The strongest buildings finally fall into decay Plants and animals are always either growing or decaying In short, all is changing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aethereal Elements and Their Qualities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>The philosophers assure us that above the clouds there is an aethereal air much subtler than ours.
That air is not composed of vapors of the earth, but is an element in itself. Above this air there is another, much subtler body, which they call the element of fire.
These two elements are mixed with liquids and solids of all the inferior bodies. This aethereal air and fire fill the in-between spaces* among the parts of the real air that we breathe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aethereal Universe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s think about a universe, beyond this one, confined in imaginary spaces which are infinite. Let us go back in time after all the matter has been created. At this point, the aethereal has filled all. We limit our space to the distance from the earth to the distant stars. This space has nothing other than the aether.
This aether can be divided into any parts and according to any shapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Creation of the Universe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>God put inequality and confusion among the parts of matter at the beginning.
The parts were then reduced to:
 one size, and one middling motion.  It thus took the form of the aethereal air.
Before it was moved by God, the hardest and most solid body in the world*.
 *Superphysics Note: As a triangle
 This equality could not be totally perfect because:
 There is no void at all in the aethereal world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between Our Sensations and the Things That Produce Them</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>There is a difference between our sensation of light and the objects that we see.Words come from human convention. They cause us to conceive of things. Our ears lets us hear the sound of the words Our eyes lets us see the faces of persons.
But it is our mind that gives us the meaning of those sounds and faces, having remembered what those sounds and that face signifyat the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ebb and Flow of the Sea</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>The whole mass of the Earth is caused by the presence of the moon, and also about some particular things that depend on that motion.
Consider the moon at B (where you can suppose it to be immobile in comparison with the speed at which the matter of the heaven below it moves), and consider that this matter of the heaven, having less space to pass through between O and 6 than between B and 6 (if the moon does not occupy the space between O and B), and consequently having to move a bit faster there, cannot fail to have the force to push the whole earth a little bit toward D, so that its center T moves away (as you can see) a little bit from the point M, which is the center of the small heaven ABCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Face of the Heaven of that New World Must Appear to Its Inhabitants Completely Like That of Our World</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>How do the inhabitants of Earth see the face of their heaven as wholly like that of ours?
First, they must see the body marked S as completely full of light and like our sun, given that that body sends rays from all points of its surface toward their eyes.
Because it is much closer to them than the stars, it must appear much greater to them. The parts of the small heaven ABCD that turns about the earth offer some resistance to those rays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Heat and Light</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Light naturally exists in the stars and flame, or fire.
Movement in Parts When flame burns wood, we see that it moves the small parts of the wood and separates them from one another.
 This transforms the subtler parts into fire, air, and smoke, and leaving the grosser parts as ashes.  Body A cannot move Body B unless Body A itself were also moving [7].
It means that the flame&amp;rsquo;s body that acts against the wood is composed of small parts*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin and the Course of the Planets and Comets</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>The parts of the matter are very diverse. Most of them take the form of the aethereal fire or the aethereal air from breaking and dividing by collision with one another.
Nevertheless, among them are two sorts that had to retain the form of the third element:
 Those which had shapes so extended and so impeding that, when they collided with one another, it was easier for them to join together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Planets= the Earth and Moon</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Similarly, there are several things to note concerning the planets.
 They all tend toward the center of the system that contains them.  They can never arrive at those centers since the sun and fixed stars already occupy the center.
But, in order to make you understand distinctly in what places the planets should stop, look for example at the one marked ~ [Saturn], which I suppose to follow the course of the matter of the heaven toward the circle K</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Properties of Light</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>The principal properties of light are:
 It travels in all directions about bodies that are&amp;quot;luminous&amp;quot; It travels to any distance It travels in an instant It travels ordinarily in straight lines, as rays of light These rays coming from diverse points can come together at the same point These rays coming from the same point can go out toward different points These rays coming from diverse points and going toward diverse points, can pass through the same point without impeding one another They can also sometimes impede one another, to wit, when their force is very unequal and that of some of the rays is much greater than that of the others They can be diverted by reflection They can be diverted by refraction Their force can be increased Their force can be diminished, by the diverse dispositions or qualities of the matter that receives them  There are the principal qualities that one observes in light and that all agree with this action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Rules of Nature of the Aethereal Universe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>How could Nature untangle the confusion of the chaos after creation? What are the laws of nature that God has imposed on her?
God created the &amp;ldquo;laws of nature&amp;rdquo; which determine how changes take place in the universe.
Matter:
 has naturally diverse motions since the beginning when they were created, touches one another on all sides, without any void in between they collide with each other when they move.  Rule 1: State Continuity Rule 1: A body always continues in the same state unless a collision with others causes it to change that state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Void-- Why are we not Aware of Certain Bodies?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Why can&amp;rsquo;t we sense the aether? If we could sense it, we will free ourselves from an error with which we have had since childhood, when we believed that there were no other bodies around us except those that could be sensed.
Thus that, if the aether were one of them, then, we would sense it so very faintly that it could not be as material nor as solid as those other bodies [matter] that we sense more clearly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What gives objects their Weight?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/world/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>What is the weight of this earth?
There is a force that unites all its parts and that makes them all tend toward its center, according to its size and solidity.
The parts of the aether surrounding it turns much faster than its parts about its center. This also causes them to move away with more force from its center and consequently to push the parts of the earth back toward its center.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
