<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Life Map on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Life Map on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Affection Lines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-09-affection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-09-affection/</guid>
      <description>The lines of Affection or Marriage:
 are on the Mount of Mercury run from the percussion toward the inside of the palm.  In some hands, there are none of these lines. In others, many are seen.
From time immemorial, older palmists used them to show marriage.
Their value in practice is considerable if:
 used up to their limit, and in combination.  But used by themselves, as a hard-and-fast indication of marriage, they will lead to constant error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read the Affection Lines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-09b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-09b/</guid>
      <description>There are 2 ways to read the age on lines of Affection:
 What age the affection occurs  Use the Heart line as a lower mark, and the top of the Mount of Mercury as the upper.
This space must be subdivided into the average years of life, bringing the middle of the Mount at 36, and the top at 70 years. Thus:
 all lines of Affection appearing before the middle of the Mount occur before 36 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read the Heart Line</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-05b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-05b/</guid>
      <description>Classification Classifying the subject&amp;rsquo;s type is the first step.
The following is the order of those ruled by the head:
 Saturnian Lunarian Mercurian Jupiterian Martian  The following is the order of those ruled by the heart:
 Apollonian Venusian  Line Length The length of the line is the next step.
If the line rises normally but runs only a short distance and stops (32), it indicates that the subject will have serious difficulty at the time at which it ends, even if all the other lines go on to their normal length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Main, Minor, Chance Lines, Proportion, Two Hands</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-02b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-02b/</guid>
      <description>Aside from the Main lines, there are 7 Minor lines:
 the Ring of Solomon the Ring of Saturn the Girdle of Venus the lines of Affection the line of Mars the line of Intuition the Bracelets, three in number, but of which only the upper one is worthy of consideration  There is another Minor line, called the Via Lascivia, and supposed to be a sister line to the Mercury line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apollo Line</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-11-apollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-11-apollo/</guid>
      <description>THE line of Apollo is a vertical line rising, if long, from the upper part of the Mount of Moon, if short, higher in the hand, and running toward the Mount of Apollo, sometimes ending high on that Mount, and sometimes not reaching to it.
It has been variously called the line of the Sun, and the line of Brilliancy, and to it has been ascribed the gift of great artistic talents, wealth, and fame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Line of Life</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-07-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-07-life/</guid>
      <description>THE line of Life isthe third line which receives the Electric Current upon its entrance through the finger of Jupiter.
This line:
 rises at the side of the hand under the finger of Jupiter encircles the Mounts of Lower Mars and Venus in most cases ends under the Mount of Venus at the base of the hand.  The line of Life indicates:
 the health of the subject during the various periods of life his physical strength in general, and whether he lives during each period on his nervous force or relies upon muscular robustness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Saturn Line</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We make our fortunes and we call them fate.&amp;rdquo; - B. DISRAELI
THE line of Saturn is the fourth Main line which receives the Current.
 It is also called the &amp;ldquo;line of Fate&amp;rdquo; It rises at the base of the hand and runs upward  I hypothesize that the Current from the Life line passes into the Saturn line on its return from the brain. Thus, the Saturn line is read from the bottom upward  Its scale indicating the various years of life is in Chapter 4  Childhood is the extreme lower part of the line Old age is on the Mount of Saturn  The line of Saturn does not indicate health difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age As Indicated On The Lines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-04-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-04-age/</guid>
      <description>UP to this time, there has not been discovered any way of positively telling from the hand the present age of a subject.
There is no marking in the hand or on the lines which will, independent of everything else, indicate this. But by close observation of the general appearance, color, and skin, you can approximate the correct age within a few years.
Youthful skin is fresh looking, elastic, generally well colored, and has the appearance of vitality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defects and Repair</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-03-defects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-03-defects/</guid>
      <description>IN examining lines, note first the character of the lines themselves.
By this I mean their clearness, depth, evenness, and whether they are perfect or defective. If the latter is the case, what is the defect, does it cover the entire line or only a part of it, is the line repaired after the defect, does it regain its original depth and clearness, or does it show diminishing strength until it gradually fades away?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girdle of Venus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-13-girdle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-13-girdle/</guid>
      <description>Small lines, called Minor lines, do not appear in every hand. They occur often enough in the same locations to take them out of the class called chance lines as a division by themselves.
These Minor lines are not of great importance. They often have only one interpretation.
Girdle of Venus This rises between the fingers of Jupiter and Saturn and runs across the Mounts of Saturu and Apollo, ending between the fingers of Apollo and Mercury (523).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line of Intuition, Via Lascivia</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-08-intuition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-08-intuition/</guid>
      <description>The Lines of Influence are on the Mount of Venus and inside the Life line.
 Some of these run parallel to the Life line. Others run across the Mount (277).  These introduce factors outside of the subject himself as his &amp;ldquo;environment.&amp;rdquo;
The Hindus have an elaborate system of using these lines of Influence.
Only the lines which run inside the Life line are properly lines of Influence. These show that &amp;lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line of Intuition, Via Lascivia</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-14b-intuition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-14b-intuition/</guid>
      <description>The line of Intuition lies at the side of the hand near the percussion.
It rises on the Mount of Moon, and after describing a curve toward the Plain of Mars, ends on or near the Mount of Mercury.
It occupies the same position as the line of Mercury, but is distinguished from it by its curved formation, though I consider it practically a Mercury line. The presence of this line, if well marked, adds greatly to the intuitive faculty of a subject, though this may be only another name for Mercurian shrewdness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line of Mars, Ring of Solomon, Ring of Saturn</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-14-minor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-14-minor/</guid>
      <description>THE line of Mars rises on the lower Mount of Mars and runs inside of the Life line and very close beside it.
The two are sister lines, in fact, and in order to be in full strength the former must run so near to the Life line that it is manifestly related only to it and is not one of the lines of Influence on the Mount of Venus. This line was called the line of Mars because it rises upon one of the Martian Mounts, and its effect is to strengthen its sister line and to indicate a stronger constitution than is shown by even a deep Life line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Main, Minor, And Chance Lines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>No two hands are exactly alike because no two people are exactly alike in character, temperament, or in any other way.
Thousands of experiments have proven that in whatever way these persons differ, a corresponding change is found in the hand.
The nearer people are like each other, the nearer alike are the lines in their hands.
The hands of children are often similar with those of their parents. Even though you do not at first accept this hypothesis as being true, nevertheless give it a trial, and apply it faithfully and carefully to your line reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercury Line</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-12-mercury/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-12-mercury/</guid>
      <description>THE line of Mercury has been variously called=
 the line of Health the line of Liver the Hepatica  It should start on the Mount of Moon and run upward on the percussion to the Mount of Mercury, from which it takes its name (478).
This line is valuable as an indicator of the state of the digestive apparatus, the operation of the liver, and it also shows the presence of various maladies and conditions which may arise from the impairment of these most important functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showing The Various Judgments Drawn From The Hand</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/appendix/</guid>
      <description>Here is Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s chapter on Palmistry written around 350 B.C.This is the oldest treatise on palmistry. There has been progress since then
Being engaged in this third Part to shew what Judgments may be drawn according to Physiognomy, from the several Parts of the Body, and coming in Order to speak of the Hands, it has put me under a Necessity of saying something about Palmistry, which is a Judgment made of the Conditions, Inclinations, and Fortunes of Men and Women, from their various Lines and Characters which Nature has imprinted in the Hands, which are almost as various as the Hands that have &amp;rsquo;em.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heart Line</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-05-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-05-heart/</guid>
      <description>Upon entering our bodies through the finger of Jupiter, the first line reached by the Electric Current is the line of Heart. It is so named because it accurately reflects the heart&amp;rsquo;s condition and operation.
It deals with that central life-sustaining mechanism which pumps and controls the blood stream, which, by its quantity and quality, so largely affects our health and temperament.
The line of Heart rises from some point under or near the finger of Jupiter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life Map</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&#34;The soul contains in itself the event that shall presently befall it. The event is only the actualizing of its thought.&#34; Emerson  Lines found in certain places always indicate the same thing. Certain formations of these lines invariably show the good, bad, or weak operation of the things they indicate.
Lines show details of the life. When events have strongly impressed themselves on the brain, the lines have appeared, disappeared, broken, or changed in certain parts of the hand as these events have produced good or bad results for the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Line of Head</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-06-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/benham/palmistry/part-2/chapter-06-head/</guid>
      <description>The line of the Head is the second line which receives the Electric Current when it enters our bodies through the finger of Jupiter. It runs across the hand below the line of Heart.
It absolutely indicates the subject&amp;rsquo;s:
 amount of mentality kind of mentality power of mental concentration ability to exert self-control.  The mind plays a tremendous part in the shaping of our destiny.
No matter how fine the rest of the human machine may be, it can never operate perfectly unless there is a proper mental attitude.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
