<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Defense of the State on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Defense of the State on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Public Finances</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/title-05w/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/title-05w/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: General Rules
Article 163. A supplementary law shall make provisions for: (CA No. 40, 2002)
 public finances; foreign and domestic public debt, including the debt of the autonomous government agencies, foundations and other entities controlled by the Government; granting of guarantees by government entities; issuance and redemption of public debt bonds; financial supervision of governmental entities and entities owned by the Federal Government; foreign exchange transactions carried out by bodies and agencies of the Union, of the states, of the Federal District and of the municipalities compatibility of the functions of the official credit institutions of the Union, safeguarding all the characteristics and full operational conditions of those intended for regional development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Defense of the State</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Section 1: The State of Defense Article 136. The President of the Republic may, after hearing the Council of the Republic and the National Defense Council, decree a state of defense to preserve or to promptly re-establish, in specific and restricted locations, the public order or the social peace threatened by serious and imminent institutional instability or affected by major natural calamities.
Paragraph 1. The decree instituting the state of defense shall determine the period of its duration, shall specify the areas to be encompassed and shall indicate, within the terms and limitations of the law, the coercive measures to be in force from among the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Article 142. The Armed Forces, comprised of the Navy, the Army and the Air Force, are permanent and regular national institutions, organized on the basis of hierarchy and discipline, under the supreme authority of the President of the Republic, and are intended for the defense of the Country, for the guarantee of the constitutional powers, and, on the initiative of any of these, of law and order.
Paragraph 1. A supplementary law shall establish the general rules to be adopted in the organization, training and use of the Armed Forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/title-05z/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-05/title-05z/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
