<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science and Hypothesis on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science and Hypothesis on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ELECTRO-DYNAMICS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Ampère’s immortal work is &amp;ldquo;Théorie des phénomènes electro-dynamiques, uniquement fondée sur expérience&amp;rdquo;.
He had made no hypotheses; but as we shall not be long in recognising, he was mistaken; only, of these hypotheses he was quite unaware.
On the other hand, his successors see them clearly enough, because their attention is at- tracted by the weak points in Ampère’s solution. They made fresh hypotheses, but this time deliberately. How many times they had to change them before they reached the classic system, which is perhaps even now not quite definitive, we shall see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENERGY AND THERMO-DYNAMICS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>Energetics The difficulties raised by the classical mechanics have led certain minds to prefer a new system which they call Energetics.
Energetics took its rise in consequence of the discovery of the principle of the con- servation of energy. Helmholtz gave it its definite form. We begin by defining two quantities which play a fun- damental part in this theory.
They are kinetic energy, or vis viva, and potential energy. Every change that the bodies of nature can undergo is regulated by two experimental laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EXPERIMENT AND GEOMETRY</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>The principles of geometry are not experimental facts. Euclid’s postulate cannot be proved by experiment.  Think of a material circle, measure its radius and circumference, and see if the ratio of the two lengths is equal to π. What have we done?  We have made an experiment on the properties of the matter with which this roundness has been realised, and of which the measure we used is made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helmholtz’s Theory</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-13b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-13b/</guid>
      <description>I have dwelt upon the consequences of Ampère’s theory and on his method of explain- ing the action of open currents. It is difficult to disregard the paradoxical and artificial character of the propositions to which we are thus led. We feel bound to think “it cannot be so.”
Helmholtz has been led to look for something else. He rejects the fundamental hypothesis of Ampère— the mutual electro-dynamics.
action of two elements of current reduces to a force along their join.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HYPOTHESES IN PHYSICS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>PART IV. NATURE.
The Rôle of Experiment and Generalisation.—Exper- iment is the sole source of truth. It alone can teach us something new; it alone can give us certainty. These are two points that cannot be questioned. But then, if experiment is everything, what place is left for mathe- matical physics? What can experimental physics do with such an auxiliary—an auxiliary, moreover, which seems useless, and even may be dangerous? However, mathematical physics exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MATHEMATICAL MAGNITUDE AND EXPERIMENT</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Continuum cannot be explained by geometry. The geometer always seeks to represent shapes. But these are only instruments to him. He uses space in his geometry just as he uses chalk.
Too much importance must not be attached to accidents which are often nothing more than the whiteness of the chalk.
The pure analyst has not to dread this pitfall. He has disengaged mathematics from all extraneous elements, and he is in a position to answer our question:—“Tell me exactly what this continuum is, about which mathematicians reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NON-EUCLIDEAN GEOMETRIES</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>PART II. SPACE.
Every conclusion presumes premises which are either:
 obvious, or can be established only if based on other propositions  We cannot go back in this way to infinity, every deductive science, and geometry in particular, must rest upon a certain number of indemonstrable axioms.
All treatises of geometry begin therefore with the enunciation of these axioms. But there is a distinction to be drawn between them. Some of these, for example, “Things which are equal to the same thing are equal to one another,” are not propositions in geometry but propositions in analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPTICS AND ELECTRICITY</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Fresnel’s Theory The best example that can be chosen is the theory of light and its relations to the theory of elec- tricity.
The science of optics is more advanced than any other branch of physics because of Fresnel.
The theory called the theory of undulations forms a complete whole. But we must not ask from it what it cannot give us. The object of mathematical theories is not to reveal to us the real nature of things; that would be an unreasonable claim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RELATIVE AND ABSOLUTE MOTION</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>The Principle of Relative Motion Sometimes endeavours have been made to connect the law of acceleration with a more general principle. The movement of any sys- tem whatever ought to obey the same laws, whether it is referred to fixed axes or to the movable axes which are implied in uniform motion in a straight line. This is the principle of relative motion; it is imposed upon us for two reasons: the commonest experiment confirms it; the consideration of the contrary hypothesis is singularly repugnant to the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPACE AND GEOMETRY</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Let us begin with a little paradox. Beings whose minds were made as ours, and with senses like ours, but without any preliminary education, might receive from a suitably-chosen external world impressions which would lead them to construct a geometry other than that of Euclid, and to localise the phenomena of this external world in a non-Euclidean space, or even in space of four dimensions.
As for us, whose education has been made by our actual world, if we were suddenly transported into this new world, we should have no difficulty in referring phenom- ena to our Euclidean space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CALCULUS OF PROBABILITIES</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>What has that calculus to do with physical science? The questions I shall raise—without, however, giving them a solution—are naturally raised by the philosopher who is examining the problems of physics. So far is this the case, that in the two preceding chapters I have several times used the words “probability” and “chance.”
“Predicted facts can only be probable.”
However solidly founded a prediction may appear to be, we are never absolutely certain that experiment will not prove it false; but the probability is often so great that practically it may be accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CLASSICAL MECHANICS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>PART 3: FORCE
The English teach mechanics as an experimental science. Here on the Continent, it is taught always as a deductive and à priori science.
The English are right.
Why did the Continental scientists stay so long in theory?
On the other hand, if the principles of mechanics are only experimental, then they are merely approximate and provisory. It means we can have new experiments to modify or abandon them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fourth Geometry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-03b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-03b/</guid>
      <description>Among these explicit axioms there is one which seems to me to deserve some attention, because when we abandon it we can construct a fourth geometry as coherent as those of Euclid, Lobatschewsky, and Riemann.
To prove that we can always draw a perpendicular at a point A to a straight line AB, we consider a straight line AC movable about the point A, and initially identical with the fixed straight line AB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF MATHEMATICAL REASONING</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/science/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>PART I. NUMBER AND MAGNITUDE.
The very possibility of mathematical science seems an insoluble contradiction.
If this science is only deductive in appearance, from whence is derived that perfect rigour which is challenged by none?
If, on the contrary, all its propositions can be derived by formal logic, how is it that mathematics is not reduced to a gigantic tautology?
The syllogism can teach us nothing essentially new. If everything must spring from the principle of identity, then everything should be capable of being reduced to that principle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
