<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Soul on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Soul on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Socrates&#39; Story on Reincarnation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The Story of Er Socrates I will tell you of the heroic tale of Er the son of Armenius, a Pamphylian by birth.
He was slain in battle. Ten days later when the bodies of the dead are decomposing, his body was found unaffected by decay. It was carried home to be buried.
On the 12th day, as he was lying on the funeral pile, he returned to life and told them what he had seen in the other world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Immortality of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Socrates Imitation is only a kind of play or sport. The tragic poets are imitators in the highest degree. Imitation is concerned with that which is thrice removed from the truth. Imitation addresses what faculty in man?
A body is large when seen near and appears small when seen from afar. The same object appears straight when seen out of the water, and crooked when in the water. The concave becomes convex due to the illusion on colours to which the sight is liable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Immortality of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The Just Are Rewarded, and the Unjust are Punished in the Next Life Glaucon You have not mentioned the greatest prizes and rewards which await virtue.  Socrates Socrates= Virtue is great prize in itself. If there are greater prizes, then they must be of an inconceivable greatness. Forty years is surely a little thing compared with eternity. Then just say that there is nothing to reward virtue in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Nature</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Socrates Here, my dear Glaucon, is the supreme peril of our human state. Therefore, the utmost care should be taken.
Let each of us leave every other kind of knowledge and seek and follow one thing only.
This will help us learn and discern between good and evil. In this way, we can always and everywhere choose the better life.
We should consider the bearing of all these things on virtue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shallow Philosophy and Religion as Poetry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-10/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Imitation is Thrice removed from the truth. Socrates One of the many excellences in our State is the rejection of imitative poetry. All poetical imitations are ruinous to the understanding of the hearers. The knowledge of their true nature is the only antidote to them.
I have always had an awe and love of Homer. He is the great teacher of the poets on tragedy. But a man is not to be revered more than the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
