<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Considerations on Gravitation on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Considerations on Gravitation on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Considerations on Gravitation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/part-8/</guid>
      <description>Every theory of gravitation has to deal with the problem of the influence, exerted on this force by the motion of the heavenly bodies. The solution is easily deduced from our equations; it takes the same form as the corresponding solution for the electromagnetic actions between charged particles.[4]
I shall only treat the case of a body A, revolving around a central body M, this latter having a given constant velocity p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations on Gravitation by Lorentz</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Can we ascribe gravity to a certain state of the aether?
A theory of universal attraction, founded on such an assumption, would take the simplest form if new hypotheses about the aether could be avoided, i.e. if the two states which exist in an electric and a magnetic field, and whose mutual connection is expressed by the well known electromagnetic equations were found sufficient for the purpose.
If further it be taken for granted that only electrically charged particles or ions, are directly acted on by the aether, one is led to the idea that every particle of ponderable matter might consist of two ions with equal opposite charges — or at least might contain two such ions — and that</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations on Gravitation by Lorentz</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/lorentz/gravitation/part-5/</guid>
      <description>The following are insufficient to account for universal attraction:
 the states of the aether electromagnetic laws  Yet we can try to establish a theory of gravity similar to electricity with some features in common with it.
I use Mossotti&amp;rsquo;s idea which has been afterwards accepted by Wilhelm Weber and Zöllner.
They say every particle of ponderable matter consists of two oppositely electrified particles. Between 2 particles of matter, there will be:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
