<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bangsamoro Basic Law on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bangsamoro Basic Law on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bangsamoro Justice System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-10/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. Justice System in the Bangsamoro
It shall consist of:
 Shari’ah law for Muslims only Tribal justice system for the indigenous peoples Local courts and alternative dispute resolution systems.  For Muslims, the justice system in the Bangsamoro shall give primary consideration to Shari’ah, and customary rights and traditions of the indigenous peoples in the Bangsamoro.
Nothing herein shall be construed to operate to the prejudice of non-Muslims and non-indigenous peoples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangsamoro Transition Authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-16/</guid>
      <description>Article 16: Bangsamoro Transition Authority (BTA) Section 1. Transition Period
The transition or interim period to establish the Bangsamoro shall start upon ratification of this Basic Law.
It is ratified upon proclamation of the Commission on Elections, or its duly authorized officers, that plebiscite is in favor of creating the Bangsamoro. This will be confirmed by the GPH and MILF negotiating panels.
Transition period shall end upon the dissolution of the BTA as provided in this Basic Law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-09/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. Basic Rights in the Bangsamoro
In addition to the basic rights already enjoyed by the citizens residing in the Bangsamoro, the Bangsamoro Government shall guarantee the following enforceable rights:
a. Right to life and to inviolability of one’s person and dignity; b. Right to freedom and expression of religion and beliefs; c. Right to privacy; d. Right to freedom of speech; e. Right to express political opinion and pursue democratically political aspirations; f.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economy And Patrimony</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-13/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. Bangsamoro Economy and Social Justice
The Bangsamoro Government’s economic policies and programs shall be based on the principle of social justice.
Pursuant to this principle, the Bangsamoro Parliament shall legislate laws pertaining to the Bangsamoro economy and patrimony that are responsive to the needs of its people.
Sustainable Development Section 2. Equitable and Sustainable Development
In order to protect and improve the quality of life of the inhabitants of the Bangsamoro, development in the Bangsamoro shall be carefully planned, taking into consideration the natural resources that are available for its use and for the use of future generations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiscal Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-12/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. Fiscal Autonomy
The Bangsamoro:
 shall earn all the fund mentioned here can create its sources of revenues as provided in this law  It shall prepare its budget according with an annual appropriations law by the Bangsamoro Parliament. Section 2. Auditing
Bangsamoro Commission on Audit (BCA) is created to audit the public funds of the Bangsamoro. It can examine, audit, and settle all accounts pertaining to the revenue and receipts of, and expenditures or uses of funds and property, owned or held in trust by, or pertaining to the public funds utilized by the Bangsamoro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Principles And Policies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-06/</guid>
      <description>Article 6: Intergovernmental Relations Section 1. Asymmetric Relationship
The relationship between the Central Government and the Bangsamoro Government shall be asymmetric. This is reflective of the recognition of their Bangsamoro identity, and their aspiration for self-governance.
This makes it distinct from other regions and other local governments.
Section 2. Parity of Esteem
The Central Government and the Bangsamoro Government shall be guided by the principles of parity of esteem and accepted norms of good governance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identity and Purpose</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 1: NAME AND PURPOSE Section 1. Name - Bangsamoro Basic Law Section 2. Entity Name - Bangsamoro Section 3. Purpose – establish a political entity
Article 2: BANGSAMORO IDENTITY Section 1. Bangsamoro People
These are natives of Mindanao, the Sulu archipelago and its adjacent islands including Palawan, and their descendants, whether of mixed or3 of full blood at the time of conquest and colonization.
Section 2. Freedom of Choice. – The freedom of choice of other indigenous peoples shall be respected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-12b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-12b/</guid>
      <description>Loans Section 22. Foreign and Domestic Loans; Bills, Bonds, Notes and Obligations
 a. Loans, Credits, and Other Forms of Indebtedness  The contracting of loans, credits, and other forms of indebtedness by the Bangsamoro Government shall be for Bangsamoro&amp;rsquo;s development and the people&amp;rsquo;s welfare.
Subject to acceptable credit worthiness, such loans may be secured from domestic and foreign lending institutions, except foreign and domestic loans requiring sovereign guaranty, whether explicit or implicit, which would require the approval of the Central68 Government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powers Of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-05/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. Reserved Powers
Reserved powers are matters over which authority and jurisdiction are retained by the Central Government. The Central Government shall exercise the following reserved powers:
 Defense and external security; Foreign policy; Coinage and monetary policy; Postal service; Citizenship and naturalization;7 Immigration; Customs and tariff as qualified by Section 2(10), Article V of this Basic Law; Common market and global trade, provided that the power to enter into economic agreements given to the ARMM under R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Order And Safety</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-11/</guid>
      <description>Article 11: Public Order And Safety Section 1. Public Order and Safety
The Bangsamoro Government shall have primary responsibility over public order and safety within the Bangsamoro. There shall be cooperation and coordination between the Central Government and the Bangsamoro Government through the intergovernmental relations mechanism.
Section 2. Bangsamoro Police
There is hereby created a Bangsamoro Police which shall be organized, maintained, supervised, and utilized for the primary purpose of law enforcement and maintenance of peace and order in the Bangsamoro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rehabilitation And Development</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-14/</guid>
      <description>Article 14: Rehabilitation And Development Section 1. Rehabilitation and Development
The Bangsamoro Government, with funding from the Central Government, shall rehabilitate, reconstruct and development the Bangsamoro as part of the normalization process.
It shall formulate and implement a rehabilitation and development program that will address the needs of:
 MILF combatants/BIAF members decommissioned women auxiliary forces internally displaced persons poverty-stricken communities.  Section 2. Special Development Fund
The Central Government shall provide a Special Development Fund to the Bangsamoro for rehabilitation and development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shari’ah and Tribal Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-10b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-10b/</guid>
      <description>Section 10. Shari’ah Judicial and Bar Council
The Shari’ah Judicial and Bar Council shall recommend to the Judicial and Bar Council the applicants to be:
 judges in the Shari’ah District and Circuit Courts the justices of the Shari’ah High Court.  The Judicial and Bar Council shall give utmost consideration to the Shar’iah Judicial and Bar Council nominees in recommending appointees to the President.
The President shall issue the appointments within 90 days from the submission by the Judicial and Bar Council of the list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bangsamoro Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-07/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. Powers of Government
The powers of government shall be vested in the Bangsamoro Parliament, which shall exercise those powers and functions expressly granted to it in this Basic Law, and those necessary for or incidental to the proper governance and development of the Bangsamoro.
It shall set policies, legislate on matters within its authority, and elect a Chief Minister, who shall exercise executive authority in its behalf.24
Section 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zones of Joint Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-13b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/bbl/article-13b/</guid>
      <description>Section 18. Zones of Joint Cooperation
This law creates Zones of Joint Cooperation in the Sulu Sea and the Moro Gulf.
Its coordinates shall be defined by an ad hoc joint body composed of representatives.&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; from:
 the Department of Environment Natural Resources (DENR) the National Mapping and Resource Information Authority (NAMRIA) appropriate agencies of the Bangsamoro Government, of equal number. &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;  The Joint Body:
 shall be convened within 30 days after the ratification of this Basic Law ceases to exist after it has established the coordinates of the Bangsamoro territory, including the Bangsamoro Waters and the Zones of Joint Cooperation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
