<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Title 3: Duties, Human Rights And Guarantees on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Title 3: Duties, Human Rights And Guarantees on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-6/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-6/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>TITLE VI. SOCIOECONOMIC SYSTEM
Chapter I. Socioeconomic Order and the Function of the State in the Economy Reference to fraternity/solidarity Article 299 The economic regime of the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela is based on the principles of social justice, democratization, efficiency, free competition, protection of the environment, productivity and solidarity, with a view to ensuring overall human development and a dignified and useful existence for the community. The State, jointly with private initiative, shall promote the harmonious development of the national economy, to the end of generating sources of employment, a high rate of domestic added value, raising the standard of living of the population and strengthen the economical sovereignty of the country, guaranteeing the reliability of the law; the solid, dynamic, sustainable, continuing and equitable growth of the economy to ensure a just distribution of wealth through participatory democratic strategic planning with open consultation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
