<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Formation of Languages Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Formation of Languages Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nouns and Adjectives</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>THE assignment of names to denote objects creates nouns substantive. It is one of the first steps towards the formation of language.
Two savages, who had never been taught to speak, but had been bred up remote from the societies of men, would naturally begin to form that language by which they would endeavour to make their mutual wants intelligible to each other, by uttering certain sounds, whenever they meant to denote certain objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The English Language versus the French and Italian</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Language would probably have continued upon this footing in all countries, nor would ever have grown more simple in its declensions and conjugations, had it not become more complex in its composition, in consequence of the mixture of several languages with one another, occasioned by the mixture of different nations.
As long as any language was spoken by those only who learned it in their infancy, the intricacy of its declensions and conjugations could occasion no great embarrassment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Prepositions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>If invention of prepositions was more difficult.
Every preposition denotes some relation considered in concrete with the co-relative object. The preposition &amp;ldquo;above&amp;rdquo; denotes the relation of superiority, not in abstract, as it is expressed by the word superiority, but in concrete with some co-relative object.
In this phrase, for example, the tree above the cave, the word above expresses a certain relation between the tree and the cave, and it expresses this relation in concrete with the co-relative object, the cave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Simplification of Languages</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>In this way, language becomes simpler in its principles, just as it grows more complex in its composition, and the same thing has happened in it, which commonly happens with regard to mechanical engines.
All machines are generally, when first invented, extremely complex in their principles, and there is often a particular principle of motion for every particular movement which it is intended they should perform. Succeeding improvers observe, that one principle may be so applied as to produce several of those movements; and thus the machine becomes gradually more and more simple, and produces its effects with fewer wheels, and fewer principles of motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbs=  Personal and Impersonal</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/language/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Verbs must necessarily have been coëval with the very first attempts towards the formation of language. No affirmation can be expressed without the assistance of some verb. We never speak but in order to express our opinion that something either is or is not. But the word denoting this event, or this matter of fact, which is the subject of our affirmation, must always be a verb.
Impersonal verbs, which express in one word a complete event, which preserve in the expression that perfect simplicity and unity, 316 which there always is in the object and in the idea, and which suppose no abstraction, or metaphysical division of the event into its several constituent members of subject and attribute, would, in all probability, be the species of verbs first invented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
