<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 1 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 1 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meditation with an object</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/chapter-01b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/chapter-01b/</guid>
      <description>Meditation with an object follows these stages:
  exterior examining
  interior judicial action
  joy
  realization of individual being.
  In the practice of meditation, a beginning may be made by fixing the attention upon some external object, such as a sacred image or picture, or a part of a book of devotion. In the second stage, one passes from the outer object to an inner pondering upon its lessons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Master</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Spiritual consciousness may be gained by ardent service of the Master.  If we think of our lives as tasks laid on us by the Master of Life, if we look on all duties as parts of that Master’s work, entrusted to us, and forming our life-work; then, if we obey, promptly, loyally, sincerely, we shall enter by degrees into the Master’s life and share the Master’s power. Thus we shall be initiated into the spiritual will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/indian/yoga/book-1/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>OM: Here are the Instructions for Union.  Union [yoga] means union of:
 the individual soul with the Oversoul the personal consciousness with the Divine Consciousness  In union, the mortal becomes immortal, and enters the Eternal.
Therefore, salvation is:
 first, freedom from sin and the sorrow which comes from sin then a divine and eternal well-being, wherein the soul partakes of the being, the wisdom and glory of God.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
