<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Statute Of The International Court Of Justice Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Statute Of The International Court Of Justice Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Membership</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 1 The INTERNATIONAL COURT OF JUSTICE established by the Charter of the United Nations as the principal judicial organ of the United Nations shall be constituted and shall function in accordance with the provisions of the present Statute.
Chapter 1= Organization Of The Court Article 2 The Court shall be composed of a body of independent judges, elected regardless of their nationality from among persons of high moral character, who possess the qualifications required in their respective countries for appointment to the highest judicial offices, or are jurisconsults of recognized competence in international law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles 13-33</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>Article 13  The members of the Court shall be elected for nine years and may be re-elected; provided, however, that of the judges elected at the first election, the terms of five judges shall expire at the end of three years and the terms of five more judges shall expire at the end of six years. The judges whose terms are to expire at the end of the above-mentioned initial periods of three and six years shall be chosen by lot to be drawn by the Secretary-General immediately after the first election has been completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Competence Of The Court</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 34  Only states may be parties in cases before the Court. The Court, subject to and in conformity with its Rules, may request of public international organizations information relevant to cases before it, and shall receive such information presented by such organizations on their own initiative. Whenever the construction of the constituent instrument of a public international organi- zation or of an international convention adopted thereunder is in question in a case before the Court, the Registrar shall so notify the public international organization concerned and shall communicate to it copies of all the written proceedings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedure</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Article 39  The official languages of the Court shall be French and English. If the parties agree that thecase shall be conducted in French, the judgment shall be delivered in French. If the parties agree that the case shall be conducted in English, the judgment shall be delivered in English. In the absence of an agreement as to which language shall be employed, each party may, in the pleadings, use the language which it prefers; the decision of the Court shall be given in French and English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Opinions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/icj/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Article 65  The Court may give an advisory opinion on any legal question at the request of whatever body may be authorized by or in accordance with the Charter of the United Nations to make such a request. Questions upon which the advisory opinion of the Court is asked shall be laid before the Court by means of a written request containing an exact statement of the question upon which an opinion is required, and accompanied by all documents likely to throw light upon the question.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
