<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Universal Declaration of Human Rights Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Universal Declaration of Human Rights Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Preamble</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/article-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/article-01/</guid>
      <description>Preamble The foundation of freedom, justice and peace in the world is the recognition of:
 the inherent dignity, and the equal and inalienable rights of all members of the human family  Disregard and contempt for human rights have resulted in barbarous acts which have outraged the conscience of mankind.
The highest aspiration of the common people is a world where:
 humans have the freedom of speech there is freedom from fear and want  Human rights should be protected by the rule of law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preamble</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/article-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/article-22/</guid>
      <description>Article 22
Everyone, as a member of society:
 has the right to social security is entitled to realize the economic, social and cultural rights for his dignity and the free development of his personality.  These are done through national effort and international cooperation, according to the organization and resources of each State.
Article 23
Everyone has the right to:
 work free choice of employment just and favourable conditions of work protection against unemployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/article-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/human-rights/article-13/</guid>
      <description>Article 13
Everyone has the right to:
 freedom of movement and residence within the borders of each state. to leave any country, including his own, and to return to his country.  Article 14
Everyone has the right to seek and to enjoy in other countries asylum from persecution.
This right may not be invoked in the case of prosecutions genuinely arising from non-political crimes or from acts contrary to the purposes and principles of the United Nations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
