<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sentences from Pythagoras on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sentences from Pythagoras on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eurytus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/eurytus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/eurytus/</guid>
      <description>The Pythagorean Eurytus and his followers beheld the images of things themselves in numbers. They rightly attributed certain numbers to certain things, according to their peculiarity.
A particular number is the boundary of this plant, and again, another number of this animal; just as of a triangle 6 is the boundary, of a square 9, and of a cube 8.
The musician harmonizes his lyre through mathematical numbers. Likewise, nature harmonizes hers through her own natural numbers, orderly arranges, and modulates her productions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music According to Pythagoras</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/music/</guid>
      <description>P. 88. In this way, music was discovered by Pythagoras.
The principles of music are explained below:
Take two brazen chords, such as are used in harps. The chords made from sheep intestines are false or obnoxious to the change of the air.
A———————B C———————D | E
These chords should be perfectly equal and equally stretched, so as to be in unison. There may be only one sound, though there are two strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoric Ethical Sentences From Stobæus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/strobeus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/strobeus/</guid>
      <description>These have been omitted in the Opuscula Mythologica, etc. of Gale.
Do not even think of doing what should not be done. Choose rather to be strong in soul than in body.
Be persuaded that things of a laborious nature contribute more than pleasures to virtue.
Every passion of the soul is most hostile to its salvation. It is difficult to walk at one and the same time in many paths of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoric Sentences= The Symbols</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/symbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/symbols/</guid>
      <description>As we live through soul, it must be said that by the virtue of this we live well; just as because we see through the eyes, we see well through the virtue of these.
It must not be thought that gold can be injured by rust, or virtue by baseness.
We should betake ourselves to virtue as to an inviolable temple, in order that we may not be exposed to any ignoble insolence of soul with respect to our communion with, and continuance in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Select Sentences Of Sextus The Pythagorean</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/sextus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/sextus/</guid>
      <description>To neglect things of the smallest consequence, is not the least thing in human life.
The wise man, and the despiser of wealth, resembles God.
Do not investigate the name of God, because you will not find it. For every thing which is called by a name, receives its appellation from that which is more worthy than itself,[90] so that it is one 269 person that calls, and another that hears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The eternal essence of number</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/math/</guid>
      <description>P. 106. The eternal essence of number is the most providential principle of the universe, etc.
The great Syrianus noted down how the Pythagoreans philosophized about numbers, which I wrote in my Theoretic Arithmetic.
The Pythagoreans turned from the vulgar paths and delivered their philosophy in secret to those who were worthy to receive it. They expressed it through mathematical names.
Forms and numbers are things which are the first separated from impartible union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tetractys</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/tetractys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/tetractys/</guid>
      <description>The tetrad was called by the Pythagoreans every number, because it comprehends in itself all the numbers as far as to the decad, and the decad itself. The sum of 1, 2, 3, and 4, is 10.
Hence they called both the decad and the tetrad as every number.
The decad was a number in energy, but the tetrad was a number in capacity.
The sum of these four numbers 1, 2, 3, 4 made up the tetractys, in which all harmonic ratios are included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtues</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/virtue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/sentences/virtue/</guid>
      <description>P. 134. Not to step above the beam of the balance.
The 14th Symbol is explaind by Iamblichus:
“This symbol exhorts us to the exercise of justice, to the honoring equality and moderation in an admirable degree, and to the knowledge of justice as the most perfect virtue, to which the other virtues give completion, and without which none of the rest are of any advantage.
It also admonishes us, that it is proper to know this virtue not in a careless manner, but through theorems and scientific demonstrations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
