<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indian Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AMENDMENT OF THE CONSTITUTION</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-20/</guid>
      <description>5 [Power of Parliament to amend the Constitution and procedure therefor.]— 6 [(1) Notwithstanding anything in this Constitution, Parliament may in exercise of its constituent power amend by way of addition, variation or repeal any provision of this Constitution in accordance with the procedure laid down in this article.]  [(2)] An amendment of this Constitution may be initiated only by the introduction of a Bill for the purpose in either House of Parliament, and when the Bill is passed in each House by a majority of the total membership of that House and by a majority of not less than two-thirds of the members of that House present and voting, 8 [it shall be presented to the President who shall give his assent to the Bill and thereupon] the Constitution shall stand amended in accordance with the terms of the Bill: Provided that if such amendment seeks to make any change in— (a) article 54, article 55, article 73, 9 [article 162, article241 or article 279A] or</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizenship</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-02/</guid>
      <description>Citizenship at the commencement of the Constitution.—At the commencement of this Constitution, every person who has his domicile in the territory of India and— (a) who was born in the territory of India; or (b) either of whose parents was born in the territory of India; or (c) who has been ordinarily resident in the territory of India for not less than five years immediately preceding such commencement, shall be a citizen of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIRECTIVE PRINCIPLES OF STATE POLICY</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-04/</guid>
      <description>Definition.—In this Part, unless the context otherwise requires, “the State” has the same meaning as in Part 3.
  Application of the principles contained in this Part.—The provisions contained in this Part shall not be enforceable by any court, but the principles therein laid down are nevertheless fundamental in the governance of the country and it shall be the duty of the State to apply these principles in making laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUNDAMENTAL RIGHTS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-03/</guid>
      <description>Definition  In this Part, unless the context otherwise requires, “the State” includes the Government and Parliament of India and the Government and the Legislature of each of the States and all local or other authorities within the territory of India or under the control of the Government of India.
Laws inconsistent with or in derogation of the fundamental rights  (1) All laws in force in the territory of India immediately before the commencement of this Constitution, in so far as they are inconsistent with the provisions of this Part, shall, to the extent of such inconsistency, be void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OFFICIAL LANGUAGE</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-17/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER I. LANGUAGE OF THE U NION
Official language of the Union  (1) The official language of the Union shall be Hindi in Devanagari script.
The form of numerals to be used for the official purposes of the Union shall be the international form of Indian numerals.
(2) Notwithstanding anything in clause (1), for a period of fifteen years from the commencement of this Constitution, the English language shall continue to be used for all the official purposes of the Union for which it was being used immediately before such commencement: Provided that the President may, during the said period, by order 5 authorise the use of the Hindi language in addition to the English language and of the Devanagari form of numerals in addition to the international form of Indian numerals for any of the official purposes of the Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHORT TITLE, COMMENCEMENT AND REPEALS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-22/</guid>
      <description>Commencement.—This article and articles 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 60, 324, 366, 367, 379, 380, 388, 391, 392 and 393 shall come into force at once, and the remaining provisions of this Constitution shall come into force on the twenty-sixth day of January, 1950, which day is referred to in this Constitution as the commencement of this Constitution.  [394A. Authoritative text in the Hindi language.—(1) The President shall cause to be published under his authority,—</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEMPORARY, TRANSITIONAL AND SPECIAL PROVISIONS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-21/</guid>
      <description>Temporary power to Parliament to make laws with respect to certain matters in the State List as if they were matters in the Concurrent List.—Notwithstanding anything in this Constitution, Parliament shall, during a period of five years from the commencement of this Constitution, have power to make laws with respect to the following matters as if they were enumerated in the Concurrent List, namely:— (a) trade and commerce within a State in, and the production, supply and distribution of, cotton and woollen textiles, raw cotton (including ginned cotton and unginned cotton or kapas), cotton seed, paper (including newsprint), food-stuffs (including edible oilseeds and oil), cattle fodder (including oil-cakes and other concentrates), coal (including coke and derivatives of coal), iron, steel and mica; (b) offences against laws with respect to any of the matters mentioned in clause (a), jurisdiction and powers of all courts except the Supreme Court with respect to any of those matters, and fees in respect of any of those matters but not including fees taken in any court;  160but any law made by Parliament, which Parliament would not but for the provisions of this article have been competent to make, shall, to the extent of the incompetency, cease to have effect on the expiration of the said period, except as respects things done or omitted to be done before the expiration thereof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE PANCHAYATS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-09/</guid>
      <description>Definitions.—In this Part, unless the context otherwise requires  (a) “district” means a district in a State; (b) “Gram Sabha” means a body consisting of persons registered in the electoral rolls relating to a village comprised within the area of Panchayat at the village level; (c) “intermediate level” means a level between the village and district levels specified by the Governor of a State by public notification to be the intermediate level for the purposes of this Part;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE STATES</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-06/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER I.—GENERAL
Definition.—In this Part, unless the context otherwise requires, the expression “State” 5 [does not include the State of Jammu and Kashmir].  C HAPTER II.—T HE E XECUTIVE
Governors of States.—There shall be a Governor for each State:  [Provided that nothing in this article shall prevent the appointment of the same person as Governor for two or more States.] 154. Executive power of State.—(1) The executive power of the State shall be vested in the Governor and shall be exercised by him either directly or through officers subordinate to him in accordance with this Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE UNION AND ITS TERRITORY</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-01/</guid>
      <description>Name and territory of the Union.  India, that is Bharat, shall be a Union of States.
The territory of India shall comprise:
 the territories of the States   other territories as may be acquired.  Admission or establishment of new States  Parliament may by law admit into the Union, or establish, new States on such terms and conditions as it thinks fit.
Formation of new States and alteration of areas, boundaries or names of existing States  Parliament may by law:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE UNION AND ITS TERRITORY</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-19/</guid>
      <description>PART 19: MISCELLANEOUS
Protection of President and Governors and Rajpramukhs.—(1) The President, or the Governor or Rajpramukh of a State, shall not be answerable to any court for the exercise and performance of the powers and duties of his office or for any act done or purporting to be done by him in the exercise and performance of those powers and duties:  Provided that the conduct of the President may be brought under review by any court, tribunal or body appointed or designated by either House of Parliament for the investigation of a charge under article 61:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE UNION TERRITORIES</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-08/</guid>
      <description>[239. Administration of Union territories.—(1) Save as otherwise provided by Parliament by law, every Union territory shall be administered by the President acting, to such extent as he thinks fit, through an administrator to be appointed by him with such designation as he may specify. (2) Notwithstanding anything contained in Part VI, the President may appoint the Governor of a State as the administrator of an adjoining Union territory, and where a Governor is so appointed, he shall exercise his functions as such administrator independently of his Council of Ministers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Union</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-05/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 1: THE EXECUTIVE
The President of India  There shall be a President of India.
Executive power of the Union  (1) The executive power of the Union shall be vested in the President and shall be exercised by him either directly or through officers subordinate to him in accordance with this Constitution.
(2) Without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing provision, the supreme command of the Defence Forces of the Union shall be vested in the President and the exercise thereof shall be regulated by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/3rdscehd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/3rdscehd/</guid>
      <description>THIRD SCHEDULE [Articles 75(4), 99, 124(6), 148(2), 164(3), 188 and 219]  Forms of Oaths or Affirmations I Form of oath of office for a Minister for the Union:— “I, A. B., do swear in the name of God that I will bear true faith solemnly affirm and allegiance to the Constitution of India as by law established, 1 [that I will uphold the sovereignty and integrity of India,] that I will faithfully and conscientiously discharge my duties as a Minister for the Union and that I will do right to all manner of people in accordance with the Constitution and the law, without fear or favour, affection or ill-will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-10/</guid>
      <description>PART X THE SCHEDULED AND TRIBAL AREAS
Administration of Scheduled Areas and tribal areas.—(1) The provisions of the Fifth Schedule shall apply to the administration and control of the Scheduled Areas and Scheduled Tribes in any State 1 *** other than 2 [the States of Assam, 3 [ 4 [Meghalaya, Tripura and Mizoram.]]] (2) The provisions of the Sixth Schedule shall apply to the administration of the tribal areas in the States of Assam, 5 [, 6 [Meghalaya, Tripura and Mizoram].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-12/</guid>
      <description>PART XII FINANCE, PROPERTY, CONTRACTS AND SUITS
CHAPTER I.—F INANCE
1 [264. Interpretation.—In this Part, “Finance Commission” means a Finance Commission constituted under article 280.] 265. Taxes not to be imposed save by authority of law.—No tax shall be levied or collected except by authority of law. 266. Consolidated Funds and public accounts of India and of the States.—(1) Subject to the provisions of article 267 and to the provisions of this Chapter with respect to the assignment of the whole or part of the net proceeds of certain taxes and duties to States, all revenues received by the Government of India, all loans raised by that Government by the issue of treasury bills, loans or ways and means advances and all moneys received by that Government in repayment of loans shall form one consolidated fund to be entitled “the Consolidated Fund of India”, and all revenues received by the Government of a State, all loans raised by that Government by the issue of treasury bills, loans or ways and means advances and all moneys received by that Government in repayment of loans shall form one consolidated fund to be entitled “the Consolidated Fund of the State”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-13/</guid>
      <description>PART XIII TRADE, COMMERCE AND INTERCOURSE WITHIN INDIA
Freedom of trade, commerce and intercourse.—Subject to the other provisions of this Part, trade, commerce and intercourse throughout the territory of India shall be free. Power of Parliament to impose restrictions on trade, commerce and intercourse.— Parliament may by law impose such restrictions on the freedom of trade, commerce or intercourse between one State and another or within any part of the territory of India as may be required in the public interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-14/</guid>
      <description>PART XIV SERVICES UNDER THE UNION AND THE STATES
CHAPTER I.—S ERVICES
Interpretation.—In this Part, unless the context otherwise requires, the expression “State” 1 [does not include the State of Jammu and Kashmir.] Recruitment and conditions of service of persons serving the Union or a State.—Subject to the provisions of this Constitution, Acts of the appropriate Legislature may regulate the recruitment, and conditions of service of persons appointed, to public services and posts in connection with the affairs of the Union or of any State: Provided that it shall be competent for the President or such person as he may direct in the case of services and posts in connection with the affairs of the Union, and for the Governor 2 *** of a State or such person as he may direct in the case of services and posts in connection with the affairs of the State, to make rules regulating the recruitment, and the conditions of service of persons appointed, to such services and posts until provision in that behalf is made by or under an Act of the appropriate Legislature under this article, and any rules so made shall have effect subject to the provisions of any such Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-15/</guid>
      <description>PART XV ELECTIONS
Superintendence, direction and control of elections to be vested in an Election Commission.—(1) The superintendence, direction and control of the preparation of the electoral rolls for, and the conduct of, all elections to Parliament and to the Legislature of every State and of elections to the offices of President and Vice-President held under this Constitution 4 *** shall be vested in a Commission (referred to in this Constitution as the Election Commission).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-16/</guid>
      <description>PART XVI SPECIAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO CERTAIN CLASSES
Reservation of seats for Scheduled Castes and Scheduled Tribes in the House of the People.— (1) Seats shall be reserved in the House of the People for — (a) the Scheduled Castes; 2 [(b) the Scheduled Tribes except the Scheduled Tribes in the autonomous districts of Assam; and] (c) the Scheduled Tribes in the autonomous districts of Assam. (2) The number of seats reserved in any State 3 [or Union territory] for the Scheduled Castes or the Scheduled Tribes under clause (1) shall bear, as nearly as may be, the same proportion to the total number of seats allotted to that State 2 [or Union territory] in the House of the People as the population of the Scheduled Castes in the State 2 [or Union territory] or of the Scheduled Tribes in the State 2 [or Union territory] or part of the State or Union territory, as the case may be, in respect of which seats are so reserved, bears to the total population of the State 2 [or Union territory].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/in/part-18/</guid>
      <description>PART XVIII EMERGENCY PROVISIONS 352. Proclamation of Emergency.—(1) If the President is satisfied that a grave emergency exists whereby the security of India or of any part of the territory thereof is threatened, whether by war or external aggression or 1 [armed rebellion], he may, by Proclamation, make a declaration to that effect 2 [in respect of the whole of India or of such part of the territory thereof as may be specified in the Proclamation].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
