<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Noble Quran Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Noble Quran Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ABRAHAM (Ibrahim)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-014a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-014a/</guid>
      <description>4  We never sent any messenger except in the language of his people, to make things clear for them.  5  We sent Moses with Our signs: “Bring your people out of darkness into light, and remind them of the Days of Allah.” In that are signs for every patient and thankful person.”
 Moses said to his people, “Remember Allah’s blessings upon you, as He delivered you from the people of Pharaoh, who inflicted on you terrible suffering, slaughtering your sons while sparing your daughters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COLUMN (as-Saff)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-061/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-061/</guid>
      <description>1  O you who believe! Why do you say what you do not do? 3  It is most hateful to Allah that you say what you do not do. 4  Allah loves those who fight in His cause, in ranks, as though they were a compact structure.
 5  When Moses said to his people, “O my people, why do you hurt me, although you know that I am Allah’s Messenger to you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONSULTATION (ash-Shura)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-042a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-042a/</guid>
      <description>As for those who take masters other than Him: Allah is in charge of them, and you are not responsible for them.
  Thus We inspired you with an Arabic Quran, that you may warn the Central City and whoever is around it, and to warn of the Day of Assembly, of which there is no doubt; a group in the Garden, and a group in the Furnace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DECORATIONS (az-Zukhruf)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-043a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-043a/</guid>
      <description>How many a prophet did We send to the ancients? No messenger came to them, but they ridiculed him. We destroyed people more powerful than they, and so the example of the ancients has passed away.   9  And if you asked them, “Who created the heavens and the earth?” They would say, “The Mighty, the Knower created them.”
 10  He who made the earth a habitat for you, and traced pathways for you on it, that you may be guided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DETAILED (Fussilat)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-041a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-041a/</guid>
      <description>5  And they say, “Our hearts are screened from what you call us to, and in our ears is deafness, and between us and you is a barrier.
So do what you want, and so will we.”
 6  Say, “I am only a human like you; it is inspired in me that your God is One God. So be upright towards Him, and seek forgiveness from Him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIVORCE (at-Talaq)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-065/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-065/</guid>
      <description>1  O Prophet! If any of you divorce women, divorce them during their period of purity, and calculate their term.
Be pious and do not evict them from their homes, nor shall they leave, unless they have committed a proven adultery.
These are the limits of Allah—whoever oversteps Allah’s limits has wronged his own soul. You never know; Allah may afterwards bring about a new situation.
 2  Once they have reached their term, either retain them honorably, or separate from them honorably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FORGIVER (Ghafir)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-040a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-040a/</guid>
      <description>5  Before them the people of Noah rejected the truth, as did the confederates after them. Every community plotted against their messenger, to capture him. And they argued with falsehood, to defeat with it the truth. But I seized them. What a punishment it was!
 Thus the sentence of your Lord became realized against those who disbelieve, that they are to be inmates of the Fire.
  Those who carry the Throne, and those around it, glorify their Lord with praise, and believe in Him, and ask for forgiveness for those who believe: “Our Lord, You have encompassed everything in mercy and knowledge; so forgive those who repent and follow Your path, and protect them from the agony of the Blaze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GATHERING (at-Taghabun)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-064/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-064/</guid>
      <description>Everything in the heavens and the earth praises Allah. To Him belongs the Kingdom, and to Him all praise is due, and He is Able to do all things.
 2  It is He who created you. Some of you are unbelievers, and some of you are believers. And Allah perceives what you do. 3  He created the heavens and the earth with truth, and He designed you, and designed you well, and to Him is the final return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JOSEPH (Yusuf)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-012a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-012a/</guid>
      <description>2  We have revealed it an Arabic Quran, so that you may understand.
 3  We narrate to you the most accurate history, by revealing to you this Quran.
Although, prior to it, you were of the unaware.
 4  When Joseph said to his father, “O my father, I saw eleven planets, and the sun, and the moon; I saw them bowing down to me.” 5  He said, “O my son, do not relate your vision to your brothers, lest they plot and scheme against you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAN (al-Insan)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-076/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-076/</guid>
      <description>1  Has there come upon man a period of time when he was nothing to be mentioned?
 2  We created man from a liquid mixture, to test him; and We made him hearing and see- ing. 3  We guided him to the way, be he appreciative or unappreciative. 4  We have prepared for the faithless chains, and yokes, and a Searing Fire. 5  But the righteous will drink from a cup whose mixture is aroma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MARY (Maryam)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-019/</guid>
      <description>1-8  Zechariah called to the Lord in seclusion:
Zechariah “My Lord, my bones have become feeble. My hair is gray. I have never been disappointed in my prayer to you. I fear for my dependents after me. My wife is barren. So grant me an heir from Yourself, and to inherit the House of Jacob and make him pleasing.&amp;quot;  Allah “O Zechariah, We give you good news of a son, whose name is John, a name We have never given before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUHAMMAD (Muhammad)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-047a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-047a/</guid>
      <description>Those who disbelieve and repel from the path of Allah—He nullifies their works.
 2  While those who believe, and work righteousness, and believe in what was sent down to Muhammad—and it is the truth from their Lord—He remits their sins, and relieves their concerns.
 3  That is because those who disbelieve follow falsehoods, while those who believe follow the truth from their Lord. Allah thus cites for the people their examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noah (Nuh)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-071/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-071/</guid>
      <description>We sent Noah to his people: “Warn your people before there comes upon them a painful punishment.” 2  He said, “O my people, I am to you a clear warner. 3  Worship Allah and reverence Him, and obey me. 4  And He will forgive you of your sins, and reprieve you until a stated term. Allah’s term cannot be deferred once it has arrived, if you only knew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROHIBITION (at-Tahrim)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-066/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-066/</guid>
      <description>1  O prophet! Why do you prohibit what Allah has permitted for you, seeking to please your wives? Allah is Forgiving and Merciful.
 2  Allah has decreed for you the dissolution of your oaths.  3  The Prophet told something in confidence to one of his wives. But when she disclosed it, and Allah made it known to him; he communicated part of it, and he avoided another part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROSTRATION (as-Sajdah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-032a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-032a/</guid>
      <description>is from the Lord of the Universe.
Yet they say, “He made it up.” In fact, it is the Truth from your Lord, to warn a people who received no warner before you, that they may be guided.
 4  Allah is He who created the heavens and the earth and everything between them in six days, and then established Himself on the Throne. Apart from Him, you have no master and no intercessor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QAF (Qaf)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-050a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-050a/</guid>
      <description>1  Qaf.
By the Glorious Quran.
They marveled that a warner has come to them from among them. The disbelievers say, “This is something strange.
 3  When we have died and become dust? This is a farfetched return.” 4  We know what the earth consumes of them, and with Us is a comprehensive book. 5  But they denied the truth when it has come to them, so they are in a confused state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules on Divorce and Widows</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002d/</guid>
      <description>Divorced women shall wait by themselves for 3 periods.  It is not lawful for them to conceal what Allah has created in their wombs, if they believe in Allah and the Last Day. Meanwhile, their husbands have the better right to take them back, if they de- sire reconciliation. And women have rights similar to their obligations, according to what is fair. But men have a degree over them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHEBA (Saba’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-034a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-034a/</guid>
      <description>3  Those who disbelieve say, “The Hour will not come upon us.”
Say, “Yes indeed, by my Lord, it will come upon you. He is the Knower of the unseen.” Not an atom&amp;rsquo;s weight in the heavens and the earth, or anything smaller or larger, escapes His knowledge. All are in a Clear Record. 4  That He may recompense those who believe and do good works. Those will have for- giveness, and a generous provision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMOKE (ad-Dukhan)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-044a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-044a/</guid>
      <description>2  By the Enlightening Scripture. 3  We have revealed it on a Blessed Night— We have warned.
 4  In it is distinguished every wise command. A decree from Us. We have been sending messages.
 As mercy from your Lord. He is the Hearer, the Knower.
  Lord of the heavens and the earth and what is between them, if you know for sure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TA-HA (Ta-Ha)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-020a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-020a/</guid>
      <description>3  But to you to make only as a reminder for him who fears. revelation from He who created the earth and the high heavens.
 To Allah belongs everything in the heavens and the earth, and everything between them, and everything beneath the soil.
  If you speak aloud—He knows the secret, and the most hidden.
  Allah, there is no god but He, His are the Most Beautiful Names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ARGUMENT (al-Mujadilah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-058/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-058/</guid>
      <description>1  Allah has heard the statement of she who argued with you concerning her husband, as she complained to Allah. Allah heard your conversation. Allah is Hearing and Seeing. 2  Those of you who estrange their wives by equating them with their mothers—they are not their mothers. Their mothers are none else but those who gave birth to them. What they say is evil, and a blatant lie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CAVE (al-Kahf)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-018a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-018a/</guid>
      <description>4  Warn those who say, “Allah has begotten a son.” 5  They have no knowledge of this, nor did their forefathers. Grave is the word that comes out of their mouths. They say nothing but a lie.
 Perhaps you may destroy yourself with grief, chasing after them, if they do not be- lieve in this information.
  We made what is upon the earth an ornament for it, to test them as to which of them is best in conduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CHAMBERS (al-Hujurat)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-049a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-049a/</guid>
      <description>1  Do not place your opinions above that of Allah and His Messenger, and fear Allah. 2  O you who believe! Do not raise your voices above the voice of the Prophet, and do not speak loudly to him, as you speak loudly to one another, lest your works be in vain without you realizing. 3  Those who lower their voices before Allah’s Messenger—those are they whose hearts Al- lah has tested for piety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE COMPASSIONATE (ar-Rahman)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-055/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-055/</guid>
      <description>1  The Compassionate. 2  Has taught the Quran.
 3  He created man. 4  And taught him clear expression. The sun and the moon move according to plan.
 And the stars and the trees prostrate themselves.
  And the sky, He raised; and He set up the balance. taste My punishment and My warnings.
  We made the Quran easy to memorize. Is there anyone who would memorize?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CONSTELLATIONS (al-Buruj)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-085/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-085/</guid>
      <description>1  By the sky with the constellations. 2  And by the Promised Day.
 3  And by the witness and the witnessed.
 4  The People of the Trench were destroyed
 5  The fire supplied with fuel while they sat around it.
And were witnessing what they did to the believers. They begrudged them only because they believed in Allah the Almighty, the Praiseworthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE DEFRAUDERS (al-Mutaffifin)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-083/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-083/</guid>
      <description>Woe to the defrauders.
When they take a measure from people, they take in full.
 3  But when they measure or weigh to others, they cheat. 4  Do these not know that they will be resurrected for a Great Day when mankind will stand before the Lord of the World?
 Not at all. The record of the wicked is in Sijjeen.
  But how can you know what Sijjeen, a numerical book, is?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE DUNES (al-Ahqaf)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-046a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-046a/</guid>
      <description>3  We did not create the heavens and the earth and what lies between them except with rea- son, and for a finite period. But the blasphemers continue to ignore the warnings they receive.
 4  Say, “Have you considered those you worship instead of Allah? Show me which por- tion of the earth they have created. Or do they own a share of the heavens? Bring me a scripture prior to this one, or some trace of knowledge, if you are truthful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ENROBED (al-Muddathir)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-074/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-074/</guid>
      <description>1  O you Enrobed one. 2  Arise and warn 3  and magnify your Lord. 4  Purify your clothes. 5  And abandon abominations.
 And show no favor seeking gain.
  And be constant for your Lord.
  When 9  That 10  For the Trumpet is blown. Day will be a difficult day. the disbelievers—not easy. 11  Leave Me to him whom I created alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ENWRAPPED (al-Muzzammil)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-073/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-073/</guid>
      <description>1  O you Enwrapped one. 2  Stay 3  For up during the night, except a little. half of it, or reduce it a little.
 4  Or add to it; and chant the Quran rhythmically.
 5  We are about to give you a heavy message. vigil of night is more effective, and better suited for recitation.
In the daytime, you have lengthy work to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heifer (Al-Baqarah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002a/</guid>
      <description>This is the Book in which there is no doubt, a guide for the righteous.
 3  The righteous are those who:
 believe in the unseen perform the prayers give from what We have provided for them. believe 4  in what was revealed to you are certain of the Hereafter. guided 5  from their Lord.  These are the successful.
 6  The disbelievers will disbelieve whether you have warned them or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heifer (Al-Baqarah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002b/</guid>
      <description>22  Allah sustains you. Therefore, do not assign rivals to Allah.
 23  If you doubt the Prophet Mohammad, then call your witnesses if you are truthful.
 But 24  you will not—then beware the Fire whose fuel is people and stones, prepared for the disbelievers.   And give good news to those who believe and do righteous deeds; that they will have gardens beneath which rivers flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heifer (Al-Baqarah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-002c/</guid>
      <description>We gave Moses the Scripture, and sent a succession of messengers after him. And We gave Jesus son of Mary the clear proofs, and We supported him with the Holy Spirit.  Is it that whenever a messenger comes to you with anything your souls do not desire, you grew arrogant, calling some impostors, and killing others?
 And they said, “Our hearts are sealed.” Rather, Allah has cursed them for their ingrati- tude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE INEVITABLE (al-Waqi’ah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-056/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-056/</guid>
      <description>1  When the inevitable occurs, the low will be raised high.
The earth will be shaken with a shock.
the mountains are crushed and crum- 6. And they become scattered dust. 39. A 4  When
 And you become three classes.
  Those on the Right—what of those on the Right?
  9-10. And those on the Left—what of those on the Left? The forerunners are the nearest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE MOBILIZATION (al-Hashr)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-059a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-059a/</guid>
      <description>2  It is He who evicted those who disbelieved among the People of the Book from their homes at the first mobilization. You did not think they would leave, and they thought their fortresses would protect them from Allah. But Allah came at them from where they never expected, and threw terror into their hearts. They wrecked their homes with their own hands, and by the hands of the believers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE MOON (al-Qamar)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-054/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-054/</guid>
      <description>1  The Hour has drawn near, and the moon has split.
 2  Yet whenever they see a miracle, they turn away, and say, “Continuous magic.” 3  They lied, and followed their opinions, but everything has its time.
 4  And there came to them news containing a deterrent.
 5  Profound wisdom—but warnings are of no avail.
 So turn away from them. On the Day when the Caller calls to something terrible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE MOUNT (at-Tur)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-052/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-052/</guid>
      <description>1-6. By the Mount and the seething sea, in the frequented House with the elevated roof, in a Book inscribed with a published scroll.
7-8. The punishment of your Lord is coming.There is nothing to avert it.
 9  On the Day when the heaven sways in agitation. 10  And the mountains go into motion. 11  Woe on that Day to the deniers.
 Those who play with speculation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE NIGHT JOURNEY (al-Isra’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-017a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-017a/</guid>
      <description>1  Glory to Him who journeyed His servant by night, from the Sacred Mosque, to the Far- thest Mosque, whose precincts We have blessed, in order to show him of Our won- ders. He is the Listener, the Beholder. 2  And We gave Moses the Scripture, and made it a guide for the Children of Israel: Take none for protector other than Me. 3  The descendants of those We carried with Noah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE NIGHTLY VISITOR (at-Tariq)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-086/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-086/</guid>
      <description>1  By the sky and at-Tariq (Piercing Star).
 4  There is no soul without a Protector over it.
 5  Let man consider what he was created from.
 He was created from gushing liquid. Coming from between the backbone and the breastbones.
  He is certainly able to return him. 9  On the Day when the secrets are disclosed. 10  He will have no strength, and no supporter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE PEN (al-Qalam)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-068/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-068/</guid>
      <description>1  Noon. By the pen, and by what they inscribe.
 2  By the grace of your Lord, you are not insane.
 3  In fact, you will have a reward that will never end.
 4  And you are of a great moral character. 5  You will see, and they will see.
Which of you is the afflicted. Your Lord knows best who has strayed from His path, and He knows best the well-guided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE PROPHETS (al-Anbiya)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-021a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-021a/</guid>
      <description>1  Mankind’s reckoning has drawn near, but they turn away heedlessly.
 2  No fresh reminder comes to them from their Lord, but they listen to it playfully. 3  Their hearts distracted, the wrongdoers confer secretly, “Is this anything but a mortal like you? Will you take to sorcery, with open-eyes?”
 4  He said, “My Lord knows what is said in the heaven and the earth; and He is the Hearer, the Knower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ROCK (al-Hijr)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-015/</guid>
      <description>And they said, “O you who received the message, you are insane.”
  Why do you not bring us the angels, if you are truthful?”
  We do not send the angels down except with reason, and they will not be held back. 9  Surely We revealed the Message, and We will surely preserve it.
   10  We sent others before you, to the former communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ROLLING (at-Takwir)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-081/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-081/</guid>
      <description>1  When the sun is rolled up. 2  When the stars are dimmed.
 3  When the mountains are set in motion.
 4  When the relationships are suspended.
 5  When the beasts are gathered.
When the oceans are set aflame. When the souls are paired. When the girl, buried alive, is asked: what crime was she killed? 10  When the records are made public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE RUPTURE (al-Inshiqaq)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-084/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-084/</guid>
      <description>1  When the sky is ruptured. hearkens to its Lord, as it must.
 3  And when the earth is leveled out.
And casts out what is in it, and becomes empty.
hearkens to its Lord, as it must.
O man! You are laboring towards your Lord, and you will meet Him.
As for him who is given his book in his right hand.  He will have an easy settlement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SPREADERS (adh-Dhariyat)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-051/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-051/</guid>
      <description>1  By the spreaders spreading. 2  And those carrying loads. 3  And those moving gently. 4  And those distributing as commanded.
 5  What you are promised is true. 6. Judgment 7. By will take place. the sky that is woven. 8. You differ in what you say. 9  Averted from it is he who is averted. 10  Perish the imposters. 11  Those who are dazed in ignorance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE STAR (an-Najm)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-053/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-053/</guid>
      <description>1  By the star as it goes down. friend has not gone astray, nor has he erred.
 2  Your 3  Nor 4  It does he speak out of desire. is but a revelation revealed.
 5  Taught
The to him by the Extremely Powerful. one of vigor. He settled. While Then he was at the highest horizon. he came near, and hovered around. 9  He was within two bows’ length, or closer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE UNLEASHED (al-Mursalat)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-077/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-077/</guid>
      <description>1  [The Day of Judgement will be] unleashed in succession. It will:
 storm turbulently scatter far and wide separate decisively delivering a message, either excusing or warning  On that day:
 the stars will be obliterated the sky is fractured the mountains are blown away the messengers are alerted  It will be deferred until the Day of Decision.
And what will teach you what the Day of Decision is?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE WOMAN TESTED (al-Mumtahina)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-060/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-060/</guid>
      <description>1  Do not take My enemies and your enemies for supporters, offering them affection, when they have disbelieved in what has come to you of the Truth.
They have expelled the Messenger, and you, because you believed in Allah, your Lord. If you have mobilized to strive for My cause, seeking My approval, how can you secretly love them?
I know what you conceal and what you reveal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THRONGS (az-Zumar)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-039a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-039a/</guid>
      <description>3  Is not to Allah that sincere faith is due? As for those who take guardians besides Him, “We only worship them that they may bring us nearer to Allah.” Allah will judge between them regarding their differences. Allah does not guide the lying blasphemer.
 4  If Allah wanted to have a son, He could have selected from His creation at will. Glory be to Him. He is Allah, the One, the Prevailing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VICTORY (al-Fath)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-048a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-048a/</guid>
      <description>1  We have granted you a conspicuous victory. 2  That Allah may forgive you your sin, past and to come, and complete His favors upon you, and guide you in a straight path. 3  And help you with an unwavering support.
is He who sent down tranquility into the hearts of the believers, to add faith to their faith. To Allah belong the forces of the heavens and the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAYS OF ASCENT (al-Ma’arij)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-070/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-070/</guid>
      <description>1  Someone asked about the imminent torment.
The disbelievers cannot repel it.
Him the angels and the Spirit ascend on a Day the duration of which is 50,000 years. 4  Unto be patient, with sweet patience. 6. They see it distant. 7. But We see it near. 8. On the Day when the sky will be like molten brass. 9  And the mountains will be like tufted wool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOVEREIGNTY (al-Mulk)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-067/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-067/</guid>
      <description>Blessed is He in whose hand is the sovereignty, and Who has power over everything. 2  He who created death and life—to test you—as to which of you is better in conduct. He is the Almighty, the Forgiving. 3  He who created seven heavens in layers. You see no discrepancy in the creation of the Compassionate. Look again. Can you see any cracks?
 4  Then look again, and again, and your sight will return to you dazzled and exhausted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Family of Imran (Ali ‘Imran)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-003a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-003a/</guid>
      <description>2-3  Allah sent down to you:
 the Book with the Truth, confirming what came before it the Torah the Gospel.   4  He also sent down the the Criterion [of the Torah] before those, as guidance for mankind.
Those who have rejected Allah’s signs will have a severe punishment. Allah is able to take revenge.
 5  Nothing is hidden from Allah.
  6  He who forms you in the wombs as He wills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Family of Imran (Ali ‘Imran)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-003b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-003b/</guid>
      <description>28  Believers are not to take disbelievers forfriends instead of believers. Whoever does that has nothing to do with Allah, unless it is to protect your own selves against them. Allah warns you to beware of Him.
To Allah is the destiny.
 29  Say, “Whether you conceal what is in your hearts, or disclose it, Allah knows it.” He knows everything in the heavens and the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLOT (al-’Alaq)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-096/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-096/</guid>
      <description>In it descend the angels and the Spirit, by the leave of their Lord, with every command. 5  Peace
CLEAR EVIDENCE (al-Bayyinah)  Read: In the Name of your Lord who created. 2  Created 3  Read: 4  He And your Lord is the Most Generous. 5  Taught 6. In 8. But he considers himself exempt. to your Lord is the return. 9  Have 10  A man what he never knew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HISTORY (al-Qasas)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-028a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-028a/</guid>
      <description>4  Pharaoh exalted himself in the land, and divided its people into factions. He persecuted a group of them, slaughtering their sons, while sparing their daughters. He was truly a corrupter. 5  But We desired to favor those who were oppressed in the land, and to make them lead- ers, and to make them the inheritors.
 And to establish them in the land; and to show Pharaoh, Hamaan, and their troops, the very thing they feared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hud</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-011a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-011a/</guid>
      <description>2  That you shall worship none but Allah. “Iam a warner to you from Him, and a bearer of good news.” 3  “And ask your Lord for forgiveness, and re- pent to Him. He will provide you with good sustenance until a stated term, and will be- stow His grace on every possessor of virtue. But if you turn away, then I fear for you the punishment of a grievous Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRON (al-Hadid`)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-057/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-057/</guid>
      <description>death, and He has power over all things. 3  He is the First and the Last, and the Outer and the Inner, and He has knowledge of all things. 4  It is He who created the heavens and the earth in six days, then settled over the Throne. He knows what penetrates into the earth, and what comes out of it, and what descends from the sky, and what ascends to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KNEELING (al-Jathiyah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-045/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-045/</guid>
      <description>1  Ha, Meem. The revelation of the Book is from Allah. 3  In the heavens and the earth are proofs for the believers. 4  And in your own creation, and in the creatures He scattered, are signs for people of firm faith. 5  And in the alternation of night and day, and in the sustenance Allah sends down from the sky, with which He revives the earth after its death, and in the circulation of the winds, are marvels for people who reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIVESTOCK (al-An’am)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-006a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-006a/</guid>
      <description>2  Allah created you from clay, then decided a term—a term determined by him.
Yet the disbelievers doubt.
 4  Not one of their Lord’s signs comes to them, but they turn away from it.
 5  They denied the truth when it has come to them.
 But soon will reach them the news of what they used to ridicule.   Have they not considered how many generations We destroyed before them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LUQMAN (Luqman)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-031a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-031a/</guid>
      <description>Among the people is he who trades in distracting tales; intending, without knowledge, to lead away from Allah’s way, and to make a 4  Those  mockery of it. These will have a humiliating punishment.
 And when Our Verses are recited to him, he turns away in pride, as though he did not hear them, as though there is deafness in his ears. So inform him of a painful punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORIGINATOR (Fatir)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-035a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-035a/</guid>
      <description>3  O people! Remember Allah’s blessings upon you. Is there a creator other than Allah who provides for you from the heaven and the earth? There is no god but He. So how are you misled? 4  If they reject you, messengers before you were also rejected. To Allah all matters are returned. 5  O people! The promise of Allah is true; so let not the lowly life seduce you, and let not the Tempter tempt you away from Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REPENTANCE (at-Tawbah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-009a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-009a/</guid>
      <description>1  Give a declaration of immunity coming from Allah and His Messenger to the polytheists with whom you had made a treaty.
 2  Travel the land for 4 months.
 3  And a proclamation from Allah and His Messenger to the people on the day of the Greater Pilgrimage, that Allah has disowned the polytheists, and so did His Messenger. If you repent, it will be better for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RESURRECTION (al-Qiyamah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-075/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-075/</guid>
      <description>I swear by:
 the Day of Resurrection. the blaming soul.  Does man think that We will not reassemble his bones? 4  Yes, We are Able to reconstruct his fingertips. 5  But man wants to deny what is ahead of him. 6. He asks, “When is the Day of Resurrection?”
When vision is dazzled. And the moon is eclipsed. And the sun and the moon are joined together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAAD (Saad)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-038a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-038a/</guid>
      <description>1  Saad. By the renowned Quran.
Those who disbelieve are steeped in arrogance and defiance.
 3  How many generations have We destroyed before them? They cried out when it was too late to escape.
 4  And they marveled that a warner has come to them from among them. The disbelievers said, “This is a lying magician.”
 5  “Did he turn all the gods into one God?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE BEE (an-Nahl)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-016a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-016a/</guid>
      <description>1  The command of Allah has come, so do not rush it. Glory be to Him; exalted above what they associate.
 2  He sends down the angels with the Spirit by His command, upon whom He wills of His servants: “Give warning that there is no god but Me, and fear Me.”
 3  He created the heavens and the earth with justice. He is exalted above the associations they attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE BELIEVERS (al-Mu’minun)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-023a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-023a/</guid>
      <description>1  Successful are the believers who:
  2  are humble in their prayers.  3  avoid nonsense.  4  who work for charity.  5  who safeguard their chastity. from their spouses, or their dependents—for then they are free from blame.   But whoever seeks anything beyond that—these are the transgressors.
  Those who are faithful to their trusts and pledges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Christians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-005b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-005b/</guid>
      <description>14  We received the pledge of the Christians.
 But they neglected some of what they were reminded of. So We provoked enmity and hatred among them until the Day of Resurrection;  Allah will then inform them of what they used to craft.
 15  O People of the Book! Our Messenger has come to you, clarifying much of what you kept hidden of the Book, and overlooking much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CONFEDERATES (al-Ahzab)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-033a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-033a/</guid>
      <description>1  O Prophet! Fear Allah, and do not obey the unbelievers and the hypocrites. Allah is Knowledgeable and Wise. 2  And follow what is revealed to you from your Lord. Allah is fully aware of what you do. 3  And put your trust in Allah. Allah is enough as a trustee. 4  Allah did not place two hearts inside any man&amp;rsquo;s body. Nor did He make your wives whom you equate with your mothers, your actual mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CRITERION (al-Furqan)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-025a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-025a/</guid>
      <description>Blessed is He who sent down the Criterion upon His servant, to be a warning to humanity.
 2  He to whom belongs the kingdom of the heavens and the earth, who took to Himself no son, who never had a partner in His kingship; who created everything and determined its measure.
 3  And yet, instead of Him, they produce for themselves gods that create nothing, but are themselves created; that have no power to harm or benefit themselves; and no power over life, death, or resurrection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ELEVATIONS (al-A’raf)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-007a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-007a/</guid>
      <description>Scripture was revealed to you, so let there be no anxiety in your heart because of it. You are to warn with it—and a reminder for the believers. 3  Follow what is revealed to you from your Lord, and do not follow other masters beside Him. Little you recollect.
 4  How many towns have We destroyed?
Our might came upon them by night, or while they were napping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE FIG (at-Tin)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-095/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-095/</guid>
      <description>And  he will be satisfied. 93. MORNING LIGHT (adh-Duha) 1  By 1  By the fig and the olive. 2  And Mount Sinai. 3  And this safe land. 4  We the morning light. 2  And your work is done, turn to devotion. the night as it settles. 3  Your Lord did not abandon you, nor did He forget. 4  The Hereafter is better for you than the First.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE JINN (al-Jinn)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-072/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-072/</guid>
      <description>A band of jinn listened in and said ‘We have heard a wondrous Quran.
  2  It guides to rectitude, so we have believed in it We will never associate anyone with our Lord.  Our Lord never had a mate, nor a child.    But the fools among us used to say nonsense about Allah.    We thought that humans and jinn would never utter lies about Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE LIGHT (an-Nur)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-024a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-024a/</guid>
      <description>1  A chapter that We have revealed, and made obligatory, and revealed in it clear Verses, that you may take heed.
 2  The adulteress and the adulterer—whip each one of them a hundred lashes, and let no pity towards them overcome you regarding Allah’s Law, if you believe in Allah and the Last Day. And let a group of believers witness their punishment. 3  The adulterer shall marry none but an adulteress or an idolatress; and the adulteress shall marry none but an adulterer or an idolater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE PILGRIMAGE (al-Hajj)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-022a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-022a/</guid>
      <description>1  Be conscious of your Lord. The quaking of the Hour is a tremendous thing.
 2  On that Day:
 every nursing mother will discard her infant every pregnant woman will abort her load you will see the people drunk, even though they are not drunk   3  Some person will argue about Allah without knowledge and follow every defiant devil.
 4  He will misguide his followers and lead them to the torment of the Blaze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE POETS (ash-Shu’ara’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-026a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-026a/</guid>
      <description>3  Perhaps you will destroy yourself with grief, because they do not become believers. 4  If We will, We can send down upon them a sign from heaven, at which their necks will stay bent in humility. 5  No fresh reminder comes to them from the Most Merciful, but they turn their backs at it. 6. They have denied the truth, but soon will come to them the news of what they ridiculed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE REALITY (al-Haqqah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-069/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-069/</guid>
      <description>2  What is the Reality? 4  Thamood and Aad denied the Catastrophe.
As for Thamood, they were annihilated by the Overwhelming.
 And as for Aad; they were annihilated by a furious, roaring wind.
  He unleashed it upon them for seven nights and eight days, in succession. You could see the people tossed around, as though they were stumps of hollow palm-trees.
  Can you see any remnant of them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE ROMANS (ar-Rum)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-030a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-030a/</guid>
      <description>2  The Romans have been defeated. 3  In a nearby territory. But following their defeat, they will be victorious. 4  In a few years. The matter is up to Allah, in the past, and in the future. On that day, the believers will rejoice. 5  In Allah’s support. He supports whomever He wills. He is the Almighty, the Merciful.
 The promise of Allah—Allah never breaks His promise, but most people do not know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SPIDER (al-’Ankabut)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-029a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-029a/</guid>
      <description>Have the people supposed that they will be left alone to say, “We believe,” without being put to the test?
 3  We have tested those before them. Allah will surely know the truthful, and He will surely know the liars. 4  Or do those who commit sins think they can fool Us? Terrible is their opinion! looks forward to the meeting with Allah—the appointed time of Allah is coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SPOILS (al-Anfal)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-008a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-008a/</guid>
      <description>1  They ask you about the bounties. Say, “The bounties are for Allah and the Messenger.” So be mindful of Allah, and settle your differences, and obey Allah and His Messenger, if you are believers. 2  The believers are those whose hearts tremble when Allah is mentioned, and when His revelations are recited to them, they strengthen them in faith, and upon their Lord they rely. 3  Those who perform the prayer; and from</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Table (al-Ma’idah)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-005a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-005a/</guid>
      <description>1  O you who believe! Fulfill your commitments.
Livestock animals are allowedm except those specified. Wild game is not allowed while you are in pilgrim sanctity.
 2  Do not violate:
 Allah’s sacraments the Sacred Month the offerings the garlanded those heading for the Sacred House seeking blessings from their Lord and approval.  When you have left the pilgrim sanctity, you may hunt.
And let not the hatred of people who barred you from the Sacred Mosque incite you to aggression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THUNDER (ar-Ra’d)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-013a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-013a/</guid>
      <description>4  On earth are adjacent terrains, and gardens of vines, and crops, and date-palms, from the same root or from distinct roots, irrigated with the same water.
We make some taste better than others. In that are proofs for people who reason. 5  Should you wonder—the real wonder is their saying: “When we have become dust, will we be in a new creation?”
Those are they who defied their Lord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women (an-Nisa’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004a/</guid>
      <description>1  O people! Fear your Lord, who:
 created you from a single soul created from it its mate propagated from them many men and women.  Revere Allah and your parents.  2  Give orphans their properties.
Do not:
 substitute the bad for the good. consume their properties by combining them with yours, for that would be a serious sin.   3  If you fear you cannot act fairly towards the orphans—then marry the women you like—two, or three, or four.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women (an-Nisa’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004b/</guid>
      <description>15  Those of your women who commit lewdness, you must have four witnesses against them, from among you.
If they testify, confine them to the homes until death claims them, or Allah makes a way for them.
 16  If 2 Muslim men commit it, punish them both.
But if they repent and reform, leave them alone.  17  Some people commit evil out of ignorance, but repent soon after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women (an-Nisa’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004c/</guid>
      <description>43  Do not approach the prayer:
 while you are drunk, so that you know what you say after sexual orgasm—unless you are travelling—until you have bathed.  If you are sick, or traveling, or one of you comes from the toilet, or you have had intercourse with women, and cannot find water, find clean sand and wipe your faces and your hands with it.
 44  Have you not considered those who were given a share of the Book?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women (an-Nisa’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004d/</guid>
      <description>69  Whoever obeys Allah and the Messenger are blessed by Allah.
They are together with:
 the prophets the sincere, the martyrs, and the upright.  Excellent are those as companions.
 71  Take your precautions
 Mobilize in groups or mobilize altogether.   72  Among you is he who lags behind. Then, when a calamity befalls you, he says, “Allah has favored me, that I was not martyred with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women (an-Nisa’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004e/</guid>
      <description>88  You are divided into 2 factions regarding the hypocrites.
 But Allah Himself has overwhelmed them on account of what they did. Do you want to guide those whom Allah has led astray? You will never find a way for whomever Allah leads astray.   89  They would love to see you disbelieve, just as they disbelieve, so you would become equal.
 So do not befriend any of them, unless they emigrate in the way of Allah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women (an-Nisa’)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004f/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mohammad/quran/sura-004f/</guid>
      <description>135  Stand firmly for justice, as witnesses to Allah, even if against yourselves, or your parents, or your relatives.
Allah takes care of both rich or poor,
So do not follow your desires, lest you swerve.
 136  Whoever rejects Allah, His angels, His Books, His messengers, and the Last Day, has strayed far in error.
 137  Those who believe, then disbelieve, then believe, then disbelieve, then increase in disbelief, Allah will not forgive them, nor will He guide them to a way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
