<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Nature of Justice on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Nature of Justice on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Justice?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Persons in the dialogue:
   Socrates, the narrator      Glaucon    Adeimantus    Polemarchus    Cephalus    Thrasymachus    Cleitophon     The scene is in Cephalus&amp;rsquo; house at the Piraeus. Socrates narrates the dialogue to Timaeus, Hermocrates, Critias, and a nameless person, who are introduced in the Timaeus, the day after it happened.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice is Not the Interest of the Stronger</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Socrates I think that Periander, Perdiccas, Xerxes or Ismenias the Theban, or some other rich, proud, and mighty man, was the first to say that justice is &amp;ldquo;doing good to your friends and harm to your enemies.&amp;rdquo; But if this definition of justice also breaks down, what other can be offered?  Several times, Thrasymachus tried to get the argument into his own hands. He had been put down by the rest of the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice is the Interest of the Citizens</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-1/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Socrates To Thrasymachus: Is the attempt to determine the way of man&amp;rsquo;s life so small a matter to you?
I do not believe that injustice is more gainful than justice, even if injustice is uncontrolled and allowed to have free play. If an unjust man can commit injustice by fraud or force, it still does not convince me of the superior advantage of injustice. You should convince us that we are mistaken in preferring justice to injustice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
