<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PROTOCOL ON THE ROLE OF NATIONAL PARLIAMENTS IN THE EU on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PROTOCOL ON THE ROLE OF NATIONAL PARLIAMENTS IN THE EU on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>INFORMATION FOR NATIONAL PARLIAMENTS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/title-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/title-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 1
Commission consultation documents (green and white papers and communications) shall be forwarded directly by the Commission to national Parliaments upon publication. The Commission shall also forward the annual legislative programme as well as any other instrument of legislative planning or policy to national Parliaments, at the same time as to the European Parliament and the Council.
Article 2 Draft European legislative acts sent to the European Parliament and to the Council shall be forwarded to national Parliaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INTERPARLIAMENTARY COOPERATION</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/title-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/title-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 9
The European Parliament and national Parliaments shall together determine the organisation and promotion of effective and regular interparliamentary cooperation within the Union.
Article 10
A conference of Parliamentary Committees for Union Affairs may submit any contribution it deems appropriate for the attention of the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission. That conference shall in addition promote the exchange of information and best practice between national Parliaments and the European Parliament, including their special committees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROVISIONS ON THE TRANSIT OF PERSONS BY LAND BETWEEN KALININGRAD AND RUSSIA</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/title-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/protocols/part-01/title-5/</guid>
      <description>Article 57
The Union rules and arrangements on transit of persons by land between the region of Kaliningrad and other parts of the Russian Federation, and in particular the Council Regulation (EC) No 693/ 2003 of 14 April 2003 establishing a specific Facilitated Transit Document (FTD), a Facilitated Rail Transit Document (FRTD) and amending the Common Consular Instructions and the Common Manual ( 1 ), shall not in themselves delay or prevent the full participation of Lithuania in the Schengen acquis, including the removal of internal border controls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
