<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Einstein&#39;s Reply to Criticisms (1949) on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Einstein&#39;s Reply to Criticisms (1949) on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Einstein&#39;s Reply to Criticisms (1949)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/part-1/</guid>
      <description>I reject the basic idea of quantum theory. I do not believe that it will be useful for physics.
Born, Pauli, Heitler, Bohr, and Margenau are all firmly convinced that the riddle of the double nature of all corpuscles (corpuscular and undulatory character) has its final solution in the statistical quantum theory.
They believe that=
   Heisenberg’s indeterminacy-relation is essentially prejudicial in favour of the character of all thinkable reasonable physical theories in the mentioned sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einstein&#39;s Reply to Criticisms (1949)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Relativity How does my theory of relativity relate to philosophy?
Reichenbach has precise deductions and sharp assertions.
Robertson’s lucid discussion also is interesting mainly from the standpoint of general epistemology, although it limits itself to the narrower theme of “the theory of relativity and geometry.”
Robertson Is Reichenbach&amp;rsquo;s assertion true?  einstein  I answer with Pilate’s famous question: “What is truth?” Is a geometry — looked at from the physical point of view — verifiable or not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einstein&#39;s Reply to Criticisms (1949)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/reply/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Lemaître favours a “cosmological constant” in the equations of gravitation. I think that such a constant is not convincing in the present state of our knowledge because it makes my general relativity logically complicated.
The introduction of such a constant implies a considerable renunciation of the logical simplicity of theory, a renunciation which appeared to me unavoidable only so long as essentially static nature of space.
Hubble discovered the “expansion” of the stellar system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
