<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Utilitarianism on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Utilitarianism on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General Remarks</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>What is the foundation of morality?
This question has divided many people from the dawn of philosophy.
The young Socrates listened to the old Protagoras, the sophist, and asserted the theory of utilitarianism against the popular morality.
A similar confusion and uncertainty afflicts the first principles of all the sciences, even mathematics.
The truths which are ultimately accepted as the first principles of a science, are really the last results of metaphysical analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Utilitarianism?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>People who use utility as the moral basis usually make the ignorant blunder of defining utility as being opposed to pleasure.
Pro-utility writers, from Epicurus to Bentham, defined it not something as different from pleasure, but pleasure itself. It includes an exemption from pain.
Yet the common herd perpetually fall into this shallow mistake of separating utility and pleasure.
The Greatest Happiness Principle says that:
 actions which promote happiness are moral actions which produce the reverse of happiness are immoral  Happiness is intended pleasure, and the absence of pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Sanction Of The Principle Of Utility.</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>What are the motives to obey a moral standard? What is the source of its obligation? Whence does it derive its binding force?
Moral standards arise whenever a person is called on to adopt a standard or refer morality to any basis on which he has not been accustomed to rest it.
The customary morality from education and opinion is the only one which presents itself to the mind with the feeling of being in itself obligatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Proofs are Needed by The Principle Of Utility</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Ordinarily, ultimate ends do not admit of proof. To be incapable of proof by reasoning is common to all first principles; to the first premises of our knowledge, as well as to those of our conduct.
But the former, being matters of fact, may be the subject of a direct appeal to the faculties which judge of fact—namely, our senses, and our internal consciousness. Can an appeal be made to the same faculties on questions of practical ends?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Connection Between Justice And Utility</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/utilitarianism/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>One of the strongest obstacles to the doctrine that Utility or Happiness is the criterion of right and wrong. This has been drawn from the idea of Justice which is the powerful sentiment that resembles instinct.
This has made people think that the Just must have an existence in Nature as something absolute-generically distinct from every variety of the Expedient, and, in idea, opposed to it, though (as is commonly acknowledged) never, in the long run, disjoined from it in fact.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
