<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Bedouins on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Bedouins on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leadership cannot be handed to those not of the same descent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-11/</guid>
      <description>This is because leadership exists only through superiority, and superiority only through group feeling. 61
Therefore, the leadership over people must come from a group feeling that is superior to each individual group feeling.
Each individual group feeling that becomes aware of the superiority of the leader&amp;rsquo;s group feeling is ready to obey that leader.
A person who has become attached to people of a common descent usually does not share the group feeling arising from their common descent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House and nobility</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-13/</guid>
      <description>13. &amp;ldquo;House&amp;rdquo; and nobility come to clients and followers only through their masters and not through their own descent This is because, as we have mentioned before, only those who share in a group feeling have basic and true nobility. When such people take people of another descent as followers, or when they take slaves 78 and clients into servitude, and enter into close contact with them, the clients and followers share in the group feeling of their masters and take it on as if it were their own group feeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Feeling and Royal Authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-16/</guid>
      <description>16. The goal of group feeling is royal authority. This is because group feeling:
 gives protection and mutual defense allows the pressing of claims and other kinds of social activity  Human beings need someone to act as a restraining influence and mediator in every social organization, in order to keep the members from fighting each other.
That person must, by necessity, have superiority over the others in the matter of group feeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualification for Royal Authority</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-19/</guid>
      <description>19. A sign of the qualification for royal authority is his eager desire to acquire praiseworthy qualities, and vice versa. Royal authority is something natural to human beings, because of its social implications.
Man has the power of logical reasoning. This inclines him towards good qualities than to bad ones since evil is the result of the animal powers in him. Royal and political authority come to man qua man, because it is peculiar to man and is not found in animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Feeling and Political Stability</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-21/</guid>
      <description>21. As long as a nation retains its group feeling, the royal authority that disappears in one branch will necessarily pass to some other branch This is because the people obtain royal authority only after proving their forcefulness and finding other nations obedient to them.
Only a few are then singled out to become the actual rulers.
It could not be all of them, because there is not enough room for all to compete for leadership, and because the existence of jealousy cuts short the aspirations of many of those who aspire to high office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The vanquished always want to imitate the victor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-22/</guid>
      <description>22. The vanquished always want to imitate the victor in his distinctive marks, dress, occupation, and all his other conditions and customs This is because the soul always sees perfection in the person who is superior to it and to whom it is subservient. It considers him perfect, either because:
 its respect for him impresses it, or it erroneously assumes that its subservience was due to the victor&amp;rsquo;s perfection and not to the nature of the defeat  If that erroneous assumption fixes itself in the soul, then it becomes a firm belief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Arabs</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-25/</guid>
      <description>25. Places that succumb to the Arabs are quickly ruined This is because the Arabs are a savage nation. They enjoy savagery because it means freedom from authority. Such a natural disposition negates civilization.
All the customary activities of the Arabs lead to travel and movement. This negates the stationariness which produces civilization.
For instance, the Arabs need stones as supports for their cooking pots. They tear down buildings to get those stones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Arabs are most remote from royal leadership</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-27/</guid>
      <description>This is because they are more rooted in desert life than any other nation. They have less need of the products and grain of the hills, because they are used to a tough and hard life.
Therefore, they can dispense with other people. It is difficult for them to subordinate themselves to each other because they are used to no control and because they are in a state of savagery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bedouins are closer to being good than sedentary people</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-04/</guid>
      <description>4. Bedouins are closer to being good than sedentary people The 16 reason for it is that the soul in its first natural state of creation is ready to accept whatever good or evil may arrive and leave an imprint upon it.
Muhammad said= &amp;ldquo;Every infant is born in the natural state. It is his parents who make him a Jew or a Christian or a Magian.&amp;rdquo; 17
To the degree the soul is first affected by one of the two qualities, it moves away from the other and finds it difficult to acquire it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Feeling and Purity of lineage</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-09/</guid>
      <description>9. Purity of lineage is found only among the savage This is because of the poor life, hard conditions, and bad habitats that are peculiar to the Arabs.
They are the result of necessity that destined (these conditions) for (the Arabs), in as much as their subsistence depends on camels and camel breeding and pasturage.
The camels are the cause of the Arabs&amp;rsquo; savage life in the desert, since they feed on the shrubs of the desert and give birth in the desert sands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bedouins</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-01/</guid>
      <description>1. Both Bedouins and sedentary people are natural groups. Their differences are from the different ways in which they make their living.
Social organization enables them to cooperate toward that end and to start with the simple necessities of life, before they get to conveniences and luxuries.
 Some people adopt agriculture, the cultivation of vegetables and grains, (as their way of making a living). Others adopt animal husbandry, the use of sheep, cattle, goats, bees, and silkworms, for breeding and for their products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The reliance of sedentary people on laws destroys their fortitude and power of resistance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-2/part-06/</guid>
      <description>This is because not everyone is master of his own affairs. Their leaders are few.
As a rule, man must by necessity be dominated by someone else.
Self-reliance eventually becomes a natural quality to the people if :
 their leaders are kind and just the people are not oppressed by their laws and restrictions the people are guided by the courage or cowardice in themselves.  They become satisfied with the absence of any restraining power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
