<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 11 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 11 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The legislative Power in the Roman Republic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>THERE were no rights to contest under the decemvirs; but, upon the restoration of liberty, jealousies revived; and, so long as the patricians had any privileges left, they were sure to be st ripped of them by the plebeians.
The mischief would not have been so great had the plebeians been satisfied with this success; but they also injured the patricians as citizens. When the people assembled by curiC3A6, or ce nturies, they were composed of senators, patricians, and plebeians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>The laws that establish political liberty, as it relates to the constitution, and those by which it is established, as it relates to the citizen. The former shall be the subject of this book; the latter I shall examine in the next.
Chapter 2= Different Meanings of Liberty Liberty is the word that has the most meanings and has made the most impressions on the human mind. Some have taken it as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Constitution of England</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>IN every government there are three sorts of power=
 The legislative= this lets the prince or magistrate:   create and revise laws  The executive that implements the law of nations= This lets him:   make peace or war send or receive embassies establish the public security provide against invasions  The judiciary that implements the civil law= This lets him:   punish criminals judge the disputes between individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Monarchies we are acquainted with</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>THE monarchies that we know do not have liberty as their goal. Their only aim is the glory of:
 the subject, the state, and the sovereign.  But from these come a spirit of liberty, which can achieve great things in monarchial states, similar to liberty itself.
In a monarchy, the three powers are not distributed on the model of the constitution above-mentioned. They have each a particular distribution, according to which they border more or less on political liberty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Government of the Kings of Rome</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>THE government of the kings of Rome had some relation to that of the heroic Greek kings. It was generally good, but had a defect
In order to give an adequate idea of thi s government, I shall distinguish that of the first five kings, that of Ser vius Tullus, and that of Tarquin.
The crown was elective. Under the first five kings, the senate had the greatest share in the election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Distribution of the three Powers began to change, after the Expulsion of the Kings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>Four things greatly prejudiced Rome&amp;rsquo;s liberty.
The patricians had engrossed to themselves all public employments. An exorbitant power was annexed to the consulate. The people were often insulted and had no influence left in the public suffrages. These four abuses were redressed by the people.
  It was regulated that the plebeians might aspire to some magistracies and by degrees they were rendered capable of them all, except that of interrex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The judiciary Power in the Roman Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>THE judiciary power was given to:
 the people, the senate, the magistrates, and particular judges.  How were their civil affairs distributed?
The consuls had the judiciary power after the expulsion of the kings, as the praetors were judges after the consuls. Servius Tullus had divested himself of the power of determining of civil causes, which was not resumed by the consuls, except in some very rare cases, for that reason cal led extraordinary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Government of the Roman Provinces</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/montesquieu/spirit-of-the-laws/book-11/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>SUCH was the distribution of the three p owers in Rome. But they were far from being thus distributed in the provinc es= liberty prevailed in the center, and tyranny in the extreme parts.
When Rome extended her dominions no far ther than Italy, the people were governed as confederates. The laws of each republic were preserved.
But, when she enlarged her conquests, and the senate had no longer an immediate inspection over the provinces, nor the m agistrates residing at Rome were any longer capable of governing the empire , they were obliged to send praetors and proconsuls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
