<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phaedo by Plato Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phaedo by Plato Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Socrates in Prison</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Persons Of The Dialogue:
| Phaedo, the narrator of the dialogue to Echecrates of Phlius | | | +++ | +++ | | Echecrates | | | Socrates | | | Apollodorus | | | Simmias | | | Cebes | | | Crito | | | Attendant of the Prison | | | Scene | The Prison of Socrates | | Place of Narration | Phlius |
Echecrates Were you yourself in the prison with Socrates on the day when he drank the poison?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Socrates The real philosopher has reason to be of good cheer when he is about to die. After death he may hope to obtain the greatest good in the other world. The true devotee of philosophy is always pursuing death. He has had the desire of death all his life long.  Simmias laughingly: Our people will think that philosophers want to die, and will think them deserving death.  Socrates They are right in thinking so, but not in discovering the death that a philosopher deserves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory and Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Socrates True. I reckon that no one who heard me now, not even if he were one of my old enemies, the Comic poets, could accuse me of idle talking about matters in which I have no concern:—If you please, then, we will proceed with the inquiry.
Do humans souls go to the world below after death?
An ancient doctrine affirms that they go from here into the other world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolute ideas and the Soul</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Socrates There is an absolute beauty, and goodness, and an absolute essence of all things.
If to this, which is now discovered to have existed in our former state, we refer all our sensations, and with this compare them, finding these ideas to be pre-existent and our inborn possession—then our souls must have had a prior existence, but if not, there would be no force in the argument? There is the same proof that these ideas must have existed before we were born, as that our souls existed before we were born; and if not the ideas, then not the souls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propensities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Socrates These must be the souls, not of the good, but of the evil, which are compelled to wander about such places in payment of the penalty of their former evil way of life.
They continue to wander until through the craving after the corporeal which never leaves them, they are imprisoned finally in another body. They may be supposed to find their prisons in the same natures which they have had in their former lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opposites</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Phaedo I was close to Socrates on his right hand, seated on a sort of stool. He was on a couch which was a good deal higher.
He stroked my head, and pressed the hair upon my neck—he had a way of playing with my hair.
 Socrates We should both shave our locks today.
If I were you, and the argument got away from me, and I could not hold my ground against Simmias and Cebes, I would myself take an oath, like the Argives, not to wear hair any more until I had renewed the conflict and defeated them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Quest of Socrates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Socrates paused awhile, and seemed to be absorbed in reflection.
Socrates You are raising a tremendous question, Cebes. It involves the whole nature of generation and corruption. When I was young, I wanted to know that department of philosophy called &amp;rsquo;the investigation of nature&amp;rsquo;. I wanted to know the causes of things, like why a thing is and is created or destroyed. It appeared to me as a lofty profession.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forms and Opposites</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Socrates You say that Simmias is greater than Socrates and less than Phaedo. You predicate of Simmias both greatness and smallness.
But still you allow that Simmias does not really exceed Socrates, as the words may seem to imply, because he is Simmias, but by reason of the size which he has; just as Simmias does not exceed Socrates because he is Simmias, any more than because Socrates is Socrates, but because he has smallness when compared with the greatness of Simmias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Universe to Socrates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>I believe that the earth is a round body in the centre of the heavens.
 It does not need air or any similar force for support It is kept there and hindered from falling or inclining any way by:  the equability of the surrounding heaven and her own equipoise.    A thing in equipoise is in the centre of that which is equably diffused.
 It will not incline any way in any degree  I also believe that the earth is very vast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death of Socrates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/phaedo/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>When he had done speaking, Crito said:
Crito Do you have any commands for us, Socrates? Anything to say about your children, or anything else in which we can serve you?  Socrates Just take care of yourselves. That is a service you can render to me and to all. But if you have no thought for yourselves and do not follow the rule which I have prescribed for youit will be useless.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
