<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agreement Establishing The Asian Development Bank on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agreement Establishing The Asian Development Bank on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Article 63: SIGNATURE AND DEPOSIT   The original of this Agreement in a single copy in the English language shall remain open for signature at the United Nations Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East, in Bangkok, until 31 January 1966 by Governments of countries listed in Annex A to this Agreement. This document shall thereafter be deposited with the Secretary-General of the United Nations (hereinafter called the &amp;ldquo;Depository&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose, Functions, Membership</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 1: PURPOSE The Bank shall=
 foster economic growth and co-operation in the region of Asia and the Far East contribute to accelerate economic development of the developing member countries collectively and individually.  Region refers to the Terms of Reference of the United Nations Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East.
Article 2: FUNCTIONS  To promote investment in the region of public and private capital for development purposes To utilize the resources at its disposal for financing development of the developing member countries in the region, giving priority to those regional, sub-regional as well as national projects and programmes which will contribute most effectively to the harmonious economic growth of the region as awhole, and having special regard to the needs of the smaller or less developed member countries in the region To meet requests from members in the region to assist them in the coordination of their development policies and plans with a view to achieving better utilization of their resources, making their economies more complementary, and promoting the orderly expansion of their foreign trade, in particular, intra-regional trade To provide technical assistance for the preparation, financing and execution of development projects and programmes, including the formulation of specific project proposals; To co-operate, in such manner as the Bank may deem appropriate, within the terms of this Agreement, with the United Nations, its organs and subsidiary bodies including, in particular, the Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East, and with public international organizations and other international institutions, as well as national entities whether public or private, which are concerned with the investment of development funds in the region, and to interest such institutions and entities in new opportunities for investment and assistance; and to undertake such other activities and provide such other services as may advance its purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscriptions of each country</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/annex-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/annex-a/</guid>
      <description>INITIAL SUBSCRIPTIONS TO THE AUTHORIZED CAPITAL STOCK FOR COUNTRIES WHICH MAY BECOME MEMBERS IN ACCORDANCE WITH Article 64
Part A. REGIONAL COUNTRIES    Country Subscription in USD millions     Afghanistan 3.36   Australia 85.00   Cambodia 3.00   Ceylon 8.52   China, Republic of 16.00   India 93.00   Iran 60.00   Japan 200.00   Korea, Republic of 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscriptions of each country</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/annex-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/annex-b/</guid>
      <description>ELECTION OF DIRECTORS Section A. - Election of Directors by Governors representing regional members.   Each Governor representing a regional member shall cast all votes of the member he represents for a single person.
  The seven (7) persons receiving the highest number of votes shall be Directors, except that no person who received less than ten (10) per cent of the total voting power of regional members shall be considered as elected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 4: AUTHORIZED CAPITAL  The Bank&amp;rsquo;s authorized capital stock shall be $l,000,000,000 from 31 January 1966.  This will be divided into 100,000 shares having a par value of $10,000 each, which shall be available for subscription only by members in accordance with the provisions of Article 5 of this Agreement.
 The original authorized capital stock shall be divided into paid-in shares and callable shares. Shares having an aggregate par value of five hundred million dollars ($500,000,000) shall be paid- in shares, and shares having an aggregate par value of five hundred million dollars ($500,000,000) shall be callable shares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Of Resources</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Article 8 The resources and facilities of the Bank shall be used exclusively to implement the purpose and functions set forth respectively in Articles 1 and 2 of this Agreement.
Article 9 ORDINARY AND SPECIAL OPERATIONS  The operations of the Bank shall consist of ordinary operations and special operations. Ordinary operations shall be those financed from the ordinary capital resources of the Bank. Special operations shall be those financed from the Special Funds resources referred to in Article 20 of this Agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Borrowing And Other Miscellaneous Powers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Article 21= GENERAL POWERS The Bank shall have the power to=
 Borrow funds in member countries or elsewhere, and in this connection to furnish such collateral or other security therefore as the Bank shall determine, provided always that=   a) before making a sale of its obligations in the territory of a country, the Bank shall have obtained its approval b) where the obligations of the Bank are to be denominated in the currency of a member, the bank shall have obtained its approval c) the Bank shall obtain the approval of the countries referred to in sub-paragraphs (a) and (b) of this paragraph that the proceeds may be exchanged for the currency of any member without restriction; and d) before determining to sell its obligations in a particular country, the Bank shall consider the amount of previous borrowing, if any, in that country, the amount of previous borrowing in other countries, and the possible availability of funds in such other countries; and shall give due regard to the general principle that its borrowings should to the greatest extent possible be diversified as to country of borrowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Currencies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Article 23= Determination Of Convertibility Whenever it shall become necessary under this Agreement to determine whether any currency is convertible, such determination shall be made by the Bank after consultation with the IMF.
Article 24= Use Of Currencies  Members may not maintain or impose any restrictions on the holding or use by the Bank or by any recipient from the Bank, for payments in any country, of the following=   i) gold or convertible currencies received by the Bank in payment of subscriptions to its capital stock, other than that paid to the Bank by members pursuant to paragraph 2(b) of Article 6 and restricted pursuant to paragraphs 2(i) and (ii) of this Article; ii) currencies of members purchased with the gold or convertible currencies referred to in the preceding sub-paragraph; iii) currencies obtained by the Bank by borrowing, pursuant to sub-paragraph (i) of Article 21 of this Agreement, for inclusion in its ordinary capital resources; iv) gold or currencies received by the Bank in payment on account of principal, interest, dividends or other charges in respect of loans or investments made out of any of the funds referred to in sub-paragraphs (i) to (iii) of this paragraph or in payment of fees in respect of guarantees made by the Bank; and (v) currencies, other than the member&amp;rsquo;s own currency, received by the member from the Bank in distribution of the net income of the Bank in accordance with Article 40 of this Agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization And Management</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Article 26: STRUCTURE The Bank shall have
 a Board of Governors a Board of Directors a President one or more Vice-Presidents other officers and staff  Article 27: BOARD OF GOVERNORS= COMPOSITION  Each member shall be represented on the Board of Governors and shall appoint one Governor and one alternate.  Each Governor and alternate shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing member. No alternate may vote except in the absence of his principal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Withdrawal And Suspension Of Members, Temporary Suspension And Termination Of Bank Operations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Article 41= WITHDRAWAL  Any member may withdraw from the Bank at any time by delivering a notice in writing to the Bank at its principal office. Withdrawal by a member shall become effective, and its membership shall cease, on the date specified in its notice but in no event less than six (6) months after the date that notice has been received by the Bank. However, at any time before the withdrawal becomes finally effective, the member may notify the Bank in writing of the cancellation of its notice of intention to withdraw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status, Immunities, Exemptions And Privileges</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>This is to enable the Bank effectively to fulfill its purpose. The status, immunities, exemptions and privileges set forth in this Chapter shall be accorded to the Bank in the territory of each member.
Article 49: LEGAL STATUS
The Bank shall possess full juridical personality and, in particular, full capacity= (i) to contract; (ii) to acquire, and dispose of, immovable and movable property; and (iii) to institute legal proceedings.
Immunities Article 50: IMMUNITY FROM JUDICIAL PROCEEDINGS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amendments, Interpretation, Arbitration</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/modern/adb/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Article 59: AMENDMENTS   This Agreement may be amended only by a resolution of the Board of Governors approved by a vote of 2/3 of the total number of Governors, representing not less than three-fourths of the total voting power of the members.
  Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph 1 of this Article, the unanimous agreement of the Board of Governors shall be required for the approval of any amendment modifying= (i) the right to withdraw from the Bank; (ii) the limitations on liability provided in paragraphs 6 and 7 of Article 5; and(iii) the rights pertaining to purchase of capital stock provided in paragraph 2 of Article 5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
