<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Material Superphysics Principles on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Material Superphysics Principles on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/material/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Kepler Tensor and Removing the Metric Tensor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/kepler-tensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/kepler-tensor/</guid>
      <description>The Two Domains In the previous post , we explained the Cartesian view which saw the universe in two planes:
 Physical Aethereal  These two planes have two attributes as timespan and layer, and lead to two kinds of sources of motion:
 Physical Force Aetheral Effort  The motion is then represented by the Kepler tensor made up of:
 G or the Gravitational Signature of the Identity s or the layer where that identity is moving, set by the Cartesian View  The Five Layers of Superphysics Superphysics has five layers derived from the ancients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radioactive Relativity -- Radioactive Movement</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/radioactive-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/radioactive-relativity/</guid>
      <description>Radioactive Relativity explains the principles for the Radioactive (Weak) Layer. In Physics, this is done by the Feynman diagrams.
Feynman Diagrams These diagrams show the interaction between two particles.
It has the following lines
   Line Particle     Straight Fermion   Wavy Photon   Loop Gluon   Dashed W, Z Boson    More to come! (This is quite complicated)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational Relativity -- Action at a Distance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/gravitational-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/gravitational-relativity/</guid>
      <description>The previous post, explained aethereal relativity which deals with the movement of quanta of aether (qoas) as ideas, feelings, minds, and societies.
This post will explain gravitational relativity that deals with the movement of quanta of spacetime (qosts) as galaxies and planets and their subtypes.
The Newtonian and Einsteinian movement Newton described motion coming from an external force as a single movement. Einstein revised this by making it relative to frames of reference, as well as dividing it into smaller parts as tensors (as measuring rod S).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aethereal Relativity -- Action at a Distance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/aethereal-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/aethereal-relativity/</guid>
      <description>Aethereal Relativity is made up of the principles that dictate aethereal movement. It is the most important of all the relativities since it controls or affects all the layers underneath.
It is divided into 2 planes:
 Physical - this dictates the movement of of physical objects between galaxies, multiverses, and timelines. This is Physical Aethereal Relativity Metaphysical - this layer dictates the movement of ideas. Aethereal Relativity defaults to this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material Relativity -- Contact Forces</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/material-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/material-relativity/</guid>
      <description>According to Newton&amp;rsquo;s Second Law, net force equals mass times acceleration. This is fine for ordinary things like a ball (mass) which is pushed (force) to start rolling (acceleration).
But what about a 50kg Buddhist monk that floats and accelerates 1 meter/second 2  without any force? How can 0 = 50 1m/s^2?
Aethereal Effort To account for this, we modify Newton&amp;rsquo;s vector into a Kepler tensor that transforms based on a limiter s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spatial Layer of Superphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/spatial/</guid>
      <description>The spatial layer is below the aethereal. It leads to spacetime and sets the speed of light.
It manifests as the space, size, and age of the universe. It gives the ideas and energies from the aethereal layer a chance to cross over onto physical reality via gravitation through stars and galaxies.
The creation of gravitational nodes leads to the mutual repulsion between nodes, leading to the perception of space and time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aethereal Layer of Superphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/aethereal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/aethereal/</guid>
      <description>The aethereal is the highest layer in the universe, and is underneath only the metaphysical layer, which itself is bounded by pre-existence.
This layer is best represented by the mind or soul. We can say that the universe is one huge mind, which the Hindus call Brahma. In our matrix analogy, this mind can be seen as the RAM of a computer that generates its own virtual reality.
Unlike Science and New Age philosophy that puts emphasis on consciousness as to put all existential mysteries in it, Superphysics puts all the mysteries in the aether which is the material or principles of the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Radiant Layer of Superphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/radiant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/radiant/</guid>
      <description>The radiant layer is the third layer in the universe. It manifests as energies that spread out in space at the speed limit of spacetime (known to physics as the speed of light).
It manifests as light, magnetism, and electricity.
In terms of creation, this layer is the third layer that spreads across the space created by the spacetime layer.
   Name Traditional Name Force Particle Quantum     Radiant Fire Electromagentism Electron, Photon, etc Quantum of electricity or Qoe, Quantum of light or Qol    Unlike the spacetime layer that has a very large space of influence, this layer has a limited space to influence, which manifests as &amp;lsquo;fields&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Radioactive Layer of Superphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/radioactive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/radioactive/</guid>
      <description>The radioactive layer is the fourth layer in the universe. It downgrades the radiant energies and particles into material ones.
It manifests as radioactivity and is governed by Feynman diagrams
In terms of creation, this is the fourth layer that processes energies and matter into other kinds
   Name Traditional Name Physics Force Physics Particle Quantum Gravitation Source     Radioactive Water Weak W Z Bosons Quantum of radioactivity or Qor Neutron    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Material Layer of Superphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/material/</guid>
      <description>The material layer is the lowest layer in the universe and manifests as physical objects. A unit example is a rock.In terms of creation, this layer is the final layer in the journey of dynamic energy and entropy towards stasis and is where mind is at its most dormant state.
   Name Traditional Name Force Particle Quantum     Material Earth Strong Gluon Quantum of matter or Qom    The conversion from dormant mind into active mind then takes place in stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrons are Positive, Protons are Negative</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoe/</guid>
      <description>Have you wondered why negative ions make us feel positive, and positive ions make us feel negative?
That&amp;rsquo;s because electrons are really positively charged! Benjamin Franklin made a mistake when he called electrons as negative. Rather than confuse everyone by calling the negative as positive, we&amp;rsquo;d rather call the negative as &amp;lsquo;feminine charge&amp;rsquo;, the positive as a &amp;lsquo;masculine charge&amp;rsquo;, and neutral as a &amp;lsquo;bisexual charge&amp;rsquo;.
We shall use the word &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Five Layers of Superphysics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/five-layers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/five-layers/</guid>
      <description>Our Five Layers are derived from the Five Elements of the Greeks, Hindus, and Chinese. Such a concept is absent in science because science came from the Western civilization which is really just the Roman Empire.
The Western Limitation Physics came from Isaac Newton* who came up with classical mechanics to explain why 17th-century things move. For example, a falling apple immediately includes three of the four forces:
 Strong force to keep the apple&amp;rsquo;s identity Gravitational force to make the apple fall Electromagnetism for the apple to repel the Earth and not fall through the soil   *Newton&amp;rsquo;s Principia is written in Latin, the language of the Roman Empire</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravitational Signatures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/gravsigs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/gravsigs/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we fixed relativity* by adhering to the rules** which Socrates*** mentioned earlier:
 Photons must not be used to build the solution There must be no constant The solution and cause of movement must be inherent to the object, as opposed to being external The solution must be universal, that is, applicable to all five layers of the Greek or Asian model of Earth, Water, Fire, Air, and Ether   *We fix Newton in this post   **This adherence of logic to timeless metaphysical truths is the key aspect of the dialectical method that makes it different from the scientific method which is based on evidence supplied by the limited physical senses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Quantum of Aether or Qoa?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qoa/</guid>
      <description>We all know that physical reality exists inside space and time, and that space and time are the properties of the universe. But how were space and time and the universe created?
According to Physics, it was created through a &amp;ldquo;Big Bang&amp;rdquo; of a material Singularity. This led to matter and energy, just as we see sharpnel and light, and feel the energy from exploding fireworks. What is the nature of this Material Singularity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Quantum of Spacetime or Qost?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/qost/</guid>
      <description>The Five Layers of Superphysics In a previous post , we explained that a universe begins as a &amp;ldquo;Big Bootup&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Wakeup&amp;rdquo; when ideas flow from the metaphysical plane onto the physical plane. These ideas flow down onto the five layers or elements of the Greeks, Hindus, and Chinese in five phases:
   Phase Layer Physics Name Sequence     0 Metaphysical Pseudo-science The pre-existing ideas as potentialities are deployed onto reality   1 Aethereal Higgs The aether compiles the compound ideas as potential universes in the multiverse   2 Spatial Gravitation The compiled ideas are sent through qosts as galaxies and then as stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spin is the Reflective Ability of Particles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/spin/</guid>
      <description>Physics is based on a materialistic interpretation of reality, which is opposite of the metaphysical interpretation by Superphysics.
For example, physics prefers to view things as particles. This is consistent with the atomic model of Democritus and opposite of the musical model of Pythagoras.
 The atomic model was embraced by Newton and Einstein The musical model was embraced by Socrates and Kepler  We continue this musical paradigm by using waves instead of particles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Universal Relativity?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/universal-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/material/principles/universal-relativity/</guid>
      <description>In Superphysics, physical existence is made when the aether arbitrarily creates quanta of spacetime or qost *, which are 1-dimensional points, within itself. Each point is a discrete and unique identity filled with an arbitrary amount of qualities as potentiality.
 *pronounced as &amp;lsquo;kost&amp;rsquo;. This is supposed to be the graviton which will never be found, because it can only be felt since it lies in the spatial layer which is above the visible eletromagnetic layer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
