<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 1899 Malolos Constitution Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 1899 Malolos Constitution Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amendment Of The Constitution</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-13/</guid>
      <description>Article 89
The Assembly, on its own initiative or that of the President of the Republic, may propose amendments to the Constitution, indicating what Article or Articles are to be amended.
Article 90
This proposal having been made, the President of the Republic shall dissolve the Assembly, and shall convoke a Constituent Assembly which shall meet within three months. In the decree convoking the Constituent Assembly, the resolution mentioned in the preceding Article shall be inserted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National And Individual Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-04/</guid>
      <description>Article 6
The following are Filipinos:
 All persons born in the Philippine territory. A vessel of Philippine registry is considered, for this purpose, as part of Philippine territory. Children of a Filipino father or mother, although born outside of the Philippines. Foreigners who have obtained certification of naturalization. Those who, without such certificate, have acquired a domicile in any town within Philippine territory.  Domicile is acquired by uninterrupted residence for two years in any locality within Philippine territory, with an open abode and known occupation, and contributing to all the taxes imposed by the Nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Executive Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-07/</guid>
      <description>Title 7: Executive Article 56
The Executive Power shall be vested in the President of the Republic, who shall exercise it through his Department Secretaries.
Article 57
The administration of the particular interests of towns, provinces, and of the State shall correspond, respectively, to the Popular Assembles, the Provincial Assemblies, and to the Administration in power, in accordance with the laws, and observing the most liberal policy of decentralization and administrative autonomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legislative Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-05/</guid>
      <description>Title 5: The Legislative Power Article 33: The Assembly of Representatives
Legislative power is with the Assembly of Representatives, organized in the form and manner determined by law.
Article 34
Its Members shall represent the whole nation, and not exclusively the electors who elected them.
Article 35
No representative shall receive from his electors any imperative mandate whatsoever.
Article 36
The Assembly shall meet every year.
The President of the Republic has the right to convoke it, suspend and close its sessions, and dissolve the same, within the periods prescribed by law enacted by the Assembly or by the Permanent Commission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Republic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-01/</guid>
      <description>The President of the Council, Apolinario Mabini
Title 1: The Republic Article 1
The political association of all Filipinos is a nation with a state called the Philippine Republic
Article 2
The Philippine Republic is free and independent.
Article 3
Sovereignty resides exclusively in the people.
Title 2: The Government Article 4
The Government of the Republic is popular, representative, alternative, and responsible.
It has 3 distinct powers:
 legislative executive judicial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secretaries Of Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1899/title-09/</guid>
      <description>Article 73
The Council of Government is composed of one President and seven secretaries, each of whom shall have under his charge the portfolios of Foreign Relations, Interior, Finance, War and Marine, Public Education, Communications and Public Works, and Agriculture, Industry, and Commerce.
Article 74
All the acts done by the President of the Republic in the discharge of his duties shall be signed by the corresponding Secretary. No public official shall give official recognition to any act unless this requisite is complied with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
