<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travels in the Philippines on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travels in the Philippines on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Cacao</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>I SPRAINED my foot so badly in ascending Mayon volcano that I had to stay in the house for a month.
Under the circumstances, I was not sorry to find myself settled in a roomy and comfortable dwelling.
It was:
 on the banks of a small stream in the middle of a garden a lot of coffee, cacao, oranges, papayas, and banana trees despite the tall weeds around.  Several over-ripe berries had fallen to the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Coffee</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-10b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-10b/</guid>
      <description>The history of coffee in the Philippines is very similar to that of cacao.
The plant thrives wonderfully, and its berry has so strongly marked a flavour that the worst Manila coffee commands as high a price as the best Java.
In spite of this, however, the amount of coffee produced in the Philippines is very insignificant, and, until lately, scarcely deserved mention.
According to the report of an Englishman in 1828, the coffee-plant was:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Theater</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-10c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-10c/</guid>
      <description>When my ankle began to get better, my first excursion was to Legaspi, where some natives were giving a theatrical performance.
A Spanish political refugee directed the entertainment.
On each side of the stage, roofed in with palm leaves, ran covered galleries for the dignitaries of the place. The uncovered space between which was set apart for the common people. The performers had chosen a play taken from Persian history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>EXCURSIONS TO BULUSÁN AND SORSOGÓN.—ROAD MAKING.—PIRATES.
During the whole time I was confined to the house at Darága, the weather was remarkably fine ; but unfortunately the bright days had come to an end by the time I was ready to make a start, for the north-east monsoon, the sure forerunner of rain in this part of the Archipelago, sets in in October. In spite, however, of the weather, I determined to make another attempt to ascend the mountain at Bulusán.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spanish Priests</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>The 2 provinces of Camarines form a long continent. Its principal frontage of shore facing to the north-east and to the south-west ; which is about 10 leagues broad in its middle. Its shores are indented by many deep bays.
From about the centre of its north-eastern shore there boldly projects the peninsula of Caramúan, connected with the mainland of Camarines by the isthmus of Ysaróg. The north-eastern portions of the two provinces contain a long range of volcanic hills; the southwestern principally consisted, as far as my investigations permitted me to discover, of chalk and coral reefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spanish Governors</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-12b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-12b/</guid>
      <description>The difference in the position of the priests to that of the Government officials is seen in their respective dwellings.
The casas reules of the priests are generally small, ugly, and frequently half-ruined habitations, are not suited to the dignity of the chief authority of the province.
The conrento, on the contrary, is almost always a roomy, imposing, and wellarranged building.
In former days, when governorships were sold to adventurers whose only care was to enrich themselves, the influence of the minister of religion was even greater than it is now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Priests</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>In an hour and a half after leaving Polángui we reached Bátu, a village on the north-western shore of the lake of the same name.
The inhabitants, particularly the women, struck me by their ugliness and want of cleanliness. Although they lived close to the lake, and drew their daily drinking water from it, they never appeared to use it for washing.
The streets of the village also were dirty and neglected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicol, Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>The frame and body of bamboo; the collar and noseband of the buffalo, of chair-cane ; and the
roof of pandanus-leaves.
MANNERS AND CUSTOMS OF THE BÍCOL INDIANS. On my second journey in Camarines, which I undertook in February, I went by water from Polangui, past Bátu, as far as Nága.
The Quináli, which runs into the south-eastern corner of the lake of Bátu, runs out again on the north side as the Bícol River, and flows in a north-westerly direction as far as the Bay of San Miguél.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Domestic Philippine Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-14c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-14c/</guid>
      <description>The details of domestic economy may be narrated as follows:
For cooking purposes
An earthen pot is used for cooking. It costs between 3 and 10 cuartos. When cooking rice, is closed firmly with a banana-leaf, so that the steam of a very small quantity of water is sufficient.
The poor have no other cooking utensil. Those better off have a few cast-iron pans and dishes.
In the smaller houses, the hearth consists of:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amok, Bangungot, and Nasal Acuteness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-14d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-14d/</guid>
      <description>Under certain conditions, which the physicians, on being questioned, could not define more precisely, the natives can support neither hunger nor thirst; of which fact I have on many occasions been a witness.
It is reported of them, when forced into such a situation as to suffer from unappeased wants, that they become critically ill; and thus they often die.
Hence arises the morbid mania for imitation, which is called in Java Sakit-latar, and here Mali-mali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese and Their Earthen Jars</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>From Nága I visited the cura of Libmánan (Ligmanan) who:
 had poetical talent and a reputation of a natural philosopher collected and named pretty beetles and shells dedicated the most elegant little sonnets.  He favoured me with the following narrative :
In 1851, during the construction of a road a little beyond Libmánan, at a place called Poro, a bed of shells was dug up under 4 feet of mould, 100 feet distant from the river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tea-societies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-15b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-15b/</guid>
      <description>The following certificate translated by the interpreter of the German Consulate shows how highly ancient pots, even of native origin, are esteemed in Japan up to the present:
“This earthen vessel was found in the porcelain factory of Tschisuka in the province of Odori, in South Idzumi, and is an object belonging to the thousand graves . . . It was made by Giogiboosat (a celebrated Buddhist priest), and after it had been consecrated to heaven was buried by him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paracáli and Mambuláo</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-15c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-15c/</guid>
      <description>GOLD-WASHING Paracáli and Mambuláo are two localities well known to all mineralogists, from the red lead ore occurring there.
On the following morning I returned to Longos which only had a few miserable huts inhabited by gold-washers. They go about almost naked, probably because they work most of the day in the water and are also very poor.
The soil is composed of rubbish, decomposed fragments of crystalline rock, rich in broken pieces of quartz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>JOURNEY ALONG THE COAST OF CAMARINES.—ENCROACHMENTS OF THE SEA.&amp;ndash;
DESTROYED PALM FOREST.-PASACÁO.- BAD ROADS.
I sent my baggage from Daét to Cabusáo in a schooner. I then proceeded on foot by the road to the coast on the west side of the Bay of San Miguél.
We crossed the mouth of the river in a boat, which the horses swam after ; but they were soon abandoned from unfitness. At the mouth of the next river, Sácavin, the water was so high that the bearers stripped themselves naked and carried the baggage over on their heads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oppression Of The Igorots</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>THE YSARÓG AND ITS INHABITANTS. Tue Ysaróg (pronounced Issaró) rises up in the middle of Camarínes, between the bays of San Miguel and Lagonóy.
While its eastern slope almost reaches the sea, it is separated on its western side by a broad strip of inundated land from the Bay of San Miguél. In circumference it is at least twelve leagues; and its height 1,966 metres.* Very flat at its base, it swells gradually to 16°, and higher up to 21° of inclination, and extends itself, in its western aspect, into a flat dome-shaped summit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mazarága</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>From the Ysaróg I returned through Nága and Nabua to Yriga. The chief of the Montesinos had received daily rations for 22 men, with whom he professed to make a road to the summit; but when, on the evening of the third day, he came himself to Yriga, in order to fetch more provisions, on the pretext that the work still required some time for execution, I explained that I should endeavour to ascend the mountain on the following morning, and requested him to act as guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piracy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-18b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-18b/</guid>
      <description>Early in the morning I rode on the pastor&amp;rsquo;s horse to Legaspi, and in the evening through deep mud to the alcalde at Albáy.
It was June in the middle of the so-called dry season. But it rained almost every day. The road between Albáy and Legaspi was worse than ever.
During my visit, information arrived from the commandant of the falúas on the south coast that, as he was pursuing 2 pirate vessels, 6 others suddenly made their appearance, in order to cut off his return; for which reason he had quickly made his way back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>TRAVELS IN SÁMAR.- WEATHER.-ELECTION OF OFFICIALS.-NORTH COAST.-CÁTBA
LOGAN.&amp;ndash;THE FLYING LEMUR.&amp;ndash;SERPENT TAMERS.-TERTIARY PETRIFACTIONE. — THE RAPIDS OF THE LOQUILÓcun.-THE MAGO.
At the present time, each island has its separate governor.
The older authors called the island Tendaya, Ybabáo, and also Achan and Philippina.
In later times, the eastern side was called Ybabáo, and the western Samar, which is now the official denomination for the whole island, the eastern shore being distinguished as the Contracosta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>TRAVELS IN BÁMAR (CONTINUED).-SOUTH-SEA ISLANDERS CAST AWAY BY srorus –
BURIAL CAVERNS AND FUNERAL CUSTOMS OF THE ANCIENT BISAYANS.—CROCUDILES.&amp;ndash; IGNATIUS BEANS.-COCOA-NUT OIL.
In Guiuan, I was visited by some Micronesians. For the last 14 days, they had been in Sulangan on the small neck of land south-east from Guíuan, diving for pearl mussels (mother-of-pearl). They had sailed from Uleai (Uliai, 7° 20&amp;rsquo; N., 143° 57&amp;rsquo; E. Gr.) in five boats, each of which had a crew of 9 men and carried 40 gourds full of water, with cocoa-nuts and batata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDOLATRY OF THE DEAD</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20b/</guid>
      <description>Their chief idolatry consisted in the worship of those of their ancestors who had most distinguished themselves by courage and genius, whom they regarded as deities.
They called them humalagar, which is the same as manes in the Latin.
Even the aged died under this conceit, choosing particular places, such as one on the island of Leyté, which allowed of their being interred at the edge of the sea, in order that the mariners who crossed over might acknowledge them as deities, and pay &amp;rsquo;them respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ignatius Bean</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20c/</guid>
      <description>In the environs of Basey, the Ignatius bean grows in remarkable abundance, as it also does in the south of Sámar and in some other of the Bisayan islands. It is not present in Luzon. But it is very likely that I have introduced it there unwittingly.
Its sphere of propagation is very limited. My attempts to transplant it to the Botanical Garden of Buitenzorg were fruitless.
Some large plants intended for that purpose, which during my absence arrived for me at Darága, were incorporated by one of my patrons into his own garden ; and some, which were collected by himself and brought to Manila, were afterwards lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufacture Of Coconut Oil</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-20d/</guid>
      <description>On the southern half of the eastern border, on the shore from Borongan by Láuang as far as Guíuan, there are considerable plantations of coconuts, which are most imperfectly applied to oil production.
From Borongan and its visitas, 12,000 pitchers of coconut oil are yearly exported to Manila. Those consumed by men and pigs would suffice for at least 8,000 pitchers.
As 1,000 coconuts yield 8 pitchers and a half. The vicinity of Borongan alone yields annually 6,000,000 coconuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sulphur Smelting</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>CROCODILES.
The island of Leyté is over 25 miles long and almost 12 miles wide. It is 170 square miles.
It is divided from Sámar only by the small strait of San Juanico.
The chief town, Taclóban, or Taclobang, lies at the eastern entrance of this strait. It has a very good harbour and uninterrupted communication with Manila. It is the chief emporium of trade to Leyté, Biliran, and South and East Sámar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice Cultivation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>The inhabitants of Sámar and Leyté (I have not become closely acquainted with any others) belong to one race.*
They are, physically and intellectually, in character, dress, manners and customs, so similar that my notes, which were originally made at different points of the two islands, have, after removal of the numerous repetitions, fused into one, which affords a more complete picture. It also shows their small differences. There are no negritos either in Sámar or Leyté, but many Cimarronese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Family Economy and Debt Slavery</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-22b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-22b/</guid>
      <description>A family consisting of father, mother, and five children requires daily nearly 24 chupas of palay (rice in the husk), which, after winnowing, comes to about 12 chupas.
This at the average price of 4 reals per caban costs about half a real. The price, however, varies.
Sometimes, after the harvest, it is 3 reals per caban. Before it, ten ; and in Albay, even about thirty reals. Then about three cuartos are wanted for extras (as fish, crabs, vegetables, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Superstition</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-22c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-22c/</guid>
      <description>Superstition is rife.
Amulets Every female native wears by a string round the neck with the image of the Virgin Mary. Many also have heathen amulets. I saw an amulet taken from a daring criminal. It consisted of a small ounce flask, stuffed full of vegetable root fibres fried in oil. This is said to make its owner strong and courageous. The capture of this criminal was very difficult. But, as soon as the little flask was taken from him, he gave up all resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philippine Ports</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>In 1830, 7 new ports were opened as an experiment. But due to great frauds in the tolls, they were soon closed again.
This was followed by a custom-house for foreing trade in:
 Zamboanga in 1831 Sual in the Gulf of Lingayen, one of the safest harbours on the west coast of Luzon in 1855 Iloílo in Panay in 1855 Cebú in 1863  Before 1635, the Spaniards had established a fort at Zamboanga, which reduced the piratical excursions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugar and the Benefits of Free Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-23b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-23b/</guid>
      <description>Sugar cultivation increased in Iloilo, Antique, Panay, and Negros because of:
 the higher prices of directly-exported sugar the facility and security of the trade as contrasted with the late monopoly enjoyed by Manila  This led to the development of manufacturing.
In 1857, there were no iron sugar mills on the island. With a wooden sugar mill, only 30% of the sap remained in the cane, even after it had thrice passed through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MANILLA: LIFE IN TOWN AND SUBURB</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-02c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-02c/</guid>
      <description>Manila is inhabited by Spaniards, Creoles, the natives directly connected with them, and Chinese.
It is surrounded by walls and wide ditches on the left or southern bank of the Pasig looking towards the sea.*
It is a hot dried-up place, full of monasteries, convents, barracks, and Government buildings.
Safety, not appearance, was the object of its builders. It reminds the beholder of a Spanish provincial town, and is, next to Goa, the oldest city in the Indies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abacá or Manila Hemp</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>One of the most interesting products of the Philippines is Manila hemp, so called by the French.
But it has few uses. Because of its silky appearance, the natives call it the bandála seed.
In commerce, abacá is the plant where it comes from. It is a wild species of banana known also as Arbol de Cáñamo (hemp-tree), Musa textilis, Lin.
It looks like the edible banana tree (Musa paradisiaca), one of the most important plants of the torrid zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sesal or Sesal-hemp</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-24b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-24b/</guid>
      <description>Sesal, or sesal-hemp is known as Mexican grass and is named after the export harbour of Sisal (in the N. W. of the peninsula). For some years past, it been used increasingly as a substitute for abaca.
It:
 resembles abaca though lacking the fine gloss. is somewhat weaker costs from £5 to £10 less per ton is only used for ships&amp;rsquo; rigging.  The refuse from it has been found an extremely useful adjunct to the materials ordinarily used in the manufacture of paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abacá or Manila Hemp</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>THE TOBACCO MONOPOLY.
In terms of government revenue, tobacco is the most important product of the Philippines.
The Government has strictly monopolized its:
 cultivation manipulation sale  The Government derive a very large portion of their revenue from tobacco. Below are the estimates of its receipts:
Years | Gross Revenue | Expenses | Profit &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; | &amp;mdash; 1866-7 | $8,418,939 | $4,519,866 | $3,899,073 1867 | | 7,033,576 | $2,627,976</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abacá or Manila Hemp</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>THE CHINESE.
I have still to speak of an important portion of the population, viz. the Chinese, who are destined to play a remarkable part, inasmuch as the development of the land-cultivation demanded by the increasing trade and commercial intercourse can be effected only by Chinese industry and perseverance.
Manila has always been a favourite place for Chinese immigrants; and neither the hostility of the people, nor oppressing and prohibitory decrees for a long time on the part of the Government, not even the repeated massacres, have been able to prevent their coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Europeans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>A SCOTCH merchant invited me with such cordiality to come and stay with him.He was one of the wealthiest and most respected men in the city, the cabmen I employed insisted on being paid beforehand every time I rode in their vehicles.
This distrust was occasioned by the scanty feeling of respect most of the Europeans in Manila inspired in the minds of the natives. Many later observations confirmed this impression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Catholicism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04b/</guid>
      <description>The lack of originality, which among the half-castes appears to arise from their equivocal position, is also to be found among the Indians. Distinctly marked national customs, which one would naturally expect to find in such an isolated part of the world, are sought for in vain.
Spanish Catholicism forcibly expelled the civilisation of the Moors, the Incas, and the Philippines. This was done by appropriating in an incredible mannerall existing forms and abuses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colonial Taxation Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04c/</guid>
      <description>It was fortunate that the Philippines had no precious stones or costly spices. In the earlier days of maritime traffic, it was difficult to export the many Philippine agricultural products.
This made conquering the entire islands not worth it. The few Spaniards easily made money in the commerce with China and Mexico, that their haughtiness held themselves aloof from all enterprises which would have imposed the severest labour on the natives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bamboo</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-04d/</guid>
      <description>Bamboos with luxuriant leafy tops grow plentifully by the huts in the rice-fields which fringe the banks of the river.
The bamboo possesses, in proportion to its lightness, an extraordinary strength ;
 Boyle, in his “ Adventures among the Dyaks,” mentions that he actually found pneumatic tinder-boxes, made of bamboo, in use among the Dyaks; Bastian met with them in Burma. Boyle saw a Dyak place some tinder on a broken piece of earthenware, holding it steady with his thumb while he struck it a sharp blow with a piece of bamboo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geography of The Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>If, however, the Bashee or Batanes Islands be included, its area may be said to extend to the twenty-first parallel of north latitude. But neither southwards or northwards does Spanish rule extend to these extreme limits, nor, in fact, does it always reach the far interior of the larger islands. From the eastern to the western extremity of the Philippines the distance is about go of longitude.
Two islands, Luzon, with an area of two thousand, and Mindanao, with one of more than one thousand five hundred square miles, are together larger than all the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laguna</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>My second trip was to Laguna. I left Manila at night in a banca. A banca is a boat made out of a hollow tree, with a vaulted bamboo roof which was so low that it was almost impossible to sit upright under it. The banca-builder appeared to have neglected to consider sitting inside.
A bamboo hurdle placed at the bottom of the boat protects the traveller from the water and serves as a couch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fires in Bulacan</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>The province of Bulacan is on the northern shore of Manila Bay.
A couple of hours brought the steamer to the bar of Binuánga (not Bincanga as it is called in Coello&amp;rsquo;s map), and a third to Bulacan, the capital of the province, situated on the flat banks of an influent of the Pampanga delta.
I was the only European passenger. The others were Tagalogs, half-castes, and a few Chinese. The first more particularly were represented by women, who are generally charged with the management of all business affairs, for which they are much better fitted than the men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Houses of the People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-06b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-06b/</guid>
      <description>I visited several families and received a friendly reception from all of them.
The houses were built of planks, and were placed upon piles elevated 5 feet above the ground. They consisted of a spacious dwelling apartment which opened on one side into the kitchen, and on the other on to an open space, the azotea ;
A lofty roof of palm-trees spread itself above the dwelling, the entrance to which was through the azotea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucban</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-07b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-07b/</guid>
      <description>Lucban I reached Lucban district in 3 hours. It is a prosperous place of 13,000 inhabitants, to the north-east of Majaijai.
A year before my visit, it had been burnt to the ground.
The agricultural produce of Lucban is not very important because of the area&amp;rsquo;s mountainous nature. But it has considerable industrial activity.
The people:
 weave fine straw hats from the fibre of the leaf of the buri palm-tree (Corypha sp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The San Bernardino Straits</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>Towards the end of August I started from Manila for Albáy in a schooner which had brought a cargo of hemp and was returning in ballast.
It was fine when we set sail; but on the following day the signs of a coming storm increased so rapidly that the captain resolved to return and seek protection in the small but secure harbour of Marivéles, a creek on the southern shore of Bataan, the province forming the western boundary of the bay of Manilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legaspi in Albay</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-08b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-08b/</guid>
      <description>Legaspi Legaspi is the principal port of Albáy province.
Its roadstead, however, is very unsafe, and, being exposed to the northeasterly storms, is perfectly useless during the winter.
The northnorth-east wind is the prevailing one on this coast; the south-west breeze only blows in June and July. The heaviest storms occur between October and January.
They generally set in with a gentle westerly wind, accompanied with rain. The gale presently veers round to the north or the south, and attains the height of its fury when it reaches the north-east or the south-east.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mayon Volcano</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>My Spanish friends enabled me to rent a house in Darága,* a well-to-do town of 20,000 inhabitants at the foot of the Mayon volcano, 1.5 leagues from Legaspi.
Its summit was considered inaccessible until 2 young Scotchmen, Paton and Stewart, demonstrated the contrary. Since then, several natives have ascended the mountain, but no Europeans.
I set out on September 25 and passed the night, by the advice of Señor Muñoz, in a hut 1,000 feet above sea level in order to begin the ascent the next morning with unimpaired vigour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Relations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Magellan discovered the Philippines in his memorable first circumnavigation of the globe. He followed the sun in its apparent daily path around the world. Every successive degree he compassed on his eastern course added 4 minutes to the length of his day.
When he reached the Philippines, the difference amounted to 16 hours. This apparently escaped his notice. Elcano, the captain of his only remaining vessel, was unaware on his return to the longitude of his departure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Relations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>The Philippines was discovered by Magellan on March 16, 1521–St. Lazarus&amp;rsquo;s day.* But it was not until 1564, after many previous efforts had miscarried, that Legaspi, who left New Spain with five ships, took possession of the Archipelago in the name of Philip II.
The discoverer had christened the islands after the sanctified Lazarus. This name, however, never grew into general use; the Spaniards persistently calling them the Western Islands—Islas del Poniente; and the Portuguese, Islas del Oriente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication Between Hongkong and Spain</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-01b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-01b/</guid>
      <description>Manila lies 650 nautical miles south-east of Hongkong. A mail steamer can travel it in 3 to 4 days. This allows of a fortnightly postal communication between the Philippines and the rest of the world.
European mail reaches Manila through Singapore and Hong-Kong. Singapore is about equidistant from Hongkong and Manila. Letters therefore could be received at both ports at the same time if they were sent direct from Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earthquakes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-01c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-01c/</guid>
      <description>Manila is situated on both sides of the river Pasig. The town itself, surrounded with walls and ramparts, with its low tiled roofs and scattered towers. It appeared like some ancient European fortress.
On June 3, 1863 at 7:31pm an earthquake shook the preparations for the festival of Corpus Christi.
The firmest buildings reeled visibly, walls crumbled, and beams snapped in two. The dreadful shock lasted half a minute. But this little interval was enough to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juan de Salcédo</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-27c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-27c/</guid>
      <description>Juan de Salcédo was the most illustrious of all the conquerors.
Supported by his grandfather, Legaspi, with 45 Spanish soldiers, he fitted out an expedition at his own expense, embarked at Manila in May 1572, examined all parts of the west coast of the island, landed in all the bays which were accessible to his light-draught ships, and was well received by the natives at most of the places.
He generally found great opposition in penetrating into the interior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samar Animals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-19b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-19b/</guid>
      <description>In Sámar, the flying monkey or lemur (the káguang of the Bisayans—galeopithecus) is not rare.
These animals, which are of the size of the domestic cat, belong to the quadrumana ; but, like the flying squirrels, they are provided with a volucral membrane, which, commencing at the neck, and passing over the fore and hinder limbs, reaches to the tail; by means of which they are able to glide from one tree to another at a very obtuse angle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain Versus Britain Versus America</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-28d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-28d/</guid>
      <description>Spain should be given credit for having bettered the condition of a people who were comparatively highly civilised, but were continually distracted by petty wars which led them into a disordered and uncultivated state.
The natives of these beautiful islands have lived as comfortably during the last hundred years, protected from all external enemies and governed by mild laws, as those of any other tropical country under native or European sway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Colonial Government and Cavite Mutiny</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-27b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-27b/</guid>
      <description>Apart from the priests, the first-comers consisted only of officials, soldiers and sailors. To them, naturally, fell all the high profits of the China trade.
Manila was their chief market. It also attracted a great portion of the external Indian trade, which the Portuguese had frightened away from Malacca by their excessive cruelty.
The Portuguese still remained in Macao and the Moluccas. But they wanted those remittances which were almost exclusively sought after by the Chinese, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stalactite Springs</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-13c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-13c/</guid>
      <description>At the end of November, I left the beautiful lake of Buhi, and proceeded from its eastern angle for a short distance up the little river Sapa,* the alluvial deposits of which form a considerable feature in the configuration of the lake.
Across a marshy meadow we reached the base of the Malináo or Buhi mountain, the slippery clay of the lower slope merging higher up into volcanic sand. The damp undergrowth swarmed with small leeches; I never before met with them in such numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Galleon Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>The Manila custom-house requires many formalities which the native minor officials exercised without discretion. This is:
 different from the easy routine of the English free ports in Asia which I had just came from wearisome to me.  A respectable merchant obtained for me a guarantee, as a particular favour, to have permission to disembark after a detention of 16 hours.
But even then, I was not allowed to take the smallest article of luggage on shore with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribal People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-13b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/jagor/ph/chapter-13b/</guid>
      <description>I rode from Bátu to Nábua over a good road in half an hour. The country was flat, with rice-fields on both sides of the road.
In Bátu the rice was only just planted. In Nábua, it already was almost ripe.
I was unable to obtain any explanation of this incongruity, and know not how to account for such a difference of climate between two hamlets situated in such close proximity to one another, and separated by no range of hills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
