<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>One, Unity, and Contraries on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in One, Unity, and Contraries on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle explains One</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;One&amp;rsquo; has several meanings; the things that are directly and of their own nature and not accidentally called one may be summarized under four heads, though the word is used in more senses.
 There is the continuous, either in general, or especially that which is continuous by nature and not by contact nor by being together.  Of these, that has more unity and is prior, whose movement is more indivisible and simpler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the One? How must we conceive of It?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-2/</guid>
      <description>The substance and nature of the One exists in two ways.
What is the One? How must we conceive of It?
Should we take the One itself as being a substance, as both the Pythagoreans say in earlier and Plato in later times?
Or is there an underlying nature that indicates that the One should be described more intelligibly as a physical substance which is similar to love, or to air, or to the indefinite?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrariety according to Aristotle</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Contrariety is the greatest difference between things.
Things which differ in genus have no way to one another, but are too far distant and are not comparable; and for things that differ in species the extremes from which generation takes place are the contraries, and the distance between extremes-and therefore that between the contraries-is the greatest.
&amp;ldquo;But surely that which is greatest in each class is complete. For that is greatest which cannot be exceeded, and that is complete beyond which nothing can be found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle explains Whether and Plurality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-5/</guid>
      <description>One thing has one contrary. How is one opposed to the many? How is equal opposed to the big and the small?
&amp;ldquo;Whether&amp;rdquo; compares opposites. Opposites alone cannot be present together.
Therefore if &amp;ldquo;whether&amp;rdquo; is contrary to the more and the less, then it will be contrary to more things than one.
But if the unequal means the same as both the greater and the less together, the equal will be opposite to both (and the difficulty supports those who say the unequal is a &amp;rsquo;two&amp;rsquo;), but it follows that one thing is contrary to two others, which is impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 5</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-7/</guid>
      <description>Since contraries admit of an intermediate and in some cases have it, intermediates must be composed of the contraries.
  All intermediates are in the same genus as the things between which they stand. For we call those things intermediates, into which that which changes must change first; e.g. if we were to pass from the highest string to the lowest by the smallest intervals, we should come sooner to the intermediate notes, and in colours if we were to pass from white to black, we should come sooner to crimson and grey than to black; and similarly in all other cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 9</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-10/part-9/</guid>
      <description>Why do women and men have the same species, while female and male are contrary?
Why a female and a male animal are not different in species, though this difference belongs to animal in virtue of its own nature, and not as paleness or darkness does; both &amp;lsquo;female&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;male&amp;rsquo; belong to it qua animal. This question is almost the same as the other, why one contrariety makes things different in species and another does not, e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
