<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Principles of Philosophical Enquiries Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Principles of Philosophical Enquiries Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of Philosophical Enquiries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>In the first ages of society before the establishment of law, order, and security, people are not so curious to find out those hidden chains of events which bind together the seemingly disjointed appearances of nature.
The subsistence of a savage is precarious.
 His life is exposed to the rudest dangers everyday. He is not interested in what renders nature a more connected spectacle to his imagination. He does not notice many of these smaller incoherences which perplex philosophers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principles of Philosophical Enquiries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy first became known to the world via Socrates’ school from Plato and Aristotle. They consolidated the former systems, which were consistent with their own general principles to make their own systems.
They did not derive anything from the Ionian Philosophy.
 Plato and Aristotle derived the fundamental principles of almost all their doctrines from the Pythagorean school. Plato also borrowed something from the sects of Cratylus and Heraclitus, and Xenophanes, Parmenides, Melissus, and Zeno.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problems with Aristotle and the Stoics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/philosophy/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>There is a natural notion that those things, out of which any object is composed, must exist antecedent to that object.
This notion seems to have misled those early philosophers. But the things out of which all particular objects seem to be composed, are=
 the stuff or matter of those objects, and the form or specific Essence which determines them to be of this or that class of things  It was thought that these must have existed before the object which was made up between them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
