<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Four Virtues on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Four Virtues on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Justice is Svadharma</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom Socrates I will discover justice by starting with the assumption that our State, if rightly ordered, is perfect. Being perfect, therefore, has:
 wisdom courage temperance justice.  Wisdom is the first virtue found in a State. It means being good in counsel. Good counsel is a kind of knowledge because ignorant men cannot counsel well. There are many and diverse kinds of knowledge in a State, such as the knowledge carpentry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice is Svadharma</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Socrates The last virtue is justice which we now hunt for. The hunting grounds are dark and perplexing. I perceived something so I tracked it. At the beginning of our enquiry, there was justice tumbling about at our feet yet we never saw her. We are like people who go about looking for what was already in their hands.
The original principle at the foundation of the State is that one man should practise one thing only whatever his nature was best adapted to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nature of Science </title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Socrates The same principle holds in the sciences. The object of science is knowledge. But the object of a particular science is a particular kind of knowledge.
The science of house-building is a kind of knowledge different from other kinds. It is therefore called &amp;ldquo;architecture&amp;rdquo; because it has a particular quality which no other has. It has this particular quality because it has a particular object. This is true of the other arts and sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well-ordered States with Self-Restraint</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>Adeimantus What would you say about:
 the business of the agora, the ordinary dealings between men, the agreements with artisans, insult and injury, the commencement of actions, and the appointment of juries?   Socrates There may also arise questions about:
 impositions of market and harbour dues, the regulations of markets, police, harbours, etc.  But, heavens! Shall we condescend to legislate on any of these particulars?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom and Courage</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/simple-republic/book-4/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Adeimantus A person might say:
 that you are making the guardians miserable, and that they are the cause of their own unhappiness, that the city in fact belongs to them, but they are none the better for it, our poor guardians are no better than mercenaries quartered in the city and always at guard, whereas other men:  acquire lands, build large and handsome houses, have everything handsome about them, offer sacrifices to the gods on their own account, practise hospitality, and have gold and silver.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
