<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rent on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rent on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction on Rent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Rent is a monopoly price  1  Rent is naturally the highest which the tenant can afford to pay.
The landlord tries to leave the tenant only:
 the wages needed to maintain his workers, and ordinary profits after maintaining his capital.  Ordinary profit is the smallest share which the tenant can have without being a loser. The landlord seldom means to leave him any more. The landlord naturally tries to gain as rent whatever is left over of the price after ordinary profits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1=  Food</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-1a/</guid>
      <description>10  Food is always in demand because men, like animals, naturally multiply in proportion to their subsistence.
Food can always command labour, especially the class of labour in the neighborhood that grew it. But it might not always command a higher class of labour which have much higher wages than the class that produced the food.
 11  Agricultural lands produce more food than is needed by the agricultural labour that produces it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Raw Produce Which Not Always Affords Rent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-2a/</guid>
      <description>53  Human food is the only produce of land which always affords some rent to the landlord.
 54  After food, clothing and lodging are the two great wants of mankind.
 55  In its rude state, land has a super-abundance of the raw materials for clothing and lodging, more than it can feed.
In its improved state, it can sometimes feed more people than it can supply with clothing and lodging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Raw Produce Which Not Always Affords Rent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>Coal  61  The non-food produce of land which afford rent, do not afford it always.
Even in cultivated countries, the demand for other produce does not always afford a greater price than what is sufficient to:
 pay wages replace the stock with ordinary profits  Whether the demand affords such a price depends on different circumstances.
 62  For example, a coal mine affords rent depending on its fertility and situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precious Metals and Stones</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-2c/</guid>
      <description>74  The price of coals in Westmorland or Shropshire can have little effect on their price at Newcastle.
Their price in Lionnois has no effect at all on their price at Newcastle. The produce of distant coal mines can never compete with one another. But the produce of the most distant metallic mines frequently do. The price of metals at the most fertile mines must affect the price at every other mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The variations of the ratos between the Values the of Food and Non-Food Rude Produce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3a/</guid>
      <description>89  The increase of food from the increasing cultivation increases the demand for the non-food produce of land. This demand will then be applied to use or to ornament.
There should be only one variation in the comparative values of the commodities for use and the commodities for ornament.
The value of non-food produce should constantly rise relative to food produce.
As art and industry advance, clothing, lodging, fossils, minerals, precious metals and stones gradually become more in demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digression on the Variations in the Value of Silver During the Last Four Centuries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1a1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1a1/</guid>
      <description>First Period 1262-1570  96  In 1350 and for some time before, the average price of the quarter of wheat in England was not lower than 4 ounces of silver Tower-weight, equal to 20 shillings today.
It fell gradually. From 1500 to 1570, its price was 2 ounces of silver, equal to 10 shillings today.
 97  In 1350, the 25th of Edward 3rd enacted The Statute of Labourers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes in Judging Wheat and Silver Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1a2/</guid>
      <description>110  Many authors on prices thought that from the time of Julius Cæsar&amp;rsquo;s invasion to the discovery of American mines, silver value was continually decreasing.
They based this opinion from:
 agricultural prices and the popular notion that silver value declines as its quantity increases because rising national wealth increases the quantity of silver in every country   111  They made three mistakes on the observations on wheat=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mistakes in Judging Wheat and Silver Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1a3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1a3/</guid>
      <description>120  The most judicious writers inferred the high value of silver in ancient times not so much from the low price of wheat, but from other rude produce.
In those rude ages, wheat was a sort of manufacture. It was much dearer than unmanufactured commodities such as cattle, poultry, game, etc.
Unmanufactured commodities were much cheaper than wheat in those barbarous times.
 But this cheapness was not the effect of the high value of silver, but of the low value of those commodities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second period (1570-1640) and Third period (1650-1700)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1b/</guid>
      <description>Second Period (1570-1640)  135  The opinion on the progress of silver value from 1570-1640 is unanimous.
 136  From 1570 to 1640, the proportion of silver and wheat values were opposite.
 Silver sunk in its real value. Wheat rose in its nominal price.  Instead of 2 ounces of silver the quarter or 120 pence today, it was sold for 6 and 8 ounces of silver or 360-480 pence today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of the Three Periods</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d1c/</guid>
      <description>158  The end of this chapter has the prices of wheat from 1741-1750 and 1731-1740
Its average was not so much below the general average of the first 64 years of the century.
 The year 1740 was a year of extraordinary scarcity. The years 1730-1749 were opposite those of 1750-1769. 1730-1749 were below the century&amp;rsquo;s average, despite the dear years. 1751-1770 were above the century&amp;rsquo;s average, despite the cheap ones (for example= 1759).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Demand on Changes in Silver Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d2a/</guid>
      <description>163  Since the discovery of America, the market for its silver mines has been growing more extensive for three reasons.
Reason 1: The European market has become more extensive.  164  Most of Europe has improved since the discovery of America. England, Holland, France, Germany, Sweden, Denmark, and Russia, have all advanced in agriculture and manufactures.
Italy did not go backwards.
 The fall of Italy preceded the conquest of Peru and has recovered a little since.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Demand and the Ratio of Gold to Silver</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d2b/</guid>
      <description>169  The continual consumption of the precious metals is very sensible:
 in coin by wearing in plate both by wearing and cleaning  Such metals require a very great annual supply.
The consumption of those metals in manufactures is much more rapid and sensible though it may be less than this gradual consumption in coin and plate.
In Birmingham manufactures alone, the gold and silver annually employed in gilding and plating is more than £50,000 sterling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digression: The effect of improvement on real value of rude produce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3a/</guid>
      <description>193  Rude produce may be divided into three:
  The ones that human industry cannot multiply at all Its real price may rise to any degree.
  The ones that human industry can multiply in proportion to the demand. Its real price may rise to a certain boundary.
  The ones that human industry can multiply in a limited or uncertain way. Its real price may rise, stay the same, or even fall in the progress of improvement, according to the efforts of human industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Kind: Produce that can be multiplied according to demand</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3b1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3b1/</guid>
      <description>195  The second kind is the rude produce which human industry can multiply in proportion to the demand.
It consists of useful plants and animals which are naturally plentiful. This makes them of little use in uncultivated countries. But they gain value as cultivation advances.
During a long period of improvement, their amount diminishes while their demand increases. Their real value gradually rises until it reaches maximum profitability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Kind: Poultry and Pork</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3b2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3b2/</guid>
      <description>Poultry  202  In every farm, the offals of the barn and stables will maintain poultry.
These are fed with what would otherwise be lost and are a mere save-all. The farmer can sell his poultry for very little because they did not cost him anything. Almost all that he gets is pure gain.
Poultry prices can be so low that it discourages him from feeding any more. But in countries ill-cultivated and thinly inhabited, the poultry raised without cost are often sufficient to supply the whole demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Kind of Raw Produce</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3c1/</guid>
      <description>208  The third kind is the produce which the amount can be increased by human industry in a limited or uncertain way.
Its real price naturally rises in the progress of improvement. But it depends on the different accidents which affect human effort.
 209  The amount of some kinds of rude produce entirely depend on the amount of other kinds of rude produce.
For example, wool or raw hides are limited by the number of cattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Kind</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3c2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d3c2/</guid>
      <description>Fish  222  The multiplication fish is both limited and uncertain.
It is limited by:
 the local situation of the country the proximity of its provinces from the sea the number of its lakes and rivers the fertility or barrenness of those seas, lakes and rivers to fish  As population increases, there will be more buyers of fish. They will have more goods to buy fish with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digression Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/part-3b-d4/</guid>
      <description>229  Most of the writers who collected the money prices in ancient times, considered the low money price of wheat and other goods (the high value of gold and silver) as a proof of=
 the scarcity of those metals, and the poverty of the country then.  This notion is connected with the Commercial system It measures wealth as the abundance, and poverty as the scarcity of gold and silver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-11/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>255  Every improvement in the society&amp;rsquo;s circumstances tends to directly or indirectly=
 raise the real rent of land, and increase the landlord&amp;rsquo;s real wealth.   256  The extension of improvement and cultivation raises it directly. The landlord&amp;rsquo;s share of the produce increases with the increase of the produce.
 257  That rise in the real price of the rude produce of land is first the effect of extended improvement and cultivation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
