<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enquiry on Human Understanding on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enquiry on Human Understanding on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Metaphysics Research</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s1b/</guid>
      <description>If these studies were useless, they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be despised since they are a harmless pleasure. The sweetest and most inoffensive path of life leads through the avenues of science and learning; and whoever can either remove any obstructions in this way, or open up any new prospect, ought so far to be esteemed a benefactor to mankind.
Though these researches may appear painful and fatiguing, it is with some minds as with some bodies, which being endowed with vigorous and florid health, require severe exercise, and reap a pleasure from what, to the generality of mankind, may seem burdensome and laborious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s2/</guid>
      <description>There is a big difference between the mind&amp;rsquo;s perceptions:
 when a man feels the pain of excessive heat, or the pleasure of moderate warmth when he afterwards recalls to his memory this sensation, or anticipates it by his imagination.  These faculties may mimic the perceptions of the senses. But they never can entirely reach the force and vivacity of the original sentiment.
The utmost we say of them, even when they operate with greatest vigour, is, that they represent their object in so lively a manner, that we could almost say we feel or see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association of Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s3/</guid>
      <description>There is a connection between the different thoughts or ideas of the mind, and that, in their appearance to the memory or imagination
They introduce each other with a certain degree of method and regularity. In our more serious thinking or discourse this is so observable that any particular thought, which breaks in upon the regular tract or chain of ideas, is immediately remarked and rejected.
Even in our wildest and most wandering reveries, nay in our very dreams, we shall find, if we reflect, that the imagination ran not altogether at adventures, but that there was still a connexion upheld among the different ideas, which succeeded each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubts on the Mind&#39;s Operations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s4/</guid>
      <description>20
All the objects of human reason or enquiry may naturally be divided into two kinds:
  Relations of Ideas   This includes Geometry, Algebra, and Arithmetic &amp;ndash; every affirmation which is either intuitively or demonstratively certain.
That the square of the hypothenuse is equal to the square of the two sides, is a proposition which expresses a relation between these figures.
That three times five is equal to the half of thirty, expresses a relation between these numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubts on the Mind&#39;s Operations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s4b/</guid>
      <description>PART 2 But we have not yet attained any tolerable satisfaction with regard to the question first proposed. Each solution still gives rise to a new question as difficult as the foregoing, and leads us on to farther enquiries.  When it is asked, What is the nature of all our reasonings concerning matter of fact? the proper answer seems to be, that they are founded on the relation of cause and effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skeptical Solution to these Doubts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s5/</guid>
      <description>The passion for philosophy, like that for religion, aims at the correction of our manners and extirpation of our vices.
But because of imprudence, it can foster am inclination and push the mind more resolutely towards that side which already draws too much.
We aspire to the magnanimous firmness of the philosophic sage and try to confine our pleasures within our own minds. But we might in the end, render our philosophy like that of Epictetus and other Stoics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s6/</guid>
      <description>There is no such thing as Chance, only our ignorance of the real cause of any event.
There is certainly a probability, which arises from a superiority of chances on any side; and according as this superiority encreases, and surpasses the opposite chances, the probability receives a proportionable encrease, and begets still a higher degree of belief or assent to that side, in which we discover the superiority.
If a dye were marked with one figure or number of spots on four sides, and with another figure or number of spots on the two remaining sides, it would be more probable, that the former would turn up than the latter; though, if it had a thousand sides marked in the same manner, and only one side different, the probability would be much higher, and our belief or expectation of the event more steady and secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idea of Consequential Connection</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s7/</guid>
      <description>Math&amp;rsquo;s great advantage over the moral sciences is that its ideas are sensible.
This makes them always clear and determinate. The smallest distinction between them is immediately perceptible. The same words express the same ideas, without ambiguity or variation. An oval is never mistaken for a circle, nor an hyperbola for an ellipsis.
The isosceles and scalenum are distinguished by boundaries more exact than vice and virtue, right and wrong. If any term be defined in geometry, the mind readily, of itself, substitutes, on all occasions, the definition for the term defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Consequence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s8/</guid>
      <description>We would expect that in most disputed questions since the first origin of philosophy, that the meaning of all the terms, at least, should have been agreed upon among the disputants.
and our enquiries, in the course of two thousand years, been able to pass from words to the true and real subject of the controversy.
For how easy may it seem to give exact definitions of the terms employed in reasoning, and make these definitions, not the mere sound of words, the object of future scrutiny and examination?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Consequence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s8b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s8b/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 It is very common for people to refute a philosophical hypothesis by saying that it will have dangerous consequences to religion and morality.
Opinions that lead to absurdities are certainly false. But opinions are not false because of their dangerous consequences.
Such topics, therefore, ought entirely to be forborne; as serving nothing to the discovery of truth, but only to make the person of an antagonist odious. This I observe in general, without pretending to draw any advantage from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reason of Animals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s9/</guid>
      <description>All our reasonings concerning matter of fact are founded on a kind of Analogy, which leads us to expect from any cause the same events, which we have observed to result from similar causes.
Where the causes are entirely similar, the analogy is perfect, and the inference, drawn from it, is regarded as certain and conclusive: nor does any man ever entertain a doubt, where he sees a piece of iron, that it will have weight and cohesion of parts; as in all other instances, which have ever fallen under his observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miracles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s10/</guid>
      <description>The doctrine of miracles is not significant.
But Dr. Tillotson argues against the reality of miracles. His argument is the most concise, elegant, and strong against miracles.
The authority of Christian scriptures is founded merely in the testimony of the apostles.
 They were the eye-witnesses to the miracles of our Saviour.  Those miracles proved his divine mission.    The evidence for the truth of the Christian religion is therefore less than the truth from our senses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miracles -- Enquiry on Human Understanding Simplified</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s10b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s10b/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 The testimony of a miracle might be the entire proof of it. The falsehood of that testimony would be a real prodigy.
But there never was a miraculous event established on so full an evidence.
 In all history, no miracle has been attested to by a sufficient number of men of unquestioned good-sense, education, and learning, as to secure us against all delusion  Such people cannot be suspected of wanting to deceive others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Providence and a Future State</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s11/</guid>
      <description>My friend loves sceptical paradoxes. He advanced many principles which I do not approve of. Our conversation began with my admiring the singular good fortune of philosophy, which, as it requires entire liberty above all other privileges, and chiefly flourishes from the free opposition of sentiments and argumentation, received its first birth in an age and country of freedom and toleration, and was never cramped, even in its most extravagant principles, by any creeds, concessions, or penal statutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic (Skeptical) Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s12/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 The most philosophical reasonings have been on proving the existence of a Deity, and refute the fallacies of Atheists.
Yet most religious philosophers still dispute whether anyone can be so blinded as to be a speculative atheist. How shall we reconcile these contradictions?
The knights-errant wandered about to clear the world of dragons and giants.
They believed in them.
The skeptic is another enemy of religion.
He naturally provokes the indignation of all divines and graver philosophers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic (Skeptical) Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s12b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s12b/</guid>
      <description>It may seem a very extravagant attempt of the sceptics to destroy reason by argument and ratiocination.
Yet is this the grand scope of all their enquiries and disputes.
They try to find objections, both to our abstract reasonings, and to those which regard matter of fact and existence.
The chief objection against all abstract reasonings comes from the ideas of space and time. Ideas might be very clear in common life and to a careless view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s7b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/enquiry/s7b/</guid>
      <description>But there still remains one method of avoiding this conclusion, and one source which we have not yet examined. When any natural object or event is presented, it is impossible for us, by any sagacity or penetration, to discover, or even conjecture, without experience, what event will result from it, or to carry our foresight beyond that object which is immediately present to the memory and senses.  Even after one instance or experiment where we have observed a particular event to follow upon another, we are not entitled to form a general rule, or foretell what will happen in like cases; it being justly esteemed an unpardonable temerity to judge of the whole course of nature from one single experiment, however accurate or certain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
