<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PR Sarkar on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PR Sarkar on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5 Types of Criminals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/criminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/criminals/</guid>
      <description>There are 5 categories of criminals:
 Criminals by Nature  Some few men and women are born with a deranged mind. The cause of their mental derangement is concealed within the defects of their body and glands. Such people can be divided into two main groups.
  The people who are normally very quiet, but in whom truthfulness and doing good to others are against their nature. They derive malevolent pleasure from lying and harming others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corrective Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/justice/</guid>
      <description>Vicára is “justice” in English. It means “a particular type of mental process to ascertain the &amp;ldquo;truth&amp;rdquo;.
Human actions depend on relative principles. Justice is the truth in this relative world, within society.
The struggle between progressive and regressive forces, between good and evil, is a permanent feature of society. Justice lets the human intellect have an increasing number of opportunities to choose the path of righteousness.
Administering Justice Judgements are not always correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Judges</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/judges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/judges/</guid>
      <description>People judge the mistakes of others to the best of their own intellectual capacities. This is alright as long as people keep the ideal of welfare in front of them.
Moralists have different opinions on the final stage of the judicial process (the extent to which people have the right to penalize others).
If a person is tried and no action is taken as a result of the trial, the person in question will not have to face the possibility of a miscarriage of justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtue and Vice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/virtue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/virtue/</guid>
      <description>In most countries crime is defined with reference to a sense of pápa [vice] and puńya [virtue].
These have their roots in the religions of individual countries.
For example, English people customarily believe that suicide is one of the gravest sins. According to the customary belief of Indians, suicide is a sin, but not a grave one.
The Japanese do not consider suicide to be a sin at all.
That is why the penal codes of these three countries are different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/jobs/</guid>
      <description>Various Occupations
That which keeps something alive is said to be its vrtti [occupation]. The physical pabula on which the mind depends for its existence and development, or the objects on which the mind ideates, are one’s mental occupation. The subtlest feeling a person can experience, which fills the mind with bliss, can be said to be one’s spiritual occupation. In the same way there are various physical occupations which preserve one’s physical existence and maintain the body.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
