<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organization of the State on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organization of the State on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Federated States</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Article 25. The states are organized and governed by the Constitutions and laws they adopt, in accordance with the principles of this Constitution.
 1  All powers that this Constitution does not prohibit the states from exercising shall be conferred on them.
 2  The states shall have the power to operate, directly or by means of concession, the local services of piped gas, as provided for by law, it being forbidden to issue any provisional measure for its regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Municipalities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Article 29. Municipalities shall be governed by organic law.
The organic law will be voted in two readings:
 with a minimum interval of 10 days in between approved by 2/3 of the members of the Municipal Chamber  the Municipal Chamber shall:
 promulgate the organic law observe the principles established in:  this Constitution the Constitution of the respective state the following precepts:     election of the Mayor, Vice-Mayor and Councilmen for a term of office of 4 years, by means of direct election held simultaneously throughout the country election of the Mayor and Vice-Mayor on the first Sunday of October of the year preceding the end of the term of office of those they are to succeed, subject, in the case of municipalities with over two hundred thousand voters, to the provisions set forth in article 77 investiture of the Mayor and Vice-Mayor on January 1 of the year subsequent to the year of the election the following limits shall apply to the composition of Municipal Chambers:     Municipal Population Councilmen     15,000 inhabitants 9   15k- 30k 11   30k- 50k 13   50k- 80k 15   80k- 120k 17   120k-160k 19   160k-300k 21   300k-450k 23   450k-600k 25   600k-750k 27   750k-900k 29   900k-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Political and Administrative Organization</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 18. The political and administrative organization of Brazil comprises:
 the Union the states the Federal District the municipalities  All of them are autonomous.
 1  Brasília is the federal capital.
 2  The federal territories are part of the Union.
Their establishment, transformation into states or reintegration into the state of origin shall be regulated by a supplementary law.
 3  The states may:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Union</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Article 20. The following are property of the Union:
 the property which presently belongs to it and those which may be attributed to it the   unoccupied lands essential to the defense of the boundaries fortifications and military constructions federal routes of communication and the preservation of the environment, as defined by law;  the lakes, rivers and any watercourses in lands within its domain, or that wash more than one state, that:   serve as boundaries with other countries, or extend into foreign territory or proceed therefrom, as well as bank lands and river beaches;  the river and lake islands in zones bordering with other countries; sea beaches; ocean and off-shore islands, excluding those which are the seat of Municipalities, with the exception of areas assigned to public services and to federal environmental units, and those referred to in article 26, 2 the natural resources of the continental shelf and of the exclusive economic zone; the territorial sea; tide lands and those added to them; the hydraulic energy potentials; the mineral resources, including those of the subsoil; the natural underground cavities and the archaeological and pre-historic sites; those lands traditionally occupied by the Indians  Paragraph 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-03/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER V: The Federal District and the Territories
Section I: The Federal District
Article 32. The Federal District, which may not be divided into municipalities, shall be governed by an organic law, voted in two readings, with a minimum interval of ten days, and approved by two-thirds of the Legislative Chamber, which shall enact it, in accordance with the principles set forth in this Constitution. Paragraph 1. The legislative powers reserved to the states and municipalities are attributed to the Federal District.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
