<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aphorisms Book 1 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aphorisms Book 1 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Footnotes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/footnotes/</guid>
      <description>[2] Bacon uses the term in its ancient sense, and means one who, knowing the occult properties of bodies, is able to startle the ignorant by drawing out of them wonderful and unforeseen changes. See the 85th aphorism of this book, and the 5th cap. book iii. of the De Augmentis Scientiarum, where he speaks more clearly.—Ed.
[3] By this term axiomata, Bacon here speaks of general principles, or universal laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novum Organum</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/preface/</guid>
      <description>Those who have dogmatized on nature from self-conceit or arrogance have inflicted the greatest injury on philosophy and learning.
 They have stifled and interrupted inquiry exactly in proportion as they have prevailed in bringing others to their opinion. Their own activity has not counterbalanced the mischief they have occasioned by corrupting and destroying that of others.  On the other hand, those who think on the contrary are not contemptible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE INTERPRETATION OF NATURE</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>1  Man is the minister and interpreter of nature.
He tries to understand the order of nature.  2  The unassisted hand and the understanding left to itself possess but little power.
Effects are produced by the means of instruments and helps, which the understanding requires no less than the hand; and as instruments either promote or regulate the motion of the hand, so those that are applied to the mind prompt or protect the understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE INTERPRETATION OF NATURE</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>38  The idols and false notions which have already preoccupied the human understanding, and are deeply rooted in it, not only so beset men’s minds that they become difficult of access, but even when access is obtained will again meet and trouble us in the instauration of the sciences, unless mankind when forewarned guard themselves with all possible care against them.
 39  4 species of idols beset the human mind,[20][9] to which (for distinction’s sake) we have assigned names, calling the first Idols of the Tribe, the second Idols of the Den, the third Idols of the Market, the fourth Idols of the Theatre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE INTERPRETATION OF NATURE</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>LXXI. The sciences we possess have been principally derived from the Greeks; for the addition of the Roman, Arabic, or more modern writers, are but few and of small importance, and such as they are, are founded on the basis[47] of Greek invention. But the wisdom of the Greeks was professional and disputatious, and thus most adverse to the investigation of truth. The name, therefore, of sophists, which the contemptuous spirit of those who deemed themselves philosophers, rejected and transferred to the rhetoricians—Gorgias,[36] Protagoras, Hippias, Polus—might well suit the whole tribe, such as Plato, Aristotle, Zeno, Epicurus, Theophrastus, and their successors—Chrysippus, Carneades, and the rest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE INTERPRETATION OF NATURE</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>92  By far the greatest obstacle to the advancement of the sciences, and the undertaking of any new attempt or department, is in men’s despair and the idea of impossibility.
Men of a prudent and exact turn of thought are altogether diffident in matters of this nature, considering the obscurity of nature, the shortness of life, the deception of the senses, and weakness of the judgment.
They think, therefore, that in the revolutions of ages and of the world there are certain floods and ebbs of the sciences, and that they grow and flourish at one time, and wither and fall off at another, that when they have attained a certain degree and condition they can proceed no further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE INTERPRETATION OF NATURE</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-1/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>122  People might object that we are being singular and harsh for trying to banish all authorities and sciences with one stroke and assault by our own efforts without the help of the ancients.
Now we are aware, that had we been ready to act otherwise than sincerely, it was not difficult to refer our present method to remote ages, prior to those of the Greeks (since the sciences in all probability flourished more in their natural state, though silently, than when they were paraded with the fifes and trumpets of the Greeks); or even (in parts, at least) to some of the Greeks themselves, and to derive authority and honor from thence; as men of no family labor to raise and form nobility for themselves in some ancient line, by the help of genealogies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
