<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Magna Carta on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Magna Carta on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Articles 1 to 27</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/article-1/</guid>
      <description>The following rights are to be followed forever=
Article 1
The English Church shall be free.
It shall have its rights undiminished, and its liberties unimpaired.
Article 2
If any earl, baron, or other person that holds the King&amp;rsquo;s lands for military service dies, and at his death his heir shall be of full age and owe a ‘relief’, the heir shall have his inheritance on payment of the ancient scale of ‘relief’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles 28-61</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/article-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/article-28/</guid>
      <description>Article 28
No constable or other royal official shall take corn or other movable goods from any man without immediate payment, unless the seller voluntarily offers postponement of this.
Article 29
No constable may compel a knight to pay money for castle-guard if the knight is willing to undertake the guard in person, or with reasonable excuse to supply some other fit man to do it. A knight taken or sent on military service shall be excused from castle-guard for the period of this service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles 61-62</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/article-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/england/magna-carta/article-62/</guid>
      <description>Article 61
SINCE WE HAVE GRANTED ALL THESE THINGS for God, for the better ordering of our kingdom, and to allay the discord that has arisen between us and our barons, and since we desire that they shall be enjoyed in their entirety, with lasting strength, for ever, we give and grant to the barons the following security:
The barons shall elect twenty-five of their number to keep, and cause to be observed with all their might, the peace and liberties granted and confirmed to them by this charter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
