<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vietnamese Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vietnamese Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Economy, Society, Culture, Education, Science, Technology, Environment</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Article 50
The Socialist Republic of Vietnam constructs an independent and sovereign economy which shall:
 promote its internal resources internationally cooperate closely connect with cultural development practices social progressiveness and equality protects the environment exercises industrialization and modernization of the country  Article 51
  The Vietnamese economy is a socialist-oriented market economy with multi-forms of ownership and multi-sectors of economic structure; the state economic sector plays the leading role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Defense</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Article 64
To defend the socialist Vietnamese Fatherland is the business of the entire people.
The State shall consolidate and strengthen national defence by the entire people and the people&amp;rsquo;s security, the people&amp;rsquo;s armed forces being regarded as the core, shall develop to the full the aggregate strength of the country to defend the national territory, and shall contribute to the protection of peace in the region and in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People’s Court And People’s Procuracy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Article 102
 The people’s courts are the judicial organ of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, exercising the judicial power. The people’s courts comprise the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court and other courts established by law. The people’s courts are responsible for the protection of justice, human rights, citizen’s rights, socialist regime, interests of the State, and legal rights and interests of organizations and individuals.  Article 103
 Trials before People&amp;rsquo;s Courts shall be attended by people&amp;rsquo;s assessors, except the case of trials with reduced procedure The trials of the judges and assessors are independent and shall only obey the law; the interference into the trials of the judges and assessors by bodies, organizations, and individuals is strictly prohibited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>POLITICAL SYSTEM</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 1. The Socialist Republic of Vietnam is an independent, sovereign and united country, which in its territorial integrity comprises its mainland, islands, territorial waters and air space.
Article 2. Type of government envisioned
Mentions of social class
  The Socialist Republic of Vietnam State is a socialist rule of law State of the people, by the people, and for the people.
  The people are the masters of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam State; all state powers belong to the people whose base is the alliance between the working class, the peasantry, and the intelligentsia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Citizen’s Fundamental Rights And Duties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 14
 Political, civic, economic, cultural and social human rights and citizen’s rights are recognized, respected, protected, and guaranteed  Human rights and citizen’s rights shall only be restricted in imperative circumstances for the reasons of national defence, national security, social order and security, social morality, and the health of the community.  Article 15
 Citizen&amp;rsquo;s rights are inseparable from citizen’s duties. Binding effect of const rights Every one has the duty to respect the other’s rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Article 94
The Government:
 is the executive organ of the National Assembly exercises the executive power is the highest organ of State  The Government is accountable to the National Assembly and shall make its reports to the National Assembly, its Standing Committee, and the State President.
Article 95
 The Government shall be composed of the Prime Minister, the Deputy Prime Ministers, the Ministers, and heads of organs of ministerial rank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Local Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Article 110
 The administrative units of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam are distributed as follows:  The country is divided into provinces and cities under direct central rule.
The province is divided into districts, provincial cities, and towns.
The city is under direct central rule and is divided into urban districts, rural districts, towns, and units of similar level.
The district is divided into communes and townlets; the provincial city and the town are divided into wards and communes; the urban district is divided into wards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Assembly</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Article 69 The National Assembly is the highest representative organ of the people and the highest organ of State power of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam.
The National Assembly exercises constitutional and legislative powers, decides significant national affairs, and exercise supreme control over all activities of the State.
Article 70
The National Assembly has the following duties and powers:
 To make and amend the Constitution; to make and amend laws; To exercise supreme control over conformity to the Constitution, the law and the resolutions of the National Assembly, to examine the reports of the State President, the Standing Committee of the National Assembly, the Government, the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court, the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Procuracy, the National Commission of Election, the State Audit, and other organs created by the National Assembly; To decide on the objectives, targets, policies, and duties of the national socio- economic development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Council Of Election And The State Audit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Article 117
The National Council of Election is:
 an organ created the National Assembly organizes the election of the National Assembl directs the work of election of the People’s Councils at all levels. comprises a President, vice-Presidents, and members  The details of organization, duties and authorities of the National Council of Election, and the number of its members shall be provided by the law.
Article 118
 The State Audit is an organ created by the National Assembly, shall act independently and only obey the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State President</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/vn/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Article 86
The State President is the Head of State and represents the Socialist Republic of Vietnam internally and externally.
Article 87
The State President shall be elected by the National Assembly from among its members. He is responsible to the National Assembly for his work and reports to it. His term of office follows that of the National Assembly. At the end of the latter&amp;rsquo;s tenure he shall continue in office until a new President of the State is elected by the new legislature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
