<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inherent Morality as Virtue on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inherent Morality as Virtue on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prudence - The Individual&#39;s Character, so far as it affects his own Happiness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  1  We naturally view an individual&amp;rsquo;s character under two aspects=
 As it may affect his own happiness As it may affect the happiness of others   2  Nature first recommends the body&amp;rsquo;s preservation and healthful state to every individual&amp;rsquo;s care. Hunger and thirst, pleasure and pain, heat and cold, etc. are lessons delivered by the voice of Nature herself. Nature directs him what he should choose and avoid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Virtue of Self-command</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3a/</guid>
      <description>1  A man is said to be perfectly virtuous if he acts according to the rules of=
 perfect prudence, strict justice, and proper benevolence.  But the perfect knowledge of those rules alone will not enable him to act in this way. His own passions=
 are very apt to mislead him, and sometimes drive and seduce him to violate all the rules which he himself approves of in all his sober and cool hours  The perfect knowledge will not always enable him to do his duty if it is not supported by the most perfect self-command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Propriety</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3b/</guid>
      <description>14 The point of propriety is the degree of any passion which the impartial spectator approves of. This point is differently situated in different passions.
 In some passions, the excess is less disagreeable than the shortage.
 In such passions, the point of propriety seems to stand high, or nearer to the excess than to the shortage.
 In other passions, the shortage is less disagreeable than the excess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principle of Self-estimation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-3c/</guid>
      <description>22  The principle of self-estimation may be too high or too low.
We like to think highly of ourselves. We feel that some excessive regard is better than any shortage.
But it is different to the impartial spectator. To him, the shortage is less disagreeable than the excess.
We frequently complain of the excess than the shortage.
 When they set themselves before us, their self-estimation mortifies our own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excessive Ego=  Self-esteem, Pride, and Vanity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-4/</guid>
      <description>The Egotistic Man  31  In prosperity, the egotistic man might have some advantage over the modest man. People applaud him louder. Yet with all things fairly computed, the real advantage is always=
 in favour of the modest man, and against the egotistic man  A man is not ashamed if he only gives himself the merit due to him.
 He is content on his character&amp;rsquo;s genuine truth and solidity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Vain Man</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/section-4b/</guid>
      <description>40  It is quite otherwise with the vain man.
 He courts the company of his superiors as much as the proud man shuns it. He thinks that their splendour reflects a splendour on those who are around them. He haunts the courts of kings and the levees of ministers. He gives himself the air of being a candidate for fortune and preferment.  In reality, he possesses the more precious happiness of not being one, if he knew how to enjoy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion on Part 6</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-6/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>54  Prudence is recommended to us by the concern for our own happiness.
Justice and beneficence are recommended to us by the concern for the happiness of others. Justice restrains us from hurting that happiness. Beneficence prompts us to promote it.
Prudence is originally recommended to us by our selfish affections. Justice and beneficence are recommended to us by our benevolent affections. These are recommended to us independent of any regard to:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
