<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 12 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 12 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Substance?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Substance is the principle and cause and first part of the universe, if the universe is a whole.
if it coheres merely by virtue of serial succession, on this view also substance is first, and is succeeded by quality, and then by quantity. At the same time these latter are not even being in the full sense, but are qualities and movements of it,-or else even the not-white and the not-straight would be being; at least we say even these are, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Neither the matter nor the form comes to be-and I mean the last matter and form. For everything that changes is something and is changed by something and into something.
That by which it is changed is the immediate mover; that which is changed, the matter; that into which it is changed, the form. The process, then, will go on to infinity, if not only the bronze comes to be round but also the round or the bronze comes to be; therefore there must be a stop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion is Existed Before Creation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-5/</guid>
      <description>Some things can exist apart and some cannot. Substances can exist apart.
Therefore all things have the same causes, because, without substances, modifications and movements do not exist. Further, these causes will probably be soul and body, or reason and desire and body.
Analogically identical things are principles, i.e. actuality and potency; but these also are not only different for different things but also apply in different ways to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thought is Prior to Desire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-7/</guid>
      <description>This is a possible account of the matter.
If there were no matter, then the universe would have come out of night and &amp;lsquo;all things together&amp;rsquo; and out of non-being.
We have solved these earlier by saying that something has always moved with an unceasing motion in a circle. This is not a theory. This is a fact.
Therefore, the first heaven is eternal. There is therefore also something which moves it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spheres of Eudoxus and Callippus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-8/</guid>
      <description>Is this Substance just one? Or is there more than one of It?
The theory of Ideas does not discuss my Substance. Instead, they rely on Ideas and say that the Ideas are numbers which are unlimited. They do not say why there should be so many numbers.
My Substance is not movable either in itself or accidentally. Instead, It produces the primary eternal and single movement.
But since that which is moved must be moved by something, and the first mover must be in itself unmovable, and eternal movement must be produced by something eternal and a single movement by a single thing, and since we see that besides the simple spatial movement of the universe, which we say the first and unmovable substance produces, there are other spatial movements-those of the planets-which are eternal (for a body which moves in a circle is eternal and unresting; we have proved these points in the physical treatises), each of these movements also must be caused by a substance both unmovable in itself and eternal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divine Thought</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-9/</guid>
      <description>The nature of the divine thought involves certain problems.
Thought is the most divine of things observed by us.
If it thinks of nothing, what is there here of dignity?
It is just like one who sleeps. And if it thinks, but this depends on something else, then (since that which is its substance is not the act of thinking, but a potency) it cannot be the best substance; for it is through thinking that its value belongs to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empedocles and Anaxagoras</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-12/part-10/</guid>
      <description>Which of two ways the nature of the universe contains the good, and the highest good?
Is it something separate and by itself, or as the order of the parts?
Probably in both ways, as an army does. For its good is found both in its order and in its leader, and more in the latter; for he does not depend on the order but it depends on him.
All things are ordered together somehow, but not all alike,-both fishes and fowls and plants; and the world is not such that one thing has nothing to do with another, but they are connected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
