<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government Revenue on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government Revenue on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The funds which belong to the sovereign or commonwealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1a/</guid>
      <description>1  The revenue which pays for national defense and supporting the dignity of the chief magistrate may be drawn=
 from some fund of the commonwealth, independent of the revenue of the people; or from the revenue of the people  Part 1 The funds which belong to the sovereign or commonwealth  2  The funds which belong to the sovereign must consist in stock or land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rent and sale of government lands</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-1b/</guid>
      <description>14  Land is a fund more naturally stable and permanent.
The rent of public lands was the main source of the public revenue of many great nations above the shepherd state. The ancient Greek and Italian republics derived most of the government revenue from the rent of public lands. The ancient European sovereigns for a long time derived their revenue from the rent of the crown lands.
 15  War and the preparation for war create most of the expence of all great modern states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Taxation Maxims</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2a-tax-maxims/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2a-tax-maxims/</guid>
      <description>23  Book 1 has shown that private revenue comes from rent, profit, and wages.
Every tax must ultimately be paid from any or all of those three kinds of revenue.
Part 2 is about the taxes imposed on rent, profit, wages, and on all those three revenues. These three taxes have subdivisions. Many of those taxes are not ultimately paid by the source of revenue it is charged to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed Land Tax</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2b-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2b-article-1/</guid>
      <description>30  A tax on land rent may be based on a valuation which is fixed and does not change with the actual rent which can fluctuate with the land&amp;rsquo;s improvement or decline.
 31  A land-tax assessed according to an invariable rule becomes unequal after some time according to the lands&amp;rsquo; improvement. The tax becomes unequal even if it were equal at the start.
An example is Great Britain&amp;rsquo;s land tax where the valuation of each district to the land-tax in 1692 was very unequal at the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Land Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2c-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2c-article-1/</guid>
      <description>46  The cost of levying a variable land-tax would be greater than levying a fixed land-tax.
Some additional costs would be incurred by=
 the register offices which would be established in the different districts of the countryside, the different valuations of the lands which the proprietor chose to occupy himself.  All this cost might be below the cost incurred by many other taxes which bring a smaller revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on the produce of land</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2d-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2d-article-1/</guid>
      <description>57  Taxes on the produce of land are really taxes on rent.
They are finally paid by the landlord even if they are originally paid by the farmer. When a part of the produce is paid as tax, the farmer computes the yearly value of that part.
 He makes a proportional abatement in the rent to pay to the landlord. All farmers compute beforehand what the yearly church tithe will amount to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on House and Ground Rent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2e-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2e-article-1/</guid>
      <description>66  House rents have two parts=
 The Building-rent The Ground-rent   67  The building-rent is the interest or profit on the capital spent in building the house.
To put the builder&amp;rsquo;s trade at level with other trades, this rent should be enough to= Pay him the same interest which he would have gotten if he lent out his capital Maintain the house or to replace the capital employed in building it within a certain term of years The building-rent is the ordinary profit of building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ground Rents</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2f-article-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2f-article-1/</guid>
      <description>74  Ground-rents are a better tax subject than house-rents.
A tax on ground-rents would not raise house-rents.
It would all fall on the owner of the ground-rent.
 He always acts as a monopolist. He exacts the highest rent for the use of his ground.  Its value varies with the wealth or poverty of his competitors. The most rich competitors are in the capital. Thus, highest ground-rents are always found there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on Profit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2g-article-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2g-article-2/</guid>
      <description>86  Profits on stock naturally divides itself into two=
The part that pays the interest This part belongs to the owner of the stock The part that is in excess of what is needed to pay the interest.
 87  This latter part of profit is not taxable directly.
It is the very moderate compensation for the risk and trouble of employing the stock. The employer must have this compensation, otherwise he cannot continue this employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on the Profit of Particular Employments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2h-article-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2h-article-2/</guid>
      <description>100  In some countries, extraordinary taxes are imposed on profits when employed=
 in particular trades, and in agriculture   101  The extraordinary taxes on particular trades in England are on=
 hawkers and pedlars, hackney coaches and chairs, and keepers of ale-houses who pay for a licence to retail liquors.  During the recent war, a similar tax was proposed on shops.
The war was entered to defend the trade of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix to Articles 1 and 2-Capital Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2j-article-2appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2j-article-2appendix/</guid>
      <description>Taxes On The Capital Value of Land, Houses, and Stock  113  While property remains with the same person, its taxes never aim to reduce or take away its capital value.
Such taxes only aim to reduce or remove some part of its revenue. Property changes hands when it is transmitted from= the dead to the living, or the living to the living The taxes on such property aim to take away part of its capital value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on Land Rent</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2k-article-2appendix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2k-article-2appendix/</guid>
      <description>124  Taxation by stamp-duties and registration duties are a very modern invention.
In just over a century, stamp-duties have become almost universal in Europe. Duties on registration have become extremely common. Governments are quick to learn from each other the art of draining money from people.
125 Taxes on the transference of property from the dead to the living fall finally and immediately on the person to whom the property is transferred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wage Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2l-article-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2l-article-3/</guid>
      <description>131  Book 1 showed that the wages of lower class workers are regulated by two circumstances=
 The demand for labour  This demand requires an increasing, stationary, or declining population. It regulates the worker&amp;rsquo;s subsistence, whether liberal, moderate, or scanty.   The ordinary or average price of goods  This determines the amount of money which must be paid to the worker for his subsistence.    While the demand for labour and the price of goods remain the same, a direct tax on wages raises wages higher than the tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General taxes -- Capitation Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2m-article-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2m-article-3/</guid>
      <description>138  The taxes which should fall indifferently on every different species of revenue, are=
 Capitation taxes Taxes on consumable commodities  These must be paid indifferently from rent, wages, or profits.
Capitation Taxes  139  Capitation taxes* become arbitrary if it is proportioned to the fortune or revenue of each taxpayer.
A man&amp;rsquo;s fortune varies daily. Without an intolerable annual inquisition, it can only be guessed at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on Consumable Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2n-article-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2n-article-3/</guid>
      <description>157  The impossibility of taxing people according to their revenue by any capitation led to the invention of taxes on consumable commodities.
The state, not knowing how to directly and proportionally tax the revenue of its subjects, taxes it indirectly by taxing their expence.
Their expence is supposed to be proportional to their revenue. It is taxed by taxing the consumable commodities that they buy.
 148  Necessities are commodities needed to support life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxes on Necessities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2o-article-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2o-article-3/</guid>
      <description>155  In Great Britain, the principal taxes on necessities are those on salt, leather, soap, and candles.
 156  Salt is a very ancient and a very universal subject of taxation. It was taxed among the Romans and is presently taxed in Europe. Nobody could sensibly feel even a heavy tax on salt because it was consumed so little and could be bought gradually.
In England, it is taxed at 40 pence a bushel or three times its original price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Taxes: Customs Duties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2p-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2p-article-4/</guid>
      <description>The History of Customs Duties  165  Customs duties are much more ancient than excise duties.
They were called &amp;lsquo;customs&amp;rsquo; to denote customary payments which used from time immemorial. They were originally taxes on merchants&amp;rsquo; profits.
During the times of feudal anarchy, merchants were=
 a little better than emancipated bondmen, despised like all other burgh inhabitants.  Merchants&amp;rsquo; gains were envied. The nobility consented that the king should tallage the profits of=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Taxes -- Customs Duties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2q-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2q-article-4/</guid>
      <description>170  I showed in Book 4 that the mercantile system was not very favourable to the people&amp;rsquo;s revenue or the national annual produce.
It is not more favourable to the sovereign&amp;rsquo;s revenue, at least as that revenue depends on duties.
 171  Because of the mercantile system, the importation of several goods was banned.
It reduced the importers to smuggling. It entirely prevented the importation of foreign woollens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Taxes -- Customs Duties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2r-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2r-article-4/</guid>
      <description>178  High taxes frequently afford a smaller revenue to government than moderate taxes=
 by reducing the consumption of taxed commodities, and by encouraging smuggling.   179  When the reduction of revenue is caused by the reduction of consumption, the only remedy is to lower the tax.
 180  When the reduction of the revenue is caused by smuggling, it may be remedied=
 by reducing the temptation to smuggle, and This temptation can only be reduced by lowering the tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Taxes -- Liquor Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2s-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2s-article-4/</guid>
      <description>190  In Great Britain, liquors for private use are not liable to any excise duties.
This exemption aims to save private families from the tax-gatherer&amp;rsquo;s odious visit. It causes those duties to fall much lighter on the rich than the poor.
Distilling for private use is not very common.
 But in the countryside, many middle class and almost all rich families brew their own beer.  Their strong beer costs them 96 pence a barrel less than it costs the common brewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Taxes -- Other Taxes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2t-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2t-article-4/</guid>
      <description>201  There are several other duties which affect the price of goods more unequally and more indirectly.
An example is the French Peages. These were=
 called Duties of Passage in old Saxon times. established for maintaining roads or navigation just like our turnpike tolls  When applied to such purposes, such duties are most properly imposed according to the bulk or weight of the goods.
They were originally local and provincial duties applicable to local and provincial purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 4-General Taxes -- Taxes on luxuries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2u-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2u-article-4/</guid>
      <description>205  Taxes on luxuries generally are paid piecemeal. In the time and mode of payment they are the most convenient of all taxes. On the whole, such taxes are against the fourth maxim, but agree with the other three.
 206  Such taxes always take out or keep out from the people&amp;rsquo;s pockets more than almost any other taxes in four different ways=
  207  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Taxes -- French Taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2v-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2v-article-4/</guid>
      <description>215  In France, the different revenue laws in the different provinces require many revenue officers to=
 prevent the importation of certain goods, or subject imported goods to certain duties.  These interrupt France&amp;rsquo;s interior commerce.
Some provinces are allowed to compound for the gabelle or salt-tax. Others are exempted from it altogether. Some provinces are exempted from the exclusive sale of tobacco The farmers-general enjoy this exemption through most of France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2w-article-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2w-article-4/</guid>
      <description>221  In France, most of the crown&amp;rsquo;s actual revenue is derived from eight sources=
 Taille Capitation Two vingtiemes Gabelles Aides Traites Domaine The farm of tobacco  The last five are under farm in most of the provinces. The first three are administered everywhere directly by the government. They bring more into the treasury than the last five sources. Those five are much more wasteful and expensive to administer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Collection</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2i-article-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-2/part-2i-article-2/</guid>
      <description>106  In France, the personal taille presently (1775) imposed on the Countries of Elections is 40,107,239 livres, 16 sous.
The proportion in which this sum is assessed on those provinces varies yearly according to the reports made to the king&amp;rsquo;s council author:
 the state of the crops, and other circumstances which may affect their abilities to pay  Each generality is divided into a number of elections.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
