<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Title 4: Public Power on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Title 4: Public Power on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Competence of National Public Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 156
The following are the the competencies of the National Public Power:
 The international policy and actions of the Republic. Defense and supreme vigilance of the general interests of the Republic, public peace keeping and the proper enforcement of the laws throughout the national territory. The flag, coat of arms, national anthem, holidays, decorations and honors of a national nature. Naturalization, admission, extradition and expulsion of foreign nationals. Identification services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contracts in the Public Interest</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>Article 150
Entering into contracts in the national public interest shall require the approval of the National Assembly in those cases in which such requirement is determined by law.
No contract in the municipal, state or national public interests determined shall be entered into with foreign States or official entities, or with companies not domiciled in Venezuela, or transferred to any of the same, without the approval of the National Assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Section One. General Provisions
Article 136
Public Power is distributed among Municipal Power, that of the States Power and National Power. National Public Power is divided into Legislative, Executive, Judicial, Citizen and Electoral.
Each of the branches of Public Power has its own functions, but the organs charged with exercising the same shall cooperate with one another in attaining the ends of the State.
Article 137
The Constitution and the law shall define the authorities of the organs, which exercise Public Power, and the activities carried on by such organs shall be subject to the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Public Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Subsidiary unit government National vs subnational laws
Article 159
The States are politically equal and autonomous organs with full juridical personality, and are obligated to maintain the independence, sovereignty and integrity of the nation and to comply with and enforce the Constitution and the laws of the Republic.
Article 160
The government and administration of each State corresponds to a Governor [masculine] or Governor [feminine]. To be governor [masculine] or Governor [feminine] it is required to be Venezuelan [masculine] or Venezuelan [feminine], greater than twenty- five years old and of secular estate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-4/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Chapter IV. Municipal Public Power Municipal government Article 168 Municipalities constitute the primary political unit in the organization of the nation, and enjoy artificial personality and autonomy within the limits prescribed by the Constitution and the law. Municipal autonomy includes:
 Election of municipal authorities. Management of affairs within the scope of its competence. Creation, collection and investment of its revenues. The actions of a Municipality within the scope of its competence shall be carried out by incorporating citizen participation into the process of defining and managing public affairs and monitoring and evaluating the results achieved, in an effective, sufficient and timely manner, in accordance with law.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
