<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Axioms or Laws of Motion on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/laws-of-motion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Axioms or Laws of Motion on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/laws-of-motion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Corollaries 1-2</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/laws-of-motion/02-cor-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/laws-of-motion/02-cor-1/</guid>
      <description>Corollary 1 A body that is moved by two perpendicular forces will move in a diagonal   A force M impressed on a body at A will be uniformly carried from A to B. A force N impressed at A will be carried from A to C. If N and M act together, their forces will an the same time be carried in the diagonal from A to D.  Law 2 means that N will not at all change the velocity generated by M  The body therefore will arrive at the line BD in the same time, whether the force N be impressed or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Laws of Motion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/laws-of-motion/01-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/laws-of-motion/01-laws/</guid>
      <description>Law 1 Every body perseveres in its state of rest, or uniform motion unless it is compelled to change that state by external forces impressed on it.
 PROJECTILES persevere in their motions so far as they are not retarded by air resistance, or impelled downwards by gravity. A spinning top does not stop unless it is resisted by air. Planets and comets retain their motion as there is less resistance in outer space  Law 2 The change of motion is proportional to the external motive force impressed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
