<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Government Expenses on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government Expenses on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Article 2-Educational Institutions for the youth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3p/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3p/</guid>
      <description>130  The educational institutions for the youth may generate a revenue to defray their own expence.
The fee or honorary which the scholar pays the teacher is naturally a revenue of this kind.
 131  Even if the teacher&amp;rsquo;s reward does not come from this natural revenue, it still is unnecessary that it should be derived from the society&amp;rsquo;s general revenue.
In most countries, the collection and application of the society&amp;rsquo;s general revenue is done through the executive power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education for the Poor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3v/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3v/</guid>
      <description>181  The common people have little time to spare for education.
Their parents cannot afford to maintain them even in infancy. As soon as they are able to work, they must get employment to earn their subsistence.
That employment is generally so simple and uniform. It gives little exercise to the understanding. Their labour is so constant and so severe.
It leaves them little leisure and less inclination to think of anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Education</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3s/</guid>
      <description>159  The following was the common course of philosophical education in most European universities:
 Logic was taught first Ontology came in second Pneumatology came in third. This was the doctrine on the nature of the human soul and the Deity A debased system of moral philosophy came in fourth. This was immediately connected with:  The doctrines of Pneumatology The immortality of the human soul The rewards and punishments from the Deity to be expected in a life to come    A short and superficial system of Physics usually concluded the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Property and Corporation Rules</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3o/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3o/</guid>
      <description>119  When a mercantile company establishes a new business with a barbarous nation at their own risk and expence, it may be reasonable to:
 incorporate them into a joint stock company, and grant them a monopoly for a certain number of years in case of their success.  It is the easiest and most natural way the state can recompense them for hazarding a dangerous and expensive experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercantile Corporations as Commercial Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3d/</guid>
      <description>90  Specific institutions are necessary to facilitate specific branches of commerce. These require a specific and extraordinary costs.
 91  The commerce done with uncivilized nations needs extraordinary protection.
An ordinary counting-house gives little security to the goods of the merchants trading to the African west coast. Their warehouses should be fortified against the barbarous natives.
The Indian government&amp;rsquo;s disorders rendered such fortifications necessary even among that mild and gentle people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Copartneries vs Joint Stock Companies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3i/</guid>
      <description>104  Joint stock companies established by royal charter or by act of parliament differ from:
 regulated companies and private copartneries.   105  1. In a private copartnery, a partner needs the consent of the company to:
 transfer his share to another person, introduce a new member into the company.  Upon proper warning, each member may:
 withdraw from the copartnery, and demand payment for his share of the common stock from the copartnery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private Regulated Companies Versus Joint Stock Companies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3e/</guid>
      <description>95  Private regulated companies are companies which:
 do not do business on a joint stock of capital, are obliged to admit any qualified person who;  pays a fee  agrees to submit to company regulations, and has each member using his own capital at his own risk.    Joint stock companies are companies which:
 do business on a joint stock of capital, and has each member sharing in the common profit or loss in proportion to his share in this stock  Regulated and joint stock companies sometimes have, sometimes do not have, exclusive privileges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads Should Not Be Privatized</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3b/</guid>
      <description>78  The tolls for maintaining a high road cannot be made private property. This is because a neglected high road does not become impassable, but a a neglected canal becomes impassable.
The proprietors of the tolls for a high road might neglect road repairs yet continue to levy the same tolls. Therefore, their tolls should be managed by commissioners or trustees.
 79  In Great Britain, the abuses of the trustees in managing those tolls were very justly complained of in many cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scholarships</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3q/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3q/</guid>
      <description>139  Whatever forces students to any college or university independent of the teachers&amp;rsquo; merit or reputation reduces the necessity of that merit or reputation.
The privileges of graduates in arts, law, physics, and divinity are in some cases obtained only by residing a certain number of years in certain universities.
It forces a certain number of students to those universities, independent of the teachers&amp;rsquo; merit or reputation.
The privileges of graduates are a sort of statutes of apprenticeship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State-Owned Public Works</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3c/</guid>
      <description>85  In France, the funds for repairing high roads are under the executive power.
Those funds consist in:
 a certain number of days labour which most rural people in Europe are obliged to give for highway repair a part of the state&amp;rsquo;s general revenue which the king allocates for road repairs.   86  By the ancient law of France and other parts of Europe, rural labour was under a local or provincial magistrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The African Regulated Company of Merchants (1752-1821)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3h/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3h/</guid>
      <description>101  In 1750 long after the time of Sir Josiah Child, the African Company of Merchants, a regulated company, was established by the 23rd of George 2nd chapter 31.
It had two objects:
 Restrain the oppressive and monopolizing spirit natural to the executives of a private regulated company Force them to maintain forts and garrisons, something unnatural to them.  At first, it was expressly charged to maintain all the British forts and garrisons between Cape Blanc and the Cape of Good Hope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Board of Directors</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3n/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3n/</guid>
      <description>In Europe, the necessary qualification for an investor to vote at their general board were:
 £500, which was the original share price of a stock of the company, and at least 6 months ownership of this stock.  Parliament changed the qualifications by:
 raising the price to £1,000, declaring that the share should be acquired by one&amp;rsquo;s own purchase and not by inheritance, and at least 1 year ownership of this stock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The British East India Joint Stock Company (1600-1874)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3m/</guid>
      <description>115  The old English East India Company was established in 1600 by a charter from Queen Elizabeth.
It did business as a regulated company in its first 12 voyages to India.
 It used private capital only in their general ships. In 1612, it united into a joint stock.  Its charter was not confirmed by act of parliament and conveyed an exclusive privilege. For many years, it was not much disturbed by interlopers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The British East India Joint Stock Company (1600-1874)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3x/</guid>
      <description>193  But there are also some professions which bring no advantage or pleasure to anyone.
The supreme power must alter its conduct with regard to those professionals. It must give them public encouragement for their subsistence. It must provide against negligence by= annexing honours to their profession, establishing a long subordination of ranks and a strict dependence, or some other expedient. Examples are those employed in the finances, fleets, and magistracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hamburgh, Russian, and Eastland Regulated Companies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3f/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3f/</guid>
      <description>98  The terms of admission into the Hamburgh Company are now quite easy.
Its executives have not yet subjected the trade to any burdensome regulations.
 It was not always so.  In the mid-17th century, the fee for admission was £50.
 At one time it was £100. The company&amp;rsquo;s conduct was extremely oppressive.  In 1643, 1645, and 1661, the clothiers and free traders west of England complained them to parliament as monopolists who:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hudson&#39;s Bay (1660-1752) and South Sea Joint Stock Companies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3k/</guid>
      <description>110  Before their misfortunes in the recent war, the Hudson&amp;rsquo;s Bay Joint Stock Company was much more fortunate than the Royal African Joint Stock Company.
Their necessary costs are much smaller.
 They maintained up to 120 persons in their settlements which they called forts. 120 persons are sufficient to prepare the cargo of furs and other goods for their ships beforehand.  Their ships can seldom remain more than 8 weeks in those seas because of the ice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reformation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3zc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3zc/</guid>
      <description>221  The reformation was strong enough to overturn the church and its statein countries where the government was weak, unpopular, and not firmly established, as in Scotland.
 222  The reformation in Europe no general tribunal or an ecumenical council to settle disputes.
Disputes between the followers of the reformation in different countries could never be decided. Many disputes arose among them.
The most interesting were about the government of the church and the right of conferring ecclesiastical benefices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Royal African Joint Stock Company (1660-1752)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3j/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3j/</guid>
      <description>108  The Royal African Joint Stock Company is the predecessor of the present regulated African Company of Merchants.
Both it and the Hudson&amp;rsquo;s Bay Company had an exclusive privilege by charter which was not confirmed by an act of parliament.
The following had an exclusive privilege confirmed by act of parliament as long as they were a trading company:
 The South Sea Joint Stock Company The United Joint Stock Company of Merchants trading to the East Indies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The South Sea Joint Stock Company</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3l/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3l/</guid>
      <description>111  The South Sea Joint Stock Company never had any forts or garrisons to maintain.
It was entirely exempted from a great expence. But they had an immense capital divided among so many proprietors.
Folly, negligence, and profusion naturally prevailed in their management. The knavery and extravagance of their stock-jobbing projects are sufficiently known. Explaining those projects would be off-topic.
Their mercantile projects were not much better conducted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Turkey Company (1581-1825)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3g/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3g/</guid>
      <description>99  The fee for admission into the Turkey Company was formerly:
 £25 for all persons under 26 years old, and £50 for all persons above 26 years old.  Only mere merchants could be admitted.
This restriction excluded all shop-keepers and retailers.
By a bylaw, British manufactures could be exported to Turkey only on the company&amp;rsquo;s ships.
 Those ships always sailed from the expensive port of London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Development of Militaries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1a/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Defence Expenditures The sovereign&amp;rsquo;s first duty is to protect society from the violence and invasion of other societies.
 This can only be done through a military force. The cost of this military force in peacetime and wartime is very different in the different states and periods of the improvement of society.  The Development of Militaries  1  The hunting nation is the lowest and rudest state of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Development of Militaries</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1b/</guid>
      <description>7  In a more advanced society, two causes make it impossible for those who take the field to maintain themselves at their own expence:
 The progress of manufactures The improvement in the art of war   8  When a husbandman goes to war which starts after seed-time and ends before harvest, his revenue is not reduced with his work&amp;rsquo;s interruption.
 Nature does most of the husbandman&amp;rsquo;s remaining work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Methods of Defense: Militias and Armies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1c/</guid>
      <description>Armies are Dominated by the Soldier Mentality  15  The state can use two methods for the public defence.
 16  1. It may enforce military exercises.
It may oblige some citizens of military age to become soldiers, in addition to their current profession. It may do this through a very rigorous police, despite the people&amp;rsquo;s contrary interest, genius, and inclinations. 18 This method forms a militia
17 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superiority of Armies vs Militia</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1d/</guid>
      <description>27  History shows the superiority of a well-regulated standing army over a militia.
Philip of Macedon  28  The army of Philip of Macedon is one of the first standing armies documented.
In the beginning, his troops were probably a militia.
 Frequent wars with the Thracians, Illyrians, Thessalians, and some Greek cities near Macedon gradually formed his troops to the exact discipline of a standing army. He was careful not to disband that army when he was at peace, which was very seldom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fall of the Western Empire</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-1e/</guid>
      <description>The fall of the western empire is the third great revolution in ancient history.
 It was caused by the superiority of the militia of a barbarous nation over the militia of a civilized nation. It is the superiority of the militia of shepherd nations over the militia a nation of husbandmen, artificers, and manufacturers.  The victories gained by militias were, not over standing armies, but over other militias inferior in exercise and discipline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil government and the Superiority of birth and fortune</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>46  &amp;ldquo;Civil government supposes a certain subordination.&amp;rdquo;
The necessity of civil government gradually grows up with the acquisition of valuable property. Likewise, the principal causes which naturally introduce subordination gradually grow up with the growth of that valuable property.
 47  Four causes naturally introduce subordination:
 The superiority of personal qualifications The superiority of age The superiority of fortune The superiority of birth    48  1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice Fees from Gifts to Gratis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2c/</guid>
      <description>55  The second period of society is the age of shepherds where the inequality of fortune first begins.
This inequality:
 introduces a new degree of authority and subordination through a civil government   contributes very much to maintain and secure that authority.  The rich need to secure their own advantages and so they support a government.
 Poorer men combine to defend the property of richer men so that those richer men may combine to defend the property of the poorer men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice Fees from Gifts to Gratis</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2d/</guid>
      <description>63  The whole expence of justice might be easily defrayed by the fees of court.
The public revenue might thus be discharged from a small incumbrance without exposing justice to corruption.
When the sovereign has a share in the fees of court, it is:
 difficult to regulate the fees effectively, and difficult for the sovereign to derive any considerable revenue from them.  It is very easy where the judge is the principal person who can reap any benefit from the fees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2a-Expenses on Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-2a/</guid>
      <description>44  The sovereign&amp;rsquo;s second duty is to protect every member of society from the injustice or oppression of others.
 The administration of justice requires very different costs in the different periods of society.  Feelings in Non-Property-Owning Societies  45  A nation of hunters has:
 no property that exceeds the value of two or three days labour, and no established magistrate or any regular administration of justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Works and Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3a/</guid>
      <description>69  The sovereign&amp;rsquo;s third and last duty is building and maintaining advantageous public works and institutions for society.
The profit from these could never repay the expence to a few people. Individuals cannot be expected to build or maintain them. This duty costs very differently in the different periods of society.
 70  The public institutions and public works necessary for society are those:
 for defence for administering justice for facilitating commerce, and for public education  This chapter will be divided into 3 articles examining how their costs may be most properly defrayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Educational Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3t/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3t/</guid>
      <description>166  Different educational institutions were established in other ages and nations.
 167  In the ancient Greek republic, every free citizen was instructed in gymnastic exercises and music, under the public magistrate.
Gymnastic exercises were intended to:
 harden his body, sharpen his courage, and prepare him for war.  The Greek militia was one of the best in the world. Their public education completely answered its purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 2-Educational Subjects</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3r/</guid>
      <description>Language Learning  148  When Christianity was first established by law, a corrupted Latin had become the common language of Western Europe.
Church services and the Bible translations read in churches were both in that corrupted Latin.
After demise of the Roman empire, Latin gradually ceased to be the language of Europe.
But the people&amp;rsquo;s reverence naturally preserves the established forms and ceremonies of religion long after the reasons for their establishment have disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article 3-Moral Education for People of all Ages</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3w/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3w/</guid>
      <description>190  The educational institutions for people of all ages are chiefly those for religious instruction.
It aims to prepare them for a better world in a life to come. Its teachers may depend on=
 their students&amp;rsquo; voluntary contributions, a fund from their country such as=  a landed estate, a tithe or land-tax, an established salary or stipend.    Their exertion, zeal, and industry, will be much greater with voluntary contributions than a fixed fund.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austere vs Liberal Morals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3y/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3y/</guid>
      <description>199  In every civilized society which has the distinction of ranks, there were always two systems of morality.
 The strict or austere  This is generally admired and revered by the common people.
The liberal or loose system  The loose is commonly more esteemed and adopted by people of fashion. The vices of levity is apt to arise from great prosperity.
It leads to the excess of gaiety and good humour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Church Politics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3za/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3za/</guid>
      <description>209  In the Christian church&amp;rsquo;s ancient constitution, the bishop of each diocese was elected by the joint votes of:
 the clergy, and the people of the episcopal city.  The people did not long retain their right of election.
When they had it, they almost always acted under the clergy&amp;rsquo;s influence. The clergy soon grew weary of managing them. They found it easier to elect their own bishops themselves in the same way as the abbot was elected by the monks of the monastery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educational Fees</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3zd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3zd/</guid>
      <description>227  The church benefices cannot be very big if they are all nearly equal.
This mediocrity of benefice may be carried too far but has very agreeable effects. Only the most exemplary morals can give dignity to a man of small fortune. Levity and vanity render him ridiculous.
They are as ruinous to him as they are to common people. He must follow the moral system respected by the common people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to solve religious conflicts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3z/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3z/</guid>
      <description>202  There state can use two very easy and effective remedies to peacefully correct the disagreeably rigorous morals of little sects.
Remedy 1: 203  The study of science and philosophy. The state should make the study of science and philosophy universal among the middle class.
It could institute a probationary period for anyone who wished to:
 exercise any liberal profession, or be a candidate for any honourable office of trust or profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Decline of the Church</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3zb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3zb/</guid>
      <description>214  The gradual improvements of arts, manufactures, and commerce which destroyed the power of the great barons destroyed the whole temporal power of the clergy in Europe.
Like the great barons, the clergy found something in the manufactures and commerce which they could exchange their rude produce.
 They discovered ways of spending their whole revenues on their own persons without sharing with other people.  Their charity became gradually less extensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Expense of supporting the Sovereign&#39;s Dignity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-4/</guid>
      <description>232  The sovereign also needs a certain expence to support his dignity. This expence varies with=
 the different periods of improvement the different forms of government   233  In an opulent society, all the orders of people are everyday growing more expensive in their houses, furniture, dress, etc.
The sovereign should not be left out.
 He naturally becomes more expensive in all those articles too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Education and Basic Educational Institutions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3u/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-1/part-3u/</guid>
      <description>175  There are no public educational institutions for women. There is accordingly nothing useless, absurd, or fantastic in their common education.
They are taught what their parents judge necessary or useful for them to learn and nothing else.
Their education is used to improve the natural attractions of their person, form their mind to reserve, modesty, chastity, and economy, make them the mistresses of a family, and make them behave properly when they have become such.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
