<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 5 Government Expenses and Revenue on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 5 Government Expenses and Revenue on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ways to pay public debts-Personal treasure or credit of ruler</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3a/</guid>
      <description>1  In Book 3, I showed that the person who has a large revenue in the rude state of society can enjoy that revenue only by maintaining as many people as possible. A large revenue then might consist in basic necessities such as=
 plain food coarse clothing corn and cattle wool and raw hides  When no commerce or manufactures is available to allow him to exchange his surplus, he can only use it to feed and clothe as many people as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annuities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3c/</guid>
      <description>Translator&amp;rsquo;s note= To make large number simpler, the shillings and pences have been removed in some amounts.
  29  Besides borrowing by anticipations and perpetual funding, there are two other methods in between them=
 borrowing on annuities for terms of years borrowing on annuities for lives   30  During the reigns of King William and Queen Anne, large sums were frequently borrowed on annuities for terms of years which varied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticipations and Perpetual Funding</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>13  In Great Britain, the land and malt taxes are regularly anticipated every year by a borrowing clause.
This clause is constantly inserted into the acts which impose those taxes.
The Bank of England advances to government the total amount of those taxes at 3-8% interest.
 It receives payment as the taxes come in. Any deficiency is offset by the tax proceeds of the next year.  The only remaining unmortgaged public revenue is thus spent before it comes in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3D Bad Effects of Funding</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3d/</guid>
      <description>54  Land and capital stock are the two original sources of all private and public revenue.
Capital stock pays the wages of productive labour, whether employed in agriculture, manufactures, or commerce. The management of those two original sources of revenue belong to two sets of people=
 the proprietors of land, and the owners or employers of capital stock.   55  The proprietor of land is interested to keep his estate in as good condition as he can, for the sake of his own revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International barter taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3g/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3g/</guid>
      <description>79  It has been said that:
 the Americans have no gold or silver money. Their interior commerce is done by a paper currency.  Its gold and silver are all sent to Great Britain for the British commodities that they import from us.    Without gold and silver it is impossible to pay taxes. We already get all their gold and silver.
How can we draw from them what they do not have?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monetary Devaluation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3e/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3e/</guid>
      <description>Money Adulteration and Augmentation  61  The raising of the coin&amp;rsquo;s denomination has been the most usual way a real public bankruptcy is disguised under the appearance of a pretended payment.
For example, if an Act of Parliament doubled a coin&amp;rsquo;s denomination, the person who borrowed a coin worth four ounces of silver in the old denomination, would pay it back with a new coin worth only two ounces of silver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solutions -- Tax Reform</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-5/chapter-3f/</guid>
      <description>68  The revenue might be very much increased without increasing the burden on the people through=
 a more equal land-tax, a more equal tax on house rents, and changes in the current customs and excise system, as those mentioned in (Chapter 2n)  It would distribute the burden more equally on all. This increase would not totally liberate the public revenue.
Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s World Government  69  A much bigger revenue can be earmed by extending the British tax system to all the empire&amp;rsquo;s provinces inhabited by people of British or European descent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
