<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 4 Systems Of Political Economy on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 4 Systems Of Political Economy on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is the Political Economy?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  1  Political economy, as a science of a legislator, proposes=
 To provide a plentiful revenue or subsistence for the people by enabling them to provide it for themselves To supply the state with a revenue for the public services  It proposes to enrich both the people and the sovereign.
 2  The progress of opulence in different nations has created two systems of political economy=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Demand and the Demand Motive</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>12  The amount of commodities human industry can buy or produce is naturally regulated by the effective demand in every country.
The effective demand is the demand of the people who are willing to pay the rent, labour, and profits needed to make them and bring them to market.
Gold and silver are the commodities which best regulate themselves most exactly to this effective demand. They are most easily transported from where they are cheap, to where they are dear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money supply</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1c/</guid>
      <description>19  People say that:
Consumable commodities are soon destroyed, but gold and silver are more durable. If not continually exported, gold and silver might be accumulated for ages to increase the country&#39;s real wealth. It is most disadvantageous for any country to trade such lasting commodities for such perishable ones. However, the exchange of English hardware for French wines is not disadvantageous, even if hardware is a very durable commodity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-1d/</guid>
      <description>31  The importation of gold and silver is not the sole benefit from foreign trade. All nations derive two benefits from it:
 It carries out their surplus produce which has no demand at home It brings back something else for which there is a demand.  Foreign trade gives a value to their nations&amp;rsquo; superfluities by exchanging them for something else.
The narrowness of the home market limits a country&amp;rsquo;s division of labour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Restraints on foreign imports which can be produced at home</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2a/</guid>
      <description>1  The monopoly of domestic industry is secured through high duties or import bans of foreign goods which can be produced at home.
The ban on importing foreign live cattle or foreign salt secures the monopoly of the home market for meat to British graziers.
The high duties on wheat imports amount to a ban in times of moderate plenty. Such duties give a like advantage to wheat growers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free importation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>16  } Merchants and manufacturers derive the greatest advantage from this monopoly of the home-market.
The high duties on foreign wheat amount to a ban in times of moderate plenty. These duties, with the ban on the importation of foreign cattle and salt, are not so advantageous to British graziers and farmers as other bans are to British merchants and manufacturers. Manufactures, especially those of the finer kind, can be more easily transported than wheat or cattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retaliatory Restraints</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2c/</guid>
      <description>23  There are two cases when it will be advantageous to lay some burden on foreign industry to encourage domestic industry.
 24  When an industry is needed for national defence. When a tax is imposed by foreign countries on certain products of the home country.
Case 1: National Defence For example, Great Britain&amp;rsquo;s defence depends very much on its sailors and shipping.
The act of navigation very properly gives British sailors and shipping the monopoly of British trade by= absolute prohibitions or heavy burdens on foreign shipping The following are the principal dispositions of this Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring Free Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-2d/</guid>
      <description>40  It may be deliberated how to properly restore the free importation of foreign goods after it has been interrupted, especially when its local monopoly already employs so many people.
In this case, humanity may require that the freedom of trade should be restored slowly, with much reserve and circumspection.
If those high duties and prohibitions were all removed at once, cheaper foreign goods might enter so fast. They would deprive our people of their employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5g/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5g/</guid>
      <description>The two following Accounts are joined to illustrate what is said in the Book 4, Chapter 5 on the Tonnage bounty to the White Herring Fishery.
An Account of Busses fitted out in Scotland for 11 Years, with the Number of Empty Barrels carried out, and the Number of Barrels of Herrings caught; also the Bounty at a Medium on each Barrel of Seasteeks, and on each Barrel when fully packed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colony assemblies and Representation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7j/</guid>
      <description>151  Under the present system of management, Great Britain only derives loss from her colonies.
 152  The following proposal never was and never will be adopted by any nation=
Great Britain should voluntarily give up all authority over her colonies. The colonies should be left to elect their own magistrates and enact their own laws. The colonies should make peace and war as they might think proper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Treaties</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-6a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-6a/</guid>
      <description>1  The commerce of foreign merchants and manufacturers becomes so favoured when a nation=
enters a treaty that permits the entry of certain goods from that foreign country, while banning those from other countries exempts the goods of that foreign country from duties, while subjecting those of other countries.
Those foreign merchants and manufacturers derive great advantage from the treaty.
They enjoy a monopoly in the country so indulgent to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumption Motive</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8c/</guid>
      <description>37  The exportation of raw materials is subjected to high duties, wherever they are not banned.
 38  By the 8th George 1st chapter 15, all British exports were rendered duty-free except for=
 alum, lead, lead ore, tin, coppers, litharge of lead, tanned leather, coals, wool cards, white woollen cloths, coney hair or wool, hares&amp;rsquo; wool, hair of all sorts, zinc, all kinds of skins, glue, horses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digression on Bank Deposits, particularly of Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>12  A big state, such as England, can have its currency consist almost entirely of its own coin. Should this currency be worn, clipt, or degraded below its standard value, the coin&amp;rsquo;s reform can re-establish its currency.
But a small state, such as Genoa or Hamburgh, can seldom have its currency all consist of its own coin.
 It must be made up of the coins of the states it transacts with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digression on the wheat trade &amp; wheat laws=  The Carrying Trade of Wheat</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5f/</guid>
      <description>73  In years of scarcity, the distress caused by the strict execution of those laws was probably very great.
But sometimes, its execution was suspended by temporary statutes which allowed wheat imports for a limited time. The necessity of these temporary statutes demonstrates the impropriety of this general one.
 74  These restraints on importation came before the bounty&amp;rsquo;s establishment.
They were dictated by the same spirit and principles of those bounties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digression on the wheat trade and wheat laws=  Domestic wheat market</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5d/</guid>
      <description>40  The praises for the following are unmerited:
 The law which establishes the wheat export bounty The regulations connected with the bounty  This is demonstrated by examining the nature of=
the wheat trade, and the British laws related to it
This is a very important subject, justified by this long digression.
 41  The wheat merchant&amp;rsquo;s trade is composed of four separate branches which can be done by the same person=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digression on the wheat trade and wheat laws=  Foreign wheat market</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5e/</guid>
      <description>62  The 15th of Charles 2nd c 7 authorizes two very absurd popular prejudices.
 63  It supposes that when wheat prices rise to 576 pence the quarter, wheat is likely to be so engrossed as to hurt the people.
But it is evident that wheat cannot be so engrossed by the inland dealers to hurt the people. 576 pence the quarter is a very high price. But in years of scarcity, it is the common price immediately after harvest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawbacks</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>1  Merchants and manufacturers are not content with the monopoly of the home market.
They want the most extensive foreign sale for their goods. But their country=
 has no jurisdiction in foreign nations can seldom grant them any monopoly overseas.  They generally petition for encouragements to exportation.
 2  Drawbacks seem the most reasonable of these encouragements.
Drawing back the imposed excise or inland duty upon exportation, can never cause more exportation than if there were no duty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Democracy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7e/</guid>
      <description>72  British policy on the colony trade was more liberal and less oppressive, even if it were dictated by the same mercantile spirit as that of other nations.
 73  Except their foreign trade, English colonists had completely liberty to manage their own affairs their own way.
It is equal to the liberty of their fellow-citizens at home. It is secured in the same way by representatives of the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Karma</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7k/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7k/</guid>
      <description>166  The discovery of America and the Cape of Good Hope are the two greatest and most important events recorded in history.
It is impossible that their great consequences could have been seen. No human wisdom can foresee what benefits or misfortunes may result from those great events. They were generally beneficial by= uniting the most distant parts of the world enabling those parts to= relieve one another&amp;rsquo;s wants increase one another&amp;rsquo;s enjoyments encourage one another&amp;rsquo;s industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Export Bounties on Real Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>1  In Great Britain, export bounties are frequently petitioned for.
They are sometimes granted to particular domestic industries. Through bounties, our merchants and manufacturers can pretend to sell their goods cheaper than their rivals in the foreign market. They say more of their goods will be exported. The balance of trade will then more favour our own country. &amp;quot;We cannot give our workmen a monopoly in the foreign as we have done in the home market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Colonies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7c/</guid>
      <description>37  The English colonies in North America have progressed the fastest.
 38  &amp;ldquo;Plenty of good land, and liberty to manage their own affairs their own way, seem to be the two great causes of the prosperity of all new colonies.&amp;rdquo;
 39  In the plenty of good land, the English colonies of North America are inferior to the colonies of Spain and Portugal.
The English colonies are not superior in land to some French colonies before the late war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enumerated Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7d/</guid>
      <description>47  Only enumerated commodities from the British colonies are confined to the market of Great Britain.
These commodities are called such because they were enumerated in the act of navigation and other subsequent acts. The rest are called non-enumerated. Non-enumerated commodities may be exported directly if= they are on British or Plantation ships, and their owners and 3/4 of the mariners are British.
 48  Some of the most important products of America and the West Indies are non-enumerated commodities:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export Bans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8b/</guid>
      <description>15  The same commodities which we gave bounties on importation from America were subjected to considerable duties when imported from other countries.
The interest of our American colonies was regarded as the same with Great Britain. Their wealth was considered as our wealth. It is said that whatever money was sent to them all came back to us by the balance of trade. We could never become poorer by spending for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary Restraints on Importation from Countries Where the Balance is supposed to be Disadvantageous</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3a/</guid>
      <description>Unreasonableness of the Balance of Trade  1  The second expedient of the commercial system to increase the amount of gold and silver is to lay extraordinary restraints on imports from countries where the balance of trade is disadvantageous.
Thus in Great Britain, Silesia lawns may be imported for home consumption on paying certain duties. But French cambrics and lawns can only be imported in London where they are warehoused for re-exportation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>France &amp; England; Balance of Produce &amp; Consumption</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3d/</guid>
      <description>41  Because of these maxims, the commerce between France and England has been subjected to so many discouragements and restraints.
If those two countries considered their real interest, without mercantile jealousy or national animosity, French commerce might be more advantageous to Great Britain than any other country. Great Britain&amp;rsquo;s commerce will also be more advantageous to France. France is the nearest neighbour to Great Britain. The returns of the trade between the southern coast of England and the northern coasts of France might be expected at 4-6 times a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gold in Coinage</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-6b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-6b/</guid>
      <description>17  The goldsmith&amp;rsquo;s trade is very big in Great Britain.
Most of the new plate that they sell is made from old plate melted down. Thus, the addition made to the whole plate of the kingdom cannot be very great. It could require only a very small annual importation.
 18  It is the same case with the coin.
Nobody imagines that the annual gold coinage of more than £800,000 a year for 10 years, was an addition to the money in the kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Stock Is Naturally Distributed To Seek Employment Advantageous To Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7l/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7l/</guid>
      <description>172  I have shown in Book 2 that every country&amp;rsquo;s mercantile stock naturally seeks the employment most advantageous to its own country.
If the stock is employed in the carrying trade, its country becomes the emporium of the goods of all countries. But that stock&amp;rsquo;s owner necessarily wishes to dispose as much of those goods as he can dispose at home.
He saves himself the trouble, risk, and cost of exportation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercantile Governments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7m/</guid>
      <description>Destructive Colonial Policies  187  The English and Dutch companies only established 2 considerable colonies:
 Jakarta South Africa  Those two companies have made big conquests in the East Indies. The natural genius of an exclusive company showed itself in how they governed their new subjects.
In the spice islands, the Dutch burn all the spiceries beyond what they expect to sell in Europe for the profit that they want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monopoly from the Act of Navigation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7g/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7g/</guid>
      <description>105  By the act of navigation, England assumed to herself the monopoly of the colony trade.
The foreign capitals employed in it were withdrawn from it. The English capital which did a part of it now did the whole. The capital which supplied the colonies with part of the European goods they wanted was now all employed to supply them with the whole. But English capital could not supply the colonies with all European goods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motives for Establishing Colonies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7a/</guid>
      <description>1  The interest which created the first European settlements in America and the West Indies was not so plain and distinct as the interest which established ancient Greek and Roman colonies.
 2  All the ancient Greek states possessed a very small territory.
When the people multiplied beyond what that territory could maintain, some of them searched for new habitation in remote parts. The warlike neighbours who surrounded them made it difficult enlarge their territory at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production Bounties -- Herring Bounty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5c/</guid>
      <description>25  A bounty on production would more directly encourage the production of any commodity than an export bounty.
It would impose only one tax on the people which is paid as the bounty. It would lower the price of the commodity in the home market. Instead of imposing a second tax on the people, it might at least repay them for the first tax they paid. Production bounties have been very rarely granted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxation by requisition</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7j2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7j2/</guid>
      <description>157  It has been proposed that the colonies should be taxed by requisition.
The British parliament would determine the sum each colony should pay. The provincial assembly would assess and levy it in the best way suited to the province. In this way, what concerned the whole empire would be determined by the assembly which inspects and superintends the affairs of the whole empire.
The provincial affairs of each colony might still be regulated by its own assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Advantages Europe Derived From The Discovery of America And The Cape Of Good Hope</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7f/</guid>
      <description>87  Such were the advantages the American colonies derived from the policy of Europe.
 88  What are the advantages Europe derived from the discovery and colonization of America?
 89  Those advantages are:
 The general advantages which Europe, as one great country, derived from those great events The particular advantages which each colonizing country derived from its colonies   90  The general advantages which Europe derived are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causes of Prosperity of new Colonies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7b/</guid>
      <description>23  The colony of a civilised nation which acquires a waste country or one thinly inhabited, advances more rapidly to wealth and greatness than any other human society.
 24  The colonists carry with them a knowledge of agriculture and useful arts superior to what was naturally known by barbarous nations.
They carry with them too=
 the habit of subordination some notion of the regular government which takes place in their own country=  the system of laws which supports the government a regular administration of justice    They naturally establish something of the same kind in the new settlement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Discoveries of Christopher Columbus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7a2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7a2/</guid>
      <description>8  But the countries Columbus discovered did not resemble those he was looking for.
Instead of the wealth, cultivation, and populousness of China and India, he found countries which were= uncultivated and covered with wood inhabited by tribes of naked and miserable savages He was not willing to believe that they were different from the countries described by Marco Polo. Marco Polo was the first European to visit and describe China or the East Indies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Monopoly -- Spain and Portugal</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7h/</guid>
      <description>127  The monopoly of the colony trade forced some British capital from all foreign trade of consumption to a carrying trade. It forced it from supporting British industry towards supporting the industry of the colonies and other countries.
 128  For example, the goods purchased with the great tobacco surplus of 82,000 hogsheads are not all consumed in Great Britain.
Part of them such as linen from Germany and Holland are returned to the colonies for their consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Monopoly on the Nation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-7i/</guid>
      <description>143  The monopoly hinders the country&amp;rsquo;s capital from maintaining so great a quantity of productive labour as it would otherwise maintain.
It hinders it from affording so great a revenue to its industrious people as it would otherwise afford. Capital can be increased only by savings from revenue. The monopoly hinders capital from= affording so great a revenue as it would otherwise afford increasing so fast as it would otherwise increase maintaining more productive labour affording more revenue to the industrious people of that country The wages of labour is one great original source of revenue for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Money Price of Grains Regulates The Money Price of All Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-5b/</guid>
      <description>11  The real effect of the bounty is not so much to raise the real value of wheat as to degrade the real value of silver.
It makes silver buy less wheat and other home-made commodities because the money price of wheat regulates the money price of all other home-made commodities.
 12  The money price of wheat regulates the money price of labour.
The money price of labour must always enable the labourer to buy sufficient wheat to maintain him and his family in the liberal, moderate, or scanty manner which the advancing, stationary, or declining state of society oblige his employers to maintain him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unreasonableness of those extraordinary Restraints on other Principles</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-3c/</guid>
      <description>30  In Part 1, I showed how unnecessary it is to lay extraordinary restraints on foreign imports from those countries with a disadvantageous balance of trade, even on the principles of the commercial system.
Equilibrium Fallacy  31  Nothing, however, can be more absurd than this whole doctrine of the balance of trade, on which these restraints and almost all the other regulations of commerce are founded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion on Mercantilism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>1  The mercantile system proposes to enrich every country through two great engines:
 The encouragement of exportation The discouragement of importation  But the mercantile system follows an opposite plan with some commodities:
 To discourage exportation To encourage importation  It pretends that its ultimate object is always the same &amp;ndash; to enrich the country by an advantageous balance of trade.
It discourages the exportation of raw materials and the instruments of trade, in order to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Physiocrats</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9a-physiocrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9a-physiocrats/</guid>
      <description>Economic systems which represent the produce of land as the principal source of wealth  1  No nation has ever adopted the system which represents the produce of land as the sole source of the country&amp;rsquo;s revenue and wealth.
It presently exists only in the speculations of a few learned and ingenuous French men.
![Jean Baptiste Colbert](https= //socioecons.files.wordpress.com/2014/11/220px-colbert_mg_8447_cropped.jpg)
 3  Mr. Colbert was the famous minister of Louis 14th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unproductive class</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9b-unproductive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9b-unproductive/</guid>
      <description>14  The unproductive class is composed of merchants, artificers, and manufacturers.
It is maintained and employed at the expence of=
 the proprietor class, the cultivator class.  These two furnish the unproductive class with=
 raw materials, the fund of its subsistence, the corn and cattle it consumes while employed.  The proprietors and cultivators finally pay=
 The wages of all the unproductive class&amp;rsquo; workers. The profits of all their employers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Errors of the Physiocrats</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9c-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9c-errors/</guid>
      <description>24  According to the liberal and generous system of the Physiocrats, a landed nation can raise its own artificers, manufacturers, and merchants best by granting the most perfect freedom of trade to the artificers, manufacturers, and merchants of all other nations.
This would raise the value of its own surplus produce. This continual increase gradually establishes a fund which raises up all the artificers, manufacturers, and merchants that it needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foreign Economic systems</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9d-foreign-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9d-foreign-systems/</guid>
      <description>39  The political economy of modern European nations was more favourable to manufactures and foreign trade, the industry of the towns, than to agriculture, the industry of the countryside.
Other nations were more favourable to agriculture than to manufactures and foreign trade.
The Policy of China  40  The policy of China favours agriculture more than all other employments.
In China, the condition of a labourer much superior to the condition of an artificer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greek and Roman Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9e/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-4/chapter-9e/</guid>
      <description>47  The policy of the ancient Greek and Roman republics honoured agriculture more than manufactures or foreign trade.
They discouraged manufactures or foreign trade more than encouraging agriculture directly or intentionally.
In several ancient Greek states, foreign trade was banned. In several others, the employments of artificers and manufacturers were considered hurtful to the human body&amp;rsquo;s strength and agility. It rendered the body incapable of habits which their military and gymnastic exercises tried to form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
