<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Five Rings on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Five Rings on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro and Book 1</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have been many years training in the Way of Strategy, called Ni Ten Ichi Ryu, and now I think I will explain it in writing for the first time.
It is now during the first ten days of the tenth month in the twentieth year of Kanei (1645). I have climbed mountain Iwato of Higo in Kyushu to pay homage to heaven, pray to Kwannon, and kneel before Buddha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Water Book</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-2/</guid>
      <description>The spirit of the Ni Ten Ichi school of strategy is based on water.
This Water Book explains methods of victory as the long-sword form of the Ichi school. This can be grasped intuitively. The principles of strategy are written down here in terms of single combat, but you must think broadly so that you attain an understanding for ten-thousand-a-side battles.
Strategy is different from other things in that if you mistake the Way even a little you will become bewildered and fall into bad ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tke Fire Book</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-3/</guid>
      <description>In this the Fire Book of the Ni To Ichi school of strategy I describe fighting as fire.
In the first place, people think narrowly about the benefit of strategy.
By using only their fingertips, they only know the benefit of three of the five inches of the wrist. They let a contest be decided, as with the folding fan, merely by the span of their forearms. They specialise in the small matter of dexterity, learning such trifles as hand and leg movements with the bamboo practice sword.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tke Void Book</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-5/</guid>
      <description>The Ni To Ichi Way of Strategy is recorded in this the Book of the Void. What is called the spirit of the void is where there is nothing. It is not included in man&amp;rsquo;s knowledge. Of course the void is nothingness. By knowing things that exist, you can know that which does not exist. That is the void.
People in this world look at things mistakenly, and think that what they do not understand must be the void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tke Wind Book</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/musashi/five-rings/book-4/</guid>
      <description>In strategy you must know the Ways of other schools, so I have written about various other traditions of strategys in this the Wind Book.
Without knowledge of the Ways of other schools, it is difficult to understand the essence of my Ichi school. Looking at other schools we find some that specialise in techniques of strength using extra-long swords.
Some schools study the Way of the short sword, known as kodachi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
