<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 1 Productivity and the Distribution of Revenue on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 1 Productivity and the Distribution of Revenue on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Division of Labour</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1-division/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1-division/</guid>
      <description>1  Division of labour causes improvements in:
 productivity, and  The greatest improvement is in this.   the skill, dexterity, and judgment in work.   2  The effects of division of labour is carried furthest in very trifling manufactures. These manufactures:
 supply the small wants of a few people have a few workers who can often be=  collected into the same workhouse, and placed under the spectator&amp;rsquo;s view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specialization</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>Generally, the work of one man in a rude state of society is the work of several men in an improved one. In every improved society:
 the farmer is generally just a farmer, and the manufacturer is just a manufacturer.  The labour needed to produce any manufacture is almost always divided among many hands.
So many different trades are employed in each branch of the linen and woollen manufactures:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Causes the Increase in Productivity?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1b-causes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1b-causes/</guid>
      <description>5  This great increase in productivity from the division of labour is due to three circumstances=
 The increase of dexterity in every worker The time savings commonly lost in passing from one species of work to another The invention of many machines which=   facilitate and abridge labour, and enable one man to do the work of many.  Increase in Skill  6  1. The improvement of the worker&amp;rsquo;s dexterity increases the amount of the work he can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity from the Division of Labor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1c-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-1c-productivity/</guid>
      <description>10  The division of labour greatly increases productivity. This productivity in a well-governed society creates the universal opulence which extends to the poor.
Every worker produces a lot more goods than what he himself needs. This allows all workers to exchange their excess goods among each other, creating a general plenty that diffuses itself through the different ranks of society.
 11  The accommodation of a common day-labourer in a civilized country involves a small part of the industry of so many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cause of the Division of Labour</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The Propensity to Trade, Arising from Reason and Speech, Creates the Division of Labour  1  This division of labour is not originally the effect of any human wisdom. It is the necessary, very slow, gradual, consequence of the propensity in human nature to exchange one thing for another.
 2  This propensity to trade probably arises from our faculty for reason and speech more than it being an original principle of human nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Division of Labour is Limited by the Size of the Market</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Market Size is The Most Important Factor that Leads to the Division of Labour in Society  1  Since the power of exchanging creates the division of labour, the extent of the market must always limit that division. When the market is very small, no one can dedicate himself entirely to one employment because few people will buy his excess produce.
 2  There are some industries possible only in a big town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin and Use of Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-4a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-4a/</guid>
      <description>Money was invented to facilitate trade  1  When the division of labour is established, the labour of each man can only supply a very small part of his own needs.
 He supplies the rest with the produce of the labour of others. Everyone lives by exchanging and the society grows into a commercial society.   2  But when the division of labour first began, this power of exchanging was frequently very much clogged and embarrassed in its operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Coinage</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-4b/</guid>
      <description>9  The inconvenience and difficulty of weighing those metals precisely gave rise to to the institution of coins.
The stamp entirely covers both sides of the coin and sometimes the edges. It was supposed to ascertain the metal&amp;rsquo;s fineness and weight. Therefore, such coins were received by tale as today, without the trouble of weighing.
 10  The denominations of those coins originally expressed the weight or amount of metal in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real and Nominal Price of Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5a/</guid>
      <description>Superphysics note: The core of the misunderstanding of Smith&amp;rsquo;s Labour Theory of Value is the ambiguity of the word &amp;rsquo;labour&amp;rsquo;. Here, we replace it with &amp;rsquo;toil and trouble&amp;rsquo; to equate it more to psychology, emotions, and subjectiveness, instead of physical force or objectiveness. Toil and trouble is more related to suffering and non-suffering. A link to the original translation with the word &amp;rsquo;labour&amp;rsquo; will be posted in the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grains versus Silver in terms of the temporal aspect of value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-5b/</guid>
      <description>15  At distant times, equal amounts of labour will be bought more nearly with equal amounts of wheat, the worker&amp;rsquo;s subsistence, than with perhaps any other commodity.
At distant times, equal amounts of wheat will enable its possessor to buy or command nearly the same amount of the labour of other people. Although equal amounts of wheat will not do it exactly.
The worker&amp;rsquo;s subsistence &amp;amp; enjoyments depend on the advancing, stagnant, or reversing state of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rent, Wages, and Labor</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-6b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-6b/</guid>
      <description>9  The real value of the parts of price is measured by the amount of labour which each part can purchase or command.
Labour measures the value that resolves itself into labour, rent, and profit.
 10  The price of every commodity finally resolves itself into some or all of those three parts. In every improved society, all the three, more or less, become components of the price of most commodities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Component Parts of the Price of Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-6a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-6a/</guid>
      <description>In the rude state, price has one component= Wages  1  In the rude state of society, only the quantity of labour regulates the exchangeable value of commodities.
For example, in a nation of hunters, a beaver is twice as hard to kill than a deer.
 A beaver is naturally exchanged for, or is worth, two deer. The produce of two hours of labour should naturally be worth double the produce of one hour&amp;rsquo;s labour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Natural and Market Price of Commodities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-7a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-7a/</guid>
      <description>1  Average rates of wages and profits exist in all societies. These are naturally regulated by= the society&amp;rsquo;s=
 general circumstances, riches or poverty, advancing, stationary, or declining condition, and the nature of each employment in the society.   2  Average rates of rent also exist in all societies. These are regulated by=
 the general circumstances of the society where the land is situated, and the natural or improved fertility of the land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monopolies Through Secrets in Trade and Manufactures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-7b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-7b/</guid>
      <description>Keeping Up the Market Price Above the Natural Price through Secrets of Trade and Manufactures  20  The market price always gravitates towards the natural price.
But it may stay above the natural price for long periods due to=
 natural accidents, and man-made accidents, as in regulations   21  When the effective demand increases, sellers are careful to conceal this increase to prevent new rivals.
Those rivals would reduce the market price to its natural price or even below it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wages</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8a/</guid>
      <description>Wages are Determined by Employers. Independent workers earn by the profit of their own work  1  The produce of labour makes upthe natural wages of labour.
 2  In the rude state, without the appropriation of land or stock, the whole produce of labour belongs to the labourer.
 He has no landlord nor master to share with him.   3  Had this state continued, wages would have increased with the productivity from the division of labour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advancing, Stagnating, Reversing Movement</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8b/</guid>
      <description>22  Wages rise from the continual increase of the national wealth, not from its actual greatness.
Wages are highest in countries growing rich the fastest, and not in the richest countries.
England is currently richer than North America. But North American wages are much higher than English wages.
In New York before the start of the American Revolution:
 common labourers earn the value of 24 English pence a day [In London, the common wage is 18 pence].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wages in Great Britain</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8c/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8c/</guid>
      <description>27  In Great Britain, wages are in excess of what is needed to bring up a family.
We do not need to calculate the lowest sum needed to raise a family because there are many plain symptoms that wages are not at their lowest rates.
  28  Summer wages are different from winter wages in Great Britain.  Summer wages are always highest. The maintenance of a family is most expensive in winter due to high fuel costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wages in Great Britain</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8d/</guid>
      <description>Poverty and the Importance of High Wages in Increasing the Industry of the Poor  35  Is this improvement in the working poor good or bad for society?
The answer is obvious.
The working poor makes up the majority of every great society. What improves the majority can never be an inconvenience to the whole.
No society can surely be flourishing and happy if the majority were poor and miserable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Wages From the Inverse Relationship Between Labour and Stock</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-8e/</guid>
      <description>44  Some pretend that:
 workers are more idle in bountifulyears and more industrious during a shortage . a good harvest relaxes their industry, while a scanty one quickens their industry.  Above-ordinary wages may render some workers idle, but not all workers. In reality, people work better:
 when they are well fed than ill fed, when they are in good spirits than when they are disheartened, when they are in good health, than when they are sick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal and Market Interest Rates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-9b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-9b/</guid>
      <description>11  In our North American and West Indian colonies, both wages and interest, and consequently profits, are higher than in England.
Both the legal and market interest rates in the colonies run from 6-8%. High wages and high profits, however, rarely go together, except in the peculiar circumstances of new colonies.
Compared to other countries, a new colony:
 is more under-stocked relative to its territorial size for some time, is more under-peopled relative to the size of this stock, has more land than they have stock to cultivate, uses its stock to cultivate the most fertile and best situated land with access to waterways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profits</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-9a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-9a/</guid>
      <description>Interest is the Best Indicator of Profits  1  The rise and fall in profits depend on the increasing or declining movement of the society&amp;rsquo;s wealth.
This is also the cause of the rise and fall in wages, although those causes affect profits and wages very differently.
 2  The increase of stock raises wages and lowers profit.
When the stocks of merchants are turned into the same trade, their mutual competition lowers their profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Maximum Population and Maximum Stocks</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-9c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/wealth-of-nations/book-1/chapter-9c/</guid>
      <description>14  Wages and profits would be very low in a country:
 which had acquired maximum riches natural to its soil, climate, and location, and which could not advance further but was not going backwards.  A country at maximum population would have so much competition for employment. Wages would be reduced to bare sufficiency, preventing the population from increasing.
A country fully stocked in all the trades possible would have great competition everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
