<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Prince on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Prince on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Balancing the Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-03b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-03b/</guid>
      <description>The prince who holds a country of different language, customs and law, should:
 strengthen his weaker neighbours weaken his more powerful ones  He should be careful that no foreigner as powerful as himself shall get established there.
Some powerful foreigner will always be invited by those who are unhappy with the prince, either through:
 excess of ambition or fear.  The Romans were brought into Greece by the Aetolians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Many Kinds Of Principalities There Are, How They Are Acquired</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>There are only two kinds of states:
 Republics Principalities  Principalities are either:
 hereditary, where the family has long, established control new  entirely new like Milan to Francesco Sforza members added to the hereditary state of the prince who has acquired them, as was the kingdom of Naples to that of the King of Spain.    Such states thus acquired are either accustomed to live under a prince, or to live in freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Alexander&#39;s Successors Remained Loyal</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>It is difficult to holding on to a newly acquired state. How could the the countries conquered by Alexander the Great remain loyal to his successors?
Alexander became the master of Asia in a few years, and died before completing the task. We would expect his whole empire to rebel. Nevertheless, his successors maintained themselves, and had no other difficulty than that which arose among themselves from their own ambitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Principalities Acquired By One&#39;s Own Arms And Ability</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>A wise man should always:
 follow the paths beaten by great men imitate those who have been the best  In this way, if his ability does not equal theirs, at least it will have some traces of it.
He should act like skilled archers who aim much higher in order to reach a very far target. This is not done just to reach that great height, but to use that height to help him reach his distant target.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Principalities Acquired By Arms or Good Fortune</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>Private citizens who become princes solely through good fortune rise easily but have trouble staying on top.
 They do not have any difficulties on the way up, because they fly. But they have many difficulties when they reach the top.  Such are people who get a state either by money or by favour. This happened to many:
 in Greece in the cities of Ionia and the Hellespont  In those places, princes were made by Dariusfor his own security and glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Who Have Obtained A Principality By Wickedness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>A prince can also rise from a private situation through:
 Wickedness, either ancient or modern The favor of his fellow-citizens, becoming a prince from a private citizen  Agathocles Agathocles, the Sicilian, became King of Syracuse from a low and humble position. He was the son of a pot maker, through all the changes in his fortunes always led a wicked life.
But he also was very skilled in mind and body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Church Principalities</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>All of the difficulties with church principalities occur prior to getting possession. This is because they:
 are acquired either by capacity or good fortune can be held without either since they are sustained by the ancient laws of religion.  These laws are so powerful. The principalities may be held no matter how their princes behave.
These princes:
 have states and do not defend them, yet they are not taken away have subjects and do not rule them, yet do not rebel  So only such principalities are secure and happy, being supported by powers which the human mind cannot reach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How The Strength Of All Principalities Should Be Measured</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Should a prince have so much power to support himself with his own resources?
Or should he always need the assistance of others?
 &amp;ldquo;Self-reliant princes&amp;rdquo; are those who have plenty of men or money to raise an army sufficient to join battle for defense.  &amp;ldquo;Dependent princes&amp;rdquo; are those who always are forced to defend themselves by sheltering behind walls.  Dependent princes should provision and strengthen their towns, and not on try to defend the countryside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercenaries and How Many Kinds Of Soldiers There Are</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>What is the means of attack and defence which go with each of the principalities?
A prince must have his foundations well laid, otherwise he will go to ruin. The chief foundations of all states, new, old, or mixed, are good laws and good arms.
There cannot be good laws if the state is not well-armed. It follows that where they are well-armed they have good laws. The arms with which a prince defends his state are either:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Constitutional Principality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>A &amp;ldquo;constitutional principality&amp;rdquo; emerges when a leading citizen becomes the prince by the favour of his fellow citizens and not by wickedness or violence.
A fortunate cleverness is needed to attain to it, not genius or fortune. Such a principality is obtained either:
 by the favour of the people or by the favour of the nobles.  These two distinct parties are found in all cities.
 The people do not wish to be ruled or oppressed by the nobles The nobles wish to rule and oppress the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auxiliaries, Mixed Armies, And One&#39;s Own Soldiers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Auxiliaries are the other kind of most useless soldiers. They are employed when a prince needs other forces to aid and defend him.
This was done by Pope Julius most recently. He had poor results from his mercenaries in their attack against Ferrara so he turned to auxiliaries and bargained with Ferdinand, King of Spain, for help with men and soldiers.
These soldiers may be useful and good in themselves, but for the person who calls them in they are always disadvantageous, because by losing, a prince is thoroughly defeated, and by winning, a prince becomes under their control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the most important thing in The Art Of War</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>A prince should have no other aim or thought, nor select anything else for his study, than war and its rules and discipline.
This is the sole art that belongs to him who rules, and it is of such force that it not only supports those who are born princes, but it often enables men to rise from a private station to that rank.
When princes have thought more of ease than of arms they have lost their states, and the first cause of losing it is to neglect this art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is It Better To Be Loved Than Feared?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>Every prince should want to be considered kind and not cruel. Nevertheless, he should take care not to misuse this kindness.
Cruel to be Kind Cesare Borgia was considered cruel. Yet his cruelty calmed the Romagna, unified it, and restored it to peace and loyalty.
He was actually much more merciful than the Florentines who permitted Pistoia to be destroyed in order to avoid a reputation for cruelty. Therefore a prince, so long as he keeps his subjects united and loyal, should not mind the criticism of cruelty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Princes Are Praised Or Blamed</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>How should a prince deal with his subjects and friends?
Many have imagined republics and principalities which have never been seen. How one actually lives is far distant from how one ought to live. Anyone who neglects what is done for what ought to be done, sooner brings about his ruin rather than his preservation. A man who wishes to act entirely in a virtuous way is soon destroyed among so much that is evil in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Princes Should Keep Faith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>Princes who have done great things have held good faith of little account. They have known gotten their way through cheating. They overcame those who have relied on their word.
There are two ways of winning:
 by the rules  This is suited to men   by force.  This is suited to beasts    If winning by the rules is not sufficient, it is necessary to win by force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Should Avoid Being Hated And Despised</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>How can a prince avoid being hated or despised?
If he can succeed with this, then:
 he will have done the best he can, and he need not fear any danger in other criticisms.  He will be hated the most if he:
 is greedy exploits the property and women of his subjects  And so he must avoid doing this.
The majority of men live happily when neither their property nor their honour is threatened28.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Roman Emperors</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-19b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-19b/</guid>
      <description>Some might think that many of the Roman emperors would be an example contrary to my assertions. Some of them lived nobly and showed great qualities. Nevertheless, they lost their empire or were killed by subjects who conspired against them.
I shall discuss the following emperors:
 Marcus his son Commodus Pertinax Julian Severus his son Antoninus Caracalla Macrinus Heliogabalus Alexander Maximinus  In other principalities, a prince only has to deal with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Castles Advantageous Or Hurtful?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>In order to hold the state securely, some princes have:
 disarmed their subjects kept their subject towns divided by setting up opposing groups encouraged attacks against themselves tried to win over those whom they did not trust in the beginning of their governments built castles destroyed castles  One cannot give a final judgment on all of these unless he has the details of those states. There never was a new prince who has disarmed his subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How A Prince Should Conduct Himself To Gain A Reputation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>A prince becomes so famous by:
 great achievements setting a fine example.  Ferdinand of Aragon We have in our time Ferdinand of Aragon, the present King of Spain. He can almost be called a new prince, because he has risen, by success and glory, from being an insignificant king to be the most famous king in our part of the world.
His deeds are all great and some of them are extraordinary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Call To Liberate Italy From The Invaders</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>Is the present times right for a new prince?
Are there were elements that would give an opportunity to a wise and virtuous one to introduce a new order of things which would bring honour to him and good to the people?
So many things now come together to favour a new prince. This is the best time for one. It was necessary for:
 the Israelites to be in chains in order to make the ability of Moses clear the Persians to be oppressed by the Medes in order to discover the greatness of Cyrus the Athenians should be scattered to illustrate the capabilities of Theseus  In order to discover the virtue of an Italian spirit now, it was necessary that Italy were reduced to her current conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Fortune Affects Human Affairs And How To Resist Her</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>Many people still think that:
 human affairs are governed by fortune and by God humans with their wisdom cannot direct them no one can even help them.  Because of this, they make us believe that it is unnecessary to labour much in affairs, but to let chance govern them.
This opinion has gained more credit in our times because of the great changes in affairs which cannot have been predicted*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Personal Staff Of Princes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>The choice of staff is very important to a prince, and they are good or not according to the discrimination of the prince.
The first opinion which one forms of a prince, and of his capability, is by observing the people he has around him. When they are capable and faithful, he may always be considered wise because he has known how to recognize the capable and to keep them faithful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Princes Of Italy Lost Their States</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/machiavelli/prince/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>The actions of a new prince are more critically observed than those of an hereditary one. When princes are seen to be capable, they gain more men and make them more loyal than ancient blood.
This is because men are attracted more by the present than by the past. When they find the present good, they enjoy it and seek no further. They will also strongly defend a prince if he does not fail them in other things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
