<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovative Startup Act on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovative Startup Act on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Section 2. The State shall foster inclusive growth through an innovative economy by streamlining government and nongovernment initiatives, in both local and international spheres, to create new jobs and opportunities, improve production, and advance innovation and trade in the country.
To this end, the State shall:
 provide incentives and remove constraints aimed at encouraging the establishment and operation of innovative new businesses, businesses crucial to their growth and expansion, and strengthen, promote, and develop an ecosystem of businesses and government and nongovernment institutions that foster an innovative entrepreneurial culture in the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Benefits And Incentives</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Section 7. General Registration and Operational Benefits and Incentives. -Host agencies shall be authorized to provide the following benefits and incentives to startups and/or startup enablers who have passed their selection and application process:
(a) Full or partial subsidy for the registration and cost in the application and processing of permits and certificates required for the business registration and operation of an enterprise with the appropriate local or national government agencies;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Visas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/laws/startup/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Section 13. Startup Visas.— The Department of Foreign Affairs (DFA) shall create the following startup visas:
(a) Startup owner visa – for prospective or current foreign owner of startup or startup enabler registered in the Philippines;
(b) Startup employee visa – for foreign employee of a startup or startup enabler registered in the Philippines; and
(c) Startup investor visa – for prospective or current foreign investor of a startup or startup enabler registered in the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
