<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Australian Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Australian Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Both Houses of the Parliament</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Right of electors of States  No adult who has or acquires a right to vote at elections for the more numerous House of the Parliament of a State shall, while the right continues, be prevented by any law of the Commonwealth from voting at elections for either House of the Parliament of the Commonwealth.
 Oath or affirmation of allegiance Every senator and every member of the House of Representatives shall before taking his seat make and subscribe before the Governor-General, or some person authorised by him, an oath or affirmation of allegiance in the form set forth in the schedule to this Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance and Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Consolidated Revenue Fund  All revenues or moneys raised or received by the Executive Government of the Commonwealth shall form one Consolidated Revenue Fund, to be appropriated for the purposes of the Commonwealth in the manner and subject to the charges and liabilities imposed by this Constitution.
Expenditure charged thereon  The costs, charges, and expenses incident to the collection, management, and receipt of the Consolidated Revenue Fund shall form the first charge thereon; and the revenue of the Commonwealth shall in the first instance be applied to the payment of the expenditure of the Commonwealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Legislative power  The legislative power is with a Federal Parliament consisting of:
 the Queen a Senate a House of Representatives  These form The Parliament of the Commonwealth.
Governor-General  A Governor-General:
 is appointed by the Queen and shall be Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s representative shall have and may exercise in the Commonwealth during the Queen&amp;rsquo;s pleasure, but subject to this Constitution, such powers and functions of the Queen as Her Majesty may be pleased to assign to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Seat of Government  The seat of Government shall be:
 determined by the Parliament within territory granted to or acquired by the Commonwealth vested in and belong to the Commonwealth in the State of New South Wales, not less than 100 miles from Sydney.  Such territory shall contain an area of not less than 100 square miles, and such portion thereof as shall consist of Crown lands shall be granted to the Commonwealth without any payment therefor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New States</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>New States may be admitted or established  The Parliament may admit to the Commonwealth or establish new States, and may upon such admission or establishment make or impose such terms and conditions, including the extent of representation in either House of the Parliament, as it thinks fit.
Government of territories  The Parliament may make laws for the government of any territory surrendered by any State to and accepted by the Commonwealth, or of any territory placed by the Queen under the authority of and accepted by the Commonwealth, or otherwise acquired by the Commonwealth, and may allow the representation of such territory in either House of the Parliament to the extent and on the terms which it thinks fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powers of the Parliament</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-5/</guid>
      <description>Legislative powers of the Parliament  The Parliament shall have power to make laws for the peace, order, and good government of the Commonwealth with respect to:
   trade and commerce with other countries, and among the States    taxation; but so as not to discriminate between States or parts of States;    bounties on the production or export of goods, but so that such bounties shall be uniform throughout the Commonwealth;    borrowing money on the public credit of the Commonwealth; (v) postal, telegraphic, telephonic, and other like services; (vi) the naval and military defence of the Commonwealth and of the several States, and the control of the forces to execute and maintain the laws of the Commonwealth; (vii) lighthouses, lightships, beacons and buoys; (viii) astronomical and meteorological observations; (ix) quarantine; (x) fisheries in Australian waters beyond territorial limits; (xi) census and statistics; (xii) currency, coinage, and legal tender; (xiii) banking, other than State banking; also State banking extending beyond the limits of the State concerned, the incorporation of banks, and the issue of paper money; (xiv) insurance, other than State insurance; also State insurance extending beyond the limits of the State concerned; (xv) weights and measures; (xvi) bills of exchange and promissory notes; (xvii) bankruptcy and insolvency; (xviii) copyrights, patents of inventions and designs, and trade marks; (xix) naturalization and aliens;    foreign corporations, and trading or financial corporations formed within the limits of the Commonwealth    marriage    divorce and matrimonial causes, parental rights, custody and guardianship of infants    invalid and old-age pensions   23a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Executive Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Executive power  The executive power of the Commonwealth is vested in the Queen and is exercisable by the Governor-General as the Queen’s representative, and extends to the execution and maintenance of this Constitution, and of the laws of the Commonwealth.
Federal Executive Council  There shall be a Federal Executive Council to advise the Governor-General in the government of the Commonwealth, and the members of the Council shall be chosen and summoned by the Governor-General and sworn as Executive Councillors, and shall hold office during his pleasure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The House of Representatives</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Constitution of House of Representatives  The House of Representatives is composed of members directly chosen by the people. The number of such members shall be twice the number of the senators.
The number of members chosen in the several States shall be in proportion to the respective numbers of their people, and shall, until the Parliament otherwise provides, be determined, whenever necessary, in the following manner: (i) a quota shall be ascertained by dividing the number of the people of the Commonwealth, as shown by the latest statistics of the Commonwealth, by twice the number of the senators; (ii) the number of members to be chosen in each State shall be determined by dividing the number of the people of the State, as shown by the latest statistics of the Commonwealth, by the quota; and if on such division there is a remainder greater than one-half of the quota, one more member shall be chosen in the State.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Judicature</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Judicial power and Courts  The judicial power of the Commonwealth shall be vested in a Federal Supreme Court, called the High Court of Australia, and in such other federal courts as the Parliament creates, and in such other courts as it invests with federal jurisdiction. The High Court shall consist of a Chief Justice, and so many other Justices, not less than two, as the Parliament prescribes.
Judges’ appointment, tenure and remuneration  The Justices of the High Court and of the other courts created by the Parliament:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Senate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-1/part-2/</guid>
      <description>The Senate  The Senate shall be composed of senators for each State, directly chosen by the people of the State, voting, until the Parliament otherwise provides, as one electorate.
But until the Parliament of the Commonwealth otherwise provides, the Parliament of the State of Queensland, if that State be an Original State, may make laws dividing the State into divisions and determining the number of senators to be chosen for each division, and in the absence of such provision the State shall be one electorate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The States</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Saving of Constitutions  The Constitution of each State of the Commonwealth shall, subject to this Constitution, continue as at the establishment of the Commonwealth, or as at the admission or establishment of the State, as the case may be, until altered in accordance with the Constitution of the State.
Saving of power of State Parliaments  Every power of the Parliament of a Colony which has become or becomes a State, shall, unless it is by this Constitution exclusively vested in the Parliament of the Commonwealth or withdrawn from the Parliament of the State, continue as at the establishment of the Commonwealth, or as at the admission or establishment of the State, as the case may be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/act/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/au/act/</guid>
      <description>An Act to constitute the Commonwealth of Australia [9th July 1900]
WHEREAS the people of New South Wales, Victoria, South Australia, Queensland, and Tasmania, humbly relying on the blessing of Almighty God, have agreed to unite in one indissoluble Federal Commonwealth under the Crown of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, and under the Constitution hereby established:
And whereas it is expedient to provide for the admission into the Commonwealth of other Australasian Colonies and possessions of the Queen:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
