<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advocacy on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advocacy on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maharlikanism and the 8 Constitutional Virtues</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/maharlikanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/maharlikanism/</guid>
      <description>Maharlikanism is a set of solutions to overhaul, either gradually or totally, Philippines into Maharlika.
It is an implementation of our proposed Social Superphysics which aims overhaul the current unsustainable economic and political systems which were established by colonialism and the industrial revolution.
You could say that while the current systems had mercantilist and industrial roots, the systems from Social Superphysics has its roots in the internet and the Enlightenment. This makes it responsive, flexible, cooperative, democratic, and universal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maharlikanism is Different from the Maharlika of Marcos</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/maharlika-marcos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/maharlika-marcos/</guid>
      <description>Ferdinand Marcos was the dictator who used Maharlika for nationalist or political purposes, as part of his utopian Bagong Lipunan (New Society). This includes naming his projects as Maharlika:
 Maharlika Hall is the reception area of the Malacanang Palace Maharlika Highway is a major road network Maharlika Village is a Muslim village created by Marcos in 1974 for the army and Moro elite  Our version of Maharlika is totally different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Proposed Flag of the Republic of Maharlika</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/maharlika-flag/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/advocacy/maharlika-flag/</guid>
      <description>The current flag of the Philippines came from the group of Emilio Aguinaldo who divided it into three main colors=
 Blue Red White  Metaphysically, this manifests as the divisions between Filipinos. Instead of unity, each Filipino associates with his own tribe or dialect such as Tagalog, Bisaya, Tausug, Ilocano, etc.
To unify Filipnos, we propose a Maharlikan flag made up of=
 1 golden sun with 8 rays - This represents the Supreme Entity, whether as God, Allah, Brahma, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
