<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 1 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 1 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom is knowledge of certain principles and causes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-1/</guid>
      <description>The Sight is the Most Important Sense to Aristotle ALL men by nature desire to know.
An indication of this is the delight we take in our senses which are useful and loved for themselves.
The most important is the sense of sight. We prefer seeing over the other senses.
The reason is that this, most of all the senses, makes us know and brings to light many differences between things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sciences</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-2/</guid>
      <description>What is wisdom?  The wise man knows all things, as far as possible, although he does not know each of them in detail.
  A person is wise if he can learn things that are difficult
  Sense-perception is common to all. So it is easy and is not a mark of Wisdom.
A man is wiser if he is more exact and more capable of teaching the causes in every branch of knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Early Philosophers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-3/</guid>
      <description>We have to acquire knowledge of the original causes (for we say we know each thing only when we think we recognize its first cause), and causes are spoken of in four senses.
In one of these we mean the substance, i.e. the essence (for the &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; is reducible finally to the definition, and the ultimate &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; is a cause and principle)
in another the matter or substratum, in a third the source of the change, and in a fourth the cause opposed to this, the purpose and the good (for this is the end of all generation and change).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hesiod Parmenides</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-4/</guid>
      <description>One might suspect that Hesiod was the first to look for such a thing-or some one else who put love or desire among existing things as a principle. Parmenides also does this. for he, in constructing the genesis of the universe, says:- &amp;quot;
&amp;ldquo;Love first of all the Gods she planned. &amp;quot;
Hesiod says:
&#34;First of all things was chaos made, and then &#34;Broad-breasted earth... &#34;And love, &#39;mid all the gods pre-eminent, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pythagoreans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-5/</guid>
      <description>Contemporaneously and before these philosophers were the Pythagoreans.
They were the first to take up mathematics. They advanced it and made it the principle of all things.
In these principles, numbers are by nature the first.
In numbers they seemed to see many resemblances to the things that exist and come into being-more than in fire and earth and water (such and such a modification of numbers being justice, another being soul and reason, another being opportunity-and similarly almost all other things being numerically expressible);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato&#39;s Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Plato followed the Pythagoreans. But it had pecullarities that distinguished it from the philosophy of the Italians.
He became familiar with Cratylus in his youth and with the Heraclitean doctrines (that all sensible things are ever in a state of flux and there is no knowledge about them), these views he held even in later years.
Socrates was busying himself about ethical matters and neglecting the world of nature as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 7</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-7/</guid>
      <description>None of the early philosophers who speak about &amp;lsquo;principle&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;cause&amp;rsquo; mentioned any principle except those which have been distinguished in our work on nature.
But all evidently have some inkling of them, though only vaguely.
For some speak of the first principle as matter, whether they suppose one or more first principles, and whether they suppose this to be a body or to be incorporeal.
For example:
 Plato spoke of the big and the small The Italians spoke of the infinite Empedocles spoke of fire, earth, water, and air Anaxagoras of the infinity of things composed of similar parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle&#39;s Substance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-8/</guid>
      <description>Some philosophers say that the universe is one and posit one kind of thing as matter, and as corporeal matter which has spatial magnitude, evidently go astray in many ways.
They say that the elements of bodies only, not of incorporeal things, though there are also incorporeal things.
In trying to state the causes of generation and destruction, and in giving a physical account of all things, they do away with the cause of movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forms are not Real</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-1/part-9/</guid>
      <description>Some philosophers think that the Ideas are the causes of the things around us.
They introduced other Ideas equal in number to these phenomena. A man who wanted to count things will not be able to count if they were few. So he adds to them in order to count them. The Forms are practically equal to, or at least not fewer than the things that they represent.They say each thing has an entity which has the same name and exists apart from the substances [matter].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
