<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life of Pythagoras by Iamblichus on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life of Pythagoras by Iamblichus on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Early Life of Pythagoras</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>All men of sound understandings call on divinity when entering any philosophic discussion.
Chapter 2= The Early Days Ancæus dwelt in Samos in Cephallenia and was begot by Jupiter, whether he derived the fame of such an honorable descent through virtue, or through a certain greatness of soul.
He surpassed the rest of the Cephallenians in wisdom and renown.
This Ancæus, therefore, was ordered by the Pythian oracle to form a colony from Arcadia and Thessaly; and that besides this, taking with him some of the inhabitants of Athens, Epidaurus, and Chalcis, and placing himself at their head, he should render an island habitable, which from the virtue of the soil and land should be called Melamphyllos;[8] and that he should call the city Samos, on account of 3 Same in Cephallenia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras Sails for Egypt</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Pythagoras was thus benefited by and learned from Thales. For this, he entirely abstained from wine, animal food, and voracity. He confined himself to such essential nutrition which was easy to digest.
Because of this:
 his sleep was short his soul vigilant and pure, and his body stayed in a state of perfect and invariable health  These enabled him to sail to Sidon, being persuaded that this was his natural country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras in Samos</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>He was admired even more after his return to Samos, by the more aged inhabitants. He appeared to them to be more beautiful and wise, and to possess a divine gracefulness in a more eminent degree. Hence, he was publicly called upon by his country to benefit all men, by imparting to them what he knew.
Nor was he averse to this request, but endeavoured to introduce the symbolical mode of teaching, in a way perfectly similar to the documents by which he had been instructed in Egypt; though the Samians did not very much admit this mode of tuition, and did not adhere to him with that according aptitude which was requisite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pythagoreans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>Most of his disciples were auditors whom they call Acusmatici.
On his first arrival in Italy, according to Nicomachus, being captivated by one popular oration alone, they exceeded two thousand in number.
These, with their wives and children, being collected into one very large and common auditory, called Homacoïon, and which for its magnitude resembled a city, founded a place which was universally called Magna Græcia.
This many people received laws and mandates from Pythagoras as so many divine precepts, and without which they engaged in no occupation, dwelt together with the greatest general concord, celebrated and ranked by their neighbours among the number of the blessed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filial Piety</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>When he was traveling from Sybaris to Crotona, he met some fishermen who were then drawing their nets heavily laden with fish. He told them that he knew the exact number of the fish they had caught.
But the fishermen promising they would perform whatever he should order them to do, if the event corresponded with his prediction, he ordered them, after they had accurately numbered the fish, to return them alive to the sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policies for the Senators</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>Afterwards, a thousand men having called Pythagoras into the senate-house, and praised him for what he had said to their sons. They wanted him, if he had any thing advantageous to say to the Crotonians, to unfold it to those who were the leaders of the administration.
He was also the first that advised them to build a temple to the Muses, in order that they might preserve the existing concord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Policies for Boys</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Pythagoras advised the boys to neither revile any one, nor take vengeance on those that reviled.
He likewise exhorted them to pay diligent attention to learning, which derives its appellation from their age.
He added, that it was easy for a modest youth to preserve probity through the whole of life; but that it was difficult for one to accomplish this, who was not naturally well disposed at that age; or rather it is impossible that he who begins his course from a bad impulse, should run well to the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras was a Philosopher</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Pythagoras was the first who called himself a philosopher.
This was not a new name. , but previously instructing us in a useful manner in a thing appropriate to the name.
He said that the entry of men into the present life resembled the progression of a crowd to some public spectacle where men of every description assemble with different views.
One hastens to sell his wares for money and gain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; service to the world</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>Conceiving, however, that the first attention which should be paid to men, is that which takes place through the senses; as when some one perceives beautiful figures and forms, or hears beautiful rythms and melodies, he established that to be the first erudition which subsists through music, and also through certain melodies and rythms, from which the remedies of human manners and passions are obtained, together with those harmonies of the powers of the soul which it possessed from the first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pythagorean Educational System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>He therefore prepared his disciples for erudition, he did not immediately receive into the number of his associates those who came to him 51 for that purpose, till he had made trial of, and judiciously examined them.
Hence, he asked how they associated with their parents, and the rest of their relatives.
He then surveyed:
 their unseasonable laughter, their silence, and their speaking when it was not proper. their desires with whom they associated how they conversed with them how they employed their leisure time, and what were the subjects of their joy and grief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pythagorean Monks and Pythagorist Civilians</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>He grouped his disciples according to their respective merits.
For this would be uncommunicative and unjust. While therefore he imparted a convenient portion of his discourses to each, he benefited as much as possible all of them, and preserved the proportion of justice, by making each a partaker of the auditions according to his desert.
Hence, he called some of them Pythagoreans, but others Pythagorists just as we denominate some men Attics, but others Atticists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abaris</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>Universally, Pythagoras discovered many paths of learning.
He delivered an appropriate portion of wisdom conformable to the proper nature and power of each. The following is an example.
Abaris, an old Scythian, came from the Hyperboreans, unskilled and uninitiated in the Grecian learning. Pythagoras put him through trials and immediately considered him adapted to be an auditor of his dogmas. He instructed him in the shortest way in his:
 treatise On Nature, and treatise On the Gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pythagorean Method of Learning</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>How did Pythagoras teach his students?
  First, he tested them if they were able to refrain from speaking. He surveyed whether they could conceal in silence and preserve what they had learnt and heard.
  Second, he observed whether they were modest.
  He was much more anxious that they should be silent than that they should speak. He likewise directed his attention to every other particular; such, as whether they were astonished by the energies of any immoderate passion or desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoric Discipline and Symbols</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Pythagoras also exhorted to remove contention and strife from true friendship, and especially from all friendship, if possible.
But if this is not possible, at least expel it from:
 paternal friendship, and universally from the friendship with elders and benefactors.  Contending with your friends because of anger or some other similar passion destroys the existing friendship.
But the smallest lacerations and ulcerations should happen in friendships. This will happen if both friends know how to yield and subdue their anger, and especially the younger of the two belonging to some one of the above-mentioned orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagorean Diet</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>Nutrition greatly contributes to the best discipline when properly used.
Pythagoras instituted as a law the rejection of all such food as is flatulent, and the cause of perturbation. But he approved of food contrary to this. He ordered it to be used, viz. such food as composes and compresses the habit of the body.
Thus, the millet was a plant adapted to nutrition. But he altogether rejected such food as is foreign to the Gods; because it withdraws us from familiarity with the Gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoric discipline</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>Pythagoras believed that music contributed greatly to health, if it were used appropriately.
He was accustomed to employ a purification of this kind, but not in a careless way.
d he called the medicine which is obtained through music by the name of purification. But he employed such a melody as this about the vernal season.
For he placed in the middle a certain person who played on the lyre, and seated in a circle round him those who were able to sing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Harmonic Science and Harmonic Ratios</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>Pythagoras invented the harmonic science and harmonic ratios.
He wanted to invent a tool to aid the hearing which would be as firm and unerring as:
 a ruler or compass is unerring to the eyes. a dioptric instrument by Jupiter a balance scale  As he was walking near a brazier’s shop, he heard from a certain divine casualty the hammers beating out a piece of iron on an anvil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Political Contributions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>The Crotonians used to be impelled to make sumptuous funerals and interments.
Someone said to them that he had heard Pythagoras say that the Olympian Gods attended to the dispositions of those who sacrificed, and not to the number of the sacrifices. On the contrary, the terrestrial Gods, as being allotted the government of things less important, rejoiced in banquets and lamentations, and farther still, in continual libations, in delicacies, and in celebrating funerals with great expense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Religious Policies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>What were the virtues espoused by Pythagoras?
Let this, therefore, be one specimen of his piety, which also we have before mentioned, that he knew what his soul was, and whence it came into the body, and also its former lives, and that of these things he gave most evident indications.
After this also, let the following be another specimen; that once passing over the river Nessus with many of his associates, he spoke to it, and the river in a distinct and clear voice, in the hearing of all his followers, answered, Hail Pythagoras!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Political Contributions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-29/</guid>
      <description>Of his wisdom, however, the commentaries written by the Pythagoreans afford, in short, the greatest indication; for they adhere to truth in every thing, and are more concise than all other compositions, so that they savour of the ancient elegance of style, and the conclusions are exquisitely deduced with divine science.
They are also replete with the most condensed conceptions, and are in other respects various and diversified both in the form and the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Temperance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-30/</guid>
      <description>Pythagoras cultivated justice and delivered it to mankind. How did he avoid injustice?
For thus we shall discover how he avoided the latter, and what methods he adopted in order that the former might be properly ingenerated in the soul.
The principle of justice is the common and the equal, through which, in a way most nearly approximating to one body and one soul, all men may be co-passive, and may call the same thing mine and thine; as is also testified by Plato, who learnt this from the Pythagoreans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Approach ye genuine philosophic few, The Pythagoric Life belongs to you: But far, far off ye vulgar herd profane; For Wisdom’s voice is heard by you in vain: And you, Mind’s lowest link, and darksome end, Good Rulers, Customs, Laws, alone can mend.  Introduction Pythagoras was the father of philosophy.
Plato is the most genuine and the best of all his disciples.
Pythagoras&amp;rsquo; biographer, Iamblichus, is well known to every Platonist that he was seen by them as divine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Temperance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-31/</guid>
      <description>How was temperance cultivated by Pythagoras? How did he delivere it to his associates?
We have already therefore narrated the common precepts concerning it, in which it is said that every thing incommensurate should be cut off with fire and sword. The abstinence also from animal food, is a precept of the same species; and likewise from certain foods calculated to produce intemperance, and impeding the vigilance and genuine energies of the reasoning power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Political Contributions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-32/</guid>
      <description>The fortitude of the Pythagoreans was shown by:
 the admirable deeds of Timycha those Pythagoreans who chose to die rather than transgress Pythagoras&amp;rsquo; rule on beans and other things  Such also are the deeds which Pythagoras himself generously accomplished, when he travelled everywhere alone, and underwent immense labors and dangers, choosing to leave his country, and dwell among strangers.
Likewise, when he dissolved tyrannies, gave an orderly arrangement to confused polities, and emancipated cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Community of Pythagoraeans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-33/</guid>
      <description>With respect to the amity, however, which subsists in all things towards all, Pythagoras delivered it in the clearest manner.
And, the amity of the Gods indeed towards men, he unfolded through piety and scientific cultivation; but that of dogmas towards each other, and universally of the soul towards the body, and of the rational towards the species of the irrational part, through philosophy, and the theory pertaining to it. With respect to the amity of men also towards each other; that of citizens he delivered through sane legislation, but that of strangers through a correct physiology; and that between man and wife, or children, or brothers, 163 and kindred, through unperverted communion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pythagoras&#39; Political Contributions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-34/</guid>
      <description>The Greeks who joined the community of the Pythagoreans were ordered to use their native language because the Pythagoreans did not approve of foreign languages.
Foreigners also united themselves to the Pythagoric sect such as:
 the Messenians the Lucani Picentini the Romans  Metrodorus was the son of Thyrsus who was the father of Epicharmus. He transferred most of his doctrine to medicine.
He says that Epicharmus, and prior to him Pythagoras, conceived that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of the Pythagoreans</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-35/</guid>
      <description>There were persons hostile to the Pythagoreans and rose against them.
Stratagems were employed to destroy them during the absence of Pythagoras. Some say that he went to Pherecydes the Syrian, but others to Metapontum.
The Cylonians&amp;rsquo; Account Many causes, however, of the stratagems are enumerated. And one of them, which is said to have originated from the men called Cylonians, was as follows:
Cylon the Crotonian became the leader for his birth, renown, and wealth, as well as for his severe, violent, turbulence, and tyrannical manners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Successors to Pythagoras</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/life/chapter-36/</guid>
      <description>Aristæus was the successor of Pythagoras.
He was the son of Damophon the Crotonian, who lived at the same time as Pythagoras, was seven ages prior to Plato.
Aristæus was eminently skilled in the Pythagoric dogmas. This made him:
 worthy to succeed Pythagoras in his school, educate his children, marry his wife Theano  Pythagoras himself taught in Aristaeus&amp;rsquo; school. But Aristæus, when much advanced in 189 years, relinquished the school.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
