<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aphorisms Book 1 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aphorisms Book 1 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Proximate Instances wanting the Nature of Heat</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>The rays of the moon, stars, and comets, are not found to be warm to the touch, nay, the severest cold has been observed to take place at the full of the moon. Yet the larger fixed stars are supposed to increase and render more intense the heat of the sun, as he approaches them, when the sun is in the sign of the Lion, for instance, and in the dog-days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proximate Instances wanting the Nature of Heat</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>22  The first prerogative instance is solitary instance.
Solitary instances are those which exhibit the required nature in subjects that:
 have nothing in common with any other subject regarding the nature in question do not exhibit the required nature in resembling subjects  Those resembling subjects:  remove prolixity accelerate and confirm exclusion, so that a few of them are of as much avail as many.      An example is color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Precepts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>X. We now discuss our precepts.
The interpretation of nature has 2 divisions:
 The creation of axioms from experiment.  This has 3 divisions:
 To the senses To the memory To the mind or reason  The deriving of new experiments from axioms  We must first prepare as a foundation for the whole, a complete and accurate natural and experimental history. We must not imagine or invent, but discover the acts and properties of nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reign of Man NATURE</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>1  The aim of human power is to generate a new nature on a body.
The aim of human knowledge is to discover the true form or difference of a given nature.
; and subordinate to these primary labors are two others of a secondary nature and inferior stamp. Under the first must be ranked the transformation of concrete bodies from one to another, which is possible within certain limits; under the second, the discovery, in every species of generation and motion, of the latent and uninterrupted process from the manifest efficient and manifest subject matter up to the given form: and a like discovery of the latent conformation of bodies which are at rest instead of being in motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>XXV. In the fourth rank of prerogative instances we will class clandestine instances, which we are also wont to[166] call twilight instances; they are as it were opposed to the conspicuous instances, for they show the required nature in its lowest state of efficacy, and as it were its cradle and first rudiments, making an effort and a sort of first attempt, but concealed and subdued by a contrary nature. Such instances are, however, of great importance in discovering forms, for as the conspicuous tend easily to differences, so do the clandestine best lead to genera, that is, to those common natures of which the required natures are only the limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-w/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-w/</guid>
      <description>XLVIII. In the twenty-fourth rank of prerogative instances we will place wrestling instances, which we are also wont to call instances of predominance. They are such as point out the predominance and submission of powers compared with each other, and which of them is the more energetic and superior, or more weak and inferior. For the motions and effects of bodies are compounded, decomposed, and combined, no less than the bodies themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/chapter-x/</guid>
      <description>L. In the 26th rank of prerogative instances we will place the generally useful instances.
They are such as relate to various points, and frequently occur, sparing by that means considerable labor and new trials. The proper place for treating of instruments and contrivances, will be that in which we speak of the application to practice, and the methods of experiment. All that has hitherto been ascertained, and made use of, will be described in the particular history of each art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/footnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/bacon/nova/book-2/footnotes/</guid>
      <description>FOOTNOTES [71] Τὸ τὶ ἦν εἶναι, or ἦν οὐσία of Aristotle.—See lib. iii. Metap.
[72] These divisions are from Aristotle’s Metaphysics, where they are termed, 1. ὓλη ἢ τὸ ὑποκείμενον. 2. τὸ τὶ ἦν εἶναι. 3. ὅθεν ἡ ἀρχὴ τῆς κινήσεως. 4. τὸ οὗ ἕνεκεν—καὶ τὸ ἀγαθόν.
[73] See Aphorism li. and second paragraph of Aphorism lxv. in the first book.
[74] Bacon means, that although there exist in nature only individualities, yet a certain number of these may have common properties, and be controlled by the same laws.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
