<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Title 8: Protection Of The Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Title 8: Protection Of The Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Constitutional Guarantees</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-8/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-8/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 333
This Constitution shall not cease to be in effect if it ceases to be observed due to acts of force or because or repeal in any manner other than as provided for herein.
In such eventuality, every citizen should bring it back into actual effect.
Article 334
All of the judges of the Republic, within their respective spheres of competence and in accordance with the provisions of this Constitution and law, are obligated to ensure the integrity of the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>States of Exception</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-8/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-8/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Article 337
The President, at a meeting of the Cabinet of Ministers, can decree states of exception. These are social, economic, political, natural or ecological circumstances which seriously affect the nation&amp;rsquo;s security, institutions and citizens, in the face of which the powers available to cope with such events are insufficient.
In such case, the guarantees contained in this Constitution may be temporarily restricted, with the exception of those relating to the right to life, prohibition of incommunicative detention or torture, the right to due process, the right to information and other intangible human rights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
