<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fragments on Pythagoras on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fragments on Pythagoras on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Archytas&#39; Treatises</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/archytas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/archytas/</guid>
      <description>Treatise On Ethical Erudition Virtue is sufficient to prevent infelicity. Vice leads to the non-attainment of felicity. The bad man is always miserable whether he is in affluence, for he employs it badly; or whether he is in penury; just as the blind man, whether he has light, and the most splendid visible object before him, or whether he is in the dark [is always necessarily without sight].
But the good man is not always happy, for felicity does not consist in the possession, but in the use of virtue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crito&#39;s Treatises</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/crito/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/crito/</guid>
      <description>Treatise On Prudence And Prosperity Prudence and prosperity subsist, with reference to each other, as follows= Prudence indeed is effable and possesses reason; for it is something orderly and definite. But prosperity is ineffable and irrational; for it is something disorderly and indefinite. And prudence, indeed, is prior, but prosperity is posterior in beginning and in power. For the former is naturally adapted to govern and define; but the latter to be governed and defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euryphamus&#39; Treatise On Human Life</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/euryphamus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/euryphamus/</guid>
      <description>The perfect life of man falls short of the life of God, because it is not self-perfect. But it surpasses that of irrational animals, because it has virtue and felicity.
For neither is God in want of external causes; since being naturally good and happy, he is perfect from himself; nor any irrational animal.
Brutes have no reason and no science pertaining to actions.
But the nature of man partly consists of:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hipparchus&#39; Treatise On Tranquillity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/hipparchus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/hipparchus/</guid>
      <description>Men live but for a very short period. If their life is compared with the whole of time, they will make a most beautiful journey as it were, if they pass through life with tranquillity.
This however they will possess in the most eminent degree, if they accurately and scientifically know themselves, viz. if they know that they are mortal and of a fleshly nature, and that they have a body which is corruptible and can be easily injured, and which is exposed to every thing most grievous and severe, even to their latest breath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metopus&#39; Treatise on Virtue</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/metopus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/metopus/</guid>
      <description>Virtue is the perfection of human nature.
For every being becomes perfect, and arrives at the summit of excellence according to the proper nature of its virtue.
Thus, a horse&amp;rsquo;s virtue is that which leads to the perfection of the nature of a horse.
The same reasoning is applicable to the parts of a thing.
Thus, the virtue of the eyes is acuteness of vision.
This in the nature of the eyes is the summit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polus&#39; Treatise On Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/polus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/polus/</guid>
      <description>Justice may be called the mother and the nurse of the other virtues.
Without this, a man can neither be temperate, nor brave, nor prudent.
It is the harmony and peace, in conjunction with elegance, of the whole soul.
The strength of this virtue will become more manifest, if we direct our attention to the other habits.
For they have a partial utility, and which is referred to one thing; but this is referred to whole systems, and to a multitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Treatise On Felicity from Hippodamus the Thurian</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/hippodamus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/hippodamus/</guid>
      <description>Of animals, some are the recipients of felicity, but others are incapable of receiving it.
Those animals are receptive of it that have reason. For felicity cannot subsist without virtue; and virtue is first ingenerated in that which possesses reason.
But those animals are incapable of receiving felicity, that are destitute of reason. For neither can that which is deprived of sight, receive the work or the virtue of sight; nor can that which is destitute of reason, be the recipient of the work, or the virtue of that which possesses reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theages&#39; Treatise On The Virtues</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/theages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/pythagoras/fragments/theages/</guid>
      <description>The parts of the soul are:
 the reasoning power which has dominion over knowledge anger which has dominion over impetus desire which intrepidly rules over the soul&amp;rsquo;s appetites  When these three parts pass into one, and exhibit one appropriate composition, then virtue and concord are produced in the soul.
 But when they are divulsed from each other by sedition, then vice and discord are produced in the soul.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
