<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moral Systems based o the Principle of Approbation on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moral Systems based o the Principle of Approbation on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-love</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 1 After the inquiry on the nature of virtue, the next important question in Moral Philosophy is about the principle of approbation.
The principle of approbation is the power of the mind which renders certain characters agreeable or disagreeable to us. It makes us=
 prefer one tenour of conduct to another, denominate the one right and the other wrong, consider the one kind of conduct as the object of approbation, honour, and reward, and consider the other kind of conduct as the object of blame, censure, and punishment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Which Make Reason the Principle of Approbation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Hobbes&amp;rsquo; Doctrine 8 Mr. Hobbes&amp;rsquo; doctrine is that=
 a state of nature is a state of war before civil government was created, there could be no peaceful society  According to him, therefore=
 to preserve society was to support civil government to destroy civil government was to end society  But the existence of civil government depends on the obedience paid to the supreme magistrate. The moment he loses his authority, all government is ended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Based on Feelings</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-7/section-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>1-17 Moral systems based on feelings can be divided into two classes.
18
  According to some, the principle of approbation is founded on a particular faculty of perception.   This is exerted by the mind at the view of actions or affections.
 Some actions affect this faculty agreeably and are stamped as right, laudable, and virtuous. Some actions affect it disagreeably and are stamped as wrong, blamable, and vicious.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
