<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 8 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 8 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matter and Number</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-3/</guid>
      <description>A name sometimes means the composite substance, or the actuality or form.
e.g. whether &amp;lsquo;house&amp;rsquo; is a sign for the composite thing, &amp;lsquo;a covering consisting of bricks and stones laid thus and thus&amp;rsquo;, or for the actuality or form, &amp;lsquo;a covering&amp;rsquo;, and whether a line is &amp;rsquo;twoness in length&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;twoness&amp;rsquo;, and whether an animal is soul in a body&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;a soul&amp;rsquo;;
for soul is the substance or actuality of some body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The matter of Democritus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-2/</guid>
      <description>The substance which exists as underlying and as matter is generally recognized, and this that which exists potentially, it remains for us to say what is the substance, in the sense of actuality, of sensible things.
Democritus thinks there are three kinds of difference between things:
 their rhythm (shape) their turning (position) their intercontact (order)  The underlying body (matter) is one and the same, but they differ in those three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin of substance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Even if all things come from the same first cause or have the same things for their first causes, and if the same matter serves as starting-point for their generation, yet there is a matter proper to each, e.g. for phlegm the sweet or the fat, and for bile the bitter, though perhaps these come from the same original matter.
There come to be several matters for the same thing, when the one matter is matter for the other; e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unity of definitions and numbers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-6/</guid>
      <description>What is the cause of the unity of definitions and numbers?
In the case of all things which have several parts and in which the totality is not, as it were, a mere heap, but the whole is something beside the parts, there is a cause; for even in bodies contact is the cause of unity in some cases, and in others viscosity or some other such quality.
A definition is a set of words which is one not by being connected together, like the Iliad, but by dealing with one object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is inside matter?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-8/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Our goal is the causes, principles, and elements of substances.
Some substances are recognized by every one. But some have been advocated by particular schools. Those generally recognized are the natural substances:
 fire, earth, water, air, &amp;amp;c. the simple bodies plants and their parts animals and the parts of animals the physical universe and its parts  Others say that Forms and the objects of mathematics are substances.
Others say that there are other substances, the essence and the substratum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
