<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Karl Marx* on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Karl Marx* on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/marx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/1/</guid>
      <description>MIA: Marxists: Marx &amp;amp; Engels: Library: 1848: Manifesto of the Communist Party: Preface
Preface | 1872 German Edition | 1882 Russian Edition | 1883 German Edition | | 1888 English Edition | 1890 German Edition | 1892 Polish Edition | 1893 Italian Edition |
The 1872 German Edition The Communist League, an international association of workers, which could of course be only a secret one, under conditions obtaining at the time, commissioned us, the undersigned, at the Congress held in London in November 1847, to write for publication a detailed theoretical and practical programme for the Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/2/</guid>
      <description>MIA: Marxists: Marx &amp;amp; Engels: Library: 1848: Manifesto of the Communist Party: Chapter 1: [German Original]
Manifesto of the Communist Party A spectre is haunting Europe — the spectre of communism. All the powers of old Europe have entered into a holy alliance to exorcise this spectre: Pope and Tsar, Metternich and Guizot, French Radicals and German police-spies.
Where is the party in opposition that has not been decried as communistic by its opponents in power?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/3/</guid>
      <description>MIA: Marxists: Marx &amp;amp; Engels: Library: 1848: Manifesto of the Communist Party: Chapter 2: [German Original]
Chapter II. Proletarians and Communists In what relation do the Communists stand to the proletarians as a whole?
The Communists do not form a separate party opposed to the other working-class parties.
They have no interests separate and apart from those of the proletariat as a whole.
They do not set up any sectarian principles of their own, by which to shape and mould the proletarian movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/4/</guid>
      <description>MIA: Marxists: Marx &amp;amp; Engels: Library: 1848: Manifesto of the Communist Party: Chapter 3: [German Original]
Chapter III. Socialist and Communist Literature
 Reactionary Socialism A. Feudal Socialism Owing to their historical position, it became the vocation of the aristocracies of France and England to write pamphlets against modern bourgeois society. In the French Revolution of July 1830, and in the English reform agitation[A], these aristocracies again succumbed to the hateful upstart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/manifesto/5/</guid>
      <description>MIA: Marxists: Marx &amp;amp; Engels: Library: 1848: Manifesto of the Communist Party: Chapter 4: [German Original]
Chapter IV. Position of the Communists in Relation to the Various Existing Opposition Parties Section II has made clear the relations of the Communists to the existing working-class parties, such as the Chartists in England and the Agrarian Reformers in America.
The Communists fight for the attainment of the immediate aims, for the enforcement of the momentary interests of the working class; but in the movement of the present, they also represent and take care of the future of that movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruling Class</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/engels/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/engels/1/</guid>
      <description>The ideas of the ruling class are in every epoch the ruling ideas, i.e. the class which is the ruling material force of society, is at the same time its ruling intellectual force.
The class which has the means of material production at its disposal, has control at the same time over the means of mental production, so that thereby, generally speaking, the ideas of those who lack the means of mental production are subject to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
