<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 1973 Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 1973 Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ACCOUNTABILITY OF PUBLIC OFFICERS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-13/</guid>
      <description>Article 13: ACCOUNTABILITY OF PUBLIC OFFICERS
Section 1. Public office is a public trust. Public officers and employees shall serve with the highest degree of responsibility, integrity, loyalty, and efficiency, and shall remain accountable to the people.
SEC. 2. The President, the Members of the Supreme Court, and the Members of the Constitutional Commissions shall be removed from office on impeachment for, and conviction of, culpable violation of the Constitution, treason, bribery, other high crimes, or graft and corruption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMENDMENTS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-16/</guid>
      <description>Section 1.
(1) Any amendment to, or revision of. this Constitution may be proposed by the Batasang Pambansa upon a vote of three-fourths of all its Members, or by a constitutional convention.
(2) The Batasang Pambansa may, by a vote of two-thirds of all its Members, call a constitutional convention or, by a majority vote of all its Members, submit the question of calling such a convention to the electorate in an election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BATASANG PAMBANSA</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-08/</guid>
      <description>Article 8:
Section 1. The Legislative power shall be vested in a Batasang Pambansa.
SEC. 2. The Batasang Pambansa which shall be composed of not more than 200 Members unless otherwise provided by law, shall include representatives elected from the different regions of the Philippines, those elected or selected from various sectors as may be provided by law, and those chosen by the President from the members of the Cabinet. Regional representatives shall be apportioned among the regions in accordance with the number of their respective inhabitants and on the basis of a uniform and progressive ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BATASANG PAMBANSA</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-09/</guid>
      <description>Article IX
THE PRIME MINISTER, THE CABINET AND THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE
Section 1 There shall be a Cabinet which shall be composed of Ministers with or without portfolio appointed by the President. At least a majority of the Members of the Cabinet who are heads of ministries shall come from the Regional Representatives of the Batasang Pambansa.
The Prime Minister shall be the head of the Cabinet. He shall, upon the nomination of the President from among the Members of the Batasang Pambansa, be elected by a majority of all the Members thereof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BILL OF RIGHTS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-04/</guid>
      <description>Article 4: BILL OF RIGHTS
Section 1. No person shall be deprived of life, liberty, or property without due process of law, nor shall any person be denied the equal protection of the laws.
SEC. 2. Private property shall not be taken for public use without just compensation.
SEC. 3. The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers, and effects against unreasonable searches and seizures of whatever nature and for any purpose shall not be violated, and no search warrant or warrant of arrest shall issue except upon probable cause to be determined by the judge, or such other responsible officer as may be authorized by law, after examination under oath or affirmation of the complainant and the witnesses he may produce, and particularly describing the place to be searched, and the persons or things to be seized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GENERAL PROVISIONS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-15/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. The flag of the Philippines shall be red, white, and blue, with a sun and three stars, as consecrated and honored by the people and recognized by law.
SEC. 2. The interim Batasang Pambansa may by law adopt a new name for the country, a national anthem, and a national seal, which shall all be truly reflective and symbolic of the ideals, history, and traditions of the people. Thereafter, the national name, anthem, and seal so adopted shall not be subject to change except by constitutional amendment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LOCAL GOVERNMENT</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-11/</guid>
      <description>Article 11: LOCAL GOVERNMENT Section 1. The territorial and political subdivisions of the Philippines are the provinces, cities, municipalities, and barrios.
SEC. 2. The Batasang Pambansa shall enact a local government code which may not thereafter be amended except by a majority vote of all its Members, defining a more responsive and accountable local government structure with an effective system of recall, allocating among the different local government units their powers, responsibilities, and resources, and providing for the qualifications, election and removal, term, salaries, powers, functions, and duties of local officials, and all other matters relating to the organization and operation of the local units.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Territory</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 1: THE NATIONAL TERRITORY Section 1. The national territory comprises the Philippine archipelago, with all the islands and waters embraced therein, and all the other territories belonging to the Philippines by historic right or legal title, including the territorial sea, the air space, the subsoil, the sea-bed, the insular shelves, and the other submarine areas over which the Philippines has sovereignty or jurisdiction.
The waters around, between, and connecting the islands of the archipelago, irrespective of their breadth and dimensions, form part of the internal waters of the Philippines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The President</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1973/article-07/</guid>
      <description>Section 1. The President shall be the head of state and chief executive of the Republic of the Philippines.
SEC. 2. No person may be elected President unless he is a natural-born citizen of the Philippines. a registered voter, able to read and write, at least fifty years of age on the day of election for President, and a resident of the Philippines for at least ten years immediately preceding such election.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
