<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Measure of Time Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Measure of Time Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No Intuition of Simultaneity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/time/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/time/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Two psychological phenomena happen simultaneously in two different consciousnesses. What does simultaneous mean?
What do I mean by &amp;ldquo;a physical phenomenon which is before or after a psychological phenomenon&amp;rdquo;?
In 1572, Tycho Brahe noticed a new star. It took 200 years for the light from that star to reach our earth. That star therefore began before the discovery of America. But this statement has no meaning and is just an outcome of a convention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Difficulties Regarding Time</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/time/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/poincare/time/part-1/</guid>
      <description>I
As long as we do not go outside the domain of consciousness, the notion of time is relatively clear.
We easily distinguish our present sensation from the remembrance of past sensations or the anticipation of future sensations.
When we say that two conscious facts are simultaneous, we mean that they profoundly interpenetrate, so that analysis can not separate them without mutilating them.
For an aggregate of sensations to have become a remembrance capable of classification in time, it must have ceased to be actual.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
