<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Superphysics Principles on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Superphysics Principles on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Entity Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/entity-rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/entity-rights/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!
Entity rights give the right to exist to anything perceived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral Consequentialism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/moral-consequentialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/moral-consequentialism/</guid>
      <description>Our proposed moral system, derived from Adam Smith, David Hume, and Socrates, is based on a clear definition of morality as happiness for the most entities possible for the longest time possible.
The &amp;ldquo;most entities possible&amp;rdquo; encompasses moral space, while &amp;ldquo;for the longest time possible&amp;rdquo; encompasses moral time. The end goal of maximizing moral space and time, by specifying &amp;ldquo;most&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;longest&amp;rdquo;, is the attainment of the state of peace. This ultimate state then answers the purpose of creation and closes the loop of existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything is an Idea</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/idea/</guid>
      <description>The previous post explained that the Creator of the universe created the universe from Its Own metaphysical ideas and feelings, just as a novelist writes a novel from a stream of ideas and feelings coming from his metaphysical mind.
The purpose of ideas is to create experience. However, experience can only exist if there is an experiencer. Thus, there are only two things in this &amp;lsquo;matrix&amp;rsquo; of Existence:
 the experiencer the experience of ideas and feelings  The Positive and Negative Forces Before existence began, the Absolute Creator had nothing to create those experiencer and experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything is a Mind</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/mind/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Then,&#34; you ask, &#34;do you mean to tell us that THE ALL is LIFE and MIND?&#34;  Yes! and No! is our answer. The Kybalion  The previous post talked about ideas and feelings as making up experience. But what about the experiencer or the mind that experiences those ideas and feelings?
For the Experiencer to actually experience the infinite combination of ideas and feelings, It needs a container for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law of Conservation of Idea</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/law-conservation-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/law-conservation-idea/</guid>
      <description>The law of conservation of mass and energy is:
Matter and Energy cannot be created nor destroyed  We extend this to the aethereal layer of ideas and feelings: Ideas and Feelings cannot be created nor destroyed    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Morality?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/what-is-morality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/what-is-morality/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post , we explained that everything in existence has a dharma which represents the design or plan made by its inventor or creator.
 A smartphone is designed to withstand being dropped a few feet, but not many meters A basketball, on the other hand, is designed to withstand being dropped from long distances  We can say that the dharma of a smartphone in this sense is different from that of a basketball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Consciousness?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/consciousness/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post , we explained that there are only two things in Existence:
 experience experiencer  Experience is split up into ideas and feelings. Feelings then have two categories:
 the impersonal part of Existence as the Matrix (or Brahma, Tao, Sunya, the Whole) the personal part of Existence as the Supreme Entity (or God, Allah, Yahweh, Kali, Ganesh, etc. which are really created by the positive feelings of the experiencer)  The Experiencer has two parts as mind and consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re in a Matrix!</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/matrix/</guid>
      <description>We know the existence of thing through our perceptions of it. Each perception has two aspects:
 physical metaphysical  For example, when we see a mug, we have both the physical perception of a mug and a metaphysical idea of a mug nearly at the same time.
  The Two Domains This means that the mug exists in two domains of reality:
 the physical mug exists in the physical domain, which we see and touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Impartial Spectator?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/impartial-spectator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/impartial-spectator/</guid>
      <description>Aside from the division of labor, Adam Smith is famous for his concept of the impartial spectator. This spectator is the thing that guides us to do the right thing and avoid doing wrong. Many people would equate it to conscience, even if Smith mentioned that it is not so:
These must be left to the decision of the man within the breast, the supposed impartial spectator, the great judge and arbiter of our conduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;God&#39; and Existence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/principles/god/</guid>
      <description>The question &amp;lsquo;Does God exist?&amp;rsquo; can be answered by &amp;lsquo;Can you perceive Existence?&amp;rsquo;.
Earlier, we said that:
 every physical perception has a metaphysical idea-equivalent each idea produces an opposite idea: beauty has ugliness, health has disease a mind is an arena to experience such perceptions and ideas all our minds are inside a larger mind which we call the Matrix and is roughly equivalent to the Brahma by the Hindus, the Tao by the Taoists, Sunya by the Buddhists, and the Whole by Parmenides  Notice how the Matrix, Brahma, Tao, and the Whole are impersonal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
