<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Another illustration of this kind of error is the baseless conclusion critical readers of historical works draw when they hear about the position of judges and about the leadership in war and the command of armies that judges (formerly) exercised.
Their misguided thinking leads them to aspire to similar positions. They think that the office of judge at the present time is as important as it was formerly. When they hear that the father of Ibn Abi &amp;lsquo;Amir, who had complete control over Hisham, and that the father of Ibn &amp;lsquo;Abbad, one of the rulers of Sevilla, were judges, 168 they assume that they were like present-day judges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iram</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Iram was a city having columns. Ad b. Us b. Iram had two sons Shadid and Shaddid, who ruled after him. Shadid perished. Shaddad became the sole ruler of the realm, and the kings there submitted to his authority.
When Shaddad heard a description of Paradise, he said= &amp;ldquo;I shall build something like it.&amp;rdquo;
He lived 900 years and built the large city of Iram in the desert of Aden over a period of 300 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahya bin Aktham</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-3/</guid>
      <description>A parallel or similar story is that reported by all (the historians) about Yahya bin Aktham, the judge and friend of al-Ma&amp;rsquo;mun.101 He is said to have drunk wine together with al-Ma&amp;rsquo;mun and to have gotten drunk one night.
He lay buried among the sweet basil until he woke up. The following verses are recited in his name: O my lord, commander of all the people! He who gave me to drink was unjust in his judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/introduction/part-1/</guid>
      <description>History is a discipline that is very useful and has many different approaches. It makes us acquainted with
 the conditions of past nations as they are reflected in their national character. the biographies of the prophets and with the dynasties and policies of rulers.  The study of history requires:
 many sources greatly varied knowledge a good speculative mind and thoroughness  These lead the historian to the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
