<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being a servant is not a natural way of making a living</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-03/</guid>
      <description>The ruler must use the services of men, such as soldiers, policemen, and secretaries., in all the departments of political power (imarah).
For each department, he will be satisfied with men who, he knows, are adequate, and he will provide for their sustenance from the treasury. All this belongs to political power and the living made out of it. The authority of political administration extends to all these men, and the highest royal authority is the (common) source of (power for) their various branches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Meaning Of Sustenance And Profit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-01/</guid>
      <description>Profit is the value realized from human labor.
Man, by nature, needs something to feed him and to provide for him in all the conditions and stages of his life from the time of his (early) growth to his maturity and on to his old age.
Everyone tries to get things. Thus, whatever is obtained by one is denied to the other, unless he gives something in exchange for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ways of making a living</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-02/</guid>
      <description>Livelihood (making a living) means the desire for sustenance and the effort to obtain it. &amp;ldquo;Livelihood&amp;rdquo; (ma&amp;rsquo;ash) is a maf&amp;rsquo;al formation from `aysh &amp;ldquo;life.&amp;rdquo;
The idea is that &amp;lsquo;aysh &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo; is obtained only through the things that go into making a living, and they are therefore considered, with some exaggeration, &amp;ldquo;the place of life.&amp;rdquo; 14
Sustenance and profit may be obtained - through- having the power to take them away from others and to appropriate them according to a generally recognized norm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treasure Hunting is not a natural way of making a living</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-04/</guid>
      <description>Many weak-minded persons in cities hope to discover hidden treasure and profit from it.
They believe that all the treasures of the nations of the past were stored underground and sealed with magic talismans. These seals can then be broken only by those who have the necessary knowledge and can offer the proper incense, prayers, and sacrifices to break them.
The citizens in Ifriqiyah believe that the European Christians who lived in Ifriqiyah before Islam, buried their property and entrusted its (hiding place) to written lists, until such time as they might find a way to dig it up again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranks are useful in securing property</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-05/</guid>
      <description>The person of rank who is highly esteemed is materially more fortunate and wealthier than a person who has no rank.
This is because the person of rank is served by the labor of others. They try to approach him with their labor, since they want to be close to (him) and are in need of (the protection) his rank affords. People help him with their labor in all his needs, whether these are necessities, conveniences, or luxuries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The character of merchants are inferior to those of leading personalities and remote from manliness</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-14/</guid>
      <description>A merchant concerns himself with buying and selling, earning money and making a profit. This requires cunning, willingness to enter into disputes, cleverness, constant quarreling, and great persistence.
These are things that belong to commerce. They are qualities detrimental to and destructive of virtuousness and manliness, because it is unavoidable that actions influence the soul.
Good actions influence it toward goodness and virtue. Evil and deceitful actions influence it in the opposite sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agriculture is a way of making a living for weak people and Bedouins in search of subsistence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-08/</guid>
      <description>This is because agriculture is a natural and simple procedure. As a rule, sedentary people, or people who live in luxury, do not practice it. Those who practice it are characterized by humility.
When Muhammad saw a plowshare in one of the houses of the Ansar (in Medina). He said= &amp;ldquo;Such a thing never entered anyone&amp;rsquo;s house save accompanied by humbleness.&amp;rdquo;
Al-Bukhari explained this (statement) as referring to too intense an occupation with (agriculture) and he entitled the chapter in which he dealt with the tradition in question= &amp;ldquo;Warning against the consequences of (too intensive an) occupation with agricultural implements or transgression of the stipulated limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crafts are perfected only in a large and perfect sedentary civilization</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-16/</guid>
      <description>As long as sedentary civilization is incomplete and the city not fully organized, people are concerned only with the necessities such as obtaining of food.
Then, when the city is organized and the (available) labor increases and pays for the necessities and is more than enough (for the inhabitants), the surplus is spent on luxuries.
The crafts and sciences are the result of man&amp;rsquo;s ability to think, through which he is distinguished from the animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-24/</guid>
      <description>This is the first and oldest craft of sedentary civilization. It is the knowledge of how to go about using houses and mansions for cover and shelter. This is because man has the natural disposition to reflect upon the outcome of things.
Thus, he must reflect upon how to avert the harm arising from heat and cold by using houses which have walls. and roofs to intervene between him and those things on all sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midwifery</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-27/</guid>
      <description>Midwifery is a craft that shows how to proceed in bringing the new-born child gently out of the womb of his mother and how to prepare the things that go with that.
It also shows what is good for (a new-born child), after it is born, as we shall mention. The craft is as a rule restricted to women, since they, as women, may see the pudenda of other women. The woman who exercises this craft is called midwife (qabilah, literally, &amp;ldquo;the woman who receives&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calligraphy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-29/</guid>
      <description>Writing is the outlining and shaping of letters to indicate audible words which, in turn, indicate what is in the soul. It comes second after oral expression, It is a noble craft, since it is one of the special qualities of man by which he distinguishes himself from the animals. Furthermore, it reveals what is in (people&amp;rsquo;s minds.
It enables the intention (of a person) to be carried to distant places, and, thus, the needs (of that person) may be executed without (him) personally taking care of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book production</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-5/part-30/</guid>
      <description>Formerly, people were concerned with scholarly writings and (official) records. These were copied, bound, and corrected with the help of a transmission technique 204 and with accuracy.
This is because the ruling dynasty was important, along with the things that depend on sedentary culture. All that has disappeared now as the result of the disappearance of the dynasties and the decrease of civilization.
In Islam, it had formerly reached tremendous proportions in the &amp;lsquo;Iraq and in Spain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
