<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecasts and Predictions on Social Cycles on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forecasts and Predictions on Social Cycles on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Russia (and Ukraine)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/russia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/russia/</guid>
      <description>Current Cycle Years per Cycle Social Age     Negative Militant 15 5    The Russia-Ukraine war The Russia-Ukraine war really began in abstract on February 8, 2022 when the French President Macron failed to get the Russian President Putin to change his plan to attack Ukraine which actually began on February 24.
The blame for all this can be put on Biden and somewhat on Macron:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix Afghanistan</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/afghanistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/afghanistan/</guid>
      <description>Afghanistan fell to the Taliban in the middle of August, three months after the US announced a complete withdrawal of its troops.
The fall surprised a lot of people, especially since the US spent 20 years building the country from scratch. It was the job of the Afghan army to defend their country and they were doing a decent job before 2021, despite the corruption of their leaders.
This all changed when Trump announced a withdrawal of the US military by May 1, 2021, a policy which was continued by Biden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction Successes and Failures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/predictions/</guid>
      <description>Tsz-chang asked: Is it possible to forecast the state of the country 10 generations from now?
Confucius: The Yin dynasty adopted the rules and manners of the Hu line of kings. It is possible to tell whether it retrograded or advanced. The Chow line has followed the Yin and adopted its ways. Whether there has been deterioration or improvement may also be determined. Some other line may take up in turn those of Chow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/philippines/</guid>
      <description>   Current Cycle Years per Cycle Social Age     Militant 12 5.5    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Cycles of Egypt</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/egypt/</guid>
      <description>Current Cycle Years per Cycle Social Age     Populist 19     The Arab Spring shows a Worker cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Cycles of Israel</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/israel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/israel/</guid>
      <description>Current Cycle Years per Cycle Social Age     Philosopher 12     The quick ceasefire in 2021 shows Israel transitioning from the Militant to the Philosopher cycle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Cycles of Myanmar</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/myanmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/myanmar/</guid>
      <description>Current Cycle Years per Cycle Social Age     Populist 16     The current coup or civil war is explained by the populist cycle shifting to the militant cycle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Cycles of Palestine</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/palestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/palestine/</guid>
      <description>Current Cycle Years per Cycle Social Age     Philosopher 13     The entry of the intellectual cycle explains the ceasefire of 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Cycles of United States</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/united-states/</guid>
      <description>Current Cycle Years per Cycle Social Age     Negative Militant 17     The current Militant mentality manifests as the belligerent attitude of Trump supporters which invaded the Capitol, as well as increased racism and police brutality</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix Japan: Why Abenomics and Keynesian Economics Failed</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/japan/</guid>
      <description>Japan has been suffering from chronic deflation since 1991 after the bursting of their asset price bubble. This is similar in pattern to the secular stagnation in the US after the 2008 Financial Crisis. Both problems persist because they have been given the wrong solutions in the form of &amp;ldquo;quantitative easing&amp;rdquo; (QE) in the US, and &amp;ldquo;Abenomics&amp;rdquo; in Japan.
What is Abenomics? Abenomics is a set of economic policies organized into three arrows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Greece</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/greece/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/greece/</guid>
      <description>We can use our DCTI tool to analyze the Greek crisis to prove that the current solutions of austerity and high taxes are not the best ones. Such solutions are are a relic of the mercantile way of thinking of an economy as a business, instead of, naturally, as a society, family, or group of friends. The proper solution will involve the whole EU and will help the union stay together*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Venezuela</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/venezuela/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/cycles/venezuela/</guid>
      <description>The DCTI tool can diagnose the economic health of societies according the maxims of Adam Smith.
A society, whether it be a family, corporation, or country, is wealthy if its productivity or value produced exceeds its own demand or value needed. This productivity is shown in the “Industry” column below, while the demand is shown in the “Demand” column. A society is wealthy if its Industry bars are higher than its Demand bars and poor if it is lower.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
