<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotations from Mao Zedong on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotations from Mao Zedong on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Communist Party</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>The force at the core leading our cause is the Chinese Communist Party, which is based on Marxism-Leninism.
A revolution requires a revolutionary party. Without the Marxist-Leninist revolutionary theory and style, it is impossible to lead the working class and the masses to defeat imperialism and its running dogs.
&#34;Revolutionary Forces of the World Unite, Fight Against Imperialist Aggression!&#34; (November 1948), Selected Works, Vol. IV, p. 284.*  Without the efforts of the Chinese Communist Party, without the Chinese Communists as the mainstay of the Chinese people, China can never achieve independence and liberation, or industrialization and the modernization of her agriculture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classes And Class Struggle</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Classes struggle, some classes triumph, others are eliminated. Such is history, such is the history of civilization for thousands of years. To interpret history from this viewpoint is historical materialism; standing in opposition to this viewpoint is historical idealism.
&#34;Cast Away Illusions, Prepare for Struggle&#34; (August 14, 1949), Selected Works, Vol. 4 p. 428.  In class society everyone lives as a member of a particular class, and every kind of thinking, without exception, is stamped with the brand of a class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socialism And Communism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Communism is complete. It has:
 proletarian ideology a new social system.  It is most complete, progressive, revolutionary and rational system in human history.
Feudalism is obsolete. Capitalism is obsolete in the Soviet Union and is dying fast in other countries.
The communist ideological and social system alone is full of youth and vitality, sweeping the world.
&#34;On New Democracy&#34; (January 1940), Selected Works, Vol. II, pp. 360-61.*  The socialist system will eventually replace the capitalist system; this is an objective law independent of man&amp;rsquo;s will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Correct Handling Of Contradictions Among The People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>We are confronted by 2 types of social contradictions:
 those between ourselves and the enemy those among the people themselves.  These two are totally different in their nature.
On the Correct Handling of Contradictions Among the People (February 27, 1957), 1st pocket ed… p. 2.  To understand these two different types of contradictions correctly, we must first be clear on what is meant by &amp;ldquo;the people&amp;rdquo; and what is meant by &amp;ldquo;the enemy&amp;rdquo;… At the present stage, the period of building socialism, the classes, strata and social groups which favour, support and work for the cause of socialist construction all come within the category of the people, while the social forces and groups which resist the socialist revolution and are hostile to or sabotage socialist construction are all enemies of the people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War and Peace</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>War is the highest form of struggle for resolving contradictions when they have developed to a certain stage, between classes, nations, states, or political groups
War has existed ever since the emergence of private property and classes.
&#34;Problems of Strategy in China &#39;s Revolutionary War&#34; (December 1936), Selected Works, Vol. I, p. 180.  &amp;ldquo;War is the continuation of politics.&amp;rdquo; In this sense war is politics and war itself is a political action; since ancient times there has never been a war that did not have a political character…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imperialism And All Reactionaries Are Paper Tigers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>All reactionaries are paper tigers. In appearance, the reactionaries are terrifying, but in reality they are not so powerful. From a long-term point of view, it is not the reactionaries but the people who are really powerful.
&#34;Talk with the American Correspondent Anna Louise Strong&#34; (August 1946), SelectedWorks, Vol. IV, p. 100.  Just as there is not a single thing in the world without a dual nature (this is the law of the unity of opposites), so imperialism and all reactionaries have a dual nature - they are real tigers and paper tigers at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dare to Struggle, Dare to Win</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>People of the world:
 unite and defeat the U.S. aggressors and all their running dogs! be courageous, dare to fight, defy difficulties and advance wave upon wave. Then the whole world will belong to the people.  Monsters of all kinds shall be destroyed.
&#34;Statement Supporting the People of the Congo (L.) Against U.S. Aggression&#34; (November 28, 1964), People of the World, Unite and Defeat the U.S. Aggressors and All Their Lackeys, 2nd ed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People&#39;s War</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>The revolutionary war is a war of the masses; it can be waged only by mobilizing the masses and relying on them.
&#34;Be Concerned with the Well-Being of the Masses, Pay Attention to Methods of Work&#34; (January 27, 1934), Selected Works, Vol. I. p. 147.*  What is a true bastion of iron? It is the masses, the millions upon millions of people who genuinely and sincerely support the revolution. That is the real iron bastion which it is impossible, and absolutely impossible, for any force on earth to smash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The People&#39;s Army</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>Without a people&amp;rsquo;s army the people have nothing.
&#34;On Coalition Government&#34; (April 24, 1945), Selected Works, Vol. III, pp. 296-97.  This army is powerful because all its members have a conscious discipline; they have come together and they fight not for the private interests of a few individuals or a narrow clique, but for the interests of the broad masses and of the whole nation. The sole purpose of this army is to stand firmly with the Chinese people and to serve them whole-heartedly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Of Party Committees</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>The Party committee system is an important Party institution for:
 ensuring collective leadership preventing any individual from monopolizing the conduct of affairs.  In some leading bodies, one individual usually monopolizes the conduct of affairs and decide important problems.
Solutions to important problems are decided not by Party committee meetings but by one individual, and membership in the Party committee has become nominal.
Differences of opinion among committee members cannot be resolved and are left unresolved for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relations Between Officers And Men</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Our army has always had two policies:
 We must be ruthless to our enemies, we must overpower and annihilate them We must be kind to our own, to the people, to our comrades and to our superiors and subordinates, and unite with them.  Speech at the reception given by the Central Committee of the Party for model study delegates from the Rear Army Detachments (September 18, 1944).  We hail from all corners of the country and have joined together for a common revolutionary objective… Our cadres must show concern for every soldier, and all people in the revolutionary ranks must care for each other, must love and help each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mass Line</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>The people, and the people alone, are the motive force in the making of world history.
&amp;ldquo;On Coalition Government&amp;rdquo; (April 24, 1945), Selected Works, Vol. III, p. 257.* The masses are the real heroes, while we ourselves are often childish and ignorant, and without this understanding it is impossible to acquire even the most rudimentary knowledge.
&amp;ldquo;Preface and Postscript to Rural Surveys&amp;rdquo; (March and April 1941), Selected Works, Vol. III, p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Work</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>The system of Party representatives and of political departments, adopted for the first time in China, entirely changed the complexion of these armed forces. [1] The Red Army, which was founded in 1927, and the Eighth Route Army of today have inherited this system and developed it.
&#34;Interview with the British Journalist James Bertram&#34; (October 25, 1937), Selected Works, Vol. II, p. 54  The People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army has developed its vigorous revolutionary political work, which is an important factor in winning victory over the enemy, on the basis of a people&amp;rsquo;s war and of the principles of unity between army and people, of unity between commanders and fighters and of disintegrating the enemy troops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relations Between The Army And The People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>The army must become one with the people so that they see it as their own army. Such an army will be invincible…
&#34;On Protracted War&#34; (May 1938), Selected Works, Vol. II, p. 186.  Every comrade must be helped to understand that as long as we rely on the people, believe firmly in the inexhaustible creative power of the masses and hence trust and identify ourselves with them, we can surmount any difficulty, and no enemy can crush us while we can crush any enemy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy In The 3 Main Fields</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>A proper measure of democracy should be put into effect in the army, chiefly by abolishing the feudal practice of bullying and beating and by having officers and men share weal and woe.
Once this is done, unity will be achieved between officers and men, the combat effectiveness of the army will be greatly increased, and there will be no doubt of our ability to sustain the long, cruel war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education And The Training Of Troops</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>Our educational policy must enable everyone who receives an education to develop morally, intellectually and physically and become a worker with both socialist consciousness and culture.
On the Correct Handling of Contradictions Among the People (February 27, 1959), 1st pocket ed., p. 44.  As for education for cadres whether at work or in schools for cadres, a policy should be established of focusing such education on the study of the practical problems of the Chinese revolution and using the basic principles of Marxism-Leninism as the guide, and the method of studying Marxism- Leninism statically and in isolation should be discarded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving The People</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>We should be modest and prudent, guard against arrogance and rashness, and serve the Chinese people heart and soul…
&amp;ldquo;China&amp;rsquo;s Two Possible Destinies&amp;rdquo; (April 23, 1945), Selected Works, Vol. III p. 253. Our point of departure is to serve the people whole-heartedly and never for a moment divorce ourselves from the masses, to proceed in all cases from the interests of the people and not from one&amp;rsquo;s self-interest or from the interests of a small group, and to identify our responsibility to the people with our responsibility to the leading organs of the Party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patriotism And Internationalism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>Can a Communist, who is an internationalist, at the same time be a patriot?
We hold that he not only can be but must be. The specific content of patriotism is determined by historical conditions. There is the &amp;ldquo;patriotism&amp;rdquo; of the Japanese aggressors and of Hitler, and there is our patriotism.
Communists must resolutely oppose the &amp;ldquo;patriotism&amp;rdquo; of the Japanese aggressors and of Hitler. The Communists of Japan and Germany are defeatists with regard to the wars being waged by their countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Our Country Through Diligence And Frugality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>We must see to it that all our cadres and all our people constantly bear in mind that ours is a big socialist country but an economically backward and poor one, and that this is a very great contradiction. To make China rich and strong needs several decades of intense effort, which will include, among other things, the effort to practise strict economy and combat waste, i.e., the policy of building up our country through diligence and frugality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionary Heroism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>This army has an indomitable spirit and is determined to vanquish all enemies and never to yield. No matter what the difficulties and hardships, so long as a single man remains, he will fight on.
&#34;On Coalition Government&#34; (April 24, 1945), Selected Works, Vol. III, p. 264.*  Give full play to our style of fighting - courage in battle, no fear of sacrifice, no fear of fatigue, and continuous fighting (that is, fighting successive battles in a short time without rest).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-reliance And Arduous Struggle</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>Or policy is based on our own strength. That means regeneration through one&amp;rsquo;s own efforts.
We are not alone; all the countries and people in the world opposed to imperialism are our friends.
Nevertheless, we stress regeneration through our own efforts. Relying on the forces we ourselves organize, we can defeat all Chinese and foreign reactionaries.
&amp;ldquo;The Situation and Our Policy After the Victory in the War of Resistance Against Japan&amp;rdquo; (August 13, 1945), Selected Works, Vol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods Of Thinking And Work</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>The history of mankind is one of continuous development from the realm of necessity to the realm of freedom. This process is never-ending. In any society in which classes exist class struggle will never end.
In classless society the struggle between the new and the old and between truth and falsehood will never end.
In the fields of the struggle for production and scientific experiment, mankind makes constant progress and nature undergoes constant change, they never remain at the same level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigation And Study</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>Everyone engaged in practical work must investigate conditions at the lower levels. Such investigation is especially necessary for those who know theory but do not know the actual conditions, for otherwise they will not be able to link theory with practice.
Although my assertion, &amp;ldquo;No investigation no right to speak&amp;rdquo;, has been ridiculed as &amp;ldquo;narrow empiricism&amp;rdquo;, to this day I do not regret having made it; far from regretting it, I still insist that without investigation there cannot possibly be any right to speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correcting Mistaken Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>Even if we achieve gigantic successes in our work, there is no reason whatsoever to feel conceited and arrogant. Modesty helps one to go forward, whereas conceit makes one lag behind. This is a truth we must always bear in mind.
&amp;ldquo;Opening Address at the Eighth National Congress of the Communist Party of China &amp;quot; (September 15, 1956).
With victory, certain moods may grow within the Party - arrogance, the airs of a self-styled hero, inertia and unwillingness to make progress, love of pleasure and distaste for continued hard living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity and Discipline</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>The unification of our country, the unity of our people and the unity of our various nationalities - these are the basic guarantees of the sure triumph of our cause.
On the Correct Handling of Contradictions Among the People (February 27, 1957). 1st pocket ed., pp. 1-2.
It is only through the unity of the Communist Party that the unity of the whole class and the whole nation can be achieved, and it is only through the unity of the whole class and the whole nation that the enemy can be defeated and the national and democratic revolution accomplished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criticism And Self-criticism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>The Communist Party does not fear criticism because:
 the truth is on our side as Marxists the basic masses, the workers and peasants, are on our side.  Speech at the Chinese Communist Party&#39;s National Conference on Propaganda Work (March 12, 1957), 1st pocket ed., p. 14.  Thoroughgoing materialists are fearless; we hope that all our fellow fighters will courageously shoulder their responsibilities and overcome all difficulties, fearing no setbacks or gibes, nor hesitating to criticize us Communists and give us their suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Communists</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>A Communist should:
 have largeness of mind be staunch and active look upon the interests of the revolution as his very life subordinate his personal interests to those of the revolution always and everywhere adhere to principle wage a tireless struggle against all incorrect ideas and actions, so as to consolidate the collective life of the Party and strengthen the ties between the Party and the masses  He should be more concerned about the Party and the masses than about any individual, and more concerned about others than about himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Youth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-30/</guid>
      <description>The world is yours, as well as ours, but in the last analysis, it is yours. Young people, full of vigour and vitality, are in the bloom of life, like the sun at eight or nine in the morning. Our hope is placed on you.
The world belongs to you. China &amp;rsquo;s future belongs to you.
Talk at a meeting with Chinese students and trainees in Moscow (November 17, 1957).  We must help all our young people to understand that ours is still a very poor country, that we cannot change this situation radically in a short time, and that only through the united efforts of our younger generation and all our people, working with their own hands, can China be made strong and prosperous within a period of several decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture And Art</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-32/</guid>
      <description>In the world today all culture, all literature and art belong to definite classes and are geared to definite political lines.
There is no such thing as art for art&amp;rsquo;s sake, art that stands above classes, art that is detached from or independent of politics.
Proletarian literature and art are part of the whole proletarian revolutionary cause. They are, as Lenin said, cogs and wheels in the whole revolutionary machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-32b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-32b/</guid>
      <description>In transforming a backward agricultural China into an advanced industrialized country, we are confronted with arduous tasks and our experience is far from adequate. So we must be good at learning.
&#34;Opening Address at the Eighth National Congress of the Communist Party of China &#34; (September 15, 1956).  Conditions are changing all the time. To adapt to the new conditions, one must study. Even those who have a better grasp of Marxism and are comparatively firm in their proletarian stand have to go on studying, have to absorb what is new and study new problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mao/quotations/chapter-31/</guid>
      <description>A man in China is usually subjected to the domination of 3 systems of authority:
 political authority clan authority religious authority  Women, are also dominated by these, but also dominated by the men as the authority of the husband.
These four authorities - political, clan, religious and masculine - are the embodiment of the whole feudal-patriarchal ideology and system. They are the four thick ropes binding the Chinese people, particularly the peasants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
