<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enquiry on The Principles Of Morals Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enquiry on The Principles Of Morals Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Appendix 1=  Moral Sentiments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-1/</guid>
      <description>The General Principles of Morals What are the general principles of morals? How far do REASON or SENTIMENT enter into moral judgments?
One of the foundations of moral praise is the usefulness of a quality or action. Therefore, reason decides morality since only reason can=
 instruct us in the tendency of qualities and actions point out their beneficial consequences to society and to their possessor.  But=
 doubts may arise opposite interests may occur preference must be given to one side, from very nice views, and a small overbalance of utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix 2=  The Ego (Self-Love)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-2/</guid>
      <description>THERE is a principle, supposed to prevail among many, which is utterly incompatible with all virtue or moral sentiment; and as it can proceed from nothing but the most depraved disposition, so in its turn it tends still further to encourage that depravity.
Some people think that=
 BENEVOLENCE is mere hypocrisy friendship a cheat public spirit a farce fidelity a snare to procure trust and confidence we pursue only our private interest but we wear these fair disguises to put others off their guard, and expose them the more to our wiles and machinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-love</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-5b/</guid>
      <description>PART 2 Self-love is a principle in human nature of such extensive energy.
In general, the interest of each individual is so closely connected with that of the community. This made philosophers think that our concern for the public could be resolved into a concern for our own happiness and preservation.
They saw every moment, instances of approbation or blame, satisfaction or displeasure towards characters and actions; they denominated the objects of these sentiments, VIRTUES, or VICES.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Farther Considerations With Regard To Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-3/</guid>
      <description>The intention of this Appendix is to give some more particular explication of the origin and nature of Justice, and to mark some differences between it and the other virtues.
The social virtues of humanity and benevolence exert their influence immediately by a direct tendency or instinct, which chiefly keeps in view the simple object, moving the affections, and comprehends not any scheme or system, nor the consequences resulting from the concurrence, imitation, or example of others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Verbal Disputes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/appendix-4/</guid>
      <description>It is very common for philosophers to=
 encroach on the province of grammarians engage in disputes of words, while they imagine that they are handling controversies of the deepest importance and concern.  It was in order to avoid frivolous altercations that I endeavoured to state with the utmost caution the object of our present enquiry;
I proposed to list mental qualities which are=
 the object of love or esteem, and form a part of personal merit; and on the other hand, a catalogue of those the object of censure or reproach, and which detract from the character of the person possessed of them; subjoining some reflections concerning the origin of these sentiments of praise or blame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Society</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-4/</guid>
      <description>There would be no need for governments or political society if everyone could observe justice and equity and had the strength of mind to resist present pleasure and advantage.
In such a case of natural justice, we would not need any positive laws. There would be no need for magistrates when there is never any disorder.
When a number of political societies are erected, and maintain a great intercourse together, a new set of rules are immediately discovered to be USEFUL in that particular situation; and accordingly take place under the title of Laws of Nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Utility Pleases</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-5/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 It seems so natural a thought to ascribe to their utility the praise, which we bestow on the social virtues, that one would expect to meet with this principle everywhere in moral writers, as the chief foundation of their reasoning and enquiry.
In common life, we may observe, that the circumstance of utility is always appealed to; nor is it supposed, that a greater eulogy can be given to any man, than to display his usefulness to the public, and enumerate the services, which he has performed to mankind and society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-3/</guid>
      <description>PART 1 Justice is useful to society. This gives it its merit. But is public utility the SOLE origin of justice? Are the benefits of justice the SOLE foundation of its merit?
Let us suppose that nature has bestowed on the human race such profuse ABUNDANCE of all EXTERNAL conveniencies, that, without any uncertainty in the event, without any care or industry on our part, every individual finds himself fully provided with whatever his most voracious appetites can want, or luxurious imagination wish or desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertisement</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-1/</guid>
      <description>Author&amp;rsquo;s Advertisement Most of the principles, and reasonings, contained in this volume, were published in my A Treatise Of Human Nature
I thought of that book before I left College. I wrote and published it not long after. But it was not successful. I realized that my mistake was to publish too early.
I thus divided the work into the following smaller works which corrects his deficiencies in my reasoning and in my expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benevolence</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-2/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Sympathy We esteem the benevolent affections.
The epithets sociable, good-natured, humane, merciful, grateful, friendly, generous, beneficent, or their equivalents, are known in all languages. They universally express the highest merit, which HUMAN NATURE can attain.
People who have these amiable qualities joined with abilities which lead to the good government or education of mankind are seen as somewhat divine. The following qualities might expose a hero or politician to the public&amp;rsquo;s envy:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-2p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-2p2/</guid>
      <description>The good of mankind is the only object of all the laws of justice. Men&amp;rsquo;s possessions should be separated for the peace and interest of society.
The rules which separate them further serve the interests of society.
We shall suppose that a creature, possessed of reason, but unacquainted with human nature, deliberates with himself what rules of justice or property would best promote public interest, and establish peace and security among mankind=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-2p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-2p3/</guid>
      <description>A man&amp;rsquo;s property is anything which it is lawful for him, and for him alone, to use. but what rule have we, by which we can distinguish these objects?
Here we must have recourse to statutes, customs, precedents, analogies, and a hundred other circumstances; some of which are constant and inflexible, some variable and arbitrary.
But their ultimate goal is the interest and happiness of human society.
Where this enters not into consideration, nothing can appear more whimsical, unnatural, and even superstitious, than all or most of the laws of justice and of property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualities Useful To Ourselves</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-6/</guid>
      <description>PART 1 Where a quality or habit is subjected to our examination, if it appear in any respect prejudicial to the person possessed of it, or such as incapacitates him for business and action, it is instantly blamed, and ranked among his faults and imperfections. Indolence, negligence, want of order and method, obstinacy, fickleness, rashness, credulity; these qualities were never esteemed by any one indifferent to a character; much less, extolled as accomplishments or virtues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Beauty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-6p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-6p2/</guid>
      <description>All ancient moralists say that physical beauty is like a beautiful mind. We both praise a handsome man and a man with a beautiful mind.
One considerable source of BEAUTY in all animals is the advantage which they reap from the particular structure of their limbs and members, suitably to the particular manner of life, to which they are by nature destined. The just proportions of a horse, described by Xenophon and Virgil, are the same that are received at this day by our modern jockeys; because the foundation of them is the same, namely, experience of what is detrimental or useful in the animal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualities Immediately Agreeable To Ourselves</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-7/</guid>
      <description>A sad group of people sometimes has a lively member who suddenly animates their conversation. Such a cheerfulness carries great merit with it and most more readily communicates itself all around. The flame spreads through the whole circle; and the most sullen and morose are often caught by it.
Horace says that sad people hate happy people. However, I do not believe so. I see that serious people are more delighted where the happiness is moderate and decent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualities Immediately Agreeable To Others</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-8/</guid>
      <description>[Footnote= The natural definition of virtue is a quality of the mind agreeable to or approved of by every one who considers or contemplates it. Some qualities produce pleasure because they are useful to society or to the person himself, Other qualities produce pleasure more immediately. This is the case with the class of virtues here.]
The mutual shocks in SOCIETY and the oppositions of interest and ego have constrained mankind to establish the laws of JUSTICE, in order to preserve the advantages of mutual assistance and protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-9/</guid>
      <description>PART 1 IT is surprising that any man in so late an age, should find it requisite to prove, by elaborate reasoning, that Personal Merit consists altogether in the possession of mental qualities, USEFUL or AGREEABLE to the PERSON HIMSELF or to OTHERS.
It might be expected that this principle would have occurred even to the first rude, unpractised enquirers concerning morals, and been received from its own evidence, without any argument or disputation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moral obligations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-9p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/hume/morals/section-9p2/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 Why do we agree to moral obligations?
Though the philosophical truth of any proposition by no means depends on its tendency to promote the interests of society; yet a man has but a bad grace, who delivers a theory, however true, which, he must confess, leads to a practice dangerous and pernicious. Why rake into those corners of nature which spread a nuisance all around? Why dig up the pestilence from the pit in which it is buried?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
