<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Economic Financial Order on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Economic Financial Order on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agricultural Policy and National Financial System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Article 184. The Union can expropriate, on account of social interest, for purposes of agrarian reform, the rural property which is not performing its social function, against prior and fair compensation in agrarian debt bonds with a clause providing for maintenance of the real value, redeemable within a period of up to twenty years computed as from the second year of issue, and the use of which shall be defined in the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The General Principles of the Economic Activity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 170. The economic order, founded on the appreciation of the value of human work and on free enterprise, is intended to ensure everyone a life with dignity, in accordance with the dictates of social justice, with due regard for the following principles:
 national sovereignty; private property; the social function of property; free competition; consumer protection; environment protection, which may include differentiated treatment in accordance with the environmental impact of goods and services and of their respective production and delivery processes; reduction of regional and social differences; pursuit of full employment; preferential treatment for small enterprises organized under Brazilian laws and having their head-office and management in Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Policy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/br/title-07/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>Article 182. The urban development policy carried out by the municipal government, according to general guidelines set forth in the law, is aimed at ordaining the full development of the social functions of the city and ensuring the well-being of its inhabitants.
Paragraph 1. The master plan, approved by the City Council, which is compulsory for cities of over twenty thousand inhabitants, is the basic tool of the urban development and expansion policy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
