<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Title 7: National Security on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Title 7: National Security on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 322
National security is an essential competence and responsibility of the State, based on the overall development of the latter, and its defense is the responsibility of all Venezuelans, as well as of all public and private law natural and juridical persons within the geographical limits of Venezuela. Article 323 The National Defense Council is the highest consultative organ for planning and advising the Public Power as to matters relating to the overall defense of the Nation, its sovereignty and the integrity of its geographical space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax and Monetary System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Section One. Budget System
Article 311
Fiscal Policy shall be governed and implemented on principles of efficiency, solvency, transparency, responsibility and fiscal balance. Fiscal Policy is to be balanced over a multiyear budget framework, in such manner that ordinary revenues shall be sufficient to cover ordinary expenses. The National Executive shall submit for enactment by the National Assembly a multiyear framework for budgeting that establishes the maximum limits of expenditures and indebtedness to be contemplated in national budgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The National Armed Forces</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-7/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Article 328
The National Armed Forces constitute an essentially professional institution, with no political orientation, organized by the State to guarantee the independence and sovereignty of the Nation and ensure the integrity of its geographical space, through military defense, cooperation for the purpose of maintaining internal order and active participation in national development, in accordance with this Constitution and the law.
In performing their functions, they are at the exclusive service of the Nation, and in no case at the service of any person or political partisanship.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
