<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Title 9: Constitutional Reforms on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Title 9: Constitutional Reforms on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amendments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-9/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-9/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1. Amendments Article 340
Amendments add to or modify one or more articles of the Constitution, without altering its fundamental structure.
Article 341
The procedure for adopting amendments is:
 The initiative may emanate from 15% of the citizens registered with the Civil and Electoral Registry, from 39% of the members of the National Assembly or from the President, sitting with the Cabinet of Ministers. When the initiative emanates from the National Assembly, the amendment shall require approval by a majority of the members of that body, and shall be debated in accordance with the procedure established under this Constitution for the enactment of laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporary Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-9/temporary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-9/temporary/</guid>
      <description>SOLE DEROGATION PROVISION The Constitution of the Republic of Venezuela decreed on January 23, 1961 is hereby derogated. The rest of the juridical order shall remain in effect to the extent not in conflict with this Constitution.
TEMPORARY PROVISIONS   The special law on the regime for the Capital District as provided for under article 18 of this Constitution shall be approved by the National Constituent Assembly, and shall preserve the territorial integrity of the State of Miranda.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
