<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supersociology on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supersociology on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Have a Strong Christmas!</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/strong-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/strong-christmas/</guid>
      <description>The year 2021 is nearly over and along with it the experiences of the year:
 The Delta variant is giving way to the Omicron The stagnation of 2020 is giving way to inflation, exactly as predicted by our model The conflict with China and Russia is slowly building up  This is fully in line with our dialectical* model that predicted this crisis back in 2015 . According to it, the next crisis for the next few years would be a currency crisis, as a natural effect of the current stagnation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story of Jewish Politics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/jewish-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/jewish-politics/</guid>
      <description>The Jews at the time of Moses were torn between two sides:
 those who wanted to stay comfortably in Egypt as slaves and employees  These are the left-wing or liberals   those who wanted to be independent and leave Egypt  These are the right-wing or nationalists    Right-wing Moses A right-wing leader named Moses emerged and brought them out of Egypt and formed the God Party with its Ten Commandments as its Constitution which was forced onto all 12 Tribes even on the Levites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Regulation Requires Fellow-Feeling</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/self-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/self-regulation/</guid>
      <description>Many liberals advocate the self-regulation as an alternative to regulation by governments and institutions. They usually borrow passages from Adam Smith who said that the government should not lay its hand on the freedom of individuals to act as they see fit. They say that invisible hand of self-interest is much better at regulating the self:
Every individual works to render the society’s annual revenue as great as he can. He generally does not intend to promote the public interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Feudalism?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/what-is-feudalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/what-is-feudalism/</guid>
      <description>Feudalism is a way of controlling huge land areas where each land is divided into fiefs under a lord who is under a king, who is really the strongest lord. Thus, it can be viewed as a delegated way of governance.
Forms of feudalism were practiced in Persia, India, and Turkey. The opposite of feudalism is the republican city-states of Greece and Rome.
Feudalism&amp;rsquo;s key characteristic is that the land stays with the nobility&amp;rsquo;s family forever and is not subdivided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Pre-Crisis Years (2016-2018)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/precrisis-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/precrisis-years/</guid>
      <description>Our model, derived from the principles laid by David Hume, Adam Smith, and Socrates, designated 2019 as the start of a global stagflation.
This stagflation will increase from 2020 onwards up to 2030 when it will reach its peak, culminating in some kind of conflict. A stagflation is a phenomenon which has low employment and output while having high prices at the same time.
A Primer: The Metaphysics of Societies According to Eastern social cycle theory, history repeats itself because humans are bound by Nature which is dualistic in itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Civilizations Collapse</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/how-civilizations-collapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/how-civilizations-collapse/</guid>
      <description>Societies are created when indvidual people come together under a common interest to achieve something. For example:
 a group of military countries form an alliance for mutual defense or to attack another country a group of criminals agree to join forces to be a crime syndicate a group of teenagers agree to meet after school to start a rock band  All such alliances, syndicates, and bands are societies that require its members to agree to be part of the group or project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith = Hume = Socrates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/hume-smith-socrates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/hume-smith-socrates/</guid>
      <description>People&amp;rsquo;s confusion regarding Smith&amp;rsquo;s works, such as his stand on capitalism, arises because he did not define nor explain self-interest, private ownership, and why a person should have the profits of one&amp;rsquo;s own work.
It is but equity that those who feed, clothe and lodge the the people, should have such a share* of the produce of their own labour  Capitalism violates the concept of profit-sharing by giving all the profits* to the investor or owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Society, Nation, and State?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/society-nation-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/supersociology/society-nation-state/</guid>
      <description>Society &amp;lsquo;Society&amp;rsquo; comes from the Latin socius which means companion which is an abstract term.
Nation &amp;lsquo;Nation&amp;rsquo; comes from the Latin natus which refers to birth. Thus, a nation can have two meaning:
 The place where a person was born &amp;ndash; this leads to nationality The ethnicity of the person at birth &amp;ndash; this leads to &amp;lsquo;Cherokee nation&amp;rsquo; if one&amp;rsquo;s parents are both Cherokee  State A state is a formalized society that is non-arbitrary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
