<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/superphysics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Superphysics Future</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/future/</guid>
      <description>Economic Superphysics (Pantrynomics) Labor Theory of Value and Effort instead of Marginal Pricing and Money
Social Superphysics Coordinated governments instead of self-intereted governments
Material Superphysics Interstellar spaceships instead of skyscrapers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superphysics Defintions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/definitions/</guid>
      <description>Superphysics    Word Meaning     Adharmic not being in line with one&amp;rsquo;s dharma or the nature of things. This replaces the concept of &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;evil&amp;rsquo; which are based on the limited ego.   Dharmic being in line with one&amp;rsquo;s dharma or the nature of things. This replaces the concept of &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; which is based on the limited ego.   Consciousness the experiencer of experiences   Ego the feeling of the self   Mind the arena for experiences   Soul the mind when viewed independently of the body   Critical Feeling the expansion of one&amp;rsquo;s feelings onto other entities other than the self   Omnitheism a paradigm that views all Supreme Entities as different versions of one Supreme Entity   Dharma the inherent, metaphysical nature of any discrete identity with reference to the creator of that identity   Eagle the equation for everything, according to Superphysics   Tao the natural flow of the evolution or mechanics of a discrete identity   Positive Force the force or flow of the Tao that leads to unification   Negative Force the force or flow of the Tao that leads to separation and isolation   Positive feelings feelings that naturally make us feel lighter, such as happiness, contentment, love, peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Superphysics?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/what-is-superphysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/what-is-superphysics/</guid>
      <description>The Englightenment From the time of Plato and Aristotle up to Kant, philosophy dominated the study of human knowledge in the West. It included metaphysics and was only countered, or offset, by religion:
 Socrates was countered by Hesiod Copernicus was countered by the Church  A similar pattern existed in Asia:
 Buddhism was countered by Hinduism and Vedanta Taoism was countered by Confucianism  Science was then called Natural Philosophy which dealt with natural physical phenomena which were put under metaphysical principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI is Autonomous Intelligence, Not Artificial</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/ai-is-autonomous/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/ai-is-autonomous/</guid>
      <description>The tech world was abuzz with the word artificial intelligence or AI in 2016 after Google released Tensorflow in late 2015.
AI is a big field which includes machine learning and data mining. Many startup companies market themselves as being AI-based. Most of the time, they just use a machine learning algorithm to produce different outputs which might not be useful.
What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with artificial? The problem is that intelligence is merely the ability to connect ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feelings vs Sentiments vs Emotions vs Sensations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/feelings-sentiments-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/feelings-sentiments-emotions/</guid>
      <description>While simplifying Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s Theory of Moral Sentiments, I had to think a lot whether to change &amp;lsquo;sentiments&amp;rsquo; into &amp;lsquo;feelings&amp;rsquo; especially since the latter is nowadays more commonly used than the former.
Feelings vs Sentiments &amp;lsquo;Sentiment&amp;rsquo; is Latin for feeling.
&amp;lsquo;Feeling&amp;rsquo; is Old English for the ability of the heart to perceive, as opposed to:
 &amp;lsquo;sight&amp;rsquo;, the ability of the eye &amp;rsquo;think&amp;rsquo;, the ability of the brain &amp;lsquo;hearing&amp;rsquo;, the ability of the ear  Thus, &amp;lsquo;sentiment&amp;rsquo;, being Latin, is merely more formal and scientific than &amp;lsquo;feelings&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kant versus Hume -- A Showdown</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/kant-versus-hume/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/kant-versus-hume/</guid>
      <description>Hume was very much against shallow, unenlightened philosophers who wrote a lot of nonsense.
Kant is one such philosopher.
Hume already said that there was no such thing as a priori knowledge, but Kant refuted this by saying some were a priori. In reality, Kant was referring to belief and not knowledge.
Major Difference 1: A Priori; Belief Versus Knowledge There are a priori beliefs that you do not know where it came from (like why Person 1 likes chocolate instead of crisps, but Person 2 likes crisps instead of chocolate)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Critical Feeling?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/critical-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/critical-feeling/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, we defined moral as a quality that produces happiness for now and for as long as possible, for the self and for as many entities as possible.
The problem is that the Negative Force (the force that is tasked to create reality) is designed to limit and compress things. This limitation is seen in the ego in actively-conscious entities*.
 *It is actually strongest in non-living (non-actively-conscious) entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Difference Between Reasonable vs Unreasonable?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/reasonable-vs-unreasonable/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/reasonable-vs-unreasonable/</guid>
      <description>The Enlightenment was said to be a period where reason dominated. So it follows that before and after that period, people were unreasonable or less reasonable.
The word &amp;ldquo;reason&amp;rdquo; comes fron Latin ratus which is to reckon, think, or judge.
This is similar yet different from the word &amp;ldquo;intellect&amp;rdquo; which comes from intelligo or to understand.
The problem is that these definitions only account for logic or the connection of ideas, and not the feeling that powers those connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Socratic Dialectics?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/socratic-dialectics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/socratic-dialectics/</guid>
      <description>The Original Dialectics, Based on the Nature of Things The Dialectics of Socrates, or David Hume&amp;rsquo;s science of man, is a system of analysis based on the invisible metaphysical True Nature or Dharma or Tao* of anything that exists in reality.
Its goal is to solve real, visible problems in order to keep up with that invisible nature, dharma, or tao. Or rather, problems crop up when one goes against that dharma or tao.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
