<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 4 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 4 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Should Science Do?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Should the sciences inquire into the truths which are in mathematics called axioms, and into substance?
This also involves philosophy or the science of the philosopher; for these truths hold good for everything that is, and not for some special genus apart from others. And all men use them, because they are true of being qua being and each genus has being.
But men use them just so far as to satisfy their purposes; that is, as far as the genus to which their demonstrations refer extends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Some philosophers assert that it is possible for the same thing to be and not to be.
Writers on nature use this language.
But it is impossible for anything to be and not to be at the same time. The uneducated even demand that this be demonstrated. It is impossible for everything to be demonstrated as this would lead to an infinite regression that would end up with no demonstration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 6</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Who is to be the judge of things? All such questions have the same meaning. These people demand that a reason shall be given for everything; for they seek a starting-point, and they seek to get this by demonstration, while it is obvious from their actions that they have no conviction. But their mistake is what we have stated it to be; they seek a reason for things for which no reason can be given; for the starting-point of demonstration is not demonstration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protogoras</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-5/</guid>
      <description>From the same opinion proceeds the doctrine of Protagoras.
Both doctrines must be alike true or alike untrue. If all opinions and appearances are true, all statements must be at the same time true and false.
For many men hold beliefs in which they conflict with one another, and think those mistaken who have not the same opinions as themselves; so that the same thing must both be and not be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The contradictions of Heraclitus</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-8/</guid>
      <description>The one-sided theories which some people express about all things cannot be valid.
On the one hand the theory that nothing is true (for, say they, there is nothing to prevent every statement from being like the statement &amp;rsquo;the diagonal of a square is commensurate with the side&amp;rsquo;), on the other hand the theory that everything is true.
These views are the same as that of Heraclitus. for he who says that all things are true and all are false also makes each of these statements separately, so that since they are impossible, the double statement must be impossible too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One Science</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-1/</guid>
      <description>The one Science investigates:
 being as being and the attributes which belong to this in virtue of its own nature.  This is not the same as any of the so-called special sciences. None of these others treats universally of being as being. They cut off a part of being and investigate the attribute of this part.
The mathematical sciences, on the other hand, do this.
This Science explains the first principles and the highest causes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True or False</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-4/part-7/</guid>
      <description>There cannot be an intermediate between contradictories.
One subject must either affirm or deny any one predicate.
This is clear if we define what the true and the false are.
To say of what is that it is not, or of what is not that it is, is false,
while to say of what is that it is, and of what is not that it is not, is true
So that he who says of anything that it is, or that it is not, will say either what is true or what is false;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
