<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dialectics of Nature on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dialectics of Nature on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Forms of Motion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/motion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/motion/</guid>
      <description>Motion in the most general sense, conceived as the mode of existence, the inherent attribute of matter, comprehends all changes and processes occurring in the universe, from mere change of place right up to thinking.
The theory of motion began as from the simplest change of place and the mechanics of heavenly bodies and terrestrial masses.
 It was followed by the theory of molecular motion, physics, and immediately afterwards, the science of the motion of atoms, chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dialectics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/dialectics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/dialectics/</guid>
      <description>The general nature of dialectics to be developed is the science of interconnections, in contrast to metaphysics.
The laws of dialectics are abstracted, therefore, from:
 the history of nature and the history of human society.  These laws are nothing but the most general laws of these 2 aspects of historical development, as well as of thought itself.
They can be reduced to 3 developed by Hegel in his idealist fashion as mere laws of thought:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/introduction/</guid>
      <description>(1883)
MODERN natural science, which alone has achieved an all-round systematic and scientific development, as contrasted with the brilliant natural-philosophical intuitions of antiquity and the extremely important but sporadic discoveries of the Arabs, which for the most part vanished without results – this modern natural science dates, like all more recent history, from that mighty epoch which we Germans term the Reformation, from the national misfortune that overtook us at that time, and which the French term the Renaissance and the Italians the Cinquecento, although it is not fully expressed by any of these names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Science and the Spirit World</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/spirit/</guid>
      <description>Modern dialectics is split into 2 extremes.
One is based on natural science which, like the German philosophy of nature, tries to force the objective world into the framework of its subjective thought.
Another is based on mere experience. It disdains thought and prefers the extreme emptiness of thought. This school prevails in England.
Its father was Francis Bacon. He pushed the empirical-inductive method to attain:
   rejuvenation alteration of stature and features transformation of one body into another the production of new species power over the air the production of storms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Part played by Labour in the Transition from Ape to Man</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/ape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/ape/</guid>
      <description>I
Political economists assert that labour is the source of all wealth. And it really is the source – next to nature, which supplies it with the material that it converts into wealth.
But it is even infinitely more than this. It is the prime basic condition for all human existence, and this to such an extent that, in a sense, we have to say that labour created man himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Crookes</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/spirit2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/engels/dialectics/spirit2/</guid>
      <description>The second eminent adept among English natural scientists is Mr. William Crookes. He discovered the chemical element thallium and the radiometer.
Mr. Crookes began to investigate spiritualistic manifestations about 1871. For this, he used physical and mechanical appliances, spring balances, electric batteries, etc.
Mr. Crookes was just as completely captivated as Mr. Wallace:
For some years, a young lady, Miss Florence Cook, has exhibited remarkable mediumship, which latterly culminated in the production of an entire female form purporting to be of spiritual origin, and which appeared barefooted and in white flowing robes while she lay entranced in dark clothing and securely bound in a cabinet or adjoining room.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
