<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 13 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 13 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Substamce as Matter</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-1/</guid>
      <description>The substance of sensible things is matter. We are asking whether there is, besides the sensible substances, any which is immovable and eternal. If there is, what is it?
 One opinion says that the objects of mathematics-i.e. numbers and lines and the like-are substances Another opinion says that the Ideas are substances   Some recognize these as two different classes of substance Some recognize both as having one nature, Some say that the mathematical substances are the only substances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The propositions of mathematics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-3/</guid>
      <description>The universal propositions of mathematics do not deal with objects which exist separately, apart from extended magnitudes and from numbers.
but with magnitudes and numbers, not however qua such as to have magnitude or to be divisible, clearly it is possible that there should also be both propositions and demonstrations about sensible magnitudes, not however qua sensible but qua possessed of certain definite qualities.
For as there are many propositions about things merely considered as in motion, apart from what each such thing is and from their accidents, and as it is not therefore necessary that there should be either a mobile separate from sensibles, or a distinct mobile entity in the sensibles, so too in the case of mobiles there will be propositions and sciences, which treat them however not qua mobile but only qua bodies, or again only qua planes, or only qua lines, or qua divisibles, or qua indivisibles having position, or only qua indivisibles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Ideas and Forms</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-4/</guid>
      <description>The supporters of the Idea theory were led to it to answer the truth of things. They accepted the Heraclitean sayings which describe all sensible things as ever passing away. If knowledge or thought is to have an object, there must be some other and permanent entities, apart from those which are sensible. There could be no knowledge of things which were in a state of flux.
Socrates occupied himself with the excellences of character and became the first to raise the problem of universal definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Number and Unit</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-8/</guid>
      <description>What is the differentia of a number and of a unit if it has a differentia?
Units must differ either in quantity or in quality. Neither of these are possible.
But number qua number differs in quantity. If the units also did differ in quantity, number would differ from number, though equal in number of units.
Are the first units greater or smaller, and do the later ones increase or diminish?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numbers are not Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-7/</guid>
      <description>Are the units associable or inassociable?
If inassociable, in which of the two ways we distinguished. For it is possible that any unity is inassociable with any, and it is possible that those in the &amp;lsquo;itself&amp;rsquo; are inassociable with those in the &amp;lsquo;itself&amp;rsquo;, and, generally, that those in each ideal number are inassociable with those in other ideal numbers.
 All units are associable and without difference, we get mathematical number-only one kind of number, and the Ideas cannot be the numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 9</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-9/</guid>
      <description>There is no contact in numbers, but succession. Between the units, there is nothing. Between those in 2 or in 3 one might ask whether these succeed the 1-itself or not, and whether, of the terms that succeed it, 2 or either of the units in 2 is prior.
Similar difficulties occur with regard to the classes of things posterior to number,-the line, the plane, and the solid. For some construct these out of the species of the &amp;lsquo;great and small&amp;rsquo;; e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Individual and the Unieversal</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-10/</guid>
      <description>If substances are not separate, and in the way in which individual things are said to be separate, we shall destroy substance in the sense in which we understand &amp;lsquo;substance&amp;rsquo;; but if we conceive substances to be separable, how are we to conceive their elements and their principles?
If they are individual and not universal then:
 real things will be just of the same number as the elements, and the elements will not be knowable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Forms and Numbers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-13/part-5/</guid>
      <description>How do the Forms contribute to sensible things, either eternal or non-eternal?
The Forms cause neither movement nor any change in those things. But again they help in no wise either towards the knowledge of other things (for they are not even the substance of these, else they would have been in them), or towards their being, if they are not in the individuals which share in them; though if they were, they might be thought to be causes, as white causes whiteness in a white object by entering into its composition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
