<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 14 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 14 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Numbers are not the causal principle</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-5/</guid>
      <description>If it is equally impossible not to put the good among the first principles and to put it among them in this way, then the principles are not being correctly described, nor are the first substances.
Nor does any one conceive the matter correctly if he compares the principles of the universe to that of animals and plants, on the ground that the more complete always comes from the indefinite and incomplete-which is what leads this thinker to say that this is also true of the first principles of reality, so that the One itself is not even an existing thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One versus Number</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-1/</guid>
      <description>This substance must be enough.
All philosophers make the first principles contraries= as in natural things, so also in the case of unchangeable substances. But since there cannot be anything prior to the first principle of all things, the principle cannot be the principle and yet be an attribute of something else.
To suggest this is like saying that the white is a first principle, not qua anything else but qua white, but yet that it is predicable of a subject, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pythagorean Numbers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Some people believe that the Ideas exist as numbers. They do this by setting out each term apart from its instances. Out of the unity of each general term, they try to explain why number must exist.
Their reasons, however, are neither conclusive nor possible in themselves. This is why we should not assert the existence of number.
The Pythagoreans saw many attributes of numbers belonging to sensible bodies. They supposed real things to be numbers themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do people believe that the numbers exist</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-14/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Can eternal things consist of elements?
If they do, they will have matter for everything that consists of elements is composite.
Since, then, even if a thing exists for ever, out of that of which it consists it would necessarily also, if it had come into being, have come into being, and since everything comes to be what it comes to be out of that which is it potentially (for it could not have come to be out of that which had not this capacity, nor could it consist of such elements), and since the potential can be either actual or not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
