<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parmenides by Plato Simplified  on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parmenides by Plato Simplified  on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Socrates, Zeno, and Parmenides</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>PERSONS OF THE DIALOGUE= Cephalus, Adeimantus, Glaucon, Antiphon, Pythodorus, Socrates, Zeno, Parmenides, Aristoteles.
Cephalus rehearses a dialogue which is supposed to have been narrated in his presence by Antiphon, the half-brother of Adeimantus and Glaucon, to certain Clazomenians.
We had come from our home at Clazomenae to Athens, and met Adeimantus and Glaucon in the Agora.
Adeimantus Welcome, Cephalus. is there anything which we can do for you in Athens?  Cephalus Can you tell me the name of your half brother, which I have forgotten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Exercise on Logic</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Parmenides These, Socrates are a few, and only a few of the difficulties if we view ideas as having an an absolute unity.
Anyone against this will deny the very existence of this unity. Even if they do exist, he will say that they must of necessity be unknown to man. He will seem to have reason on his side, and will be very difficult to convince.
A man must be gifted with very considerable ability before he can learn that everything has a class and an absolute essence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Motion of the One</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Parmenides Hinduism     The One Nirguna Brahma   The Whole Saguna Brahma   The Not One Maya    The One Cannot Have Parts 1.a. If there is one thing, then it cannot be many and cannot have parts.
If it cannot have parts, then it cannot be a whole because a whole implies having parts.
Then, if the one is to remain one, it will not be a whole, and will not have parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Whole</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>The Whole (Brahma) 1.b. Let us return to the original hypothesis to see if any new aspect of the question appears. If the One exists, then we have to work out all the consequences.
We will start at the beginning.
If the One exists, then It will have being. But its being will not be the same with the One. If it were the same, it would not be the being of the One and; nor would the One have participated in being, for the proposition that one is would have been identical with the proposition that one is one;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relativity of Motion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>The One then is necessarily both at rest and in motion.
The One is at rest since it is in Itself as a Whole.On the contrary, the One which is ever in the Others is never in the same and is therefore never at rest.
The One as a Whole is not a part of Itself. Thus, It cannot be related to Itself in the same way as a whole is related to its part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relativity of the One to the Others</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>There is another argument. In so far as it is affected in the same way it is not affected otherwise, and not being affected otherwise is not unlike, and not being unlike, is like.
But in so far as it is affected by other it is otherwise, and being otherwise affected is unlike.
Then because the One is the same with the Others and other than the Others, on either or both of these two grounds, then the One will be both like and unlike the others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sequence and Cycle of Creation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Does the One as a Whole experience time? Does it become older and younger than Itself and Others? To exist is to be in the present time To have been is to be at a past time To be about to be is to be at a future time  Then the One, since it has being also has time.
Time is always moving forward.
This means that the One is always becoming relatively older than Its past Self, since It moves forward in time and experiences more time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relativity of Time</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>Is the One becoming older and younger than the Others, and the Others being younger and older than the one?
An age gap between two things in the present will still be the same age gap in the future. This is because the future implies that the same amount of timespan is added to both things*.
 *Translator&amp;rsquo;s Note= A 1-year old and a 6 year-old today will be a 2-year old and a 7-year old next year with the same age gap</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Will to Change</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>For the third time, let us consider: If the One is both one and many and is neither one nor many and experiences time, then it must exist when it is the Real One, but not exist when it is the Illusory One.  But It cannot exist when not existing, nor not exist when existing. Then the One exists sometimes and not exist sometimes, and there is a time when it switches from existence to non-existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multiplicity of the Whole</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>1.aa.
But if the One exists, what will happen to the Others?
The Others are not the One, but they participate in the One in a certain way.
Because the others are other than the one inasmuch as they have parts; for if they had no parts they would be simply one.
The parts are related to a whole. A whole is one made up of many. The parts will be parts of the one, for each of the parts is not a part of many, but of a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One is All</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>1.bb. If the One exists, what must be the affections of the Others?
The one must be distinct from the Others, and the Others distinct from the one.
Why, because there is nothing else beside them which is distinct from both of them; for the expression &amp;lsquo;one and the others&amp;rsquo; includes all things.
Then we cannot suppose that there is anything different from them in which both the one and the others might exist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Arising From the Illusion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>*Superphysics note: Here, Parmenides calls the Illusion as not
 2.a. What is the consequence if the One is not?
&amp;ldquo;The One is not&amp;rdquo; is different and opposed to &amp;ldquo;the not One is not.&amp;rdquo;
If largeness is not, if smallness is not, or anything of that sort, does he not mean, whenever he uses such an expression, that &amp;lsquo;what is not&amp;rsquo; is other than other things?
So when he says &amp;lsquo;If one is not&amp;rsquo; he clearly means, that what &amp;lsquo;is not&amp;rsquo; is other than all others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Absolute One</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>2.b. Let us go back to the beginning, and see the consequences that will follow. If One is not, we ask what will happen in respect of one?
The words &amp;lsquo;is not&amp;rsquo; signify an absence of being. When we say that a thing is not, we mean that it has no existence.Then, that which is not cannot exist.
We said that:
 becoming was the assumption of existence being destroyed was the assumption of non-existence  Then one that is non-existing cannot lose or gain existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Infinite Divisibility of the Others within the Illusion of the One</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>2.aa. If the One is an Illusion, what becomes of the Others? The Others become other than each Other, for the only remaining alternative is that they are other than nothing.
They are each Other than one another, as being plural and not singular. If One is an Illusion, then the Others cannot be singular. Instead, every particle of them is infinite in number.
Even if you take the smallest fraction, which seemed one, in a moment, it splits up into many as in a dream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One is All and All are One</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/parmenides/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>2.bb. Once more, let us go back to the beginning, and ask if the one is not, and the others of the one are, what will follow. In the first place, the others will not be one?
Nor will they be many; for if they were many one would be contained in them. But if no one of them is one, all of them are nought, and therefore they will not be many.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
