<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 1935 Constitution Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The 1935 Constitution Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-14/</guid>
      <description>Article 14: General Provisions Section 1: Flag
The flag of the Philippines shall be red, white, and blue, with a sun and three stars, as consecrated and honored by the people and recognized by law.
Section 2
All public officers and members of the armed forces shall take an oath to support and defend the Constitution.
Section 3
The Congress shall take steps toward the development and adoption of a common national language based on one of the existing native languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judicial Department</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-08/</guid>
      <description>Article 8: Judicial Department Section 1. The judicial power is in the Supreme Court and in such inferior courts.
Section 2. Congress
 can define, prescribe and apportion the jurisdiction of various courts cannot deprive the Supreme Court of  its original jurisdiction over cases affecting ambassadors, other public ministers, and consuls its jurisdiction to review, revise, reverse, modify   cannot affirm on appeal, certiorari, or writ of error, as the law or the rules of court may provide, final judgments and decrees of inferior courts in:   All cases in which the constitutionality or validity of any treaty, law, ordinance, or executive order or regulation is in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Territory</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-01/</guid>
      <description>Article 1: The National Territory Section 1. The Philippines comprises all the territory ceded to the US by the Treaty of Paris of December 10, 1898.
The limits are in Article 3 of the said treaty. This includes all the islands in:
 the treaty concluded at Washington between the US and Spain on November 7, 1900 the treaty concluded between the US and Britain on January 2, 1930 all the territory of the present Philippine Government  Article 2: Declaration of Principles Section 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Executive Department</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-07/</guid>
      <description>Article 7: Executive Department Section 1. The executive power shall be vested in a President of the Philippines.
Section 2. The President and Vice-President shall be:
 in office for 4 years elected by direct vote of the people.  The returns of every election for President and Vice-President, duly certified by the board of canvassers of each province or city, shall be transmitted to the seat of the National Government, directed to the President of the Senate, who shall, in the presence of the Senate and the House of Representatives, open all the certificates, and the votes shall then be counted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legislative Department</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ph/1935/article-06/</guid>
      <description>Section 1
The Congress shall have Legislative power. It will consist of a Senate and a House of Representatives
The Senate Section 2
The Senate shall have 24 Senators chosen by the qualified electors of the Philippines.
Section 3.
The term of office of Senators is 6 years beginning on December 30 after their election.
The first Senators elected under this Constitution shall, in the manner provided by law, be divided equally into three groups, the Senators of the first group, to serve for a term of six years; those of the second group, for four years; and those of the third group, for two years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
