<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How orbits are found when no focus is given on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How orbits are found when no focus is given on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lemma 17</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-17/</guid>
      <description>LEMMA 17 If from any point of a given conic section, to the four produced sides AB, CD, AC, DB, of any trapezium ABDC inscribed in that section, as many right lines PQ, PR, PS, PT are drawn in given ang ei, each line to each side ; the rectangle PQ, X PR of those on the opposite sides AB, CD, will be to the rectangle PS X PT of those on tie other two opposite sides AC, BD, in a given ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemma 19</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-19/</guid>
      <description>LEMMA 19 Find a point P from which if four right lines PQ, PR, PS, PT an drawn to as many other right lines AB, CD, AC, BD, given by posi tion, each to each, at given angles, the rectangle PQ X PR, under any two of the lines drawn, shall be to the rectangle PS X PT, under the other tivo. in a given ratio. Suppose the lines AB, CD, to which the two PQ, PR, containing one of the rect drawn to meet two other lines, given are angles, by position, in the points A, B, C, D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemma 20</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-20/</guid>
      <description>LEMMA 20 If the two opposite touch any conic angular points A and P of any parallelogram ASPQ and the sides AQ, AS section in the points A and P
of one of those angles, indefinitely produced, meet the same conic section and from the points of concourse, B and C to any fifth conic section, two right lines BD, are drawn meet- the point of tlie two other sides PS, the ing of parallelogram, indefinitely pro and PT, cut off from the sides, will duced in and the parts in B and C ; CD D PQ T R PR ; And vice versa, if those ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemma 23b (Prop 25_</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-23b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-23b/</guid>
      <description>Proposition 25 Problem 27 Draw a trajectory that shall pass through two given points, and touch three right lines given by position.
Through the concourse of any two of the tangents one with the other, and the concourse of the third tangent with the right line which passes through the two given points, draw an indefinite right line and, taking this line for the first ordinate radius, transform the figure by the preceding</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemma 24</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-24/</guid>
      <description>LEMMA 24 If three right lines, two whereof are parallel, and given by position, touch any conic section ; I say, that the semi-diameter of the section which is parallel to those two is a mean proportional between the segments of those two that are intercepted between the points of contact and the. third tangent. GB Let AF, be the two parallels touch ADB in A and B ing the conic section the third right line touching the conic section in I, and meeting the two former ; EF CD be the tangents in F and G, and let semi-diameter of the figure parallel to those tangents I say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposition 29</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/prop-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/prop-29/</guid>
      <description>Proposition 29 Problem a trajectory given in kind, that in given by position, into parts given describe lines may 21
be cut by order, kind, four right and proportion. that may be Suppose a trajectory is to be described similar to the curve line FGHI, and whose parts, similar and proportional to the parts FG, GH, HI of be intercepted between the right lines the other, AB may AD, and BD, and AD, BD and CE given by po pair of those lines, sition, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trapezium</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/newton/principia/book-1/sec-05/lemma-27/</guid>
      <description>LEMMA 27 A trapezium given in kind, the angles whereof may be in placed, respect of four right lines given by position, that are neither all paralhl among themselves, nor converge to one common point, describe , the several angles may touch the several lines. Let the four right lines ABC, AD, BD, CE, be given by position the first cutting the second in A, the third in B, and the fourth in C and suppose a ; trapezium fghi is to be described that may be similar trapezium FCHI, and whose angle /, equal to the given angle F, may touch the right line ABC and to the ; other angles g, h, i, equal to the other given angles, G, H, I, may touch the other lines AD, BD, CE, re Join FH, and upon FG.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
