<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Japanese Constitution on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Japanese Constitution on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Amendments</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Article 96. Amendments to this Constitution shall be initiated by the Diet, through a concurring vote of 2/3 or more of all the members of each House and shall thereupon be submitted to the people for ratification, which shall require the affirmative vote of a majority of all votes cast thereon, at a special referendum or at such election as the Diet shall specify.
Amendments when so ratified shall immediately be promulgated by the Emperor in the name of the people, as an integral part of this Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles 1</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 1: The Emperor Article 1. The Emperor shall be the symbol of the State and of the unity of the People, deriving his position from the will of the people with whom resides sovereign power.
Article 2. The Imperial Throne shall be dynastic and succeeded to in accordance with the Imperial House Law passed by the Diet.
Article 3. The advice and approval of the Cabinet shall be required for all acts of the Emperor in matters of state, and the Cabinet shall be responsible therefor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 2: RENUNCIATION OF WAR Article 9. Aspiring sincerely to an international peace based on justice and order, the Japanese people forever renounce war as a sovereign right of the nation and the threat or use of force as means of settling international disputes.
In order to accomplish the aim of the preceding paragraph, land, sea, and air forces, as well as other war potential, will never be maintained. The right of belligerency of the state will not be recognized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Article 83. The power to administer national finances shall be exercised as the Diet shall determine.
Article 84. No new taxes shall be imposed or existing ones modified except by law or under such conditions as law may prescribe.
Article 85. No money shall be expended, nor shall the State obligate itself, except as authorized by the Diet.
Article 86. The Cabinet shall prepare and submit to the Diet for its consideration and decision a budget for each fiscal year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cabinet</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Article 65. Executive power shall be vested in the Cabinet.
Article 66. The Cabinet has Ministers with the Prime Minister as its head, and are responsible to the Diet. These must be civilians.
Article 67. The Prime Minister shall be designated from among the members of the Diet by a resolution of the Diet.
This designation shall precede all other business.
If the House of Representatives and the House of Councillors disagree and if no agreement can be reached even through a joint committee of both Houses, provided for by law, or the House of Councillors fails to make designation within ten (10) days, exclusive of the period of recess, after the House of Representatives has made designation, the decision of the House of Representatives shall be the decision of the Diet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diet</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Article 41. The Diet shall be:
 the highest organ of state power the sole law-making organ of the State.  Article 42. The Diet has 2 Houses:
 the House of Representatives the House of Councilors  Article 43
Both Houses shall consist of elected members, representative of all the people. The number of the members of each House shall be fixed by law.
Article 44
The qualifications of members of both Houses and their electors shall be fixed by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Judiciary</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/jp/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Article 76. The judicial power is vested in a Supreme Court and inferior courts
No extraordinary tribunal shall be established, nor shall any organ or agency of the Executive be given final judicial power.
All judges shall be independent in the exercise of their conscience and shall be bound only by this Constitution and the laws.
Article 77. The Supreme Court is vested with the rule-making power under which it determines the rules of procedure and of practice, and of matters relating to attorneys, the internal discipline of the courts and the administration of judicial affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
