<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Economist by Xenophon on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Economist by Xenophon on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Wealth?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>Wealth is anything that is Useful and Beneficial Socrates Socrates= &amp;ldquo;Economy&amp;rdquo; is the name of a particular kind of knowledge or science, just like the words &amp;ldquo;medicine,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;carpentry,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;building,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;smithying,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;metal-working,&amp;rdquo; etc.
In the case of the arts just named, we can state the proper work or function of each, can we (similarly) state the proper work and function of economy?
 Critobulus A good economist at any rate must be able to manage his own house or estate well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of an Estate</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>Socrates There are two sorts of people:
 Those who spend large sums on money in building useless houses Those who spend far less but furnish it with all they need.  Here is one of the essentials of economy.
Mirroring them are two other sets of persons= The first possessors of furniture of various kinds, which they cannot, however, lay their hands on when the need arises.
They hardly know if they have got all safe and sound or not= whereby they put themselves and their domestics to much mental torture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyrus the Great</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>Boring Office and Routine Jobs are not Recomended Critobulus But why do you need to illustrate all the sciences, Socrates?
It would not be very easy to discover efficient craftsmen of all the arts, and quite impossible to become skilled in all one&amp;rsquo;s self. So please, confine yourself to the nobler branches of knowledge that I can focus on.
 Socrates A good suggestion, Critobulus.
The base mechanic arts
 have got a bad name are reasonably held in ill repute by civilised communities because they ruin the health of those who work in them, workers and overseers alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Husbandry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>Socrates Socrates= This shows that high and mighty people find it hard to hold aloof from agriculture. Devotion to it seems to be thrice blest.
Agriculture combines a certain sense of luxury with the satisfaction of an improved estate.
 It trains the body.  The Earth freely offers to those that labour all things necessary to live. If that were not enough, it further contributes luxuries.
We owe to the Earth our many delicacies of meat and vegetables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description> Critobulus Your words command my entire sympathy, when you bid us endeavour to begin each work with heaven&amp;rsquo;s help, (1) seeing that the gods hold in their hands the issues alike of peace and war.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ischomachus&#39; Trains His Wife</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>Socrates I saw him seated in the portico of Zeus Eleutherios, (1) and as he appeared to be at leisure, I went up to him and, sitting down by his side, accosted him  Socrates How is this, Ischomachus? you seated here, you who are so little wont to be at leisure?  As a rule, when I see you, you are doing something, or at any rate not sitting idle in the market-place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Management of the Military</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>Socrates Was your wife was stirred at all to greater carefulness?  Ischomachus Ischomachus= Yes. I remember how piqued she was at one time and how deeply she blushed, when I chanced to ask her for something which had been brought into the house, and she could not give it me.
So I, when I saw her annoyance, fell to consoling her. &amp;ldquo;Do not be at all disheartened, my wife, that you cannot give me what I ask for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Management</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>Socrates Did your wife appear, Ischomachus, to lend a willing ear to what you tried thus earnestly to teach her?  Isch. Yes, with promise to pay all attention. Her delight was evident, like some one&amp;rsquo;s who at length has found a pathway out of difficulties; in proof of which she begged me to lose no time in making the orderly arrangement I had spoken of.
Socrates How did you introduce the order she demanded?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Routine of an Economist</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>I thanked Ischomachus for what he had told me on the occupations of his wife.
Socrates The facts you mention reflect the greatest credit on both wife and husband.
But would you now in turn describe to me your work and business?
In doing so you will have the pleasure of narrating the reason of your fame. And I, for my part, when I have heard from end to end the story of a beautiful and good man&amp;rsquo;s works, if only my wits suffice and I have understood it, shall be much indebted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Need for a Bailiff</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Socrates But, perhaps I am preventing you from going, as you long have wished to do, Ischomachus?  Ischomachus No, I should not think of going away until the gathering in the market is dispersed.  Socrates Of course, of course, you are naturally most careful not to forfeit the title they have given you of &amp;ldquo;honest gentleman&amp;rdquo;; (2) and yet, I daresay, fifty things at home are asking your attention at this moment; only you undertook to meet your foreign friends, and rather than play them false you go on waiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal Bailiff</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>Socrates But now (I ventured), suppose you have presented strongly to the mind of some one (1) the need of carefulness to execute your wishes, is a person so qualified to be regarded as fit at once to be your bailiff?
or is there aught else which he must learn in order to play the part of an efficient bailiff?
 Most certainly there is (he answered)= it still remains for him to learn particulars—to know, that is, what things he has to do, and when and how to do them; or else, if ignorant of these details, the profit of this bailiff in the abstract may prove no greater than the doctor&amp;rsquo;s who pays a most precise attention to a sick man, visiting him late and early, but what will serve to ease his patient&amp;rsquo;s pains (2) he knows not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Morality of the Bailiff</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>Socrates Soc. Supposing the man is now so fit to rule that he can compel obedience. Is your bailiff absolute?
or even though possessed of all the qualifications you have named, does he still lack something?
 Most certainly (replied Ischomachus). One thing is still required of him, and that is to hold aloof from property and goods which are his master&amp;rsquo;s; he must not steal.
Socrates Consider, this is the very person through whose hands the fruits and produce pass, and he has the audacity to make away with them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Teach Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/socrates/the-economist/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>Socrates But suppose you have created in someone&amp;rsquo;s soul a desire for your welfare, a deep concern to help you to achieve prosperity, and taught him how to manage the field to eagerly produce a rich harvest. That someone would be worth his weight in gold.
You said that it was most important to learn how to do husbandry.  Isch= So what you now command me is to teach the art itself of tillage, Socrates?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
