<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On Liberty on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in On Liberty on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Superphysics Note: Mill&amp;rsquo;s system of liberty only prevents the violence of despotism. It does not prevent the slavery and oppression from the strong classes that prey on the weak. This manifess nowdays as the oppression from inequality and inflation
 This Essay is about Civil or Social Liberty, not about the Liberty of the Will which opposed to the doctrine of Philosophical Necessity.
What is the nature and limits of the power which can be legitimately exercised by society over the individual?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Liberty Of Thought And Discussion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The liberty of the press is one of the securities against corrupt or tyrannical government.
The law of England today on press freedom is as servile as it was in the time of the Tudors. But there is little danger of its being used against political discussion except during insurrection. The governments in constitutional countries do not often attempt to control public expression.
Let us suppose that the government is entirely at one with the people, but stifles the freedom of the press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individuality, As One Of The Elements Of Well-being</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Those are the reasons why humans should be free to:
 form opinions express their opinions without reserve  But should humans be also free to act them out?
Actions should not be as free as opinions.
On the contrary, even opinions lose their immunity, when the circumstances in which they are expressed are such as to constitute their expression a positive instigation to some mischievous act.
There might be opinions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Limits To The Authority Of Society Over The Individual</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>What is the rightful limit to self-interest?
How much of human life should be assigned to individuality, and how much to society?
Individuality should have the part of life in which it is chiefly the individual that is interested.
Society should have the part which chiefly interests society.
Society is not founded on a contract. Inventing a contract in order to deduce social obligations from it is for no good purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications--Education</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-5b/</guid>
      <description>Liberty implies that individuals should regulate each other by mutual agreement in things that jointly regard themselves and others. But since that will may change, it is often necessary that they should enter into engagements with one another. When they do, it is fit, as a general rule, that those engagements should be kept.
Yet in the laws, this general rule has some exceptions.
Persons are not held to engagements which violate the rights of third parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications--Free Trade</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/mill/liberty/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>My maxims are:
 The individual is not accountable to society for his actions, in so far as these concern the interests of no person but himself.  Advice, instruction, persuasion, and avoidance by other people if thought necessary by them for their own good, are the only measures by which society can justifiably express its dislike or disapprobation of his conduct.
Actions that hurt the interests of others should be punished socially or legally.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
