<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Title 3: Duties, Human Rights And Guarantees on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Title 3: Duties, Human Rights And Guarantees on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Civil Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Article 43
The right to life is inviolable. No law shall provide for the death penalty and no authority shall apply the same. The State shall protect the life of persons who are deprived of liberty, serving in the armed forces or civilian services, or otherwise subject to its authority.
Inalienable rights
Article 44
Personal liberty is inviolable, therefore:
Right to pre-trial release
 No person shall be arrested or detained except by virtue of a court order, unless such person is caught in fraganti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Provisions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Article 19
The State shall guarantee to every individual, in accordance with the progressive principle and without discrimination of any kind, no renounceable, indivisible and interdependent enjoyment and exercise of human rights. Respect for and the guaranteeing of these rights is obligatory for the organs of Public Power, in accordance with the Constitution, the human rights treaties signed and ratified by the Republic and any laws developing the same.
Right to development of personality</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Executive Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Chapter II. Nationality and Citizenship Section One. Nationality Requirements for birthright citizenship Article 32 Are Venezuelans by birth:
 Any person who was born within the territory of the Republic. Any person who was born in a foreign territory, and is the child of a father and mother who are both Venezuelans by birth. Any person who was born in a foreign territory, and is the child of a father or a mother, who is Venezuelan by birth, provided they have established residence within the territory of the Republic or declared their intention to obtain the Venezuelan nationality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Rights and Public Referenda</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Article 62
All citizens have the right to participate freely in public affairs, either directly or through their elected representatives. The participation of the people in forming, carrying out and controlling the management of public affairs is the necessary way of achieving the involvement to ensure their complete development, both individual and collective. It is the obligation of the State and the duty of society to facilitate the generation of optimum conditions for putting this into practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social and Family Rights</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Article 75
The State shall protect families as a natural association in society, and as the fundamental space for the overall development of persons. Family relationships are based on equality of rights and duties, solidarity, common effort, mutual understanding and reciprocal respect among family members. The State guarantees protection to the mother, father or other person acting as head of a household.
Children and adolescents have the right to live, be raised and develop in the bosom of their original family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Chapter X. Duties
Article 130 Venezuelans have the duty to honor and defend their native land symbols and cultural values and to guard and protect the sovereignty, nationhood, territorial integrity, self determination and interests of the nation. Duty to obey the constitution Article 131 Everyone has the duty to comply with and obey this Constitution and the laws and other official acts promulgated by the organs of Public Power. Article 132 Everyone has a duty to fulfill his or her social responsibilities and participate together in the political, civic and community life of the country, promoting and protecting human rights as the foundation of democratic coexistence and social peace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-3/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>Chapter VI. Culture and Educational Rights International law Provisions for intellectual property
Article 99
Cultural creation is free. This freedom includes the right to invest in, produce and disseminate the creative, scientific, technical and humanistic work, as well as legal protection of the author’s rights in his works. The State recognizes and protects intellectual property rights in scientific, literary and artistic works, inventions, innovations, trade names, patents, trademarks and slogans, in accordance with the conditions and exceptions established by law and the international treaties executed and ratified by the Republic in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
