<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 3: THE POLICIES AND FUNCTIONING OF THE UNION on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 3: THE POLICIES AND FUNCTIONING OF THE UNION on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FREE MOVEMENT OF GOODS</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3b/</guid>
      <description>Subsection 1 Customs union
Article III-151
 The Union shall comprise a customs union which shall cover all trade in goods and which shall involve the prohibition between Member States of customs duties on imports and exports and of all charges having equivalent effect, and the adoption of a common customs tariff in their relations with third countries. Paragraph 4 and Subsection 3 on the prohibition of quantitative restrictions shall apply to products originating in Member States and to products coming from third countries which are in free circulation in Member States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INTERNAL POLICIES AND ACTION</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 1: INTERNAL MARKET
SECTION 1: ESTABLISHMENT AND FUNCTIONING OF THE INTERNAL MARKET
Article 3-130
 The Union shall adopt measures with the aim of establishing or ensuring the functioning of the internal market, in accordance with the relevant provisions of the Constitution. The internal market shall comprise an area without internal frontiers in which the free movement of persons, services, goods and capital is ensured in accordance with the Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INTERPARLIAMENTARY COOPERATION</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-1/</guid>
      <description>PROVISIONS OF GENERAL APPLICATION
Article III-115: The Union shall ensure consistency between the policies and activities referred to in this Part, taking all of its objectives into account and in accordance with the principle of conferral of powers. Article III-116 In all the activities referred to in this Part, the Union shall aim to eliminate inequalities, and to promote equality, between women and men. Article III-117 In defining and implementing the policies and actions referred to in this Part, the Union shall take into account requirements linked to the promotion of a high level of employment, the guarantee of adequate social protection, the fight against social exclusion, and a high level of education, training and protection of human health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NON-DISCRIMINATION AND CITIZENSHIP</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-2/</guid>
      <description>Article III-123
European laws or framework laws may lay down rules to prohibit discrimination on grounds of nationality as referred to in Article I-4(2).
Article III-124
 Without prejudice to the other provisions of the Constitution and within the limits of the powers assigned by it to the Union, a European law or framework law of the Council may establish the measures needed to combat discrimination based on sex, racial or ethnic origin, religion or belief, disability, age or sexual orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3c/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 4: CAPITAL AND PAYMENTS
Article III-156 Within the framework of this Section, restrictions both on the movement of capital and on payments between Member States and between Member States and third countries shall be prohibited. Article III-157
 Article III-156 shall be without prejudice to the application to third countries of any restrictions which existed on 31 December 1993 under national or Union law adopted in respect of the movement of capital to or from third countries involving direct investment — including investment in real estate, establishment, the provision of financial services or the admission of securities to capital markets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3d/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 5: RULES ON COMPETITION
Subsection 1 Rules applying to undertakings
Article III-161
 The following shall be prohibited as incompatible with the internal market: all agreements between undertakings, decisions by associations of undertakings and concerted practices which may affect trade between Member States and which have as their object or effect the prevention, restriction or distortion of competition within the internal market, and in particular those which: (a) directly or indirectly fix purchase or selling prices or any other trading conditions; (b) limit or control production, markets, technical development, or investment; (c) share markets or sources of supply; (d) apply dissimilar conditions to equivalent transactions with other trading parties, thereby placing them at a competitive disadvantage; (e) make the conclusion of contracts subject to acceptance by the other parties of supplementary obligations which, by their nature or according to commercial usage, have no connection with the subject of such contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3e/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3e/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 6: FISCAL PROVISIONS
Article III-170
 No Member State shall impose, directly or indirectly, on the products of other Member States any internal taxation of any kind in excess of that imposed directly or indirectly on similar domestic products.  Furthermore, no Member State shall impose on the products of other Member States any internal taxation of such a nature as to afford indirect protection to other products.
 Where products are exported by a Member State to the territory of another Member State, any repayment of internal taxation shall not exceed the internal taxation imposed on them whether directly or indirectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3f/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 2: ECONOMIC AND MONETARY POLICY
Article III-177 For the purposes set out in Article I-3, the activities of the Member States and the Union shall include, as provided in the Constitution, the adoption of an economic policy which is based on the close coordination of Member States&amp;rsquo; economic policies, on the internal market and on the definition of common objectives, and conducted in accordance with the principle of an open market economy with free competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3g/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3g/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 2: MONETARY POLICY
Article III-185
 The primary objective of the European System of Central Banks shall be to maintain price stability. Without prejudice to this objective, the European System of Central Banks shall support the general economic policies in the Union in order to contribute to the achievement of its objectives as laid down in Article I-3. The European System of Central Banks shall act in accordance with the principle of an open market economy with free competition, favouring an efficient allocation of resources, and in compliance with the principles set out in Article III-177.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3h/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3h/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 3: INSTITUTIONAL PROVISIONS
Article 3-192
 In order to promote coordination of the policies of Member States to the full extent needed for the functioning of the internal market, an Economic and Financial Committee is hereby set up. The Committee shall have the following tasks: (a) to deliver opinions at the request of the Council or of the Commission, or on its own initiative, for submission to those institutions; (b) to keep under review the economic and financial situation of the Member States and of the Union and to report on it regularly to the Council and to the Commission, in particular with regard to financial relations with third countries and international institutions; (c) without prejudice to Article III-344, to contribute to the preparation of the work of the Council referred to in Article III-159, Article III-179(2), (3), (4) and (6), Articles III-180, III-183 and III- 184, Article III-185(6), Article III-186(2), Article III-187(3) and (4), Articles III-191 and III-196, Article III-198(2) and (3), Article III-201, Article III-202(2) and (3) and Articles III-322 and III- 326, and to carry out other advisory and preparatory tasks assigned to it by the Council; (d) to examine, at least once a year, the situation regarding the movement of capital and the freedom of payments, as they result from the application of the Constitution and of Union acts; the examination shall cover all measures relating to capital movements and payments; the Committee shall report to the Commission and to the Council on the outcome of this examination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3i/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 5: TRANSITIONAL PROVISIONS
Article III-197
 Member States in respect of which the Council has not decided that they fulfil the necessary conditions for the adoption of the euro shall hereinafter be referred to as ‘Member States with a derogation’. The following provisions of the Constitution shall not apply to Member States with a derogation: (a) adoption of the parts of the broad economic policy guidelines which concern the euro area generally (Article III-179(2)); (b) coercive means of remedying excessive deficits (Article III-184(9) and (10)); (c) the objectives and tasks of the European System of Central Banks (Article III-185(1), (2), (3) and (5)); (d) issue of the euro (Article III-186); (e) acts of the European Central Bank (Article III-190); (f) measures governing the use of the euro (Article III-191); (g) monetary agreements and other measures relating to exchange-rate policy (Article III-326); (h) appointment of members of the Executive Board of the European Central Bank (Article III-382 (2)); (i) European decisions establishing common positions on issues of particular relevance for economic and monetary union within the competent international financial institutions and conferences (Article III-196(1)); (j) measures to ensure unified representation within the international financial institutions and conferences (Article III-196(2)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3j/</guid>
      <description>CHAPTER 3: POLICIES IN OTHER AREAS
SECTION 1: EMPLOYMENT
Article III-203 The Union and the Member States shall, in accordance with this Section, work towards developing a coordinated strategy for employment and particularly for promoting a skilled, trained and adaptable workforce and labour markets responsive to economic change with a view to achieving the objectives referred to in Article I-3.
Article III-204
 Member States, through their employment policies, shall contribute to the achievement of the objectives referred to in Article III‑203 in a way consistent with the broad guidelines of the economic policies of the Member States and of the Union adopted pursuant to Article III-179(2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3k/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3k/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 2: SOCIAL POLICY
Article 3-209
The Union and the Member States, having in mind fundamental social rights such as those set out in the European Social Charter signed at Turin on 18 October 1961 and in the 1989 Community Charter of the Fundamental Social Rights of Workers, shall have as their objectives the promotion of employment, improved living and working conditions, so as to make possible their harmonisation while the improvement is being maintained, proper social protection, dialogue between management and labour, the development of human resources with a view to lasting high employment and the combating of exclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3l/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3l/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 3: ECONOMIC, SOCIAL AND TERRITORIAL COHESION
Article 3-220
In order to promote its overall harmonious development, the Union shall develop and pursue its action leading to the strengthening of its economic, social and territorial cohesion. In particular, the Union shall aim at reducing disparities between the levels of development of the various regions and the backwardness of the least favoured regions. Among the regions concerned, particular attention shall be paid to rural areas, areas affected by industrial transition, and regions which suffer from severe and permanent natural or demographic handicaps such as the northernmost regions with very low population density and island, cross‑border and mountain regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3m/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3m/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 4: AGRICULTURE AND FISHERIES
Article III-225
The Union shall define and implement a common agriculture and fisheries policy. ‘Agricultural products’ means the products of the soil, of stockfarming and of fisheries and products of first-stage processing directly related to these products. References to the common agricultural policy or to agriculture, and the use of the term ‘agricultural’, shall be understood as also referring to fisheries, having regard to the specific characteristics of this sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3n/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 5: ENVIRONMENT
Article III-233
 Union policy on the environment shall contribute to the pursuit of the following objectives: (a) preserving, protecting and improving the quality of the environment; (b) protecting human health; (c) prudent and rational utilisation of natural resources; (d) promoting measures at international level to deal with regional or worldwide environmental problems. Union policy on the environment shall aim at a high level of protection taking into account the diversity of situations in the various regions of the Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3o/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3o/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 6: CONSUMER PROTECTION
Article III-235
 In order to promote the interests of consumers and to ensure a high level of consumer protection, the Union shall contribute to protecting the health, safety and economic interests of consumers, as well as to promoting their right to information, education and to organise themselves in order to safeguard their interests. The Union shall contribute to the attainment of the objectives referred to in paragraph 1 through: (a) measures adopted pursuant to Article III-172 in the context of the establishment and functioning of the internal market; (b) measures which support, supplement and monitor the policy pursued by the Member States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3p/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3p/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 8: TRANS-EUROPEAN NETWORKS
Article III-246
 To help achieve the objectives referred to in Articles III-130 and III-220 and to enable citizens of the Union, economic operators and regional and local communities to derive full benefit from the setting-up of an area without internal frontiers, the Union shall contribute to the establishment and development of trans-European networks in the areas of transport, telecommunications and energy infrastructures. Within the framework of a system of open and competitive markets, action by the Union shall aim at promoting the interconnection and interoperability of national networks as well as access to such networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3q/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3q/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 10: ENERGY
Article III-256
 In the context of the establishment and functioning of the internal market and with regard for the need to preserve and improve the environment, Union policy on energy shall aim to: (a) ensure the functioning of the energy market; (b) ensure security of energy supply in the Union, and (c) promote energy efficiency and energy saving and the development of new and renewable forms of energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3r/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 2: POLICIES ON BORDER CHECKS, ASYLUM AND IMMIGRATION
Article III-265
 The Union shall develop a policy with a view to: (a) ensuring the absence of any controls on persons, whatever their nationality, when crossing internal borders; (b) carrying out checks on persons and efficient monitoring of the crossing of external borders; (c) the gradual introduction of an integrated management system for external borders. For the purposes of paragraph 1, European laws or framework laws shall establish measures concerning: (a) the common policy on visas and other short‑stay residence permits; (b) the checks to which persons crossing external borders are subject; (c) the conditions under which nationals of third countries shall have the freedom to travel within the Union for a short period; (d) any measure necessary for the gradual establishment of an integrated management system for external borders; (e) the absence of any controls on persons, whatever their nationality, when crossing internal borders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3s/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 3: JUDICIAL COOPERATION IN CIVIL MATTERS
Article III-269
 The Union shall develop judicial cooperation in civil matters having cross‑border implications, based on the principle of mutual recognition of judgments and decisions in extrajudicial cases. Such cooperation may include the adoption of measures for the approximation of the laws and regulations of the Member States. For the purposes of paragraph 1, European laws or framework laws shall establish measures, particularly when necessary for the proper functioning of the internal market, aimed at ensuring: (a) the mutual recognition and enforcement between Member States of judgments and decisions in extrajudicial cases; (b) the cross-border service of judicial and extrajudicial documents; (c) the compatibility of the rules applicable in the Member States concerning conflict of laws and of jurisdiction; (d) cooperation in the taking of evidence; (e) effective access to justice; (f) the elimination of obstacles to the proper functioning of civil proceedings, if necessary by promoting the compatibility of the rules on civil procedure applicable in the Member States; (g) the development of alternative methods of dispute settlement; (h) support for the training of the judiciary and judicial staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3t/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-3t/</guid>
      <description>SECTION 5: POLICE COOPERATION
Article III-275
 The Union shall establish police cooperation involving all the Member States&amp;rsquo; competent authorities, including police, customs and other specialised law enforcement services in relation to the prevention, detection and investigation of criminal offences. For the purposes of paragraph 1, European laws or framework laws may establish measures concerning: (a) the collection, storage, processing, analysis and exchange of relevant information; (b) support for the training of staff, and cooperation on the exchange of staff, on equipment and on research into crime‑detection; (c) common investigative techniques in relation to the detection of serious forms of organised crime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/eu/part-3/title-4/</guid>
      <description>TITLE 4: ASSOCIATION OF THE OVERSEAS COUNTRIES AND TERRITORIES Article III‑286
 The non‑European countries and territories which have special relations with Denmark, France, the Netherlands and the United Kingdom shall be associated with the Union. These countries and territories, hereinafter called the ‘countries and territories’, are listed in Annex II. This title shall apply to Greenland, subject to the specific provisions of the Protocol on special arrangements for Greenland.954393_TRAITE_EN_101_150 12-01-2005 14:22 Pagina 136 136 Part III The purpose of association shall be to promote the economic and social development of the countries and territories and to establish close economic relations between them and the Union.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
