<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political Economy on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political Economy on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>By labour man drew his first wealth from the earth, but scarcely had he satisfied his primitive wants, when desire made him conceive other enjoyments, not to be obtained without the aid of his fellows. Exchanges began. They extended to whatever had any value, to whatever could produce any.
They comprised mutual services and labour, no less than the fruit of labour; and gave room to the formation and increase of a new kind of wealth, which was no longer measured by the wants of him who produced it, but by the wants of all those with whom he might transact exchanges, - with whom he might carry on commerce; and hence we have named it commercial wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Production</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-7b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-7b/</guid>
      <description>Abstractly, the multiplication of food follows a geometrical progression like the multiplication of men. It follows it only much faster. In a given space and time, this progression is not followed any more by the one species than the other.
Population is arrested first, and arrests subsistence in its turn. When the obstacle is removed, both begin again to increase until they reach a new limit, equally common to both. The history of the universe has never yet presented the example of a country in which the multiplication of food could not be more rapid than that of the co-existent population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formation and Progress of Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Man has many wants. His wealth originates in this industry= his wants and desires are its employments. All that man values is created by his industry; all that he creates is destined to be consumed in satisfying his wants and desires. But, between the moment of its production by labour, and its consumption by enjoyment, the thing destined for man&amp;rsquo;s use may have an existence more or less durable. It is this thing, this accumulated and still unconsumed fruit of labour, which is called wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invention</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-7c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-7c/</guid>
      <description>The invention of the stocking frame allowed 1 man to do as much work as 100 men before. New counties adopted the customs of Europe. This kind of dress, formerly reserved for the rich, has now descended to the poorest classes.
But if, at the present day, some new discovery should enable us, by a single stocking-frame, to do the work which ten years ago was done by 100, this discovery would be a national misfortune; for the number of consumers can scarcely increase, and it would then be the number of producers which would be diminished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Wealth incessantly circulates from producers to consumers through money.
All kinds of exchange are accomplished under this form, whether the means of producing wealth are transmitted from one proprietor to another, or when land or movable capital changes its owner, or when labour is sold, or when the object destined to be consumed reaches the hands that are to use it.
Money facilitates all these exchanges. It occurs among the different contractors as a thing which all desire, and by means of which every one may find what he immediately requires; as a thing, moreover, submitted to invariable calculation, and by means of which all other values may be appreciated, this alone being their scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objects and Origins of the Science</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Political economy is an important division of the science of government. The object of government is the happiness of men, united in society.
But man is a complex being. He experiences moral and physical wants. Therefore his happiness has moral and physical aspects.
Moral Happiness The moral happiness of man, so far as it depends on his government, is intimately connected with the improvement of that government. It is the object of civil policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>Political economists must always take two elements together=  The increase of happiness in intensity Its diffusion among all classes of people  This makes the political economy the theory of beneficence. Everything which does not concern happiness in the long run does not belong to this science.
The human race originated in a single family.
It has multiplied, and spread itself over the globe. A lot of time was needed for it to adjust to the means of subsistence possible in the different parts of this globe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>The primary object of political economy is the development of national wealth; but the object of all governments, since they began to bestow any attention on this subject, has been to participate in this wealth, and to acquire the disposal of a greater share of the nation&amp;rsquo;s annual revenue. The ever increasing necessities of governments, and the excessive expense of wars, have forced princes to load their people with the weightiest possible yoke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Territorial Wealth</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>The riches proceeding from land should be the first to engage the attention of an economist or a legislator. They are the most necessary of all, because it is from the ground that our subsistence is derived; because they furnish the materials for every other kind of labour; and lastly, because, in preparation, they constantly employ the half, often much more than the half, of all the nation.
The class of people who cultivate the ground are particularly valuable for bodily qualities fitted to make excellent soldiers, and for mental qualities fitted to make good citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Physiocrats</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sismondi/economy/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>After the mid-18th century, Quesnay opposed to it his Tableau Economique. It was afterwards:
 expounded by Mirabeau and the Abbe de Riviere enlarged by Dupont de Nemours adopted by the Economists of France which spread to Italy  Quesnay&amp;rsquo;s was the second system in political economy called the &amp;ldquo;territorial system&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;the system of the economists&amp;rdquo;.
He asserts that:
 gold and silver do not themselves constitute the wealth of states no judgment can be formed concerning the prosperity of a nation, from the abundance of its precious metals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
