<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Influence of Society on Morality as Culture on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Influence of Society on Morality as Culture on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of customs on beauty</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1a/</guid>
      <description>1 The custom and fashion also have a big influence on our moral sentiments. They are the chief causes of many irregular moral opinions in different ages and nations. They dominate even our judgments concerning beauty.
2 When two objects have frequently been seen together, the imagination acquires a habit of passing easily from the one to the other. If the first appears, we assume that the second will follow. They naturally put us in mind of one another and our attention glides easily along them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom and Fashion in the Arts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>6 According to the ancient rhetoricians=
 a certain measure of verse was appropriated by nature to each species of writing each measure was naturally expressive of the writing&amp;rsquo;s character or feeling. one verse was fit for grave, and another for gay works.  These could not be interchanged without the greatest impropriety. However, modern writing contradicts this principle even though modern writing appears extremely proper. The burlesque verse in English is the heroic verse in French.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Differences Affect Morals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2b/</guid>
      <description>17 In the same way, the different situations of ages and countries give different=
 characters to their citizens, and sentiments about the praiseworthiness of those characters, according what is usual.  The politeness highly esteemed in Russia would be seen as rudeness and barbarism at the French court.
 A Polish nobleman might see a certain frugality as excessive parsimony, but it might be regarded as extravagance in Amsterdam.  Every age and country looks on that quality commonly seen in those who are esteemed among themselves, as the golden mean of that talent or virtue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Differences Affect Morals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2c/</guid>
      <description>20 This heroic and unconquerable firmness is demanded from every savage by his country&amp;rsquo;s custom and education.
It is not required of those who are brought up to live in civilized societies. They are easily pardoned if they= complain when they are in pain, grieve when they are in distress, and allow themselves to be overcome by love or discomposed by anger. Such weaknesses are not apprehended to affect the essential parts of their character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Custom on Morals</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/theory-moral-sentiments/part-5/chapter-2a/</guid>
      <description>11 Our feelings on beauty are so much influenced by custom and fashion, that the beauty of conduct is also influenced. However, this influence seems much less than it is everywhere else.
 Custom and fashion can make any physical thing agreeable, no matter how absurd. But custom and fashion can never make a character like Nero or Claudius agreeable  Nero will always be dreaded and hated. Claudius will always be scorned and derided.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
