<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multilateral Pool Clearing on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multilateral Pool Clearing on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Multilateral Pool Clearing Can Solve Currency Crises and Bilaterialism</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-1/</guid>
      <description>This is the simplified version of EF Schumacher&amp;rsquo;s Multilateral Clearing which was used by Keynes for his International Clearing Union and Bancor proposal in Bretton Woods, which were not accepted as they would regulate world trade. We build on Schumacher&amp;rsquo;s ideas and merge them with those of Adam Smith to create a multilateral free trade system which is based on gold or grains, as an implmentation of cross-border Pantrynomics .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solutions to Over-importing</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-5/</guid>
      <description>There are three solutions to over-importing:
1. Loans The deficit country could be given a loan.
This is always the easiest, though not always the most satisfactory way out. Non-industrialized countries that seek development should resort to loans. But loans should not be made if they would not lead to the necessary adjustments in their respective structures of production.
Balance should be the watchword. International loans, which allow a (justifiable) long-term lack of balance, should be the exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Clearing Office</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-2/</guid>
      <description>The International Clearing Office requires no finance of its own. It does not have to create a new international currency. It is impossible:
 to disentangle the mass of individual transactions which give rise to the various uncleared balances in the deficit countries and to ascribe any one particular balance, or part of it, to any one particular surplus country*.  The Gordian knot is cut by making all the surplus countries the joint owners of the balances in all the deficit countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-3/</guid>
      <description>The maximisation of economic benefits from world trade can be facilitated, but not automatically assured, by any purely technical system, whether bilaterl or multilateral.
How would Pool Clearing increase such benefits? Negative Balances Pool Clearing allows every country to discharge all its cash obligations to the rest of the world simply by paying its own national currency into its National Clearing Fund.
 Every Clearing Fund would can then receive any payment from international economic exchange such as:  payments for foreign goods and services*, interest, dividend and amortisation payments on old and new foreign debts, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/schumacher/pool-clearing/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Assume, then, that appropriate limits have been fixed for the deficit any one country will be allowed to incur, and the system is put into operation.
It will work smoothly as long as every nation avoids exceeding the deficit limits. In this respect it would be analogous to a Gold Standard system. It works satisfactorily as long as deficit countries balance their foreign exchange income and expenditure in such a way that their gold reserve remains intact</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
