<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Title 5: Organization Of National Public Authority on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Title 5: Organization Of National Public Authority on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>Section One. General Provisions
Article 273
Citizen Power is exercised by the Republican Ethics Council, consisting of the People Defender, the General Prosecutor and the General Comptroller of the Republic.
The organs of Citizen Power are the People Defender’s Office, the Office of Public Prosecutions and the Office of the General Comptroller of the Republic, one of whose heads shall be designated by the Republican Ethics Council as its Chairman for a one year term of office, with the possibility of re-election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electoral Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Article 292
Electoral Power is exercised by the National Electoral Council as governing body, and by the latter’s subordinate organs, the National Board of Elections, the Civil Status and Voter Registration Commission and the Commission on Political Participation and Financing, with organization and functioning as established under the pertinent organic law.
Article 293
The following are functions of Electoral Power:
 To regulate election laws and resolve any doubts and unregulated areas raised by or contained in such laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executive Vice-President</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-2c/</guid>
      <description>Article 238
The Executive Vice-President is a direct subordinate of and works closely with the President of the Republic in the latter’s capacity as Head of the National Executive. The Executive Vice-President must meet the same requirements prescribes for eligibility for the office of President of the Republic, and must not be related to the latter by either blood or marriage. Deputy executive
Article 239
The following are powers of the Executive Vice-President:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judicial Power and Justice System</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Section One. General Provisions Structure of the courts
Article 253
The power to administer justice emanates from the citizens and is exercised in the name of the Republic by authority of law. The organs comprising the Judicial Power are charged with dealing with all cases and matters within their competence, through such procedures as may be determined by the laws, and with carrying out or causing the execution of their judgments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministers and the Cabinet of Ministers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-2d/</guid>
      <description>Article 242
Ministers are direct dependencies of the President of the Republic, and when assembled together with the latter and with the Executive Vice-President, they comprise the Cabinet of Ministers.
The President of the Republic shall preside over meetings of the Cabinet of Ministers, but he shall have the power to authorize the Executive Vice President to preside over the same when he is unable to attend. Decisions made must be ratified by the President of the Republic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Executive Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Section One. President of the Republic
Article 225
Executive Power is exercised by the President of the Republic, the Executive Vice- President, the Cabinet Ministers and other officials as determined by this Constitution and by law.
Article 226
The President of the Republic is the Head of State and of the National Executive, in which latter capacity he directs the action of the government.
Article 227
In order to be elected President of the Republic, it is necessary to be Venezuelan by birth, with no other nationality, to be more than 30 years of age, not a member of the clergy and not subject to any conviction by final judgment, as well as meeting fulfill other requirements prescribed in this Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Legislative Power</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Section One. General Provisions Article 186
The National Assembly shall consist of Deputies elected in each of the federal entities by universal, direct, personalized and secret ballot with proportional representation, using a constituency base of 1.1 % of the total population of the country.
Each federal organ shall also elect three additional deputies. The native peoples of the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela shall elect three deputies in accordance with the provisions established under election law, respecting the traditions and customs thereof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization of the National Assembly</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1b/</guid>
      <description>Section 2. Organization of the National Assembly Legislative committees
Article 193
The National Assembly shall appoint ordinary and special Standing Committees. The Standing Committees, which shall be no more than 15 in number, shall relate to sectors of national activity. The National Assembly shall also have the power to create Committees of temporary nature for purposes of research and study, all of the foregoing in accordance with the applicable Regulations. The National Assembly shall have the power to create or abolish Standing Committees by the favorable vote of two thirds of the members of the Assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passage of Laws</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1c/</guid>
      <description>Article 202
The law is an act enacted by the National Assembly in legislative session.
Laws that contain a systematic set of norms regulating a particular field may also be referred to as codes.
Constitutional interpretation Constitutionality of legislation Organic laws
Article 203
Organic Laws are those designated as such by this Constitution, those enacted to organize public powers or developing constitutional rights, and those which serve as a normative framework for other laws.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Defender’s Office</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-4b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-4b/</guid>
      <description>Article 280
The People Defender’s Office promotes, defends and oversees the rights and guarantees established under this Constitution and international treaties on human rights, in addition to defending the legitimate, collective and diffuse interest of the citizens.
The People Defender’s Office shall act under the direction and responsibility of the People Defender, who shall be designated to serve for a single seven-year term. The People Defender must be a Venezuelan national over the age of 30 years, with manifest and proven competence in the field of human rights, and must meet with such requirements as to honesty, ethics and morality as may be established by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedures</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-1d/</guid>
      <description>Article 219
The first regular legislative session of the National Assembly shall begin, without advance notice, on January fifth of each year or on the first subsequent day possible, and shall continue until August 15. The second session shall begin on September 15 or the first subsequent day possible, and shall end on December 15.
Article 220
The National Assembly shall meet in special sessions to take up the matters on the agenda contained in the notice of the meeting, and any related matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Tribunal of Justice</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-3b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-3b/</guid>
      <description>Article 262
The Supreme Tribunal of Justice shall sit in plenary session and in Constitutional, Political/Administrative, Electoral, Civil Appeal, Criminal Appeal, and Social Appeal Divisions, whose composition and competence shall be determined by the pertinent organic act. The Social Division shall encompass matters relating to appeals involving agrarian matters, labor matters and minors. Attorney general Eligibility for supreme court judges Supreme court selection
Article 263
To be a justice of the Supreme Tribunal of Justice, a person must:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-4c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/constitutions/ve/title-5/chapter-4c/</guid>
      <description>Section Three. Office of Public Prosecutions
Attorney general
Article 284 The Office of Public Prosecutions shall be under the direction and responsibility of the General Prosecutor of the Republic, who shall perform his functions directly, with the assistance of such officials as may be determined by law. To be General Prosecutor of the Republic, a person must meet the same eligibility requirements that apply to justices of the Supreme Tribunal of Justice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
