<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How the Philippines fell from its Industrialization Path</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/how-industry-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/how-industry-failed/</guid>
      <description>Like most countries, the Philippines was hard hit by Covid-19 both in 2020 and 2021. However, unlike wealthier countries, it had a severe lack of vaccines, medicines, and personal protective equipment (PPEs) needed to fight the pandemic.
 The production of vaccines is the domain of biotech which India, South Korea, and Singapore are good at. The production of PPEs, on the other hand, are done by manufacturing, which China, Taiwan, and even Vietnam excel in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barter in Maharlika</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/barter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/barter/</guid>
      <description>Maharlika was no stranger to natural disasters such as typhoons and earthquakes. This was proven in the practices and myths of the country:
The first man came out of the one bamboo and the first woman from the other. These, they say, married with the approval of Linog, which is the earthquake, Barangay, William Henry Scott  Some old men were renowned for the accuracy of their weather forecasts. They predicted storms, their severity, and the flooding that would follow, three or four days in advance, or even a week, by judging from cloud formations and the color of the skies, sun, and moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dutertenomics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/dutertenomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/dutertenomics/</guid>
      <description>During his presidential campaign Duterte promised to give a comfortable life to the poor. However, the unstoppable rising prices* from 2020 directly contradict this promise since it makes life less comfortable.
 *This inflation can be most easily reduced by a global ban on cryptocurreny mining and NFTs as explained here  To see where the contradiction occurs, let&amp;rsquo;s dissect Dutertenomics. Its most prominent parts are:
 Build Build Build TRAIN Law (This is higher taxation used to pay for Build Build Build) Ease of business Land Distribution Continuation of Pantawid Pamilya of Noynoy Aquino  These policies are consistent with the Keynesian doctrine, except for &amp;ldquo;Pantawid Pamilya&amp;rdquo; which is Conditional Cash Transfer (CCT), a modified version of Universal Basic Income (UBI) implemented by former President Noynoy Aquino.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industries that are Natural to the Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/natural-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/natural-industries/</guid>
      <description>From a survey of Maharlikan industry before Legazpi came, we can list the industries that are natural to the country.
Services Call centers Those people became very familiar with us. They told us many things, their names and those of some of the islands that could be seen from that place. Their own island was Sulu, not very large. They were very pleasant and conversable.
Pigafetta  Hospitality When we had eaten, the king had a reed mat and another of palm leaves, and a leaf pillow brought in for me to sleep on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maharlika 2050</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/maharlika-2050/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/economics/maharlika-2050/</guid>
      <description>The previous post explained the problem with the Keynesian Dutertenomics, which is embodied in the neoliberal economic plan called &amp;ldquo;Ambisyon 2040&amp;rdquo; by Arsenio Balisacan.
Society Subsidizing the Rich The main flaw of that plan was that it catered to the merchant class of society and neglected the other 3 classes . That class is made up of business and monied interests.
   Class Socratic Name Hindu Name Example     Merchants Oligarchs &amp;ldquo;The Few&amp;rdquo; Vaesya Businessmen, Banks, Traders   Populists Democrats &amp;ldquo;The Many&amp;rdquo; Shudra Workers, Employees, General labor (Farm labor, fishermen, maids, etc)   Militants Tyrants Ksattriya Government, Military, Police   Philosophers Aristocrats &amp;ldquo;The Best&amp;rdquo; Brahmin Universities, Researchers, Inventors, Religions    A society needs all 4 classes to be in good shape just as a human body needs all its organs working properly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
