<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Governance on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Governance on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maharlikan Federalism -- Growth with Stability</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/federalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/federalism/</guid>
      <description>The historical Maharlika implemented a democratic confederation system similar to the one implemented by the Greek city states, the European Hanseatic league, and the Swiss Confederacy. This is the opposite of the centralized imperial system imposed by the Romans, Arab Muslims, and the Chinese.
However, a confederation is weak against empires. The Greeks were easily gobbled up by the Romans, just as the North African tribes were swallowed up by the Arabs under Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Solve Audit Problems of the Government</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/fourth-branch-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/fourth-branch-government/</guid>
      <description>On August 11, 2021, the Philippine Commission on Audit (COA) revealed that ₱67 billion of funds were misused by the Department of Health (DOH). This led to allegations of corruption, as well as a Senate investigation on the procurement activities of the DOH.
In the end, the Senate found a small company which used its connections to close a deal worth billions of pesos. This is what agents and brokers do anyway*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Principal Orders of the Katipunan Simplified</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/principal-orders-kkk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/governance/principal-orders-kkk/</guid>
      <description>This is a simplified version of the Principal Orders of the KKK (Dakilang Kautusan)
 Why we should separate from Spain We have been impelled to separate from Spain by her abusive behavior, hard-heartedness, treachery and other degradations that no Mother should inflict upon any child, such as:
  The imposition of high taxes on us, on our bodies, our produce, or our property    The Spanish squeeze out our meager profit from our work so that we are kept weak and prevented from bettering ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
