<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Money on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Money on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Measure Of Values</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-1/</guid>
      <description>The first chief function of money is to express the comparative value of commodities as the universal measure of value.
Money becomes the measure of commodities because all commodities are products of human labour. Money therefore is the measure of labour time.The expression of the value of a commodity in gold — x commodity A = y money-commodity — is its money-form or price.
1 ton of iron = 2 ounces of gold expresses the value of iron to society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Medium Of Circulation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2/</guid>
      <description>A. The Metamorphosis of Commodities Chapter 2 showed that the exchange of commodities implies contradictory and mutually exclusive conditions.
The difference between commodities and money does not sweep away these inconsistencies. Instead it develops a modus vivendi, a form in which they can exist side by side.
This is how real contradictions are reconciled.
Exchange is a process that transfers commodities from hands in which they are non-use-values, to hands in which they become use-values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The currency of money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2b/</guid>
      <description>The change of C—M—C causes the circulation of the material products of labour. It needs a given value in the shape of a commodity to begin and end the process.
The movement of the commodity is therefore a circuit.
On the other hand, the form of this movement precludes a circuit from being made by the money. The result is not the return of the money, but its continued removal further and further away from its starting-point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coin and symbols of value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-2c/</guid>
      <description>Money takes the shape of coin because it is the circulating medium.
The weight of gold represented in imagination by the prices or money-names of commodities, must confront those commodities, within the circulation, in the shape of coins or pieces of gold of a given denomination.
Coining, like the establishment of a standard of prices, is the business of the State. The different national uniforms worn at home by gold and silver as coins, and doffed again in the market of the world, indicate the separation between the internal or national spheres of the circulation of commodities, and their universal sphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Functions of Money</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/marx/capital/chapter-3/section-3/</guid>
      <description>Money is the measure of value and the medium of circulation. Gold (or silver) is therefore money.
A. Hoarding Buying and selling leads to the continuous circulation of money.
But as soon as buying and selling stops, money stops circulating.
At one time, money must be attracted in order to act as circulating coin.
At another, circulating coin must be repelled in order to act again as more or less stagnant money.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
