<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The History of Astronomy Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The History of Astronomy Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Descartes&#39; System of Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/descartes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/descartes/</guid>
      <description>Descartes was the first who tried to ascertain precisely this invisible chain that Kepler said to link the planets to the sun.
He explained that the real inertness of matter was=
 not in an aversion to motion and not in a propensity to rest  The real inertness of matter was in a power=
 of continuing indifferently either at rest or in motion, and of resisting, with a certain force, whatever tried to change its state from the one to the other  All of space was full of aether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kepler&#39;s System of Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/kepler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/kepler/</guid>
      <description>While, in Italy, the unfortunate Galileo was adding so many probabilities to the system of Copernicus, there was another philosopher employing himself in Germany, to ascertain, correct, and improve it=
Kepler, in Germany, had great genius but none of the taste or order and method of Galileo. Like other Germans, he had the most laborious industry together with an excessive passion for discovering proportions and resemblances between the different parts of nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sir Isaac Netwon</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/newton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/newton/</guid>
      <description>Keplers&amp;rsquo; laws were cemented by the observations of Cassini. But there were still constant irregularities in the motions of heavenly bodies.
Sir Isaac Newton first attempted to give a physical account of the motions of the Planets to solve such irregularities.
The physical connection, by which
Descartes tried to bind the movements of the Planets through the laws of impulse. These flow from the inertness of matter and are the easiest for the mind to undertand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tycho Brahe&#39; System of Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/brahe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/smith/astronomy/brahe/</guid>
      <description>Tycho Brahe introduced a new hypothesis that connected the irregularities in the motions of the Planets.
He completed his Treatise of Revolutions but was afraid of what people might think so that he kept it in his closet for 30 years.
Finally in old age, he allowed it to be published but died as soon as it was printed. It was almost immediately and universally disapproved of, by the learned as well as by the ignorant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
