<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solutions of Medical Superphysics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/solutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solutions of Medical Superphysics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/solutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Covid Star and the Flu Star</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/solutions/covid-flu-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/solutions/covid-flu-star/</guid>
      <description>Note  The influence of stars on behavior is one of the links between Material Superphysics and Medical Superphysics   Have you ever wondered why Covid and influenza are prevalent in Europe but not in Africa?
Life (and Viruses) Come from Stars According to science, all the matter in the universe came from stars via supernovae explosions. We extend this to add that viruses and simple bacteria, as life, also are included in such explosions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Stop COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/solutions/how-to-stop-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/solutions/how-to-stop-covid/</guid>
      <description>*This post emphasizes workarounds like Chinese medicine, Ayurveda, Ivermectin, etc because it was written when vaccines were unavailable. Vaccination is the best workaround as it &amp;lsquo;schools&amp;rsquo; the immune system on how to deal with viruses and since the policy of Medical and Social Superphysics is &amp;lsquo;prevention is better and cheaper than cure&amp;rsquo;.
 The Corona virus disease began in January in Wuhan, China just before the Lunar New Year. At that time, it bore all the signs of SARS and so the world was not so alarmed, as China and Hongkong already had experience with such an epidemic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
