<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Principles of Medical Superphysics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Principles of Medical Superphysics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Viruses are in-between Life and Ideas</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/principles/viruses-are-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/principles/viruses-are-ideas/</guid>
      <description>Viruses are not living organisms, but are merely bad idea-waves, manifesting as RNA-particles or code, which infect the code or DNA of actual living organisms. They expand exponentially, just like rumors and fashion trends, as long as there are many minds that are susceptible to fake news, rumors, and fashion. Fake news easily infects minds that have low resistance to information and are far from the truth, just as viruses easily infect those that put anything into their bodies, and are far from their natural state of health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Medical Paradigms</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/principles/5-paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/medical/physical/principles/5-paradigms/</guid>
      <description>Superphysics follows the five-layer model of the universe as described by the ancient Greeks, Hindus, and Chinese
   Superphysics Physics Greeks (Timaeus) Hindus Chinese     Aethereal Higgs Aether Akasha 水 still water   Spatial Gravitation Wind Vayu 木 moving wood   Radiant Electromagnetism Fire Tejas 火 radiant fire   Radioactive Weak Water Jala 土 transforming earth   Material Strong Earth Pritvi 金 solid metal    The 5 Medical Paradigms We apply these layers into Medical Superphysics by assigning a medical tradition to each:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
