<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What if EDSA never happened?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/edsa-never/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/edsa-never/</guid>
      <description>Marcos apologists say that the Philippines would have been better if EDSA never happened. On the other hand, Liberals or the dilawan would say that the country would&amp;rsquo;ve become worse.
So let&amp;rsquo;s use a thought-experiment using the historical events from 1986 to 2016, together with our social cycles model, to project* what would&amp;rsquo;ve happened without EDSA.
 *This assumes that US policy has a maximum patience of 20 years, just as it gave up on Afghanistan after 20 years, and on Cuba, South Vietnam and Iran in a shorter time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems in the Philippines that were Less Intense in Maharlika</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/problems-philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/problems-philippines/</guid>
      <description>The entry of the Arabs, Spanish, and Americans into the Maharlika confederation solved some of their problems but also created new ones:
  Corruption   The Spanish conquistadors were naturally corrupt, as seen in the devastation they caused to the Inca and Maya. The only reason why Maharlika was not as devastated was because the natives were maginoo and surrendered after they were defeated. The Inca and Maya, on the other hand, fought until they were nearly wiped out by war and disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Years of the Marcos Era</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/golden-years-marcos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/golden-years-marcos/</guid>
      <description>A major topic of political debate in the Philippines that often crops up every election period is whether there were Golden Years during the Marcos era.
 Liberals, left-wingers, and members of the mainstream religion say that there were no Golden Years because Marcos was a corrupt tyrant who impoverished the nation Conservatives, right-wingers, and traditional politicians would say that there were Golden Years under Marcos and that the country could have prospered if Marcos had continued his rule  To resolve this debate in a logical, data-driven way, we shall analyze the Marcos era and the causes and effects of his policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Meanings of Maharlika</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/meanings-maharlika/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/meanings-maharlika/</guid>
      <description>Maharlika was the name of the pre-colonial confederation based in the city of Manila.
 Maha means great, such as Maharashtra and Mahabharata. It adds r when it is conjugated Lika either means:  creation from Tagalog &amp;ldquo;likha&amp;rdquo; which in Sanskrit means to draw or paint cup in Sanskrit, made up of la (cup) ika (small, feminine)*     *Pottery was among the first industries of mankind. Among the creation myths of the country is the supreme god Bathala creating Maharlikans from heated clay which ended up &amp;ldquo;just right&amp;rdquo;, not being too dark like the Negritos nor too light as the East Asians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biag ni Lam-ang</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/biag-ni-lam-ang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/biag-ni-lam-ang/</guid>
      <description>A couple named Don Juan and Namongan lived in a faraway barrio of Nalbuan. One day, Don Juan left his pregnant wife and went to the mountain to punish a group of Igorots.
While he was in the mountain, Namongan gave birth to a baby boy. The baby was different from other babies because upon birth he could already speak. He wanted his name to be Lam-ang. And he was the one who chosed his godfather when he was baptized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did Colonialism Take Root?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/colonialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/colonialism/</guid>
      <description>In the previous article, we explained that Lapu Lapu, the first national hero of the Philippines, fought against the Spanish. If colonialism were so bad, why did&amp;rsquo;t the rest of the natives surrender to the colonizers who only numbered a few hundred?
1. a. Advanced tech The colonizers came with advanced technologies and useful goods that were coveted by the natives. For example, Pigafetta writes that the Spanish explorers to the Philippines exchanged their tools for much-needed food:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplified Pigafetta 1519-1521</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/simplified-pigafetta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/simplified-pigafetta/</guid>
      <description>This simplifies Pigafetta&amp;rsquo;s account of 1521 by subsituting pronouns with actual names to prevent confusion
 We left Spain on Monday morning 1519 with 237 men.
Samar (under Sulu?) At dawn on Saturday, March 16 1521, we came upon Samar island 300 leagues from Ladroni [The Marianas].
 The next day, Magellan had two tents set up on the shore for the sick, and had a sow killed for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was Lapu-Lapu a Tausug?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/was-lapu-lapu-tausug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/was-lapu-lapu-tausug/</guid>
      <description>The only reliable records that exist of Lapu Lapu is from Pigafetta:
Near that island of Cebu was an island called Mactan, which formed the port where we were anchored. The name of its village was Mactan, and its chiefs were Zula and Cilapulapu. That city which we burned was in that island and was called Bulaia.
Pigafetta  Pigafetta did mention that the Sulu people (Tausugs) did venture out to the area around Cebu and Leyte.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why America should not have colonized the Philippines</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/american-philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/maharlika/history/american-philippines/</guid>
      <description>The Atlantic wrote an article about General Pershing in the Philippines as part of the American pacification campaign.
The American system works for civilized humans that have transplanted themselves into uninhabited, uncivilized land, such as North America. It would be the best system for Australia, Alaska, Antarctica, Greenland, and Mars (being done by the American named Elon Musk).
The problem is that the Philippines already had a civilization prior to the Spanish and American period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
