<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Principles of Economic Superphysics on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Principles of Economic Superphysics on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Four Laws of Value and Four Kinds of Prices</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/four-laws-of-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/four-laws-of-value/</guid>
      <description>I shall explain [exchangable value] as fully as I can. I earnestly hopefor the reader&#39;s patience to examine something tedious, and his attention to understand what may still be obscure after the fullest explication.
Book 1, Chapter 3 of The Wealth of Nations Simplified  Pantrynomics falls under Social Superphysics which is a paradigm that sees reality as waves manifesting as particles . This is different from science which prefers particles* over waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Law of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/first-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/first-law/</guid>
      <description>Our First Law of Value is derived from the Third Law of Thermodynamics which says that absolute zero temperature is impossible to reach or maintain*. This translates to pantrynomics as every thing in the universe having value, otherwise it would not exist.
 *In Medical Superphysics, this manifests as everything being able to affect a person&amp;rsquo;s health in varying degrees. In Supersociology, this manifests as everyone having a value to society</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Law of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/second-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/second-law/</guid>
      <description>The First Law of Value introduced Exchangeable Value which is seen as Nominal Price to the Buyer. The Second Law of Value introduces Real Price which is the Exchangeable Value to the Seller.
 Real value is the value of the effort, trouble, hardship, and sentimentalism that is put into the Item by its owner or seller. This leads to the Effort theory of value that we derived from Adam Smith, which is opposite of the Labor theory of value of Karl Marx Nominal value is the value of the Item to its buyer/s who may or may not have idea of its real value to its owner  The Second Law of Value states that value goes from areas with high value to areas with low value in order to spread out the value and remove the lack in society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Third Law of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/third-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/third-law/</guid>
      <description>In order to address all the demand in society, supply has to be exchanged through a medium.
This creates the Third Law of Value which states that value is transferred through fair exchange whether it be through money, barter, points, promises, etc. This mirrors the First Law of Thermodynamics, known as the law of conservation of energy*. That law states that energy cannot be destroyed. Instead, it merely changes forms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fourth Law of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/fourth-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/fourth-law/</guid>
      <description>The market price is the nominal price that is applied on all customers for some time, from the customer&amp;rsquo;s perspective.
The Natural Price The natural price is the lowest common real price from all sellers over time, from the seller&amp;rsquo;s perspective.
This assumes that:
 the three prior laws were observed there is a sense of community instead of excessive ego that leads to profit maximization  The natural price is established by the Fourth Law of Value which says that there must be balance in any economy, whether it be a family, company, or nation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dharma as the Natural Organizing Principle</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/dharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/dharma/</guid>
      <description>Dharma in Hinduism and Buddhism is the inherent nature of things, as designed by its maker.
A baker who bakes a cake designs it as a cake and expects it to be a cake in the end, even if it starts as flour.
 If it turns out to be a pie or a large biscuit, then it does not match its design or plan. In this case, it is called a bad or awful cake and is &amp;lsquo;adharmic&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Invisible Hand of Dharma or the Tao</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/invisible-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/invisible-hand/</guid>
      <description>The invisible hand concept by Adam Smith is one of the most important ideas in our proposed economic science, making up the Second Law of Value which then leads to the effort theory of value which replaces the arbitrary marginal pricing of Neoclassical Economics.
  We start with a blank slate and separate the original definition from Smith from the shallow one from Paul Samuelson:
Smith proclaimed the principle of the ‘invisible hand’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Demand Capital Trade Industry Tool</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/dcti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/dcti/</guid>
      <description>According to Adam Smith, a crisis begins when a country&amp;rsquo;s industry does not match its capital, just as when an inexperienced entrepreneur launches a business out of speculation:
 The 2008 Financial crisis was caused by securitization unnaturally increasing industry on paper The Asian Financial Crisis was caused by hot money unnaturally increasing industry in Asia. This led to non-performing loans Black Wednesday in 1992 was caused by John Major overvaluing the pound to promote a rosy British industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eagle: Our Equation for Everything</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/eagle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/eagle/</guid>
      <description>A previous post explained how the error in Einstien&amp;rsquo;s E = mc^2 led to the universal equation of Superphysics.
By fixing Einstein&amp;rsquo;s error, the speed of light no longer becomes a constant. Without this constant, the principles of motion no longer gets a sequential or linear speed limit. They can now extend onto the metaphysical dimension where motion manifests as the movement of minds and feelings which are never constant nor strictly linear by nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2 Kinds of Arbitrage: Primary and Secondary</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/arbitrage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/arbitrage/</guid>
      <description>The social end result of the journey from nominal to real to natural value is therefore market value.
   Step Value Example Incentive     1 Nominal Woman wants a cake    2 Real Man skilled in cakes bakes a cake Primary Arbitrage   3 Market Man sells the cake to the woman and others Secondary Arbitrage   4 Natural Support, Competition, or Regulations sustain cake-making     From Primary Arbitrage to Secondary Arbitrage In the past, this was done through barter, giving more power to real value, the primary producers, and primary arbitrage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Consumption Motive?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/consumption-motive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/consumption-motive/</guid>
      <description>The Consumer is King The consumption or demand motive is one of the most important maxims of Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s economic system, aside from the Effort Theory of Value . This maxim states that all economic activity is rooted in the people or the demanders in society and not in the producers or suppliers.
This is easily seen in the concept of the human family which is the smallest and most common type of society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 4 Industries for Goods</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/four-industries-for-goods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/four-industries-for-goods/</guid>
      <description>In Book 2, Chapter 5 of the Wealth of Nations, Adam Smith explained the four industries for goods, as the four employments of capitals:
1. Extractive This includes agricultural, mining, and fishing.
2. Processing This includes manufacturing
3. Wholesale This includes warehousing and logistics. Ecommerce allows consumers to buy good directly from the warehouse or supplier.
4. Retail This includes packaging and buying at the point of sale
According to Adam Smith, extractive and processing are the better foundations of wealth than foreign trade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interest Rates and the GR Model</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/interest/</guid>
      <description>The previous post explained that quantitative easing failed because of 2 mistakes of the banking system. Those mistakes are caused by the profit maximization doctrine of Neoclassical economics.
Here, we explain that such a doctrine also explains why interest rates are currently important, when they were not so important in Classical Economics. This is proven in the reasoning of John Maynard Keynes, one of the pillars of modern economics:
 Life is determined by resources Resources are determined by work and employment Employment is determined by investment  Investment is determined by the interest rate    Interest rate is determined by liquidity preference   Liquidity preference is determined by transactional motive and speculative motive These motives are determined by expectation Government policy on interest and public spending can affect this expectation and make people spend money in order to make an economy rise from the crash  To support this logic, he created the marginal efficiency of capital curve which is the ratio between an investment&amp;rsquo;s cost and its future revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Modes of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/5-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/5-modes/</guid>
      <description>Pantrynomics uses the 4 Laws of Value to explain the dynamics of the flow of value in society. This is quantified through the DCTI tool which has 4 aspects:
 Demand (Law 1) Capital (Law 2) Trade (Law 3) Industry (Law 4)  Here, we explain the 5 modes of how the value takes shape as it flows as, or between, or among DCTI.
These modes match the 5 layers of reality:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 6 Types of Effort in Pantrynomics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/6-efforts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/6-efforts/</guid>
      <description>Useful work or effort is one of the foundations of Pantrynomics and is based entirely on Adam Smith’s Effort Theory of Value . This is totally different from Economics and Mercantilism which uses money as the basis through marginal pricing theory.
Since effort is very important, its definition becomes very important. In our theory, we have defined human effort, whether physical or mental, as ultimately rooted in psychological or metaphysical toil and trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 5 Factors that Affect Wages and Profits</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/five-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/five-factors/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for a career that gives a high salary or deciding what kind of business to establish? Adam Smith enumerated five factors that affect wages and profits:
 The agreeableness or disagreeableness of the employments  A job&amp;rsquo;s difficulty, cleanliness, and/or honorableness can lead to different wage and profit levels
The difficulty and cost of learning them  A job that requires a high degree of techincal skill will lead to higher wages than one that is simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining Rent, Wages, Profits, and Donations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/rent-wages-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/rent-wages-profit/</guid>
      <description>An important feature of Smith&amp;rsquo;s Political Economy (and the science of Pantrynomics which we created from it) is the classification ofall revenue into either rent, wages, and profit.
Such classification is not so important to Economics which focuses on the quantity or dollar value of revenue instead of its quality. This classification is difficult nowadays when other kinds of revenue have been introduced, such as interest income, different kinds of taxes, royalties, revenue from membership fees, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Economic Karma?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/economic-karma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/economic-karma/</guid>
      <description>The previous post pointed out that Smith was one of the few Western intellectuals to hint at the concept of dharma, or the natural and sustainable activities of humans, and apply it both for moral and economic purporses.
Instead of the word dharma, however, he named his concept the invisible hand. This had economic applications in The Wealth of Nations and moral applications in The Theory of Moral Sentiments.
Weaponizing the Invisible Hand The main difference between Smith&amp;rsquo;s invisible hand and Eastern dharma is that the former has moral, spiritual, and practical uses, while the latter emphasizes only its moral and spiritual use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effort Theory of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/effort-theory-of-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/effort-theory-of-value/</guid>
      <description>Summary: The effort theory of value is the foundation of Pantrynomics. It is derived entirely from Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s wheat-based valuation in the Wealth of Nations Book 1 Chapter 5. Instead of pegging value to metal coins, it pegs it to the abstract difficulty, stress, or hardship of a task to produce a product or service. This is then relativistically pegged to food through a points-ledger which the Physiocrats referred to as &amp;ldquo;The Economic Table&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Development From Zero via Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/development/</guid>
      <description>Update: April 2021  This post was made in 2015 because the model predicted a huge crisis starting in 2019 that could eventually collapse some societies.   The main advantage of Pantrynomics over Economics is that it is based on the dynamics of the human mind as explained by David Hume which was later applied by Adam Smith into his Theory of Moral Sentiments and The Wealth of Nations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tao as One&#39;s Life Purpose</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/tao-life-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/tao-life-purpose/</guid>
      <description>The core flaw of Economics, which is also the source of the unsustainability of &amp;ldquo;economic&amp;rdquo; systems, is that it focuses on utility or pleasure from external objects as their ultimate goals.
According to Adam Smith, this is wrong because utility is merely the effect of existence and is part of the deception of Nature (which in Eastern Philosophy is called Maya).
  It is this deception which rouses and keeps in continual motion the industry of mankind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith&#39;s 4 Taxation Maxims</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/taxation-maxims/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/principles/taxation-maxims/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith gave 4 maxims on taxation in The Wealth of Nations that have been largely forgotten today. Taxes should be fair, non-arbitrary, cost-effective and convenient.
Maxim 1 People should contribute towards supporting their government in proportion to their respective abilities
The rich or those who have the ability topay more should pay more than those who are less able to. Smith&amp;rsquo;s pro-poor taxation policies are found in Book 5, Chapter 2, and are as clear as day:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
