<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fallacies of Unenlightened Philosophy on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fallacies of Unenlightened Philosophy on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Fallacy of &#39;Microvita Jumps&#39; by Time Travel</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/microvita/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/microvita/</guid>
      <description>In the paper &amp;ldquo;Space, Time, and Contigency&amp;rdquo;, Dr. Rudolph quotes Indian philosopher PR Sarkar:
there cannot be steady movement. There must be acceleration – either constant acceleration or accelerated acceleration, or retardation – either constant retardation or retarding retardation. Along with these are galloping jumps. And before and after these jumps, there are biological changes, historical changes, agricultural changes and human psychic changes.”  The authors ask: what causes those jumps?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Red Herring, Ad hominem, and Other Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/red-herring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/red-herring/</guid>
      <description>People sometimes use strange jargon like “red herring” or ‘Occam’s razor” when they try to disprove arguments that they don’t like. Such words then force the other side to do research on what those jargon mean. This can potentially waste a lot of time since there are a lot of fallacies.
These fallacies were merely created by academics for the sake of creating something, just as mathematicians create paradoxes, and theoretical physicists create useless theories because thinking is part of their job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Sophistry Got Established</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/sophistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/sophistry/</guid>
      <description>In course of creating the new economic science, I’ve always wondered how false beliefs of the Marginal Revolution were able to formalize themselves into a science called Economics.
Without a doubt, it was the spirit of monopoly which originally invented and propagated this doctrine. Those who first taught it were by no means such fools as those who believed it. In every country, it is always the people’s interest to buy whatever they want the cheapest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The A Priori Fallacy of Kant</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/kant-apriori-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/kant-apriori-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>Dialectics was the most important part of Socrates&amp;rsquo; philosophy, of which the Socratic dialogue is the only part that is understood by academics. Its most important parts are the metaphysical laws that he established, such as:
 the immortality of the soul and its reincarnation the pantheist God (Brahma) as the source of all souls the superiority of the metaphysical over the physical and so on  Nowadays, dialectics seems to be understood to be an exercise in logic, without any reference to metaphysical truths, God, or to finding solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who the Heck Created the Is-Ought Problem?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/is-ought-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/superphysics/fallacies/is-ought-problem/</guid>
      <description>While reviewing my simplification of David Hume’s Treatise of Human Nature Book 3, I came upon a strange wiki article called Hume’s Is-Ought Problem
 Hume calls for caution against such inferences in the absence of any explanation of how the ought-statements follow from the is-statements. But how exactly can an “ought” be derived from an “is”? The question, prompted by Hume’s small paragraph, has become one of the central questions of ethical theory, and Hume is usually assigned the position that such a derivation is impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
