<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fallacies of Shallow Economists on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fallacies of Shallow Economists on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Market Equilibrium Fallacy Part 1</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/equilibrium-fallacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/equilibrium-fallacy/</guid>
      <description>The biggest fallacy of Economics is Market Equilibrium which is taught in basic economics or &amp;lsquo;Econ101&amp;rsquo; everywhere as the supply and demand curve forming an &amp;lsquo;X&amp;rsquo; and meeting in a state called &amp;rsquo;exact equilibrium&amp;rsquo;. Smith exposed this as mercantile sophistry in the 18th century, then called the &amp;lsquo;balance of trade&amp;rsquo;. To prove that this idea of &amp;lsquo;balance&amp;rsquo; is the same in essence with the &amp;rsquo;equilibrium&amp;rsquo; of economics, let&amp;rsquo;s compare the philosophy behind both ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Market Equilibrium Fallacy Part 2</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/equilibrium-fallacy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/equilibrium-fallacy-2/</guid>
      <description>Supply and Demand Together We combine both curves to come up with a Supply and Demand model.
Samuelson&amp;rsquo;s Version Samuelson justifies the unnatural supply curve with buying and selling through an auctioneer scenario. This is the same sophistical technique used by Jevons and Marshall, in their attempt to justify equilibrium.
Which level will the price actually go? And how much will then be produced and consumed?.. Let us proceed what an auctioneer would do, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Different Notions of Interest Rates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/interest/</guid>
      <description>The failure of quantitative easing, both in the US under Obama and in Japan as Abenomics , is proof that the operations of banking cannot directly and immediately lead to economic growth, as explained by Adam Smith:
The judicious operations of banking can increase a country’s industry, not by augmenting the country’s capital, but by rendering most of that capital productive. The Simple Wealth of Nations Book 2, Chapter 2  This is opposite the notion of Keynes that interest rates, set by banks, are the key to growing an economy:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inelastic Supply Curve Sophistry</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/inelastic-supply-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/inelastic-supply-curve/</guid>
      <description>The inelastic supply curve is the child-idea of the sophistry called the Equilibrium Theory of Economics. It manifests as a vertical line that says* that an essential, but hard-to-produce product can command whatever price its supplier wants.
 *Samuelson refers to it as the inelastic supply curve, while Case and Fair, and Roger Miller refer to it as the inelastic demand curve
 If the amount supplied is perfectly fixed, as in perishable fish for sale at whatever price, we face the perfectly inelastic supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resource Based Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/resource-based-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/resource-based-economy/</guid>
      <description>Another flawed economic paradigm, aside from the Steady State Economy is the Resource Based Economy (RBE) by Jacque Fresco . It is implemented as The Venus Project which is a tech-urban master plan. This is a necessary consequence of Mr. Fresco being a designer by trade, as opposed to being a practicing scientist or civil engineer.
  Its most striking feature is that it aims to distribute goods and services without using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Circular Flow of Economics vs Pantrynomics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/circular-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/circular-flow/</guid>
      <description>To maximize profits, business-systems pool money together in order to create the equity that makes up the firms and corporations. Such organizations then create, buy, and sell real goods and services via secondary arbitrage*.
 *The difference between market prices
 In time, these become very good at accumulating capital and starving others of it, causing a recession or crisis. Notice how &amp;lsquo;businesses&amp;rsquo; is a huge entity in the Circular Flow of Economics below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Producer&#39;s &amp; Consumer&#39;s Surplus and Deadweight Loss</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/surplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/surplus/</guid>
      <description>According to Economics, a market dis-equilibrium creates three inefficiencies:
  Producer’s Surplus — defined as “the difference between how much of a good the producer is willing to supply versus how much he receives,” or the gain the producer receives  Consumer’s Surplus —defined as a situation when “the price that consumers pay for a product or service is less than the price they’re willing to pay,” or a bargain  Deadweight loss — defined as “a cost to society created by market inefficiency”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law of Supply and Demand Fallacy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/supply-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/supply-demand/</guid>
      <description>Update: April 2021  The actual supply prices of Covid vaccines are consistent with our assertions here that the supply curve cannot be naturally vertical, and is the final proof of the sophistry of the equilibrium theory of Economics   Adam Smith’s Supply and Demand Curves (below) are the foundation our proposed science called pantrynomics which is based on Classical Economics. It can be applied to any problem in economics in order to provide common sense answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricardo&#39;s Labor Theory of Value</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/ricardo-labor-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/ricardo-labor-theory/</guid>
      <description>In his Principles of Political Economy and Taxation, David Ricardo criticizes Adam Smith&amp;rsquo;s wheat-based valuation and replaces it with his own theory which is based on money-wages.
By looking at his work, we can see that he never understood the metaphysics behind Smith&amp;rsquo;s labor theory of value in the first place. We go through his reasoning below.
Adam Smith said that the value of all things was relative to the amount of labour bestowed on their production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profit Maximization is Absurd</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/profit-maximization-is-absurd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/profit-maximization-is-absurd/</guid>
      <description>A key fallacy that is inseparably part of Economics, along with equilibrium, is the idea of profit maximization.
The idea of maximization has its origins in Newton&amp;rsquo;s Calculus which in turn has its origins in Physics. Smith and Hume never mentioned maximization nor calculus anywhere in their writings on the political economy. In fact, The Wealth of Nations has no equations at all*!
 *Instead of equality, equilibrium, equations, or 1 + 1 = 2, Smith makes extensive use of ratios, proportions, balance, or 2 : 2, as prices are psychological and not physical in nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Say&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/simple-says-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/simple-says-law/</guid>
      <description>To prove the sophistry of capitalism, we must trace the roots of its core ideas. Among its core ideas is the production motive, or the sophistical belief that what is good for the producers or sellers, or those who live by profits, is good for the nation.
This is in contrast to the consumption motive espoused by Adam Smith.
The production motive is best seen in Say&amp;rsquo;s Law which says that production is the cause of demand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karl Marx vs Adam Smith</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/marx-smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/marx-smith/</guid>
      <description>I came upon a video explaining the Marxist view of use value and exchangeable value. It was easy to see the difference between the values of Marx and those of Smith.
     Idea Marx Smith     Use Value Usefulness of an object Usefulness of an object to a person   Exchangeable Value Purely relative, intrinsic value of an object&amp;quot;(value) expressed in terms of something common to (all commodities)&amp;quot; Capital 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Iron Law of Wages of David Ricardo</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/iron-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/iron-law/</guid>
      <description>Adam Smith said that the differences in wages are due to five factors (agreeableness, trust, constancy, risk, cost of learning) and 3 states (backward, stationary, advancing).
In contrast, David Ricardo simplistically said that wages are based on the supply and demand of workers and the cost of goods and services which wages are spent on . Because of this simplicity, Ricardo concluded that wages must fall ( Iron Law of Wages ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fallacy of the Steady State Economy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/steady-state-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/social/economics/fallacies/steady-state-economy/</guid>
      <description>The current increase in global warming and overpopulation is leading to more natural disasters on top of the depletion of resources.
This causes people to look for alternative resource systems that are more sustainable. This in turn puts more non-mainstream economic proposals, both good and bad, to the public view. In this post, we shall discuss a bad proposal called the Steady State Economy.
What is the Steady State Economy? Its founder Herman Daly defines it as:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
