<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Water Conservation on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Water Conservation on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Afforestation Program</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/afforestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/afforestation/</guid>
      <description>A few hundred years ago, many of the desert regions in the world were full of trees and wildlife.
Due to tree felling by local people and commercial interests, and the depletion of the subterranean water, the deserts have spread.
Many problems occur with the disappearance of trees.
 The carbon dioxide content in the air rises as there are fewer plants to absorb the carbon dioxide which is constantly being expired into the atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Lakes for Afforestation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/lakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/lakes/</guid>
      <description>For afforestation programmes to be successful, surface water must be conserved.
This can best be accomplished by:
 increasing the water capacity of existing storage systems building new systems.  The cheapest and easiest method of creating new water storage systems is to construct small-scale ponds and lakes.
Location of artificial ponds and lakes In the rainy season observe where the surface water flows – its currents and directions – and where the rivulets created from the rain water converge together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendars for Agriculture</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/calendars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/calendars/</guid>
      <description>The Solar Calendar The Bengali months:
 are solar months take into account the seasons.  The Hindi months are lunar months so cultivation cannot be done according to the Hindi calendar.
The Gregorian calendar is also a solar calendar, but it is not adjusted. For example, when the arc is starting, it is April 14, which is the middle of the month. But if it were properly adjusted, it would be in the beginning of the month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lakeside Plantations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/lakeside/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/lakeside/</guid>
      <description>5 types of plants should be used around lakes: slope plants, boundary plants, wire plants, aquatic plants and surface plants.
A. Slope plants  pineapple asparagus aloe vera brinjal chilli.  These plants:
 conserve water and check soil erosion provide an income for local people.  Slope plants should always be planted in symmetrical horizontal lines and never in vertical lines, as this allows the water to flow away and encourages soil erosion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rivers</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/rivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/rivers/</guid>
      <description>Rivers There are 3 types of rivers:
 ice fed rain fed subterranean fed.  Ice-fed rivers cause flooding when there is an increase in the temperature, whereas rain fed and subterranean fed rivers only cause seasonal flooding when there is heavy rain. However, an increase in the temperature can dry them up.
Are the rivers in Ráŕh perennial or seasonal?
Are they ice fed or rain fed, or do they get water from subterranean sources due to the high level of the artesian water?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riverside Plantations</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/riverside/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/riverside/</guid>
      <description>Riverside plantations are important for:
 preventing floods conserving water regulating the flow of water in rivers keeping soil moist and fertile.  Some examples of plants which are useful riverside trees include banyan, date palm, neem or margosa, tamarind, simul, imli and fruit trees. If horticulture is developed along the banks of rivers, the rivers will never dry up.
Most trees with tap root systems do not alleviate riverside erosion, but eucalyptus is an exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Methods of Irrigation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/irrigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/irrigation/</guid>
      <description>The Defects of Well Irrigation Deep tube wells ae not the solution to the water crisis.
Well irrigation causes the level of the water-table to drop. The continuous use of well irrigation dries up the subterranean flow of water.
Initially, the effects of continuous well irrigation may not be easy to perceive, but eventually a fertile region will be transformed into a desert.
In fact, if the subterranean water level stays at above 20-25 feet, the surface vegetation will not be affected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Causes of Drought</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/droughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/droughts/</guid>
      <description>Why do droughts occur?
There are 3 main causes of droughts:
 The wanton destruction of plants or indiscriminate deforestation The low pressure systems over oceans and big seas The sudden changes in the angular movement of the sun and other celestial bodies like comets, nebulae and galaxies.  Deforestation prevents the plants from nourishing the earth.
The fibrous roots of plants absorb and hold considerable amounts of water which is slowly released into the soil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Conservation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/sarkar/farming/section-3/water/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of this earth, there was absolute silence – there were no living beings or even plants.
This continued for hundreds of millions of years, until the earth was properly formed.
Then a phase came when rain and storms started, and by a gradual process, life emerged.
Thanks to the rain, carbon atoms got infused with vital energy (práńa shakti). Carbon atoms along with protoplasmic clash and cohesion formed this vital energy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
