<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Method of Reasoning and seeking Truth in the Sciences on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Method of Reasoning and seeking Truth in the Sciences on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 4 Precepts</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-2b/</guid>
      <description>Among the branches of philosophy, I had, at an earlier period, given some attention to
I was intersted in:
 logic and mathematics geometry algebra  logic, its syllogisms and the majority of its other precepts are of avail – rather in the communication of what we already know, or even as the art of Lully, in speaking without judgment of things of which we are ignorant, than in the investigation of the unknown;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cartesian Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-5/</guid>
      <description>The whole whole chain of truths which I discovered would have gotten me into trouble.
I have ever remained firm in my original resolution to suppose no other principle than that of which I have recently availed myself in demonstrating the existence of God and of the soul, and to accept as true nothing that did not appear to me more clear and certain than the demonstrations of the geometers had formerly appeared;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Think Therefore I Am</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-4/</guid>
      <description>I am in doubt as to the propriety of making my first meditations in the place above mentioned matter of discourse; for these are so metaphysical, and so uncommon, as not, perhaps, to be acceptable to every one.
The foundations that I have laid are secure.
Our opinions are highly uncertain. We should reject as absolutely false all opinions which could be doubted. This is so that we can have solid truths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Good sense is the most equally distributed among men. Everyone thinks himself having it. Those who are the most difficult to satisfy in everything else, do not usually desire a larger measure of good sense than they already possess.
Their conviction shows that:
 the power of judging is by nature equal in all men the diversity of our opinions, consequently, does not arise from some being endowed with a larger share of reason than others, but solely from this, that we conduct our thoughts along different ways, and do not fix our attention on the same objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 6</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Three years have now elapsed since I finished the treatise on all these matters.
I was about to publish it when I learned that persons that I respect had condemned another physics work recently published. That work had nothing prejudicial either to religion or to the state.
This led me to fear that my own doctrines might be interpreted to be against the truth, despite my great care in not offending anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Founders</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-2/</guid>
      <description>I went to Germany, attracted by its wars.
I was returning to the army from the coronation of the emperor. Winter stopped me in an uninteresting place where I could be with my thoughts.  made up of many separate parts made by different hands  Those done by a single master is more perfect.
Thus, the buildings planned and built by a single architect are generally more elegant and commodious than those that have been renovated from the original.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Maxims</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-3/</guid>
      <description>I created a provisory code of morals with a few maxims while we rebuild the philosophical house that we live in.
Maxim 1: Obey the laws and customs of my country France I adhere firmly to the faith I had been educated from my childhood. For as I had from that time begun to hold my own opinions for nought because I wished to subject them all to examination, I was convinced that I could not do better than follow in the meantime the opinions of the most judicious;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Human Anatomy</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-5b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/descartes/method/part-5b/</guid>
      <description>From the description of inanimate bodies and plants, I passed to animals, particularly to man.
God formed the body of man wholly like to one of ours, as well in the external shape of the members as in the internal conformation of the organs, of the same matter with that I had described, and at first placed in it no rational soul, nor any other principle, in room of the vegetative or sensitive soul, beyond kindling in the heart one of those fires without light, such as I had already described, and which I thought was not different from the heat in hay that has been heaped together before it is dry, or that which causes fermentation in new wines before they are run clear of the fruit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
