<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relativity by Einstein Simplified on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Relativity by Einstein Simplified on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Physical Meaning Of Geometrical Propositions</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-01/</guid>
      <description>I adhered scrupulously to the precept of that brilliant theoretical physicist, L. Boltzmann.
We were taught that Euclid’s geometry is true. But are we really sure?
Geometry has concepts like “plane,” “point,” and “straight line.” These lead to axioms which we are inclined to accept as “true.”
From this, all the remaining propositions are shown to follow from those axioms, i.e. they are proven.
A proposition is then correct(“true”) when it has been derived in the recognised manner from the axioms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space And Time In Classical Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-03/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of mechanics is to describe how bodies change their position in space with time.
What does “position” and “space” mean?
I stand at the window of a railway carriage which is travelling uniformly.
 I drop a stone on the embankment, without throwing it. Disregarding air resistance, I see the stone descend in a straight line. A pedestrian on the footpath sees this and notices that the stone falls to earth in a parabolic curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relativity Of Simultaneity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-09/</guid>
      <description>A very long train travels with the constant velocity v.
People in this train will use the train as a rigid viewpoint for all events relative to the train.
Lightning strikes A and B simultaneously from the viewpoint of the embankment. Is it also simultaneous from the viewpoint of the train?
It is not.
The light arriving at A and B meet each other at the mid-point M of the embankment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relativity Of The Idea Of Distance</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-10/</guid>
      <description>What is the distance between the points A and B in the train in Section 9?
We need a body of reference to measure it.
 If our viewpoint is the train, then a man in the train measures the distance by using his measuring-rod to mark the distance on the floor as many times as is needed to take him from A to B. If our viewpoint is the embankment, then we measure A&#39; and B&#39; at time t using the definition of time at Section 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Results Of The Theory=  E = mc2</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-15/</guid>
      <description>Special Relativity grew out of electrodynamics and optics. It has considerably simplified the theoretical structure*. It has=
 simplified the derivation of laws considerably reduced the number of independent hypotheses which form the basis of theory  This is much more important     *Superphysics Note= We argue that relativity, through Einstein&amp;rsquo;s field equations, actually made Physics unecessarily complicated
 Special Relativity has rendered the Maxwell-Lorentz theory so plausible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minkowski’s Four — Dimensional Space (“world”)</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/appendix-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/appendix-2/</guid>
      <description>We can characterise the Lorentz transformation still more simply if we introduce the imaginary −1 ⋅ ct in place of t, as time-variable. If, in accordance with this, we insert
x 1 = x x 2 = y x 3 = z x 4 = − 1 ⋅ ct ,
and similarly for the accented system K&amp;rsquo;, then the condition which is identically satisfied by the transformation can be expressed thus=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Inferences From General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-22/</guid>
      <description>Section 20 showed that General Relativity (GR) lets us derive properties of the gravitational field in a purely theoretical way*.
 *Superphysics Note= Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s only theoretical just as Genesis is theoretical and not real!
 Let us suppose that we know the space-time “course” for any path in Galileian space relative to a non-moving viewpont. Through theoretical calculation, we can find how this path appears, as seen from a moving viewpoint K&#39; which is moving relatively to K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addition Of Velocities Employed In Classical Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-06/</guid>
      <description>The train is travelling with a constant velocity v. A man walks from the back of the train movig forward in the direction of travel with a velocity w.
How quickly, or with what velocity W, does the man advance relative to the embankment?
If the man were to stand still for a second, he would advance relative to the embankment through a distance v equal numerically to the train&amp;rsquo;s velocity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appendix 1 Simple Derivation Of The Lorentz Transformation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/appendix-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/appendix-1/</guid>
      <description>FOR the relative orientation of the coordinate systems K and K&#39; below, the x-axes of both systems permanently coincide.
We can divide the problem into parts by considering first only events which are localised on the x-axis. Any such event is represented=
 with respect to the non-movingK by the abscissa x and the time t with respect to the moving K&#39; by the abscissa x&#39; and the time t&#39;.  Find x&#39; and t&#39; when x and t are given.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behaviour Of Clocks And Measuring-rods On A Rotating Body Of Reference</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-23/</guid>
      <description>I have purposely refrained from speaking about the physical interpretation of space- and time-data in General Relativity (GR) because it would be very complicated to explain.
Assuming a space-time domain with no gravitational field relative to a reference-body K whose state of motion has been suitably chosen.
 K is then a Galileian reference-body as regards the domain considered The results of Special Relativity (SR) hold relative to K  The same domain referred to a 2nd body of reference K&#39;, which is rotating uniformly with respect to K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosmological Difficulties Of Newton’s Theory</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-30/</guid>
      <description>Einstein (Universe has no center) vs Newton (Universe has a center) The astronomer Seeliger explained a problem in classical celestial mechanics aside from the problem explained in Section 21.
How should we see the universe as a whole?
Regarding space and time, the universe is infinite. There are stars everywhere. So the density of matter, although very variable in detail, is nevertheless the same on the average everywhere.
Everywhere there is an attenuated swarm of stars of approximately the same kind and density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euclidean And Non–euclidean Continuum</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-24/</guid>
      <description>THE surface of a marble table is spread out in front of me.
I can get from any one point on this table to any other point by passing continuously from one point to a “neighbouring” one. I then repeat this process many times by going from point to point without executing “jumps.”
We express this property of the surface by describing the latter as a continuum.
Many tiny rods have been made, their lengths being small compared with the dimensions of the marble slab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exact Formulation Of General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-28/</guid>
      <description>Our provisional formulation was=
This now cannot be maintained because it required rigid reference-bodies as followed in Special Relativity (SR).
In Section 27, we replaced it with Gauss co-ordinates. This creates a new statement for General Relativity (GR)=
According to SR, the equations for the general laws of nature pass over into equations of the same form when we replace the space-time variables x, y, z, t, of a Galileian reference-body K by the space-time variables x&#39;, y&#39;, z&#39;, t&#39;, of a new reference-body K&#39; using the Lorentz transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience of Special Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-16/</guid>
      <description>Is special relativity supported by experience?
This question is not easily answered as explained by Fizeau&amp;rsquo;s experiment.
Special Relativity came from the Maxwell-Lorentz theory of electromagnetic phenomena. Thus, everything that supports the electromagnetic theory also supports Special Relativity.
Special Relativity Proven By Starlight Special Relativity can predict the effects from the light from the fixed stars because the Earth moves relatively to those stars.
One effect is=
 the apparent position of those stars resulting from the Earth&amp;rsquo;s motion around the sun (aberration), and the influence of the radial components of the relative motions of the fixed stars with respect to the earth on the colour of their starlight  This manifests itself in a slight displacement of the spectral lines of the light from a fixed star, compared with the position of the same spectral lines when they are produced by a terrestrial source of light (Doppler principle).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Co–ordinates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-25/</guid>
      <description>The solution of Gauss is as follows. We draw arbitrary u-curves u = 1 , u = 2 and u = 3 on the surface of the marble slab. Between u = 1 and u = 2 are an infinitely large number of curves corresponding to real numbers between 1 and 2. These u-curves must not intersect each other.Thus, a definite value of u belongs to every point on the surface of the marble slab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Relativity Needs the Equality of Inertial and Gravitational Mass</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-20/</guid>
      <description>Superphysics Note= Einstein invents General Relativity by creating the idea of inertial mass which is really Newton&amp;rsquo;s third law. This is why he has to say that everything is moving &amp;ndash; because his inertial gravity is not really gravity, but just action and reaction.
 Assume that, in outerspace, there is a huge glass box that serves as our reference-body. That box has a man inside it. He floats because there is no gravity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are The Foundations of Classical Mechanics And Special Relativity Unsatisfactory?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-21/</guid>
      <description>Newton&amp;rsquo;s First Law is only valid for non-moving Kwhich=
 have unique states of motion, and are in uniform translational motion relative to each other.  Relative to other reference-bodies K, the law is not valid.Both in classical mechanics and in special relativity, we differentiate between=
 viewpoints K [man outside the box] where the laws of nature can hold relatively [affected by c] viewpoints K [man inside the box] where those laws cannot hold relatively [insignificant to c]   But why are relativistic viewpoints more important* than non-relativistic viewpoints?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minkowski’s Four–dimensional Space</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-17/</guid>
      <description>Space is a 3D continuum wherein=
 an object exists in 3 co-ordinates x, y, z as Point 1 there are infinite points around Point 1  These are designated as x1, y1, z1, x2, y2, z2, x3, y3, z3, etc. These points create a “continuum”    Our universe is a 4D space-time continuum, as described by Minkowski. It has the additional coordinate of time-value t.
Every event has infinite “neighbouring” events (realised or imaginary).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relativity and the Addition Of Velocities In Classical Mechanics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-05/</guid>
      <description>Assume a railway carriage travelling uniformly, as a &amp;lsquo;uniform translation&amp;rsquo;:
 uniform: constant velocity and direction translation: although the carriage changes its position relative to the embankment yet it does not rotate  A raven is also flying uniformly in a straight line, as observed from the embankment. If we observe the flying raven from the moving railway carriage, the raven&amp;rsquo;s motion would be of different velocity and direction. But it would still be uniform and in a straight line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special And General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-18/</guid>
      <description>Special Relativity is the principle of the physical relativity of all uniform motion. Every motion must only be considered as a relative motion. In our earler train example=
 The train is in motion relative to the embankment. Our viewpoint in this case is the embankment The embankment is in motion relative to the carriage. Our viewpoint in this case is the train  For theoretical descriptions of motion, we do not care which viewpoint we take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apparent Incompatibility Of The Law Of Propagation Of Light with Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-07/</guid>
      <description>The simplest law in physics is the one that says how light travels in empty space in straight lines with a velocity of 300,000 km/sec.
This velocity is the same for all colours, because if this were not the case, the minimum of emission would not be observed simultaneously for different colours during the eclipse of a fixed star by its dark neighbour.
The Dutch astronomer De Sitter observed double stars and showed that=</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Behaviour Of Measuring–rods And Clocks In Motion</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-12/</guid>
      <description>I place a metre-rod in the x&amp;rsquo;-axis of moving K&#39; in a way that its beginning coincides with the point x&#39; = 0 while its end coincides with the point x&#39; = 1.
What is the length of the metre rod relative to the non-moving K?
This is answered by asking where the beginning and end of the rod lie with respect to non-moving K at a time t of non-moving K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Experiment Of Fizeau</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-13/</guid>
      <description>We can move clocks and measuring-rods only with velocities that are small compared with the velocity of light. Hence, we shall hardly be able to compare the results of the previous section directly with the reality.
But, on the other hand, these results must strike you as being very singular. This is why I draw another conclusion from the theory.
In Section 6, we derived the theorem of the addition of velocities in one direction in the form which also results from the hypotheses of classical mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Experimental Confirmation Of General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/appendix-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/appendix-3/</guid>
      <description>FROM a systematic theoretical point of view, we may imagine the process of evolution of an empirical science to be a continuous process of induction.
Theories are evolved, and are expressed in short compass as statements of a large number of individual observations in the form of empirical laws, from which the general laws can be ascertained by comparison.
Regarded in this way, the development of a science bears some resemblance to the compilation of a classified catalogue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Galileian System Of Co–ordinates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-04/</guid>
      <description>The law of inertia is fundamental to the mechanics of Galilei-Newton. It is stated as=
An isolated body continues in a state of rest or of uniform motion in a straight line.  This law says something author = - the motion of the bodies - the reference-bodies or systems of co-ordinates in mechanics The law of inertia applies to fixed stars. If the Earth is a system of non-moving coordinates, then every star revolves in huge orbits around the earth in one Earth-day [geocentric].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gravitational Field</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-19/</guid>
      <description>An action at a distance must have some intermediary medium.
A magnet that attracts a piece of iron does not do so in empty space, but through a magnetic field, as per Faraday.
 In its turn, this magnetic field operates on the piece of iron, so that the iron moves towards the magnet.  This idea is arbitrary. Nevertheless, it represents electromagnetic phenomena and is applied to the transmission of electromagnetic waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Heuristic Value Of The Theory Of Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-14/</guid>
      <description>Our experience shows that=
 the principle of relativity holds true, and the speed of light in a vacuum is a constant c  By uniting these two postulates, we obtained=
 the law of transformation for co-ordinates x, y, z and the time t of the events in nature  This led to the Lorentz transformation and not the Galilei transformation of classical mechanics. The constant speed of light played an important part in this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Idea Of Time In Physics</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-08/</guid>
      <description>Lightning has struck the rails on our railway embankment simultaneously at two places A and B far distant from each other.
 A meteorologist discovered that the lightning must always strike A and B simultaneously.  How do we test if the lightning really did strike the two places at the same time? What does &amp;ldquo;simultaneous&amp;rdquo; mean?
We test simultaniety by putting an observer in the middle M between A and B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lorentz Transformation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-11/</guid>
      <description>Sections 8-10 show that the apparent incompatibility of the law of propagation of light with the principle of relativity (Section 7) arises from two unjustifiable hypotheses from classical mechanics=
  The time-interval (time) between two events is independent of the body of reference
  The space-interval (distance) between two points of a rigid body is independent of the body of reference
  If we drop those two, then the dilemma of Section 7 disappears, because the addition of velocities (Section 6) becomes invalid*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Possibility of a “finite” Yet “unbounded” Universe</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-31/</guid>
      <description>What is the structure of the universe?
Non-Euclidean geometry says that outer space is not infinite (Riemann, Helmholtz). These questions were already answered fully by Helmholtz and Poincaré=
In a 2D space, flat beings with flat implements and flat rigid measuring-rods are free to move in a plane. For them, nothing exists outside of this plane. The constructions of plane Euclidean geometry can be done through the rods, e.g. the lattice construction, considered in Section 24.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Solution Of The Problem Of Gravitation On The Basis Of General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-29/</guid>
      <description>We began with a Galileian domain where there is no gravitational field relative to the Galileian reference-body K.
Special Relativity (SR) explains the behaviour of measuring-rods and clocks with reference to K and the behaviour of “isolated” material points.
 Isolated points move uniformly and in straight lines.  Gauss coordinates Now let us refer this domain to a random Gauss co-ordinate system or to a “mollusk” as reference-body K&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Space–time Continuum Of General Relativity Is Not A Euclidean Continuum</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-27/</guid>
      <description>But according to Section 22, General Relativity (GR) cannot retain this law because, to GR, the speed of light must always depend on the coordinates when a gravitational field is present.
Section 23 explained that the presence of a gravitational field invalidates the definition of the co-ordinates and the time of SR.
According to GR, the space-time continuum cannot be Euclidean like the marble slab (with a hot center and cool sides) as an example of a 2D continuum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Space–time Continuum Of Special Relativity as a Euclidean Continuum</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-26/</guid>
      <description>We can now use Gaussian coordinates to formulate more exactly the Minkowski spacetime in Section 17. According to Special Relativity (SR), Galileian coordinate systems are preferred for describing a 4D space-time continuum.
The 4 co-ordinates x, y, z, t determine an event or a point of the 4D continuum. For the transition from one Galileian system to another, which is moving uniformly with reference to the first, the equations of the Lorentz transformation are valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure Of Space According to General Relativity</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-32/</guid>
      <description>According General Relativity (GR), the geometrical properties of space are determined by matter.Thus, we can draw conclusions about the universe&amp;rsquo;s geometrical structure based on matter.
The velocities of the stars are small as compared with the speed of light. From this, we can conclude the nature of the universe.
The behaviour of measuring-rods and clocks is influenced by gravitational fields caused by the distribution of matter. This eliminates the need for the exact validity of Euclidean geometry in our universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The System Of Co–ordinates</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/einstein/relativity/section-02/</guid>
      <description>Standard Measuring Rod To measure the distance between two points on a rigid body, we need a measuring rod as Rod S as a standard measure.
Assuming there is Point A and B are on a rigid body. We can draw a line joining them starting from Point A. We can mark off the distance S time after* time until we reach B. The number of these operations required is the numerical measure of the distance AB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
