<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book 9 on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book 9 on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Actuality is prior to potentiality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-8/</guid>
      <description>Actuality is prior to potentiality.
Potentiality is that definite kind which is a principle of change in another thing or in the thing itself regarded as other. It is every principle of movement or rest.
Nature also is in the same genus as potency. It is a principle of movement-not, however, in something else but in the thing itself qua itself. To all such potency, then, actuality is prior both in formula and in substantiality; and in time it is prior in one sense, and in another not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being and non-being</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-10/</guid>
      <description>The terms &amp;lsquo;being&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;non-being&amp;rsquo; are used in three ways:
 With reference to the categories With reference to the potency or actuality of these or their non-potency or nonactuality In the sense of true and false.  This depends, on the side of the objects, on their being combined or separated, so that he who thinks the separated to be separated and the combined to be combined has the truth, while he whose thought is in a state contrary to that of the objects is in error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capability and Potentiality and Actuality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-3/</guid>
      <description>The Megaric school says that a thing &amp;lsquo;can&amp;rsquo; act only when it is acting. When it is not acting, it &amp;lsquo;cannot&amp;rsquo; act.
 For example, he who is not building cannot build. Only one who is building can build when he is building.  A man will not be a builder unless he is building.
If, then, it is impossible to have such arts if one has not at some time learnt and acquired them, and it is then impossible not to have them if one has not sometime lost them (either by forgetfulness or by some accident or by time; for it cannot be by the destruction of the object, for that lasts for ever), a man will not have the art when he has ceased to use it, and yet he may immediately build again;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-2/</guid>
      <description>Since some such originative sources are present in soulless things, and others in things possessed of soul, and in soul, and in the rational part of the soul, clearly some potencies will, be non-rational and some will be non-rational and some will be accompanied by a rational formula.
This is why all arts are potentialities. They are originative sources of change in another thing or in the artist himself considered as other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potentiality versus Actuality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Potentiality is related to movement. What is actuality?
The potential, that we not only ascribe potency to that whose nature it is to move something else, or to be moved by something else, either without qualification or in some particular way, but also use the word in another sense, which is the reason of the inquiry in the course of which we have discussed these previous senses also.
Actuality, then, is the existence of a thing not in the way which we express by &amp;lsquo;potentially&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rational and Nonrational Potentiality</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-4/</guid>
      <description>If what we have described is identical with the capable or convertible with it, evidently it cannot be true to say &amp;rsquo;this is capable of being but will not be&amp;rsquo;, which would imply that the things incapable of being would on this showing vanish.
E.g. a man-one who did not take account of that which is incapable of being-were to say that the diagonal of the square is capable of being measured but will not be measured, because a thing may well be capable of being or coming to be, and yet not be or be about to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Potentiality?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Being&amp;rsquo; is in one way divided into individual thing, quality, and quantity, and is in another way distinguished in respect of potency and complete reality, and of function.
But what is potency and complete reality?
Potentiality and actuality extend beyond the cases that involve a reference to motion. But when we have spoken of this first kind, we shall in our discussions of actuality&amp;rsquo; explain the other kinds of potency as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When does a thing exist potentially?</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/aristotle/metaphysics/book-9/part-7/</guid>
      <description>What is &amp;ldquo;actual&amp;rdquo;?
We must distinguish when a thing exists potentially and when it does not. For it is not at any and every time.
E.g. is earth potentially a man? No-but rather when it has already become seed, and perhaps not even then.
It is just as it is with being healed; not everything can be healed by the medical art or by luck, but there is a certain kind of thing which is capable of it, and only this is potentially healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
