<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Countries and cities on Superphysics</title>
    <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Countries and cities on Superphysics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Pantry Peers</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monuments and Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-01/</guid>
      <description>1. Dynasties are prior to towns and cities Towns and cities are secondary products of royal authority because building and city planning are features of sedentary culture arising from luxury and tranquility.
The towns and cities, with their vast constructions, are set up for the masses and not for the few. Thus, a united effort and much co-operation are needed for them.
They are not among the things that are necessary matters of general concern to human beings, in the sense that all human beings desire them or feel compelled to have them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City-planning and the consequences of neglecting such planning</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-05/</guid>
      <description>Towns are dwelling places that nations use when they have reached the desired goal of luxury and of the things that go with it. Then, they prefer tranquility and quiet and turn to using houses to dwell in.
Town are built for dwelling and shelter.
Therefore, it is necessary in this connection to see to it that harmful things are kept away from the towns by protecting them against inroads by them, and that useful features are introduced and all the conveniences are made available in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hisory of the Ka&#39;bah</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-06/</guid>
      <description>The mosques and venerated buildings of the world. God singled out some places of the earth for special honor and made them the homes of His worship. This was made known by His messengers and prophets, as an act of kindness to His servants and for the purpose of facilitating their ways to happiness.
We know from the two Sahihs that the most excellent places on earth 33 are the three mosques of Mecca, Medina, and Jerusalem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Islamic Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-07/</guid>
      <description>7. There are few cities and towns in Ifriqiyah and the Maghrib. This is because these regions belonged to the Berbers for thousands of years before Islam, as a Bedouin civilization.
No sedentary culture existed among (the Berbers) long enough to reach any degree of perfection. The dynasties of European Christians and Arabs who ruled (the Berbers) did not rule long enough for their sedentary culture to take firm root (among them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The wealth and economic activity between cities depend on their population size</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-11/</guid>
      <description>This is because each person cannot obtain all the necessities of life by himself. For instance, no one, by himself, can obtain the wheat that he needs for food.
But when six persons work together to obtain their food separately or collectively, they will be able to have an excess of food. Such persons include:
 a smith and a carpenter to make the tools, a person to be in charge of the oxen, persons to plow the soil and harvest the ripe grain and all the other agricultural activities  The combined labor produces more than the needs of the workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Prices in towns</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-12/</guid>
      <description>12. The Prices in towns All markets cater to the needs of people.
Some are for necessities:
 foodstuffs like wheat and barley foods, such as beans, chick-peas, peas, and other edible grains wholesome foods such as onions, garlic, and the like.  Some are for conveniences or luxuries:
 seasonings, fruits, clothes, utensils, mounts, all the crafts, and buildings.  When a city is large and highly developed, the prices of necessary foodstuffs and corresponding items are low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital Accumulation</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-15/</guid>
      <description>15. The accumulation of estates and farms in cities, their uses and yields. The accumulation of numerous estates and farms by the citizens does not come all at once nor at one time. No one person would have enough wealth to acquire limitless (real) property. 126
Even if prosperity were as great as possible, the acquisition and accumulation of real property would be gradual. It may come about through inheritance from one&amp;rsquo;s forefathers and blood relatives, so that eventually the property of many comes to one person, who thus possesses much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sedentary culture is the goal of civilization</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-18/</guid>
      <description>The end of its life span and brings about its corruption.
Royal authority and the foundation of dynasties are the goal of group feeling. Sedentary culture is the goal of Bedouin life. Any civilization, be it a Bedouin civilization or sedentary culture, whether it concerns ruler or commoner, 142 has a physical 143 life, just as any individual created (being) has a physical life.
Reason and tradition make it clear that (the age of) forty years means the end of the increase of an individual&amp;rsquo;s powers and growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certain cities have crafts that others lack</title>
      <link>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://superphysics.org/research/ibn-khaldun/muqaddimah/chapter-4/part-20/</guid>
      <description>20. Certain cities have crafts that others lack. This is because the activities of the citizens necessitate each other, since mutual co-operation is innate in civilization. The necessary activities are restricted to certain inhabitants of the city.
They are in charge of them and become experts in the craft(s) belonging to them. These activities become their particular job. They make their living through them and derive their sustenance from them, because (these activities of theirs) are matters of general concern in the city and generally needed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
